<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Ibiza" ColCode="IBZ" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Ibiza]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With a Mediterranean climate, Ibiza enjoys mild winters and hot summers that can see temperatures exceeding 30&ordm;C (86&ordm;F) and an average of over 11 hours of sunshine per day. Rain tends to fall in the cooler winter months between October and December though occasional showers are not unusual at any time of year.<br />
<br />
The high season runs from June to September, when temperatures are at their highest, and this is the best time to visit for the infamous Ibiza nightlife or beach holidays. To avoid the crowds, visit in May or October when the weather is still sunny, rain is rare, but the party season has either yet to begin or is coming to a close.<br />
<br />
In winter the temperature rarely drops under 0&ordm;C (32&ordm;F). From November to April the average daytime temperature is about 15&ordm;C (59&ordm;F). However, when the sun comes out this can rapidly climb to 25&ordm;C (77&ordm;F).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Light to medium weights and waterproofs if visiting in the wettest season between October and December, with warmer clothing occasionally necessary for cooler evenings. July and August are particularly hot so pack beachwear for the day and loose fitting clothes for the evening.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ibiza only has one airport so once there, it's best to navigate the island via road or sea. However, many of the luxury villas do have helipads if you want to arrive in style.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The ports of San Antonio and Ibiza Town offer hop-on boats that call in at nearby beaches during the peak summer months. Yachts, speedboats and sailing boats are also available to hire from companies such as Ibiza Yacht Rentals (<a href="http://www.ibiza-yacht-rental.com" target="_blank">www.ibiza-yacht-rental.com</a>) and Boats Ibiza (<a href="http://www.boatsibiza.com" target="_blank">www.boatsibiza.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To really explore the island, it's best to hire a car, especially if you are renting a villa. If you're staying in one of the main hotels, buses and taxis can be used to get around.</p>r<p>The island roads have sporadically been tarmacked, or had their potholes filled in, so drive with care. Some roads are poorly marked.</p><p>There is a shuttle service from the airport to many of the major resorts. In addition, the bus service on the island is fairly modern and there are several different routes. In Ibiza Town the bus station is located just a few blocks from the marina. You have to buy your ticket before entering the bus and there is an office selling tickets on the same street. In the evening, however, you can buy your ticket on the bus as the office is closed. Buses run every 15-30 minutes depending on time of day and route. From June until September, Discobus (<a href="http://www.discobus.es" target="_blank">www.discobus.es</a>) operates a night bus service stopping at all the major clubs and hotels</p><p>Available taxis can be identified by a green light and charge on a metering system.</p><p>A valid passport and driving licence is required.</p><p>Traffic drives on the right and speed limits are 50kph (37mph) in towns, unless otherwise signposted, and 90kph (57mph) in rural areas. The local police have the power to collect on-the-spot fines for any traffic violations and often mount speed traps, especially during high season and Christmas. New legislation requires all cars to contain reflective safety vests which are to be worn by the driver and any passengers, in the event of breakdown or accident, who leave their vehicle outside a built up area. An 'on the spot' fine of  &euro;90 applies to the driver of any car without such a vest.</p><p>Breakdown service will be provided by individual car hire companies.</p><p>There are plenty of car hire options both at the airport and in all the major resorts. Unfortunately it should be noted that Spain has one of Europe's worst accident rate records, so driving caution and extra insurance coverage are advisable.  The minimum age for car hire ranges between 21-25 years.</p><p>Mopeds and motorbikes are available for hire in all the major resorts and is a good option for getting to some of the more out-of-the-way beaches. Over 16s can rent a machine of less than 49cc whilst for anything over 75cc you must be 18 or over. Crash helmets are compulsory.</p><p>Traffic drives on the right and speed limits are 50kph (37mph) in towns, unless otherwise signposted, and 90kph (57mph) in rural areas. The local police have the power to collect on-the-spot fines for any traffic violations and often mount speed traps, especially during high season and Christmas. New legislation requires all cars to contain reflective safety vests which are to be worn by the driver and any passengers, in the event of breakdown or accident, who leave their vehicle outside a built up area. An 'on the spot' fine of  &euro;90 applies to the driver of any car without such a vest.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of services by air are holiday charter flights from Europe, though scheduled international flights are also available from the UK and internal flights from Spanish mainland cities such as Madrid, Barcelona and Valencia.</p>
<p>The Spanish national airline is Iberia (IB) (<a href="http://www.iberia.com/" target="_blank">www.iberia.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London is 2 hours 20 minutes and from Madrid is 40 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From November to March, direct flights to Ibiza can be harder to find. However, you can still get there via Barcelona, Madrid, Valencia or Palma. Easyjet via Mallorca is the route with the shortest stop over times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From November to March, direct flights to Ibiza can be harder to find. However, you can still get there via Barcelona, Madrid, Valencia or Palma. Easyjet via Mallorca is the route with the shortest stop over times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Ibiza Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aena.es<p>Ibiza Airport is located 7km (4.5 miles) southwest of Ibiza Town.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+34 913 211 000</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With the creation of high speed ferry links between the Spanish mainland and Ibiza, taking a ferry to the island is no longer the slow haul it once was. The main ports on the island areSan Antonio and Ibiza Town. Services operate from the Spanish mainland ports of Valencia, Barcelona and Denia (located between Alicante and Valencia).</p>
<p>Journey time from Denia, the closest mainland port, is 2 hours and 15 minutes to Ibiza Town by hydrofoil and 4 hours 30 minutes to San   Antonio by car ferry. Journey time from Valencia is around 3 hours. The longest route is from Barcelona, which can take up to around 8 hours. However, if you travel by catamaran, it can take as little as 3 hours and 45 minutes. There is also a service to Palma on the island of Mallorca (Majorca), as well as Formentera. For more route and pricing information visit <a href="http://www.balearia.com/" target="_blank">www.balearia.com</a>.</p><p>It is worth noting that catamarans only operate in the summer months, usually April to September.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ibiza is an island so is not accessible by road. However, once you have arrived, there are many car hire options and taxis available to navigate the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>For emergencies call 112. Area codes are incorporated within a nine-digit number.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good throughout most of the towns though service in mountainous areas can sometimes be patchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Television programmes tend to be broadcast in Spanish, although American films and sitcoms are sometimes in English with Spanish subtitles. State-owned TVE operates TV-1 (La Primera) and TV-2 (La Dos). Antena 3, La Cuatro, Telecinco and La Sexta are privately run channels. Cadena SER and Onda Cero are popular commercial stations, and Cadena COPE is controlled by the church. <br />
<br />
Popular Spanish newspapers are available on the island, including <em>El Pa&iacute;s</em>, <em>El Mundo</em> and <em>ABC</em>. <em>Ulitima Hora Ibiza</em> is a daily local newspaper in Spanish and <em>The Ibiza Sun</em> is a free weekly English newspaper.<br />
<br />
Due to the music culture in Ibiza, there are a multitude of radio stations broadcasting dance, electronic and house music to the party crowd. Sonica is one of the most popular radio stations playing dance and house music, while Ibiza Global Radio broadcasts electronic dance music 24 hours a day, with DJ sets from all the best clubs and DJs in Ibiza. Radio RNE is state-run, operating Radio 1, Radio Clasica, Radio 3 and Radio 5. Sunshine Radio is a seasonal English-speaking radio station.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are efficient internal and international postal services (<em>correos</em>) to all countries. Airmail within Europe usually takes around five days. Main post offices are situated  in Eivissa, Santa Eularia and San Antonio.</p><p>Post offices in Ibiza are open Mon-Fri 0830- 1430, Sat 0930-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Archaeological Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The museum explores the ancient history of Ibiza and neighbouring Formentera. With some excellent displays and explanations in English, the museum sits amongst the well-preserved Ibiza Old Town, over a Carthagean burial site thought to contain over 4,000 graves.</p>]]><p><b>Atlantis Quarry</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This former coastal quarry (the source of Ibiza Old Town's defensive walls) is now a popular destination for hikers who come to see the stone hand carvings created by the hippie population over recent decades.</p>]]><p><b>Cala d'Hort</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This is one of the local's favourite beaches on the southern tip of the island. It's by no means large, but the atmosphere is relaxed and the view of the dramatic Es Vedra rock rising out of the sea is magnificent. This is also one of the most magnetic (literally) points on the planet.</p>]]><p><b>Can Marça Caves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The multilevel labyrinth of caverns was once a hotbed for alcohol and tobacco smuggling. Today these caves now offer multilingual tours amongst the ancient formations that culminate in a spectacular sound and light presentation.</p>]]><p><b>Dalt Vila (Old Town)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The narrow and well-preserved alleys and streets of this UNESCO World Heritage site are an outstanding example of a fortified citadel. The walled 16th-century Old Town crowns Ibiza Town. It offers charming selections of shops and restaurants, museums, Santa Maria Cathedral and one of the best views on the island.</p>]]><p><b>Es Vedra</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Es Vedra is the most famous part of Ibiza's landscape, almost 400m (1300 ft) of limestone jutting out of the Mediterranean Sea. Steeped in legends, it is reputedly the tip of the sunken city of Atlantis, was the island home of Homer's wailing sirens, and is the location of numerous UFO sightings in Ibiza. Head up to the lookout point of Torre des Savinar (the old pirate watchtower) for a truly breathtaking sunset view.</p>]]><p><b>Formentera Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The 30-minute ferry crossing to Formentera takes visitors to the unspoiled beaches and clear waters of Cala Saona, Illettes and Llevant. Catch a bus, hire a car, moped or bicycle from La Savina and explore this lovely tranquil island.</p>]]><p><b>Hippy market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Like a time warp back to the 1970s, this market has an enormous variety of exotic batik clothing, tailor-made leather moccasins and East Asian silver jewellery. It's held every Wednesday on the grounds of Club Punta Arabi, Es Canar and every Saturday in San Carlos (Las Dalias).</p>]]><p><b>Ibiza Rocks House</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Recently refurbished and rebranded, the legendary Pikes Hotel now goes by the name of Ibiza Rocks House (<a href="http://www.ibizarocks.com" target="_blank">www.ibizarocks.com</a>). It&rsquo;s still where the rich and famous hang out though: Wham's 'Club Tropicana' video was filmed around the pool and though drinks are far from free, you can still breathe in the atmosphere left by guests such as Kylie Minogue, Freddie Mercury, Grace Jones and Ed Sheeran, to name but a few.</p>]]><p><b>Las Salinas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>'White Gold' can be found at the salt fields on the island's southern tip. One of Ibiza's most visited landmarks, this area has been mined for salt for over 2,000 years and now offers a sparkling natural attraction and a wealth of flora and fauna. The long, wide crescent of pale sandy beach is bordered by pine woods, the water is crystal clear and, on windy days, the waves are perfect for body-surfing.</p>]]><p><b>Museum of Contemporary Art</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This small gallery holds an impressive sample of permanent and touring contemporary art which shares the island of Ibiza as a common theme. Located in an emblematic 17th-century building in the Dalt Vila, it contains an outstanding representation of the artistic creativity that emerged on the island in the 1960s, as well as an important collection of engravings and beautiful gardens.</p>]]><p><b>Portinatx</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Portinatx is on the northern-most tip of Ibiza. This small, pretty resort is known for the crystal clear waters of its two bays (ideal for snorkelling) as well as some lovely coastal hiking along the cliff tops.</p>]]><p><b>Puig des Molins</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The archaeological site of the Puig des Molins, situated at the foot of the mountain of same name, was the cemetery of Ibiza since the foundation of the city by Occidental Phoenicians at the end of the 7th century BC. The burial grounds are spread over the hill (puig) dotted with olive trees and you can make a descent into one of the interconnecting burial chambers.</p>]]><p><b>Santa Maria Cathedral</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ibiza's cathedral is located in the crown of the Old Town and is bursting with gothic and baroque splendour. Admission is free and inside there is a fine collection of silver and gold, tracing the history of worship on this site back to the 13th century.</p>]]><p><b>Santa Rafel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The village is the island's main centre for pottery. A good choice of shops will be happy to sell you their ceramic wares whilst you enjoy the views of nearby Ibiza Old Town by day and night.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$ 1.3 trillion (Spain) (2017).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Salt, fruit, fish and shellfish.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, fuels, chemicals, semi-finished goods and food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, Germany, Italy, UK and Portugal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The tourism sector is by far the biggest industry on Ibiza and the surrounding <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/balearic-islands">Balearic Islands</a>. New hotel, residential and other developments suggest the island has reconsidered its appeal and is opting instead for quality rather than quantity with an increase in the number of chic and expensive hotels opening their doors to the moneyed demographic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business people are generally expected to dress smartly. English is widely spoken in the principal cities and resorts but far less so in the provinces. Some knowledge of the Spanish language is always appreciated and sometimes essential. Punctuality is important though attitudes to such things as responding to e-mails, letters and phone calls can be surprisingly casual.<br /></p><p>Tend to vary considerably but base hours of 0900-1330 and 1700-1900 are fairly typical.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Spanish Ministry of Industry, Tourism and Trade</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 902 446 006
					Website:http://www.comercio.es
					Address: 160,Paseo de la Castellana,28071 Madrid,]]><b>Spain Convention Bureau (FEMP)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 913 643 700
					Website:http://www.femp.es/
					Address: 28005 Madrid,Calle Nuncio 8,Spain,]]><b>Ibiza Congress Centre</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 971 336 406
					Website:http://www.santaeulalia.net
					Address: 07840 Santa Eulària des Riu,Palacio de Congresos de Ibiza,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Ibiza's history and location is reflected in its culinary offerings. Fish and shellfish are the mainstay and are usually fresh off the boats that morning. Local menus use <em>bacalao</em> (cod), <em>merluza</em> (hake), <em>emperador</em> (swordfish), and <em>lenguado</em> (sole), as well as delicious white fish not often found in other countries, like <em>denton</em>, <em>sirvia </em>(amberjack) and the delicate tasting <em>dorada</em> (sea bream), often baked in salt. The freshest fish is often sold, simply cooked, from little shacks on the beach. Meat and game also feature on local menus and are popular in hearty stews. Make sure to try the local sausages <em>sobrasada</em> and <em>butifarra</em>.</p>
<p>Traditional Spanish dishes are also in abundance on a typical Ibizan menu. All the staple Spanish classics like <em>gazpacho</em> (cold tomato and pepper soup) and <em>paella</em> are widely available all over the island.</p>
<p>Given its vast tourist appeal, there are also plenty of international restaurants in the main resorts that range from fast food to creative fine dining of the highest order. From traditional tapas bars to a Moroccan restaurant complete with sushi bar, you can find every type of cuisine on the island. Vegetarians may have to hunt that bit harder for good food. <br />
<br />
Ibiza produces wine made in the traditional way with grapes from indigenous vines and the island has even been granted its own quality standards through the <em>Vins de la terra Eivissa</em> denomination.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><em>&bull; Paella</em> (based on seafood and occasionally meat with rice and saffron) generally served to two people or more.<br />
&bull; <em>Guisat de peix</em> (fish dish usually served grilled with potatoes and then taken back to the kitchen and leftovers used for a second course stew). <br />
&bull; <em>Sofrit pages</em> (stew made from meat or chicken with peppers and potatoes).<br />
&bull; <em>Borrida de Rajada</em> (freshly caught skate baked with almonds).<br />
&bull; <em>Fla&oacute;</em> (cream tart made with fresh cheese, eggs and mint).<br />
&bull; <em>Ensa&iuml;madas</em> (croissants filled with cream, chocolate, sweet pumpkin or simply dusted with icing sugar).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Some restaurants are closed during the winter months so call ahead if you're visiting out of season.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tipping is discretionary, but is generally up to 10% in city and resort restaurants; and small change in bars, smaller restaurants and family run establishments.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nowhere in the world quite does nightlife like Ibiza. Despite recent government attempts to reel in certain aspects of club culture and the 'anything goes' attitude, the island's wild scene continues to attract party goers from&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/europe">Europe</a> and beyond, drawn to the island's reputation and residencies by world-famous DJ's. These clubs are by no means cheap to get into and drinks can prove expensive once inside, so many revellers opt to get their alcoholic fill amongst the nearby bars and pubs. The party season runs between June and September with enormous parties held at the beginning and end of this period.<br />
<br />
Ibiza after dark is certainly not just the den of inequity certain European media would have their readers believe. While some areas of San Antonio, Ibiza Town and Santa Eulalia still suffer at the hands of over-indulgent, bawdy attractions and behaviour, there is still plenty of space left for those who prefer their evenings tranquil, romantic and cultured beneath what can be described as one of the most striking sunsets in Europe. Come dusk many take to the pavement cafes and watch the world go by during the traditional Iberian pastime of <em>el paseo </em>(strolling for pleasure before dinner). Also popular is hopping between the wealth of traditional bars to sample the local wine and tapas or taking a stroll on one of the plethora of beaches before a dinner of local seafood and wine.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ceramics play a big part in the retail plans of visitors to Ibiza, despite all the clay having to be imported. It's worth looking out for local independent potters selling their creations from their own workshops. Leather goods are also well represented and the island has quite a reputation for the quality of its shoe manufacturing.</p>
<p>The main shopping streets in Ibiza Town are Vara del Rey and Rosello. Ibiza&rsquo;s equivalent of the high street has stores hidden inside old buildings; look out for straw bags trimmed with leather or brightly coloured raffia. Dalt Vila, on the other hand, is a treasure trove of artisan wares and individual boutiques, all independently owned. Look beyond the restaurants and bars to find storefronts muddled in amongst the creaky doorways selling unusual and inexpensive jewellery, bags and moccasins.</p>
<p>The long and firmly established hippy community has quite a retail presence with weekly markets held at a number of locations including Ibiza Town, the Punta Arabi at Es Canar on Wednesdays and the Las Dalias market in San Carlos on Saturdays. On offer are all manner of artisan decorations and adornments for the home and body including jewellery, paintings, pottery and clothing. Local wines, spirits, salt and olive oil also make good gifts and souvenirs.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0930-1330 and 1630-2000 tends to be the rule of smaller shops whilst the majority of larger department stores, supermarkets and malls stay open from 1000-2200.<br />
<br />
Nighttime shopping in Ibiza Town can be a fun alternative. In the high season (June until September), you can browse the market-style stalls after dark, while the shops in the port often have their doors open after midnight. There&rsquo;s a great buzz around the area at this time so it&rsquo;s worth staying up and embracing the nighttime lifestyle.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a vast array of hotel options to suit every budget and taste. It's highly recommended that you book in advance if planning a visit during the peak season between May and September. Many hotels close for the winter months, so again it is worth checking specific accommodation in advance. <br />
<br />
While the resorts of Playa d'en Bossa, Talamanca, San Antonio and Santa Eulalia are largely dominated by package holiday resort hotels and cheap <em>pensiones</em>, Ibiza's Old Town and the northern rural heartlands have seen an increasing number of upmarket boutique hotels opening in recent years.</p>
<p>An Ibiza institution, the Gran Hotel (<a href="http://www.ibizagranhotel.com/es/home" target="_blank">www.ibizagranhotel.com</a>) is a luxurious option in a convenient location (a ten-minute walk from Ibiza Town). For five-star accommodation that&rsquo;s out of the centre of town, Aguas de Ibiza (<a href="http://www.aguasdeibiza.com" target="_blank">www.aguasdeibiza.com</a>) is the go-to, or for something more remote, Hacienda (<a href="http://www.hotelhacienda-ibiza.com/" target="_blank">www.hotelhacienda-ibiza.com</a>) is perched 180m (591 ft) above sea level and is a 45-minute drive from town, boasting fantastic views of the famous Es Vedra rock. Culture vultures after authentic Ibizan life should head to Mirador de Dalt Vila (<a href="http://www.hotelmiradoribiza.com" target="_blank">www.hotelmiradoribiza.com</a>), a former 19th century estate high up in the old town with views across the historic port to Formentera.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Most hotel accommodation is classified from 1 to 5 stars or hostels with <em>pensiones </em>classified from 1 to 3 stars. Also look out for the 'Q' symbol issued by the Spanish Tourist Board which designates the establishment achieving set tourism standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are an excellent option for those on a budget or planning to spend the bulk of their time and Euros in the nearby bars and clubs. Known locally as <em>pensiones </em>or <em>casas de huespedes </em>(pensions or guesthouses) they are mainly located in the party centres of Ibiza Town and San Antonio.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a vast array of hotel options to suit every budget and taste. It's highly recommended that you book in advance if planning a visit during the peak season between May and September. Many hotels close for the winter months, so again it is worth checking specific accommodation in advance. <br />
<br />
While the resorts of Playa d'en Bossa, Talamanca, San Antonio and Santa Eulalia are largely dominated by package holiday resort hotels and cheap <em>pensiones</em>, Ibiza's Old Town and the northern rural heartlands have seen an increasing number of upmarket boutique hotels opening in recent years.</p>
<p>An Ibiza institution, the Gran Hotel (<a href="http://www.ibizagranhotel.com/es/home" target="_blank">www.ibizagranhotel.com</a>) is a luxurious option in a convenient location (a ten-minute walk from Ibiza Town). For five-star accommodation that&rsquo;s out of the centre of town, Aguas de Ibiza (<a href="http://www.aguasdeibiza.com" target="_blank">www.aguasdeibiza.com</a>) is the go-to, or for something more remote, Hacienda (<a href="http://www.hotelhacienda-ibiza.com/" target="_blank">www.hotelhacienda-ibiza.com</a>) is perched 180m (591 ft) above sea level and is a 45-minute drive from town, boasting fantastic views of the famous Es Vedra rock. Culture vultures after authentic Ibizan life should head to Mirador de Dalt Vila (<a href="http://www.hotelmiradoribiza.com" target="_blank">www.hotelmiradoribiza.com</a>), a former 19th century estate high up in the old town with views across the historic port to Formentera.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Most hotel accommodation is classified from 1 to 5 stars or hostels with <em>pensiones </em>classified from 1 to 3 stars. Also look out for the 'Q' symbol issued by the Spanish Tourist Board which designates the establishment achieving set tourism standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a vast array of hotel options to suit every budget and taste. It's highly recommended that you book in advance if planning a visit during the peak season between May and September. Many hotels close for the winter months, so again it is worth checking specific accommodation in advance. <br />
<br />
While the resorts of Playa d'en Bossa, Talamanca, San Antonio and Santa Eulalia are largely dominated by package holiday resort hotels and cheap <em>pensiones</em>, Ibiza's Old Town and the northern rural heartlands have seen an increasing number of upmarket boutique hotels opening in recent years.</p>
<p>An Ibiza institution, the Gran Hotel (<a href="http://www.ibizagranhotel.com/es/home" target="_blank">www.ibizagranhotel.com</a>) is a luxurious option in a convenient location (a ten-minute walk from Ibiza Town). For five-star accommodation that&rsquo;s out of the centre of town, Aguas de Ibiza (<a href="http://www.aguasdeibiza.com" target="_blank">www.aguasdeibiza.com</a>) is the go-to, or for something more remote, Hacienda (<a href="http://www.hotelhacienda-ibiza.com/" target="_blank">www.hotelhacienda-ibiza.com</a>) is perched 180m (591 ft) above sea level and is a 45-minute drive from town, boasting fantastic views of the famous Es Vedra rock. Culture vultures after authentic Ibizan life should head to Mirador de Dalt Vila (<a href="http://www.hotelmiradoribiza.com" target="_blank">www.hotelmiradoribiza.com</a>), a former 19th century estate high up in the old town with views across the historic port to Formentera.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Most hotel accommodation is classified from 1 to 5 stars or hostels with <em>pensiones </em>classified from 1 to 3 stars. Also look out for the 'Q' symbol issued by the Spanish Tourist Board which designates the establishment achieving set tourism standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[38.908857]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[1.432378]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>571 sq km (220 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>142,065 (2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>246.9 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ibiza.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Since a parliamentary monarchy was introduced to Spain in 1978 the country has been divided into 17 autonomous regions. Ibiza is part of the Balearic Autonomous Community which has its headquarters in Palma, Mallorca.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ibiza is 571 sq km (220 sq miles), making it the third largest of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/balearic-islands">Balearic Islands</a>, an archipelago off the coast of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a> that includes <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/balearic-islands/mallorca">Mallorca</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/balearic-islands/menorca">Menorca</a>, Ibiza (<em>Eivissa</em>) and Formentera. It is located in the Mediterranean Sea, 75km (46.6 miles) to the East of the Iberian Peninsula, 82km (51 miles) southwest of Mallorca and 87km (54 miles) away from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/alicante">Alicante</a> coast.</p>
<p>Despite only measuring approximately 35km (21 miles) in length at its longest point, and just 20km (12 miles) in width, Ibiza boasts two mountain ranges, both covered in thick hardy woodland which inspired early Greek invaders to name Ibiza and neighbouring Formentera the Islas Pitiusas (Islands of Pine Trees). The Pitiusas are surrounded by over 60 small islets, such as s&acute;Espardell, s&acute;Espalmador and Penjats between Ibiza and Formentera, Es Vedr&aacute;, Es Vedranell, s&acute;Espartat, Bosc, Bledes and Conillera in the southwest and Tagomago in the northeast.</p>
<p>The highest point of Ibiza is Atalaya of Sa Talaiassa de Sant Josep, at 475m (1,561ft), while the land to the south is the lowest point and consists of salt pans that have been exploited since ancient times and continue to be both an industry and tourist attraction. The most common crops grown are olives, figs and almonds. The long, often rugged coastline is peppered with a mixture of fine sandy beaches, pebbles, rocks and cliffs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no official religion, but the majority of the population is Roman Catholic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Spanish life has undergone rapid change in recent decades and many of the stricter religious customs are giving way to modernity, particularly in the cities and among women. In spite of this, traditions remain strong; hospitality, chivalry and courtesy thrive. Handshaking is the customary form of greeting between men, while women to whom one has already been introduced may be greeted with a fleeting kiss to either cheek. Normal social courtesies should be observed when visiting someone's home and a small gift is always appreciated.<br />
<br />
The evening meal is taken late, generally 2100-2200. Smoking in public places including is banned but many of the bars and clubs are a bit lax about this and most have terraces where you can smoke too. However enforcement of the ban is getting stricter all the time.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Generally, European plugs with two round pins are in use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Mariano Rajoy Brey since 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King Felipe VI since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ibiza has been attracting a cosmopolitan crowd for centuries &ndash; Romans, Greeks, Moors, Phoenicians and Catalans all visited the White Isle, some arriving to trade and relax in the clear warm Mediterranean waters, others with conquest in mind.</p>
<p>Due to its strategic position between mainland Spain and Africa, Ibiza was highly prized as a colony and trading post and was visited by the Ancient Greeks and later ruled by both the Carthaginians and the Romans. The island fell briefly into the hands of the Vandals, and later the Byzantines, before being ruled for many centuries by the Moors &ndash; who were in turn conquered by the Catalans in 1235.</p>
<p>Kings James I conquered the island in 1235 and ordered the deportation of the local Muslim population and Christian colonists brought in from Girona. The island maintained its own self-government in several forms until 1715, when King Philip V of Spain abolished the local government&rsquo;s autonomy.</p>
<p>During the early 20th century members of the avant-garde and, in particular, the Surrealist movement were drawn to Ibiza where they established alternative lifestyle communities based on intellectualism and creativity that were to later lay the foundations for the influx of hippies and beatniks during the 1950s and 60s. All of these influences are still visible and celebrated today, as seen in Ibiza Old Town, which exudes a thriving artistic heritage as well as a number of weekly craft markets held across the island.</p>
<p>The arrival of democracy in the late 1970s led to the Statute of Autonomy of the Balearic Islands and today the island is part of the Balearic Autonomous Community, along with Mallorca, Menorca and Formentera.</p>
<p>In recent years Ibiza has been associated with its famous club scene (infamous if all tabloid newspaper stories are to be believed) and the modern invasion of international party people that ritually descend on the island during the summer months, although the government is keen to attract more salubrious tourists and has passed local laws requiring all new hotels to be five-star and all nightclubs to close by 0600 at the latest.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; In 1969 the feature film <em>More</em> was filmed on the island and features a soundtrack by Pink Floyd including a track called <em>Ibiza Bar</em></p>
<p>&bull; Large areas of the island as registered as UNESCO World Heritage Sites, including the famous God&rsquo;s Finger in Benirr&agrave;s Bay</p>
<p>&bull; Ibiza is one of many places thought to have been the birthplace of Christopher Columbus, and a monument in his honour can be found in Sant Antoni</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy and Consulate of Spain in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 452 0100 or 728 2340/30.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.maec.es</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 452 0100 or 728 2340/30.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2375 Pennsylvania Avenue<br/>Washington DC<br/>20037<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Spanish Consulate General in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7589 8989. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.conspalon.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7589 8989. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0915-1400 (visa information by appointment only).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>20 Draycott Place<br/>London<br/>SW3 2RZ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Spanish Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7235 5555. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.maec.es/subwebs/embajadas/londres/en/home/Paginas/homeen_emblondres.aspx</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7235 5555. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>39 Chesham Place<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8SB<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Consulate in Ibiza]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>902 109 356.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>902 109 356.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0830-1330.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>45-1º Apartado, Avenida Isidoro Macabich<br/>Ibiza Town<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Though Ibiza has long been synonymous with fun in the sun hedonism, a trip to the island is not all about sultry clubs and all night raves &ndash; away from the bright lights there&rsquo;s a quieter side to this destination.</p>
<p>But first to the merrymaking, because make no mistake this Spanish island is one of the premier party destinations in Europe. During the summer superstar DJs arrive en masse to spin the vinyl and keep revellers dancing until the morning light.</p>
<p>Ibiza Town is a hotbed of late night revelry. The municipality is home to the world&ndash;famous clubs Pacha and Amnesia, which share quaint cobblestone streets with more traditional attractions such as Santa Maria d&rsquo;Eivissa Cathedral.</p>
<p>Sant Antoni (San Antonio) is the real clubbing capital, though. The so-called &lsquo;Sunset Strip&rsquo; is renowned for its rowdy clubs, but there are sophisticated alternatives nearby with chic bars offering expensive cocktails and exquisite sunset views.</p>
<p>Its reputation as a party island is notorious, but Ibiza has reconnected with its 1960&rsquo;s hippy roots in recent years, with more laid-back parties and a burgeoning arts scene.</p>
<p>Those seeking quiet time or craving a bit of culture are also well catered for: Ibiza is blessed with sandy beaches, limpid waters and alluring coves, not to mention an abundance of picturesque towns and villages.</p>
<p>Families are also well catered for in relaxing resorts such as Santa Eularia des Riu (Santa Eulalia) and Es Canar (Es Cana) on the northeast coast.</p>
<p>Whether you&rsquo;re there to dance till dawn, relax on a beach, imbibe the culture or hike amidst the greenery, Ibiza is a rite of passage for every discerning traveller.</p><p>Though Ibiza has long been synonymous with fun in the sun hedonism, a trip to the island is not all about sultry clubs and all night raves &ndash; away from the bright lights there&rsquo;s a quieter side to this destination.</p>
<p>Whether you&rsquo;re there to dance till dawn, relax on a beach, imbibe the culture or hike amidst the greenery, Ibiza is a rite of passage for every discerning traveller.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
