<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Sri Lanka" ColCode="lka" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="lk" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Sri Lanka]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The western and southern areas experience their monsoon season during May to September while the northern and eastern areas are affected by the monsoon between October to January. The island is certainly a year-round destination as while one area is might be off-limits due to poor weather, the other region is likely to be experiencing good conditions.</p><p>The recommended time for a Sri Lankan getaway is during either coast's dry season - April to November for the eastern coast and December to March for the west coast and central highlands. Christmas and the New Year are particularly popular times to go to Sri Lanka, while July and August represent festival season on the island – if travelling during either time it is recommended to book well in advance to guarantee accommodation.</p><p>Generally speaking, upland areas of Sri Lanka are cooler and more temperate, with a yearly average around 16-20ºC (60-68ºF), and coastal areas are warmer with average temperatures around 27ºC (80ºF). The March-June season experiences slightly higher temperatures of up to 33ºC (92ºF), while the temperatures in November-January are a few degrees lower at around 24ºC (75ºF) at the coast. Humidity is typically rather high in Sri Lanka, averaging out at around 80% year-round. As the nation is located in the tropics, the weather can be severely affected by El Niño. Though this irregular phenomenon only occurs around every three to seven years, it can impact an area's weather for an extended length of time, raising the possibility of severe floods and storms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The weather in Sri Lanka can be unpredictable during any season so depending on where in the country you're going, it's best to take layers. The central highlands can be significantly cooler throughout the year, so you'll need warmer clothes here. Lightweight rainwear is also recommended any time of year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Domestic air services around Sri Lanka are limited, and most tourists travel by either road or train. You can arrange charter flights with FitsAir (<a href="http://www.fitsair.com" target="_blank">www.fitsair.com</a>), Cinnamon Air (<a href="http://www.cinnamonair.com" target="_blank">www.cinnamonair.com</a>) or Simplify (<a href="http://simplifly.com" target="_blank">http://simplifly.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no official river transport network, but several tour operators offer river cruises on the Bentota and Polwatta rivers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Trains connect Colombo with all tourist towns, but first-class carriages, air conditioning and dining cars are available on only a few. You can buy tickets online from Sri Lanka Railways (<a href="http://www.railway.gov.lk" target="_blank">www.railway.gov.lk</a>). Fast services operate on the major routes, including an intercity express service between Colombo and Kandy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lanka has a widespread road network, which accounts for nearly 95% of land transport across the country. Driving tends to be erratic, and most travellers either employ a locally knowledgeable driver or use public transport.</p>l<p>The quality of the country&rsquo;s road varies considerably. The main coastal arteries are modern and well maintained, while many of the mountain roads are poor quality and pockmarked with holes. Roadworks are everywhere, demonstrating the island&rsquo;s increasing prosperity and its commitment to infrastructure development.</p><p>The cheapest and most fun way to get around Sri Lanka is by bus. Most vehicles are ancient, atmospheric and packed with chattering locals, and major routes include Colombo to Kandy, Colombo to Matara and Colombo to Jaffna. The National Transport Commission (<a href="http://www.ntc.gov.lk" target="_blank">www.ntc.gov.lk</a>) publishes timetables.</p><p>These have yellow tops and red and white plates. In Colombo, taxis are metered but it's advisable to agree a rate before setting off. Drivers expect a 10% tip. A cheaper and more authentic option is to flag down a tuk-tuk - these open rickshaws are available for hire in abundance across the country.</p><p>In order to avoid bureaucratic formalities in Sri Lanka, you should obtain an International Driving Permit before departure. If not, you can obtain a temporary licence on presentation of a valid national driving licence. This must be endorsed at the AA office in Colombo.</p><p>Most roads are tarred, with a 56kph (35mph) speed limit in built-up areas and 75kph (45mph) outside towns. The minimum age for driving a car is 18.</p><p>The Automobile Association of Ceylon (<a href="http://www.aaceylon.lk" target="_blank">www.aaceylon.lk</a>) offers a national breakdown service.</p><p>This is available from several international agencies, including Hertz, Dollar and Thrifty, which are available through local partner Andrew The Car Rental Company&nbsp;(tel: +94 11 2369 836, <a href="http://andrewrentacarsrilanka.com" target="_blank">http://andrewrentacarsrilanka.com</a>). Air-conditioned minibuses are also available, and you can hire motorised rickshaws in towns and villages. Chauffeur-driven cars are less expensive and recommended. To hire a car, you must have a valid driving licence and be 18 or over.</p><p>Cycling in the cities is inadvisable, but in rural areas bikes are becoming increasingly common. There are four National Cycle Trails. Most bike hire agencies are concentrated in Colombo and Negombo.</p><p>Most roads are tarred, with a 56kph (35mph) speed limit in built-up areas and 75kph (45mph) outside towns. The minimum age for driving a car is 18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Sri Lanka Transport Board runs public buses in Colombo, where there are also private buses and minibuses. Fares are generally collected by conductors, and you can expect services to be crowded.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Sri Lanka</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">trincomalee</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Sri Lanka</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">matara</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Sri Lanka</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">badulla</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">9.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">9.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Sri Lanka</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">anuradhapura</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national carrier, Sri Lankan Airlines (<a href="http://www.srilankan.lk" target="_blank">www.srilankan.lk</a>), operates direct flights from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/frankfurt">Frankfurt</a>. Many tourists choose to divert to Sri Lanka en-route to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a> and, as a result, several carriers offer direct flights between the countries. Travelling from North America to Sri Lanka usually involves a stop in the Middle East.</p>
<p>Flights are most expensive between December and March, which is high season on the south coast beaches and in the Hill Country, while August tends to be the cheapest time to fly.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sri-lanka/colombo-bandaranaike-airport">Colombo Bandaranaike Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sri-lanka/hambantota-mattala-rajapaksa-international-airport">Hambantota Mattala Rajapaksa International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 10 hours 30 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 19 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Bandaranaike International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airport.lk<p>Bandaranaike International Airport is located 32km (20 miles) north of Colombo city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+94 11 226 4444</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main ports in Sri Lanka are Colombo, Galle, Hambantota, Kankasanthurai, Point Pedru and Trincomalee. There is currently no public ferry service operating to Sri Lanka (routes to India have started and stopped over the years).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Phone cards are available at post offices and shops and public payphones are a common sight throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mobile usage is much more common than landlines, and it is possible to buy a Sri Lankan sim card which can then be topped up from any local vendors. Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies. Coverage in the south and west is good; in the north and east it is average.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafés in most towns and resorts. Whilst internet coverage is generally good, the same cannot be said for speeds, with many connections going via slower dial-up services rather than broadband.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The diverse press is divided along linguistic and ethnic lines. Many broadcasters and publications are state-owned. The <em>Daily News</em> is a state-run English-language daily newspaper, whilst the <em>Daily Mirror</em> is a private English-language daily newspaper, as is <em>The Island</em>. <em>Lankadeepa</em> is a private Sinhala daily and <em>Uthayan</em> is a private Tamil-language daily.</p><p>There are various state and privately-run television and radio stations available. In terms of television, Sri Lanka Rupavahini Corporation (SLRC) is a state-owned network that operates two channels, Rupavahini and Channel Eye, whilst private English-language stations include MTV and TNL. With regards to radio, Sri Lanka Broadcasting Corporation (SLBC) is a state-owned network that operates services in Sinhala, Tamil and English. Privately owned English radio stations include TNL Rocks, Sun FM and Yes FM.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Overseas mail usually takes 10 to 14 days.</p><p>Mon-Fri, 0830-1700, and Sat, 0830-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Sigiriya Rock Fortress</p><![CDATA[<p>Be amazed by Sri Lanka's best-known attraction, UNESCO-listed Sigiriya Rock Fortress. This stunning fifth-century palace-fortress perches atop a towering rock outcrop above the plains in the country's centre. Steps lead up from water gardens below and past murals of heavenly nymphs.</p>]]><br/><p>Temple of the Sacred Tooth</p><![CDATA[<p>Located in Kandy, an ancient religious centre for Buddhism, the octagonal, golden-roofed <em>Temple of the Sacred Tooth</em>, built between 1687 and 1707, is a stunning sacred temple, which is believed to house the left upper canine of the Lord Buddha himself. According to legend, the tooth was taken from the Buddha as he lay on his funeral pyre and smuggled to Sri Lanka hidden in Princess Hemamali&rsquo;s hair, where it survived numerous attempts to capture and destroy it. Today, this famous religious relic attracts white-clad pilgrims, bearing lotus blossoms and frangipani, every day. The temple is joined to the <em>Pattiripuwa </em>(Octagon), built in 1803, which was originally used as a prison, but now houses a collection of palm-leaf manuscripts. There are many other attractions in this ancient city, including <em>Natha Devale</em>, a stone sanctuary and the oldest building in Kandy, and<em> Mahavishnu Devale</em>, a temple which is dedicated to Vishnu, the protector of Buddhism in Sri Lanka.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bask on Sri Lanka’s many Beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lanka has roughly 1,600km (1,000 miles) of beautiful palm-shaded beaches, and Negombo – conveniently close to the airport – boasts one of the best. Other popular resorts include Beruwela, Bentota, Mount Lavinia and Hikkaduwa. Meanwhile Unawatuna near Galle claims to be among the top 15 beaches in the world. The beaches of the south are less populated and often more beautiful, but be aware that swimming can be dangerous in many areas.</p>]]><p><b>Climb Adam’s Peak</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lanka's highest mountain is deeply ingrained in Sri Lankan folklore. Also known as the Sacred Footprint – because of an indentation at the summit said to belong to Adam (of Adam and Eve fame) – Buddhists, Hindus, Muslims and Christians all consider it a holy place and a popular pilgrimage site, with over 5,000 steps to the top.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the reefs of Bentota</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The beaches of Bentota might have seen better days, but this is still one of the top places in the country to enjoy diving and snorkelling. Glimpse the country's thriving coral reefs and their myriad multi-hued inhabitants, explore underwater caves and lose yourself among barnacled shipwrecks. Kite-surfing, water-skiing and a host of other water sports are also available here.</p>]]><p><b>Explore ancient Anuradhapura</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wonder at the extraordinary civilization that ruled from the ancient capital of Anuradhapura thousands of years ago. Its majestic remains testify to an advanced city carefully planned and filled with beautiful palaces, temples and giant stupas.</p>]]><p><b>Get active in Kitulgala</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lanka's adventure capital is tucked away amid the ravines of the hill country. It offers an array of activities for adrenaline junkies, including kayaking, mountain biking and rainforest trekking. For a real rush, book yourself onto a beginner level or advanced white-water rafting experience on the wild Kelani River.</p>]]><p><b>Go diving around Pigeon Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Off the northeastern shore of Sri Lanka, this island is surrounded by a limestone reef which harbours 100 species of coral and more than 300 different types of fish. Declared a marine sanctuary in 1963, it's a prime destination for divers… and pigeons.</p>]]><p><b>Go on safari in Yala National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Sri Lanka's most popular wildlife-viewing destination, Yala National Park, on the southeastern coast. It is home to the world's highest density of leopards, as well as a wealth of other species – from elephants to birds. Another great place to do a bit of leopard spotting is in the Wilpattu National Park.</p>]]><p><b>Have a cuppa in Ella</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This delightful colonial village in the heart of Sri Lanka's Hill Country is a focus for the tea trade. Inhale the fragrant aromas of Victorian-era tea factories, drink their finest and roam the lush tea plantations that extend for miles around. The Nuwara Eliya hill station is also a popular destination.</p>]]><p><b>Imbibe city life in downtown Colombo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In Colombo, root out bargains in the Pettah market, marvel at the blossoms in the Vihara Maha Devi Park between March and early May, and sample the offerings of some of the country's best restaurants. Vel Festival, which takes place during July and August in the capital, is also spectacular.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in Kandy</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Kandy, a picturesque town that was the last stronghold of the Kandyan Kings. It is now a cultural sanctuary where age-old customs, arts, crafts, rituals and ways of life are well preserved. Its fabulous UNESCO-listed Temple of the Tooth (also known as Sri Dalada Maligawa) shelters the sacred tooth relic of the Buddha. Kandy hosts the annual Esala Perahera, an annual festival featuring parades of glittering elephants, dancers and drummers.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Dambulla Cave Temples</b></p><![CDATA[<p>These impressively conserved temples are a unique insight into Sri Lanka's Buddhist heritage. Tucked away beneath a massive rocky outcrop, they shelter an extensive collection of religious murals and exquisite Buddhas in a variety of positions. The views are fabulous too.</p>]]><p><b>Pay a visit to Buddha at Polonnaruwa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the huge reclining Buddha at Polonnaruwa, an ancient capital and another UNESCO World Heritage Site renowned for its remains of royal palaces, temples and stupas. It also has the superb Polonnaruwa museum, one of the country's best.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the waves in Talalla</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This glorious hidden beach on Sri Lanka's choppy south coast is a mecca for surfers. Other top spots with an international reputation include Hikkaduwa, Midigama and Arugam Bay (near Potuvil) on the east coast. Across the best time to go surfing is from April through to October, although on the south west coast the months between November and April can be equally as good.</p>]]><p><b>Take a hike in Knuckles Range</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Shaped like a giant fist, this rugged mountain range in the central south of Sri Lanka experiences much cooler temperatures than the rest of the country, making it perfect for hiking. Don your all-terrain boots and head for the hidden village of Meemure, where the villagers will happily lend beds to visitors for a modest fee.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Pinnawala Elephant Orphanage</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This orphanage for Asian elephants is one of the most popular tourism attractions in Sri Lanka, but it's not everyone's cup of tea. Though there are ample opportunities to feed the beasts and watch them bathe in a nearby river, ultimately they are not wild animals and are handled firmly by the resident mahoots.</p>]]><p><b>Walk atop Galle Fort</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ramble around coastal ramparts, colonial villas and atmospheric streets in the striking Dutch fort of Galle, another UNESCO World Heritage Site. Perhaps the most atmospheric of Sri Lankan towns, cobbled streets are lined with colonial villas and hotels. Its literary festival is one of the best in Asia. Galle is also a centre for crafts that include lace making, ebony carving and gem polishing.</p>]]><p><b>Wander around Sigiriya Rock Fortress</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Be amazed by Sri Lanka's best-known attraction, UNESCO-listed Sigiriya Rock Fortress. This stunning fifth-century palace-fortress perches atop a towering rock outcrop above the plains in the country's centre. Steps lead up from water gardens below and past murals of heavenly nymphs.</p>]]><p><b>Watch a game of cricket R. Premadasa Stadium</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cricket is played on every scrap of land in Sri Lanka, but the R. Premadasa Stadium in Colombo is probably the best place to catch a few overs. This vast international stadium hosts some of the biggest matches played in the country. It was the setting for the famous 1997 match, when Sri Lanka scored a record 952 runs for 6 wickets against India.</p>]]><p><b>Watch whales off Mirissa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This southern port town would be just another tropical beach resort - were it not for the pod of blue whales recently discovered living just offshore. Now Mirissa is rightly famous as one of the best places in the world to spot the biggest mammal of them all. Whale watchers often see sperm whales, dolphins, flying fish and even orcas too.</p>]]><p><b>Watch wildlife in Udawalawe National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spy on Sri Lanka's abundant wildlife (much of which is found nowhere else on Earth) in this spectacular national park. Birdwatching is superb, and as well as the famous elephants there are also leopards, deer, bears, wild boar, porcupines and monkeys to see.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$59.4 billion (2012).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Textiles and clothing, tea and spices, precious stones (including diamonds), coconut products and fish.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Textile fabrics, mineral products, petroleum, food, machinery and transportation equipment.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>India, USA, UK, China (PR) and Singapore.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Sri Lankan economy has largely recovered from the ravages of the 2004 tsunami and civil war, displaying strong growth rates in recent years. The country is certainly powering ahead of its neighbours, largely thanks to a booming tourism industry and the popularity of Sri Lankan tea and textiles. GDP expanded nearly 8% in the third quarter of 2013 and unemployment has shrunk over the past year to under 4%.</p><p>Agriculture (including tea, rubber, coconuts) sustains about one-third of the working population and contributes around a fifth of GDP. Forestry and fishing are also important, while the main industrial sectors are mining (gemstones and graphite particularly) and manufacturing (especially cement and textiles). Hydroelectricity is the main source of power, supplemented by imported oil.</p><p>Despite the twin misfortunes of the civil war and tsunami, the tourism industry has bounced back to become one of Sri Lanka's most important industries. The country attracted more than a million visitors in 2012 and large investments are currently being made to improve tourism infrastructure. The government is also consolidating its progress with market-oriented policies by implementing further deregulation, fiscal reform and privatisation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businesswear can be either formal or casual, with lightweight suits worn by most businesspeople. English is widely spoken in business circles. Appointments are necessary and it is considered polite to arrive punctually. It is usual to exchange business cards on first introduction. A good first port of call for all business enquiries is the Federation of Chambers of Commerce and Industry of Sri Lanka (<a href="http://www.fccisl.lk" target="_blank">www.fccisl.lk</a>).</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1630. Some offices are also open on Saturdays until 1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Sri Lanka Convention Bureau</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (11) 486 5050 ,244 0002
					Website:http://www.visitsrilanka.net/
					Address: 80 Galle Road,Hotel School Building,4th Floor,Colombo 3,]]><b>Ceylon Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (11) 242 1745,232 9143
					Website:http://www.chamber.lk
					Address: ,50 Navam Mawatha,Colombo 2,]]><b>National Chamber of Commerce of Sri Lanka</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (5) 874 801
					Website:http://www.nccsl.lk
					Address: ,450 DR Wijewardena Mawatha,Colombo 10,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Whether it's a home-cooked curry or a gourmet resort dinner, Sri Lankan cuisine is a treat for the taste buds. Flavours are exactly what you would expect from a nation at the historic trade junction between India and Southeast Asia, with abundant use of Indian spices and seasonings from China and other parts of Asia.</p><p>Fish and seafood feature heavily on menus, and coconut and coconut milk crop up prominently in many dishes. Rice is the centre of most meals, but <em>roti </em>(flatbread, like Indian <em>naan</em>) and <em>appam </em>(hoppers) – pancakes made from a rice and coconut milk batter – are also used to mop up curries and sauces. Curries typically have more chilli than in India, and often include coconut. Maldive fish – sun dried tuna – is another popular local ingredient.</p><p>Locals generally have richly spiced dishes for breakfast, but Western breakfasts are widely available. Street food is delicious, but to avoid stomach upsets steer clear of unpeeled fruit and salads, ice and ice cream.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Appam (hoppers): </strong>Bowl-shaped rice-flour and coconut milk pancakes, often served with a soft-baked egg on top.<br />
<strong>Idi Appa(stringhoppers): </strong>Squashed nests of fine rice noodles.<br />
<strong>Roti:</strong> Sri Lankan flatbread, often made with coconut, which accompanies most meals.<br />
<strong>Kottu roti: </strong>A stir-fried dish made from vegetables, egg and pieces of roti, chopped on the hotplate with special knives.<br />
<strong>Lamprais</strong>: Rice, curry and meatballs wrapped in a banana leaf and baked in the oven.<br />
<strong>Koola&rsquo;ya: </strong>Leftover curries, mixed together with rice and served in blended balls; often found at Hindu temples.<br />
<strong>Pol sambol</strong>: A Sri Lankan condiment, made from ground coconut, salt, fish, chillies and onions.<br />
<strong>Short eats: </strong>Sri Lankan savoury snacks, including small pastries and egg rolls.<br />
<strong>Pittu: </strong>Cylinders of ground rice layered with grated coconut and steamed.<br />
<strong>Kool</strong>: A seafood stew made with flour from roots of the palmyra palm, with prawns, squid, crab and vegetables, originally from Jaffna in the north.<br />
<strong>Tē (tea):</strong> The national drink, said to be amongst the best in the world.<br />
<strong>Toddy:</strong> Mildly alcoholic fermented drink that is tapped from palm trees &ndash; often illegally &ndash; and drunk across Sri Lanka.<br />
<strong>Arrack:</strong> A potent liquor made from the sap of palm trees.<br />
<strong>Fresh coconut water:</strong> Served straight from the shell all over the country.<br />
<strong>Lion:</strong> The country's national beer.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol cannot be sold on <em>poya</em> holidays (which occur each lunar month on the day of the full moon).</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Most hotels include a 10% service charge. Elsewhere tipping is optional, but appreciated; around 10% is appropriate.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>21.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lanka&rsquo;s nightlife scene is still in its infancy, but the country is slowly learning how to party with style. The most diverse array of bars, clubs and music venues can be found in Colombo, where seedy cattle market-style clubs are slowly being replaced by upmarket cocktail lounges, tapas bars and hip discos. For visitors looking for a more relaxed after-dinner experience, there are theatres in Colombo, cinemas showing films from the USA,&nbsp;ballet, concerts and theatre productions. All the hotels and resorts have bars and sometimes entertainment.</p>
<p>Outside Colombo, the main nightlife hubs can be found along the west and south coast of the country. Popular beach resorts such as Negombo, Bentota and Hikkaduwa have cultivated an almost western-style party culture, which revolves around pop up beach bars and rustic restaurants. Further east, things are a little classier - Mirissa boasts a small but vibrant nightlife scene, and Arugam Bay has its fair share of laid-back bars and cocktail huts. For the most incredible after-hours experience in Sri Lanka, though, head to the windswept beach of Rekawa. Here, intrepid visitors while the night away watching green turtles laying eggs on the sand and their hatchlings making the dangerous journey back to the ocean.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bustling markets, designer boutiques, modern shopping malls and gloriously kitsch souvenir stalls - whatever your holiday shopping style, Sri Lanka has it covered. Colombo boasts the most westernised shopping environment, with several elite arcades housed in five-star hotels as well as large stores around Galle Road, Paradise Road and Alexandra Place. Ambalangoda and Galle Fort are particularly famous for antiques, while the narrow streets of Pettah Bazaar make for colourful exploring. Most towns outside Colombo have daily markets, which sell everything from succulent fresh fruit to hand-woven fabrics and traditional dress.</p><p>Special purchases include handicrafts and curios of silver, brass, bone, ceramics, wood and terracotta. Also cane baskets, straw hats, reed and coir mats, spices and the island's excellent tea. Batik fabric, lace and lacquerware are also popular. Masks used in dance-dramas, processions and festivals can also be bought: they can depict kings, queens, demonic birds and snake spirits amongst other things. Sri Lanka is also rich in gems. Fabrics include batiks, cottons, rayons, silks and fine lace.</p><p>Haggling is common practice here, particularly when shopping in a bazaar or buying from one of the local handicraft sellers who roam the tourist beaches. If you're prepared to negotiate, it's possible to pick up some incredible bargains on antiques, gems and garments - but you'll need to have an eye for a genuine piece. Always check before buying gemstones to ensure the dealer has a licence from the government National Gem & Jewellery Authority.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1730, Sat 0900-1300.</p><p>It's normal for vendors to seriously inflate prices when selling to tourists. Be sure to research prices before buying, or ask a local tour guide to shop with you. Aggressive bargaining can sometimes be deemed offensive, so try to keep it on a friendly footing. Items that won't fit in your suitcase can be sent via international courier companies based in Colombo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It used to be that Sri Lanka&rsquo;s accommodation, while wide-ranging, didn&rsquo;t offer much in the way of sophistication. However the country&rsquo;s accommodation offering has rocketed since the end of the war in 2009, as more and more tourists began to visit the island, and options now range from five-star retreats such as Geoffrey Bawa&rsquo;s Heritance Kandalama hotel and the shabby chic allure of Talalla Retreat, to the low-budget backpacker shacks which, other than being cheap, have little to recommend them. Of the international-class 5-star hotels that exist, these are mostly located in the area around Negombo and along the southern coast near Galle. There are also many park bungalows run by the Department of Wildlife Conservation, which are furnished and equipped for comfort.</p>
<p>Grading: Hotels are classified from 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Inns and guesthouses offer comfortable but informal accommodation. Don't be surprised to find a distinct lack of amenities (or these being tacked on as paid-for extras) – hot water, towels, toilet paper and breakfast aren't always included. If staying in rural areas, these are more likely to be your best bet for accommodation as hotels are fewer and further between.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It used to be that Sri Lanka&rsquo;s accommodation, while wide-ranging, didn&rsquo;t offer much in the way of sophistication. However the country&rsquo;s accommodation offering has rocketed since the end of the war in 2009, as more and more tourists began to visit the island, and options now range from five-star retreats such as Geoffrey Bawa&rsquo;s Heritance Kandalama hotel and the shabby chic allure of Talalla Retreat, to the low-budget backpacker shacks which, other than being cheap, have little to recommend them. Of the international-class 5-star hotels that exist, these are mostly located in the area around Negombo and along the southern coast near Galle. There are also many park bungalows run by the Department of Wildlife Conservation, which are furnished and equipped for comfort.</p>
<p>Grading: Hotels are classified from 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It used to be that Sri Lanka&rsquo;s accommodation, while wide-ranging, didn&rsquo;t offer much in the way of sophistication. However the country&rsquo;s accommodation offering has rocketed since the end of the war in 2009, as more and more tourists began to visit the island, and options now range from five-star retreats such as Geoffrey Bawa&rsquo;s Heritance Kandalama hotel and the shabby chic allure of Talalla Retreat, to the low-budget backpacker shacks which, other than being cheap, have little to recommend them. Of the international-class 5-star hotels that exist, these are mostly located in the area around Negombo and along the southern coast near Galle. There are also many park bungalows run by the Department of Wildlife Conservation, which are furnished and equipped for comfort.</p>
<p>Grading: Hotels are classified from 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Hepatitis B <HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis B "><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever <HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever "><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid <HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid "><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus <HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus "><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies <HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies "><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria <HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria "><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A <HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A "><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria <HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria "><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Treatment is free at government hospitals and dispensaries whilst 24-hour treatment is available at Colombo National Hospital. Some hotels also have doctors. However the quality of healthcare varies widely across the country, and in the more rural areas, can be rather  rudimentary compared to Western standards. Visitors are advised to take out comprehensive travel insurance before travelling. To call an ambulance in an emergency, dial 110.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised, whilst bottled water and a variety of mineral waters are available at most hotels. Unpasteurised milk should be boiled, and if possible powdered or tinned milk is advised; these are generally available in Sri Lanka. Pasteurised and sterilised milk is available in some hotels and shops. Avoid dairy products made using unboiled milk. Beware of eating salads - vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled, and all should be washed in sterilised water. Street food in Sri Lanka is ubiquitous but use your judgement wisely and only eat well-cooked meat and fish, that have not been left sitting out.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against Japanese B encephalitis, tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. There is low incidence malaria throughout Sri Lanka, with the most northern parts being slightly more at risk from outbreaks. Anti-malarials are generally not needed. Cases of dengue fever have been reported, however, so visitors should avoid being bitten by mosquitoes. As of 2017, no cases of the Zika virus have been reported in Sri Lanka.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>(a) Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted; however, since Sri Lanka is not a predominantly Muslim country restrictions (which travellers may experience elsewhere) are unlikely to cause problems.<br /><br />(b) Hindu and Buddhist festivals are declared according to local astronomical observations and it is not possible to forecast the date of their occurrence exactly.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>National Day :
							04 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Sri Lanka by persons over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 2 bottles of wine and 1.5L of spirits.<br />
&bull; A small quantity of perfume and 250ml of eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; Souvenirs up to US$250 in value.</p>
<p>There is no duty-free allowance for tobacco products. You must declare valuable items such as cameras and laptops on arrival and must take these out of the country again when you leave.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Non-prescription drugs and pornography.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wild animals and their parts, coral, shells and protected marine products. Over 450 plants can only be exported with a licence.</p>
<p>You may only export antiques (items over 50 years old) with a permit from the Director of National Archives and the Director General of the Department of Archaeology.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lanka Rupee (LKR; symbol Rp) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of Rp2,000, 1,000, 500, 200, 100, 50, 20 and 10. Coins are in denominations of Rp10, 5, 2 and 1, and 50, 25, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents. There are also large numbers of commemorative coins in circulation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currency can be changed at authorised exchanges, banks and hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted. American Express is also often accepted. The tourist board urges caution when paying by credit card due to the potential for fraud.</p><p>Major cities have ATMs, although not all will accept international cards, especially the national bank. It is advisable to try to have some cash at hand whilst travelling, particularly in rural areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are often not accepted so are not recommended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Sat 0900-1300. Some city banks close at 1500, some even have night-time banking facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA "><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU "><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian "><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British "><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian "><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Sri Lanka, passports should have one blank page and be valid for no less than six months from the date of arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visa: free; double-entry tourist visa (ETA): US$20 in advance; multiple-entry business visa (ETA): US$30 in advance.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visas: two days; double-entry ETA&nbsp;tourist visa: 30 days; multiple-entry business visa (ETA): 30 days; tourist/business visa from embassy/high commission: 30 or 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In person at the nearest consulate (or consular section of high commission/embassy) or online (<a href="http://www.eta.gov.lk" target="_blank">www.eta.gov.lk</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The ETA tourist visa generally takes two days to come through.</p>
<p>If you apply through the embassy/high commission, allow four working days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors can request to extend their ETA by applying to the Department of Immigration and Emigration (<a href="http://www.immigration.gov.lk" target="_blank">www.immigration.gov.lk</a>). This is issued at the discretion of the authorities who must be satisfied that the applicant has sufficient funds and holds an onward or return ticket for travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[7.789021]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[80.681005]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>65,610 sq km (25,332 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>20,810,816 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>336.1 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Colombo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lanka is an island off the southeast coast of the Indian state of Tamil Nadu. It is separated from India by the Indian Ocean, in which lies the chain of islands called Adam's Bridge. Sri Lanka has an irregular surface with low-lying coastal plains running inland from the northern and eastern shores. The central and southern areas slope into the hills and mountains ranges of the Central Highlands. The highest peak is Pidurutalagala, which reaches an altitude of 2,524m (8,281ft).</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s coast consistx mainly of beaches and bays, with rocky cliffs in the northeast and southwest. Due to the southwestern location of the mountain range, precipitation is heavily weighted towards this area, with the the northern and eastern parts fall in the rain shadow of the Central Highlands. The wettest parts of the country in the south and west receive around 4,000mm of rainfall annually. There are two major national parks, in the northwest and southeast, designated as such to protect the immense biodiversity of the country&rsquo;s wildlife.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of the Sinhalese population practises Buddhism (70%). Minority religions include Hinduism (almost exclusively practised by the Tamil population), Christianity, with the majority denomination being Roman Catholic (around 6% of the population as opposed to 0.8% who are Anglicans) and Islam (practised by around 10% of the population).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shaking hands is the normal manner of greeting. It is customary to be offered tea when visiting and considered impolite to refuse. Punctuality is always appreciated, although it may not be reciprocated. If visiting someone's home, or place of business, bring a small token, such as a souvenir from home. Informal, Western dress is suitable, except when visiting Buddhist temples, where modest clothing should be worn (eg no bare legs and upper arms). Visitors should be decently clothed when visiting any place of worship, and shoes and hats must be removed. Jackets and ties are not required by men in the evenings except for formal functions when lightweight suits should be worn.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with three round or three square pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Maithripala Sirisena since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Maithripala Sirisena since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Woven through Sri Lanka&rsquo;s absorbing history is a story of strife between the country&rsquo;s two biggest ethnic groups: the Buddhist Sinhalese and the Hindu and Muslim Tamils. Almost every ancient site has two conflicting legends surrounding it, and historians often struggle to distinguish fact from myth. What is generally agreed is that Buddhism arrived on the island in the 3rd century BC, reputedly carried here by the son of the Indian emperor Ashoka.</p>
<p>The earliest Sri Lankan civilisation was based around the city of Anuradhapura, which still endures as an atmospheric ruin, along with its successor city, Polonnaruwa. The collapse of Polonnaruwa after more than two centuries saw Sinhalese power shift to the southwest of the island, creating a cultural split with the largely Tamil coastal settlements in the north, who looked to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a> for guidance.</p>
<p>This historical division survived the colonising attempts of the Portuguese, Dutch and British, and continued through WWII and independence from British colonial rule in 1948. Increasing centralisation of power within the Sinhalese community and marginalisation of Tamils led to riots in the 1950s and ultimately civil war. By the early 1980s the Sinhalese government were locked in a seemingly endless cycle of violence with the rebel organisation that came to be known as the Tamil Tigers.</p>
<p>A long-awaited deal between Sri Lanka's government and the rebel Tamil Tigers (LTTE) was concluded in early 2002, but fighting became much more serious in 2006 and much of the country became no-go areas for tourists, particularly the Tamil heartland in the north of the island. In 2009, the government escalated their offensive, and succeeded in killing the leader of the LTTE, Velupillai Prabhakran, bringing 26 years of conflict to an end.</p>
<p>Since then, peace has endured, but allegations persist of civilian massacres and human rights violations by both sides, but particularly by government forces, in the final years of the conflict. Many international politicians have called for an independent enquiry into war crime allegations, and this may finally materialise with the change of leadership from the militaristic Mahinda Rajapaksa to the more conciliatory Maithripala Sirisena.</p>
<p>Still, this vibrant little island has proved adept at bouncing back from adversity. Over a decade on from the Boxing Day tsunami in 2004, which killed more than 30,000 people across the country and destroyed many coastal towns, the country is powering ahead of the rest of the region both socially and economically. With tourism booming and infrastructure expanding, the future of Sri Lanka looks bright.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong> <br />
&bull;	Though Sri Lankans are mad about cricket, the national sport is actually volleyball. <br />
&bull;	Cinnamon originally comes from Sri Lanka and is used in many local dishes. <br />
&bull;	Sri Lanka was known as Ceylon until 1972.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[High Commission of Sri Lanka in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7262 1841.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.srilankahighcommission.co.uk/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7262 1841.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1700; 0930-1300 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>13 Hyde Park Gardens<br/>London<br/>W2 2LU<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Sri Lanka in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 483 402 528.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.slembassyusa.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 483 402 528.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2148 Wyoming Avenue<br/>Washington<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Southern India meets Buddhist Asia; Sri Lanka is a land of ancient ruins and religious relics, palm-fringed beaches and colourful reefs, balmy rainforests and local legends.</p>
<p>With memories of civil war receding, and a new government intent on healing the scars of the past, this sun-kissed island nation looks set to regain its position as the holiday capital of the Indian Ocean.</p>
<p>Life in Sri Lanka is dictated by the sea. Monsoon winds create the seasons, rainbow-coloured fishing boats deliver the bounty of the Indian Ocean to the nation&rsquo;s tables and tropical surf washes endlessly against the island&rsquo;s golden beaches. For many, this is the perfect introduction to the Indian Subcontinent.</p>
<p>While Hinduism holds sway in nearby India, Buddhism dominates Sri Lanka. Ancient temples and enigmatic <em>dagobas</em> (stupas) enshrine relics of Buddha, shaded by saplings taken from the tree under which the Buddha attained enlightenment. At times, Sri Lanka&rsquo;s Hindu, Christian and Buddhist minorities have struggled in the face of Buddhist domination, but it has shaped this island nation for millennia.</p>
<p>Across Sri Lanka, the ruins of ancient cities emerge from the jungle, while the remnants of Indian, Portuguese, Dutch and British settlements add to the delightful mishmash of historic architecture. Perhaps the most evocative monuments are Sri Lanka&rsquo;s ancient monasteries, which are still major centres for pilgrimage and devotion, particularly during the island&rsquo;s epic festivals.</p>
<p>In the Hill Country, the centre of the British occupation, colonial-era trains still wind their way through tea plantations and cascading paddy fields, but this highly populated little island is far from frozen in time: the coastline is peppered with modern resorts, beach bars, bronzed surfers and boutiques full of designer swimwear.</p>
<p>Elsewhere the forests of Yala, Udawalawe and other national parks teem with monkeys, leopards and wild elephants, while sea turtles, dolphins and blue whales can be spotted around the coast. Not bad for an island similar in size to South Carolina.</p><p>Southern India meets Buddhist Asia; Sri Lanka is a land of ancient ruins and religious relics, palm-fringed beaches and colourful reefs, balmy rainforests and local legends.</p>
<p>With memories of civil war receding, and a new government intent on healing the scars of the past, this sun-kissed island nation looks set to regain its position as the holiday capital of the Indian Ocean.</p>
<p>Life in Sri Lanka is dictated by the sea. Monsoon winds create the seasons, rainbow-coloured fishing boats deliver the bounty of the Indian Ocean to the nation&rsquo;s tables and tropical surf washes endlessly against the island&rsquo;s golden beaches. For many, this is the perfect introduction to the Indian Subcontinent.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
