<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="St Kitts And Nevis" ColCode="kna" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="kn" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[St Kitts And Nevis]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hot and tropical climate tempered by trade winds throughout most of the year. The driest period is from January to April and there is increased rainfall in summer and towards the end of the year. The volume of rain varies according to altitude; rain showers can occur throughout the year. The average annual rainfall is about 125cm (50in) to 200cm (80in) with a wetter season from May to October. Like the other Leeward Islands, St Kitts lies in the track of violent tropical hurricanes which are most likely to develop between August and October.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical lightweights, with light rainwear advisable all year round.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Several ferries make the 45-minute crossing between the islands of St Kitts and Nevis. See <a href="http://www.sknvibes.com/travel/ferry.cfm" target="_blank">www.sknvibes.com/travel/ferry.cfm</a> for the latest timetables.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The St Kitts Scenic Railway makes a 50km (30-mile) loop round the island. Passengers complete about two-thirds of the journey by train and the remaining portion by bus. The track was constructed to transport sugar cane from the island's plantations to the sugar factory in Basseterre.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There's little traffic on the islands and not even a single set of traffic lights, so exploring by car is easy.</p>l<p>A good road network on both islands makes most areas of St Kitts and Nevis easily accessible. Roads tend to be narrow, winding and not well lit at night, so extra care should be exercised. The maximum legal speed limit is 63kph (40mph) outside built-up areas and 31kph (20mph) in towns.</p><p>Colourfully decorated, privately owned vans operate on several bus routes on St Kitts. Some bus stops are established, but you can flag down vans at any point along the road. This low-cost transport service is used extensively by locals and less frequently by tourists. Licensed vans are identified by their green licence plates starting with H or HA.</p><p>Taxis serve most destinations across the islands. There is a 50% surcharge between 2200-0600. Taxi drivers expect a 10% tip.</p><p>To drive in St Kitts and Nevis, you need a full driving licence from your home country. You must also purchase a temporary St Kitts and Nevis licence, available through car hire companies and the Traffic Department.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18.</p><p>A selection of cars, motorcycles and mopeds are available to hire from several companies. It's best to book cars well in advance. Car hire companies include Avis and Hertz, as well as a number of smaller, local vendors. You usually need to be at least 25 years old to hire a car.</p><p>You can hire motorbikes, mopeds and bikes to get around the islands. Safety equipment such as a helmet is often not included in the price. Local companies include Sunny Blue Scooter Rentals (tel: +1 869 664 8755; <a href="http://www.sunnybluerental.com" target="_blank">www.sunnybluerental.com</a>).</p>
<p>St Kitts and Nevis are hot and hilly, which presents a challenge for cyclists. Nevis is the more accessible cycling destination; you can hire bikes from Bike, Kayak 'N' Windsurf Nevis (tel: +1 869 664 2843; <a href="http://bikenevis.com" target="_blank">bikenevis.com</a>).</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">St Kitts And Nevis</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">sandy_point</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">St Kitts And Nevis</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">newcastle_nevis</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.05</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">St Kitts And Nevis</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">frigate_bay</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">St Kitts And Nevis</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">cockleshell_bay</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">St Kitts And Nevis</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">charlestown_nevis</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Robert Llewellyn Bradshaw International Airport on St Kitts is the main air hub for St Kitts and Nevis. It's linked to destinations in Europe and North America by Air Canada (<a href="http://www.aircanada.com" target="_blank">www.aircanada.com</a>), American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>), British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>),&nbsp;Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) and United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>).</p>
<p>Seaborne Airlines (<a href="http://www.seaborneairlines.com" target="_blank">www.seaborneairlines.com</a>) and Winair (<a href="http://www.fly-winair.sx" target="_blank">www.fly-winair.sx</a>) connect St Kitts and Nevis with each other and with destinations across the Caribbean.</p>
<p>Low season in St Kitts and Nevis runs from June to mid-December, which is when airfares are cheapest.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 10 hours (including a stop in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/antigua-and-barbuda">Antigua</a>); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 4 hours 10 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>EC$60, payable in cash or by credit card at the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Nevis Vance W. Amory International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.nevisports.com<p>The airport is 11km (5 miles) from Charlestown on Nevis.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>St Kitts Robert L. Bradshaw International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.scaspa.com<p>The airport is 3.2km (2 miles) from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/basseterre">Basseterre</a> on St Kitts.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unscheduled ferry services run infrequently between St Kitts and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/st-maarten">St Maarten</a>. However, planes are far more frequent and reliable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unregistered roaming is available - visitors with TDMA handsets can make calls without registering, provided they can give a credit card number.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public access is available at many hotels and the Internet kiosk at the <em>Cable & Wireless </em>offices in Basseterre, St Kitts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The government operates national television and radio networks. There are several private radio stations. The main political parties publish weekly or fortnightly newspapers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes five to seven days.</p><p>Mon-Wed, Fri and Sat 0800-1500, Thurs 0800-1100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Check out the sub-aquatic sights</b></p><![CDATA[St. Kitts and Nevis aren&rsquo;t renowned as diving destinations, but snorkelers and scuba divers will find plenty of interesting sights below the waves, including a rare opportunity to dive on a black coral reef.<br />
Among the hundreds of shipwrecks around the islands are the freighters <em>River Taw </em>and<em> M.V. Talata,</em> which are popular sites. Sharks and turtles are relatively abundant and can often be seen on dives. For more information contact Dive St. Kitts (tel: 869 403 5966; <a href="http://www.divestkitts.com" target="_blank">www.divestkitts.com</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Climb Mount Liamuiga</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lofty Mount Liamuiga is a supposedly extinct volcano at the centre of St. Kitts (some believe it is merely dormant). Standing 1,156m (3,792ft), the mountain is covered in farmland at the foothills, rainforest in lower elevations and cloud forest towards the summit.<br />
A lake partially fills the 1,000-foot-deep volcanic crater, which can be reached by a series of hiking trails; the strenuous, two-hour climb is rewarded by panoramic views of neighbouring islands.</p>]]><p><b>Don your hiking boots</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are many hiking trails leading into the mountains and through the islands' verdant rainforests. Local guides can be arranged through hotels, but experienced ramblers can tackle the trails solo. On St. Kitts, the summit of Mt. Liamuiga represents a popular challenge for hikers, while Nevis Peak offers a similar experience.</p>]]><p><b>Experience bustling Basseterre</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Basseterre, the picturesque capital of St Kitts and Nevis, retains the flavour of both French and British occupation. The latter&rsquo;s influence is felt most around Independence Square, which is surrounded by beautiful Georgian buildings.<br />
Although small &ndash; Basseterre has a population of approximately 16,000 &ndash; the city is the main commercial and industrial centre on the islands. It hosts regular markets, cricket matches and is home to landmarks including St George's Anglican Church, Basseterre Co-Cathedral of Immaculate Conception and The National Museum, housed in the Treasury Building.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Brimstone Hill</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the best-preserved citadels in the Americas, Brimstone Hill is a defunct British fort and UNESCO World Heritage Site. Dubbed 'The Gibraltar of the West Indies,&rsquo; Brimstone Hill was built by African slaves during the 17th century and was the scene of a number of Anglo-French maritime battles.<br />
Surrounded by former sugar plantations, the fort commands splendid views across the limpid Caribbean waters and is home to a rich variety of flora and fauna including vervet monkeys.</p>]]><p><b>Fly through the sky</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If you want to see St Kitts in style, get in touch with Sky Safaris (tel: 896 466 4259; <a href="http://www.skysafaristkitts.com" target="_blank">www.skysafaristkitts.com</a>). This adventure company operates an advanced network of zip lines, which take passengers on a high-adrenaline tour of the rainforest, whilst offering excellent views of sugar estates and the iconic fort at Brimstone Hill.</p>]]><p><b>Frolic in limpid waters</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Come on in, the water is lovely. St Kitts and Nevis boasts some of the cleanest seawater in the Caribbean. The water is warm and mostly calm, too, which makes it great not only for swimming, but other watersports such as sailing, water skiing and deep sea fishing.</p>]]><p><b>Gallop through the rainforest</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Horse riding in the rainforest or along the beach can be arranged through various hotels and tour operators across the islands. The Nevis Equestrian Centre (tel: 869-662-9118; <a href="http://www.nevishorseback.com" target="_blank">www.nevishorseback.com</a>) organises romantic, sunset rides for adventurous couples.</p>]]><p><b>Get on your bike</b></p><![CDATA[<p>You can rent bikes on St. Kitts or Nevis, but Nevis is the more bike-friendly of the two islands, with less traffic, fewer hills and a 20-mile road circling the island. Nevis by bike is a great way to see the island at a comfortable speed; both St. Kitts and Nevis also have ample mountain-biking trails to explore.</p>]]><p><b>Hone your horticulture knowledge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Flowering orchids and flamboyant bushes are among the visual highlights at The Botanical Gardens of Nevis (tel: 869 469 3509; <a href="http://www.botanicalgardensnevis.com" target="_blank">www.botanicalgardensnevis.com</a>). These pretty gardens incorporate a rainforest conservatory &ndash; modelled on Palm House at Kew Gardens in London &ndash; which is alive with butterflies and parrots. The on-site restaurant serves Thai cuisine at lunchtime and houses an art gallery devoted to the &lsquo;first lady of Nevisian art&rsquo; Eva Wilkin.</p>]]><p><b>Hop aboard the scenic railway</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Completed in 1926, this narrow-gauge railway was originally used to transport sugar cane from the island&rsquo;s plantations to a processing factory located in Basseterre. When the sugar industry was mothballed, the line was converted into a scenic railway (tel: 869 465 7263; <a href="http://www.stkittsscenicrailway.com" target="_blank">www.stkittsscenicrailway.com</a>).<br />
Tours begin in Basseterre and take approximately three hours, covering 18 miles by rail and 12 miles by bus. The picturesque route circumnavigates the island and takes in most of the island&rsquo;s sites, including Brimstone Hill, Mount Liamuiga and some of the larger sugarcane estates.</p>]]><p><b>Imbibe local history</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Four thousand years of human history on Nevis are detailed in the Museum of Nevis History in Charlestown. Housed in a Georgian style home, the museum's exhibits include pre-European artefacts, information about local conservation efforts, a timeline of the island's political history, as well as architectural and cultural information. The museum also celebrates famous local residents, which included Horatio Nelson and American Founding Father, Alexander Hamilton.</p>]]><p><b>Saunter around Charlestown</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The charming capital of Nevis is characterised by its wooden buildings, friendly ambiance and brilliant blooms of bougainvillaea. The town is peppered with historical monuments and attractions such as the Cotton Ginnery, Alexander Hamilton's birthplace (now a museum), the Court House, the War Memorial and the Jewish Cemetery.<br />
It&rsquo;s also home to a number of old plantation houses which have been transformed into superb hotels and restaurants.</p>]]><p><b>Shake your booty in Frigate Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Frigate Bay<strong> </strong>is the main resort area on St Kitts and boasts two fine beaches, numerous hotels, a golf course and a casino. Known as &lsquo;The Strip,&rsquo; it consists of a series of popular beach bars and is the island&rsquo;s nightlife hub.<br />
Frigate Bay North is home to a smattering of beach resorts and holiday homes, while Frigate Bay South is more popular with locals.</p>]]><p><b>Soak in the rays on Pinney's Beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located north of Charlestown is Pinney's Beach, arguably one of the finest on the island. This expanse of silver sand, lined with palm trees and beach bars, is probably the most popular stretch of sand on the island.<br />
For something a little bit wilder, head further north to Black Sand Beach and Hurricane Hill, which offer stunning vistas across St Kitts and Barbuda.</p>]]><p><b>Step back in time at Romney Manor</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This 17th century former sugar estate is now home to Caribelle Batik, St Kitts (tel: 869 465 6253; <a href="http://www.caribellebatikstkitts.com" target="_blank">www.caribellebatikstkitts.com</a>), an artisanal workshop that produces vivid fabrics and fine garments for men and women. Visitors can take tours of Romney Manor, learning about the sugar and rum production process, and finding out more about the estate's previous owners, which include Sam Jefferson II (a relative of American Founding Father, Thomas Jefferson).</p>]]><p><b>Walk the Nevis Heritage Trail</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Many of Nevis&rsquo; historic attractions are found along the road which circles the island. This road forms part of the official Heritage Trail, which takes visitors to the abandoned British citadel, Fort Charles, the Hermitage Estate, now a boutique inn, and a pair of Anglican churches (St. John&rsquo;s and St. Paul&rsquo;s).<br />
The Saddle Hill fortress, near Montpelier Plantation, is known locally as &lsquo;Nelson&rsquo;s Lookout,&rsquo; and is well preserved and worth a detour. The trail begins and ends in Charlestown.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$767 million (2013).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, food, electronics, beverages, tobacco.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, manufactured goods, foods and fuel.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, UK and CARICOM countries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The St. Kitts and Nevis economy was once tied heavily to agriculture, primarily the sugar industry. A long-term decline in prices led to a shutdown of the sugar industry in 2005; the resulting economic hardship has led the government to invest heavily in tourism. <br />
<br />
The government has also responded by trying to broaden the base of the economy; bananas, yams and sweet potatoes are now important crops and the cultivation of rice and coffee is developing. Fishing is also growing in commercial importance.</p>
<p>A thriving electronics and data-processing sector is the principal success story from the government's diversification policy, as is tourism which is developing rapidly, particularly on St. Kitts, and now brings about US$161 million a year into the economy.<br />
<br />
More recently, and especially on Nevis, an 'offshore' financial services industry has developed: there are now more than 10,000 foreign businesses registered on the island and the government has been obliged to meet new international standards regarding the investigation of money-laundering. Unemployment is among the lowest in the Caribbean.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Since gaining independence from the United Kingdom, St Kitts and Nevis has become something of an offshore tax haven, offering exemptions from income, inheritance and capital gains tax. The nation also has a well-established citizenship programme, providing passports and citizenships to foreign investors.</p>
<p>When doing business men dress smartly, wearing smart trousers, shoes and a shirt and tie, or open-neck tunic shirt. For women, dress tends toward the conservative; knee-length skirts or longer are acceptable, along with polo shirts or button-up blouses.</p>
<p>The St. Kitts Marriott Resort, 858 Frigate Bay Road (tel: 869 466 1200; <a href="http://www.marriott.com/hotels/travel/skbrb-st-kitts-marriott-resort-and-the-royal-beach-casino/" target="_blank">www.marriott.com</a>) and the Four Seasons Nevis, Charlestown (tel: 869 469 1111; <a href="http://www.fourseasons.com/nevis/" target="_blank">www.fourseasons.com</a>) each has more than 5,000 square feet of meeting space, making them the primary destination for meetings and conventions in St. Kitts and Nevis.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1300-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>St Kitts &amp; Nevis Chamber of Industry and Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 465 2980
					Website:http://www.stkittsnevischamber.org
					Address: Horsford Road,PO Box 332,Basseterre,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>St Kitts and Nevis has built an excellent reputation for cuisine in recent years. Chefs on the islands guard local recipes zealously, but as well as Creole and West Indian fare, they also specialise in Chinese, Western and Indian dishes.</p><p>Charlestown's restaurants cater more for Nevisians than visitors and on both islands many of the most sophisticated restaurants are associated with hotels or resorts.</p><p>Fresh fruit is ubiquitous on both islands where colourful stalls can be found in markets and along beach promenades selling mangoes, papayas, bananas and much more. A wide range of imported drinks is available, not to mention a potent liquor known as CSR – a spirit made from sugar cane.</p><p>Local cooking is simple, spicy and makes use of the plentiful fresh fish, vegetables and fruit.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Goat waterstew:</strong> The national dish, goat, breadfruit, papaya and droppers (dumplings) in a tomato-based stock.<br/><strong>Rikkita beef: </strong>Beefsteak marinated in Champagne and hot peppers, then fried.<br/><strong>Roti:</strong> Thin pastry filled with curried potatoes, chickpeas and beef, chicken, goat, shrimp or vegetables.</p><p><strong>Mango ginger chicken: </strong>Whole chicken jointed and marinated in mango, ginger coconut milk, oil and pepper.</p><p><strong>Conkies: </strong>Like tamales, cornmeal mixed with grated sweet potato, pumpkin and coconut.<br/><strong>Pelau:</strong> Pice, pigeon peas and meat, similar to paella.</p><p><strong>Peas & rice: </strong>The Caribbean staple, made here with celery and thyme.<br/><strong>Conch:</strong> Curried, soused or in salad.</p><p><strong>Coconut rum bread pudding: </strong>Hearty pudding cake made with wheat bread, vanilla, cinnamon and raisins topped with coconut and a rum-butter sauce.</p><p><strong>Belmont Estate, Brinley Gold:</strong> Local rums.</p><p><strong>Carib, Stag, Skol:</strong> Beers are brewed on St Kitts.</p><p><strong>Killer bee: </strong>Cocktail made with rum, honey, soda, passion fruit puree, orange juice and pepper.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>In restaurants, leave 10-15%.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>&lsquo;</strong>The Strip&rsquo; in Frigate Bay, St Kitts is lined with an eclectic collection of lively beach bars and restaurants offering everything from potent cocktails and grilled lobster to live music and dancing.</p>
<p>Vibes Beach Bar (tel: 869 465 8423) and Mr. X's Shiggidy Shack are among the local hot spots. A number of hotels and inns have string or steel bands playing on Saturday nights in the peak season. Frigate Bay is also home to the Royal Beach Casino at the St. Kitts Marriott Resort (tel: 869 466 1200; <a href="http://www.marriott.co.uk/hotels/travel/skbrb-st-kitts-marriott-resort-and-the-royal-beach-casino/" target="_blank">www.marriott.com</a>), which has table games, roulette and slot machines.</p>
<p>In Nevis, most nightlife centers on the island&rsquo;s dozen or so lively bars. Standouts include Sunshine&rsquo;s Beach Bar, Lime Beach Bar and Double Deuce, which are located on Pinney&rsquo;s Beach. Entertainment can also be found in local inns and hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local crafts include carvings, batik, wall hangings and leather products. Local textiles and designs are also available. Stamp collectors should note the excellent Philatelic Bureaux in Basseterre and Charlestown. Nevis' hot pepper sauce, ranked among the Caribbean's best, is a good take-home item and can be found in local markets and stores.</p>
<p>Shopping malls on St Kitts include TDC Mall and Pelican Mall. For something more authentic swing by at the Anima Craft Market, which showcases the handiwork of local artisans. Friday and Saturday are the busy market days, and visitors should not miss the chance to witness the abundance of exotic food stalls (near the Basseterre and Charlestown ferry docks).</p>
<p>The Caribelle Batik factory at Romney Manor, St Kitts (tel: 869 465 6253; <a href="http://www.caribellebatikstkitts.com" target="_blank">www.caribellebatikstkitts.com</a>) is fabulous for fabrics; visitors can buy some wonderful clothing and textiles, or just watch how they are made.</p>
<p>Longtime St Kitts resident, Kate Spencer, from England, sells and exhibits her watercolours and oil paintings at Rawlins Plantation, Mount Pleasant (tel: 869 465 6221). Meanwhile, the Spencer Cameron Art Gallery, 10 North Independence Square (tel: 869 664 4157) in Basseterre focuses on West Indian art.</p>
<p>The Eva Wilkin Gallery, located in an 18th century windmill at the Clay Ghaut Estate, Nevis (tel: 869 469 2673), features drawings and paintings by the beloved Nevisian artist.</p>
<p>Duty-free shopping is centered on the Port Zante docks and The Circus in downtown Basseterre, which is within walking distance of the capital&rsquo;s cruise port.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0830-1200 and 1300-1600; some shops close early on Thursday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good range of hotels on the two islands, the majority being on St Kitts; most are small and owner-managed, offering a high standard of facilities and comfort. Many are converted from the great houses and sugar mills on the old estates. In general, prices are considerably reduced in the low season (mid April to mid December). Group discounts and package rates are offered by most hotels on request. A government tax of 7% is levied on all hotel bills and the hotels themselves add 10% service charge, although this varies slightly between establishments. A full list of hotels can be obtained from the tourism authorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are several guest houses on both islands. A list is available from the tourism authorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good range of hotels on the two islands, the majority being on St Kitts; most are small and owner-managed, offering a high standard of facilities and comfort. Many are converted from the great houses and sugar mills on the old estates. In general, prices are considerably reduced in the low season (mid April to mid December). Group discounts and package rates are offered by most hotels on request. A government tax of 7% is levied on all hotel bills and the hotels themselves add 10% service charge, although this varies slightly between establishments. A full list of hotels can be obtained from the tourism authorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good range of hotels on the two islands, the majority being on St Kitts; most are small and owner-managed, offering a high standard of facilities and comfort. Many are converted from the great houses and sugar mills on the old estates. In general, prices are considerably reduced in the low season (mid April to mid December). Group discounts and package rates are offered by most hotels on request. A government tax of 7% is levied on all hotel bills and the hotels themselves add 10% service charge, although this varies slightly between establishments. A full list of hotels can be obtained from the tourism authorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;St Kitts and Nevis are considered safe islands for foreign travellers - perhaps the biggest health risk is sunstroke or dehydration, so pack plenty of sunscreen and water.&amp;nbsp;In the event of a medical emergency call 911. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are large general hospitals in Basseterre and Charlestown, and a smaller public hospital at Sandy Point, St Kitts. There are no private hospitals, but several doctors and dentists are in private practice. Payment upfront will often be required, therefore health insurance is advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is chlorinated and safe. Bottled water is available. Drinking water outside main cities and towns may be contaminated and sterilisation is advisable. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Carnival Day :
							2018<br/>02 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							07 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Emancipation Day :
							06 August </p><p>National Heroes Day :
							16 September </p><p>Independence Day :
							19 September </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into St Kitts and Nevis by travellers aged 18 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos.<br />
&bull; 50 cigars.<br />
&bull; 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1.5L of wine or spirits.<br />
&bull; Goods to the value of EC$400 for residents who have been abroad for more than seven days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted imports include pornography, drugs, firearms, hazardous waste and ozone-depleting substances.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eastern Caribbean Dollar (XCD; symbol EC$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of EC$100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of EC$1, and 25, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents. US Dollars are also legal tender on the islands.<br /><br />The Eastern Caribbean Dollar is tied to the US Dollar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major currencies can be exchanged at banks on the islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major cards are widely accepted. ATMs are widely available.</p><p>ATMs are widely available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1400, Fri 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter St Kitts and Nevis, a passport valid for six months beyond the date of departure is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitor visa: US$100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Depends on individual application. Usually up to three months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy or high commission); you should make the initial application online (<a href="https://evisa.gov.kn" target="_blank">evisa.gov.kn</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow two weeks for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All visitors may be required to show proof of sufficient funds. Travellers requiring a visa must provide bank statements from the previous three months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you plan to bring your pet, you must apply to the Chief Veterinary Officer for an import permit. Your pet must also have a microchip and up-to-date rabies vaccination.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[17.357822]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-62.782998]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>261 sq km (101 sq miles). Saint Kitts: 168 sq km (65 sq miles). Nevis: 93 sq km (36 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>56,183 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>199 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Basseterre.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>St Kitts </strong>(officially known as St Christopher) lies in the northern part of the Leeward Islands in the eastern Caribbean. The high central body of the island is made up of three groups of rugged volcanic peaks split by deep ravines. The vegetation on the central mountain range is rainforest, thinning higher up to dense bushy cover. From here, the island's volcanic crater, Mount Liamuiga, rises to almost 1,200m (4,000ft). The foothills, particularly to the north, form a gently rolling landscape of sugar-cane plantations and grassland, while uncultivated lowland slopes are covered with thick tropical woodland and exotic fruits such as papaya, mangoes, avocados, bananas and breadfruit. To the southeast of the island, a low-lying peninsula, on which there are many excellent beaches, stretches towards Nevis.<br />
<br />
Some 3km (2 miles) to the south and only minutes away by air or ferry across The Narrows channel is the smaller island of <strong>Nevis</strong>, which is almost circular in shape. The island is skirted by miles of silver-sand beaches, golden coconut groves and a calm, turquoise sea in which great brown pelicans dive for the rich harvest of fish. The central peak of the island, Nevis Peak, is 985m (3,232ft) high and its tip is usually capped with white clouds. The mountain is flanked on the north and south sides by two lesser mountains, Saddle Hill and Hurricane Hill, which once served as look-out posts for Nelson's fleet. Hurricane Hill on the north side commands a view of St Kitts and Barbuda. On the island's west side, massed rows of palm trees form a coconut forest. There are pleasant coral beaches on the island's north and west coasts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Anglican and other Christian denominations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All visitors to the islands are cordially welcomed; marriages are valid after two days' residence. Islanders maintain traditions of calypso dancing and music and this can be seen particularly during the summer months. Dress is informal at most hotels. Beach attire is not appropriate for around town, in shops or in restaurants. Nudity is not permitted on any beach. For more formal occasions and functions, a lightweight suit and tie is recommended. It is illegal to dress in camouflaged clothing. Homosexuality is illegal.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 60Hz (110 volts available in some hotels). Plugs with three square pins (British-style) or three round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Timothy Harris since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor-General Samuel Weymouth Tapley Seaton since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>St Kitts and Nevis were first settled by intrepid Carib Indians, who travelled to the islands from South America. These settlers named the islands <em>Liamuiga</em> (fertile island) and <em>Oualie</em> (land of beautiful waters) and lived here happily until the Europeans arrived.</p>
<p>Christopher Columbus was the first European to sight the islands in 1493, naming them St Kitts and Nevis from the deck of his vessel. Europeans flirted with the islands throughout the following century &ndash; using them as little more than a reference point during voyages.</p>
<p>But in 1623, the British, seeking a colony in <a href="http://www.britannica.com/EBchecked/topic/337204/Lesser-Antilles" target="_blank">the Lesser Antilles</a>, landed on St Kitts. They established a port town at Old Road, the first British colony in the Caribbean, where they cultivated tobacco. Relations with the local Carib population, at that point, were affable.</p>
<p>Two years later a bruised French fleet &ndash; fresh from a battle with the Spanish navy &ndash; limped into St Kitts. Feeling sorry for them, the British allowed their fellow Europeans to settle on the island, making St Kitts the first French colony in the Caribbean.</p>
<p>The influx of foreigners bred hostility amongst the Caribs, who planned a raid on European settlements. However, the plan was foiled by the colonialists, who launched a pre-emptive attack, wiping out most of the indigenous population in a bloody event known as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kalinago_Genocide_of_1626" target="_blank">the Kalinago Genocide of 1626</a>. The remaining Caribs were deported.</p>
<p>The UK, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> and, to a lesser extent, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a> then began squabbling over the islands. During the 18th century, the mood got serious. The British built the imposing Brimstone Hill fort to defend the islands from the French, who invaded Nevis in 1706, leaving its sugar industry in tatters.</p>
<p>In 1824, Britain placed the nearby island of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/anguilla">Anguilla</a> under the administrative control of St Kitts and Nevis. At this point, the islands&rsquo; sugar industry, built largely on slave labour, was thriving once again and continued to prosper after Britain abolished slavery in 1834.</p>
<p>In 1980 the strained three-island state of St Kitts, Nevis and Anguilla eventually broke down when <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/anguilla">Anguilla</a>, seeking independence from its neighbours, secede from St Kitts and Nevis to become a British overseas territory.</p>
<p>Three years later, in 1983, St Kitts and Nevis gained independence from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>. Since then, the dominant issues for the nation have been the mothballing of the sugar industry and the relationship between the two islands &ndash; a 1998 referendum on independence was approved by 62% of Nevis voters, falling just short of the two-thirds majority needed to triggered secession from St. Kitts.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; At the turn of the 18th century, St. Kitts was the richest British colony per capita in the Caribbean, due largely to the sugar trade.<br />
&bull; Sugar production in St. Kitts and Nevis lasted 365 years before ending in 2005.<br />
&bull; Were Nevis to gain independence from St Kitts, it would be the world's smallest sovereign state after the Vatican.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of St Kitts & Nevis in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 686 2636. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.stkittsnevis.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 686 2636. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3216 New Mexico Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20016<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[High Commission for St Kitts & Nevis in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7937 9718.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.stkittsnevisuk.com</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7937 9718.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 1000-1730, Fri 1000-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>10 Kensington Court<br/>2nd Floor<br/>London<br/>W8 5DL<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Palm-fringed beaches? Check. Limpid lagoons? Check. Tropical rainforests? Check. The twin-island nation of St Kitts and Nevis embodies everything travellers have come to expect from the Caribbean, except, that is, for the crowds.</p><p>Somehow, this vibrant island state has remained under the radar of mass tourism, carving out a niche as an alternative destination for those looking to avoid more mainstream Caribbean islands.</p><p>The smallest sovereign state in the Americas, St Kitts and Nevis are compact and easy to navigate, which is just as well because the pace of life here is slow – and proudly so.</p><p>St. Kitts is the larger and more developed of the two and is home to the laidback capital, Basseterre, a former colonial outpost renowned for its historical monuments, vibrant markets and lively beach life.</p><p>Dominated by Mount Liamuiga, a dormant volcano carpeted with verdant rainforest, Kitts is also home to the defunct British fortress, Brimstone Hill, one of the best preserved citadels in the Americas and a UNESCO World Heritage Site.</p><p>Remnants of the sugar cane industry, once the beating heart of the Kitts economy, remain; old sugar plantations have found new lives as bijous hotels and restaurants, while the island's narrow-gauge railway, once used to transport the cane, has become a popular attraction.</p><p>And then there's Nevis. Fanned by trade winds and dominated by an active volcano, this island is the quieter of the two. The scenery remains relatively unchanged by progress; its undulating landscape punctuated by plantation-style hotels which offer lazy lunches and charming lodgings.</p><p>Those looking for something more adventurous can pass the days hiking through forests, pedalling down mountain trails or surveying the island's coral reefs, which are popular with scuba divers and snorkelers.</p><p>There is little competition for space on Nevis' powdery beaches, and, for the discerning gastronome, there are plenty of excellent restaurants to choose from.</p><p>St Kitts and Nevis will, alas, not stay under the radar forever. The authorities are keen to boost tourism and those familiar with this corner of the Caribbean will be hoping they do it without diluting the islands' many charms.</p>The beautiful islands of St Kitts and Nevis offer an intoxicating blend of sun, sea, lush greenery, spa retreats and absolute luxury.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
