<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="St Lucia" ColCode="lca" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="lc" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[St Lucia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The weather in St Lucia is typical of most Caribbean islands. There is a hot, tropical climate tempered by trade winds throughout most of the year with temperatures ranging from 21&deg;C (70&deg;F) to 32&deg;C (90&deg;F). The driest period is from December to May and there is increased rainfall in summer and towards the end of the year (June to November). Regionally, there is some variation.&nbsp; The beaches around the North (Castries, Gros Islet) whilst hot, receive cooling trade winds, whilst the rainforested interior of the island can get very hot and humid. St Lucia can also suffer from hurricanes; typically the hurrican season runs from June to November.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In general, light breathable fabrics are best, along with beachwear.  A light waterproof jacket may also come in handy during rain showers. Hikers should pack sensible footwear and warm clothes as temperatures drop at higher altitudes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Helicopter transfers operate between George F L Charles and Hewanorra airports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Boat charters are easily available at Castries, Marigot Bay and Rodney Bay. Water taxis are an easy way to access private beaches or go island hopping.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major centres are served by a reasonably good road network. The main cross-island route runs from Vieux Fort in the south of the island to Castries in the north. Roads are narrow and mountainous roads are steep, often with hairpin bends which are not marked. In rural areas watch out for livestock crossing the road.</p>l<p>Hiring a taxi is easy and cheap. Standard trips usually have fixed rates, but you should agree upon these before you get in as tourists are vulnerable to being overcharged. Doublecheck what currency the taxi driver is quoting (US Dollars or EC Dollars). When hiring a taxi at night, always choose a reputable company. Tipping is unnecessary.</p><p>You need to show your national driving licence or International Driving Permit to obtain a temporary local licence. These are available from car hire firms or police stations for a small fee.</p><p>Seat belts must be worn at all times.</p><p>You can hire cars in Castries, Soufri&egrave;re and Vieux Fort, or through hotels. Most cars are suitable for driving in St Lucia, but if you're driving through mountainous terrain or in bad weather conditions, a 4-wheel drive may be your best option. Hotels and local tour operators run coach trips for groups.</p><p>Seat belts must be worn at all times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local minibuses run between the towns of Castries, Vieux Fort and Soufri&egrave;re; these are an affordable option for budget travellers or those wanting an alternative experience. They do tend to be rather overcrowded however, and timetables can be unreliable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines serving St Lucia include LIAT (<a href="http://www.liat.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.liat.com</a>) and Air Caraibes (<a href="http://www.aircaraibes.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.aircaraibes.com</a>). Virgin Atlantic (<a href="http://www.virgin-atlantic.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.virgin-atlantic.com</a>) and British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) fly to St Lucia direct from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>. JetBlue (<a href="http://www.jetblue.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.jetblue.com</a>) flies direct from New York.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/st-lucia/hewanorra-international-airport">Hewanorra International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 9 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 4 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Hewanorra International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.slaspa.com<p>Hewanorra International Airport is situated 4km (2.5 miles) north of Vieux Fort and 56km (35 miles) south of Castries, on the island of St Lucia.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 758 714 9568</p>]]><b>George F. L. Charles</b><![CDATA[http://www.slaspa.com<p>The airport (services inter-island connections and small aircraft from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/puerto-rico">Puerto Rico</a> only) is 3km (2 miles) from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/castries">Castries</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main ports in St Lucia are Castries, Soufri&egrave;re and Vieux Fort.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>The international dialling code for St Lucia is 1 758.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Coverage is good. Mobile phones are available to hire. Operators on St Lucia have not yet declared roaming agreements with international mobile phone companies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public access is available at the internet kiosk at Pointe Seraphine. Other internet caf&eacute;s are also available across the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>St Lucia's newspapers and broadcasters are mainly privately owned. There are no daily newspapers. The government operates a radio network.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes up to one week.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1630, Sat 0900-1330.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Anse Chastanet</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go snorkelling and scuba-diving on St Lucia's natural and artificial coral. It is not uncommon to see turtles, nurse sharks and seahorse whilst swimming in the clear blue waters. Popular diving sites include Anse Chastanet, Anse Le Raye, Coral Gardens at the base of the Gros Piton, Fairy Land at the base of Anse Chastanet and Lesleen M Shipwreck.</p>]]><p><b>Anse de Sable</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get active at the sandy beach of Anse de Sable which offers ideal windsurfing conditions for both novices and experts. The waves at Cas en Bas and Vieux Fort are a challenge even for the most experienced. Island guests can enjoy waterskiing and parasailing above Rodney Bay.</p>]]><p><b>Canopy tour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Soar above the rainforest on a canopy tour. Adrenaline lovers can fly along a series of ziplines from 30 to 150m (100 to 500ft) in length connecting nine platforms 9 to 15m (30 to 50ft) above the ground.</p>]]><p><b>Castries</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Castries, a city located in one of the most beautiful spots in the Caribbean. Surrounded by hills, its large harbour at the head of a wide bay is a constant hive of activity. Head for the spacious Derek Walcott Square which features a 19th-century Catholic cathedral, standing in the shade of a 400-year-old samaan tree. There is also a colourful, bustling market.</p>]]><p><b>Choiseul</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the picturesque little villages of Choiseul and Laborie, which are surrounded by splendid vegetation. The Morne Coubaril Estate (<a href="http://www.stluciaziplining.com" target="_blank">www.stluciaziplining.com</a>) is also worth a visit with cocoa, manioc and sugar cane plantations to visit, plus there are ziplining activities for the more adventurous.</p>]]><p><b>Diamond Waterfalls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Marvel at the Diamond Waterfalls in the Diamond Botanical Gardens and Sulphur Springs - St Lucia's 'drive-in volcano'.</p>]]><p><b>Go sailing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hotels offer hobbycats, dinghies and small speedboats by the hour or half-day. From Marigot Bay and Rodney Bay, the more experienced sailor can hire a variety of craft. Tour operators can also arrange for stays to be coupled with a 'free floating' holiday on board a chartered yacht visiting the neighbouring islands.</p>]]><p><b>Gros Islet</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Check out the weekly Friday street party at Gros Islet, on the northwest coast of the island, stages a street party every Friday. Nearby Pigeon Island National Landmark has a small museum telling the history of the island. It was from here that Admiral Rodney set sail in 1782 and destroyed the French fleet in the Battle of the Saintes, one of the most decisive engagements in European history.</p>]]><p><b>Marigot Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to the top of Marigot Bay, a secluded, palm-fringed paradise. From here you can visit the Cul de Sac - an area famous for its three large banana plantations where the original <em>Dr Dolittle</em> was filmed.</p>]]><p><b>Morne Fortune</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Walk up Morne Fortune, where visitors have the chance to see the fortification which defends Castries. It also provides a magnificent panorama of the city and the surrounding area.</p>]]><p><b>Plantation tour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Travel back in time on a plantation tour. Fond d'Or Nature Historic Park covers the Amerindian settlements and historic buildings of the sugar age and the tropical forest surrounding it.</p>]]><p><b>Rainforests and mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the island's rainforest, mountain and plantation walks. Local guides are available to help climbers tackle the Pitons. The main areas designated for birdwatching are the Bois d'Orange Swamp, Boriel's Pond and the Piton Flore Reserve.</p>]]><p><b>Soufrière</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a trip to<strong> </strong>Soufri&egrave;re, the second-largest settlement on the island. This deep-water port stands at the foot of two extinct volcanoes known as the Pitons. Rising to 798m (2,619ft) above sea level, these are probably St Lucia's most famous landmarks. The town itself is typically West Indian, a cluster of brightly painted arcaded buildings set against the jungle vista.</p>]]><p><b>Turtle and whale watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head out to sea on a turtle and whale watching trip - a great experience for all animal lovers. St Lucia is said to be one of the best places in the world to see whales - 20 species can be seen off the coast, including sperm whales, pilot whales and humpbacks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$985 million (2010).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Bananas, cocoa, vegetables, fruit, other agricultural products, oils and fats and manufactured goods.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, fuel, manufactured goods, machinery and transport equipment, chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Barbados, Spain, Brazil, Trinidad and Tobago, UK and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>St Lucia's economy still relies heavily on agriculture but has broadened during the last 15 years. Light industry has been a key part of this process: the establishment of export processing zones and the successful attraction of foreign investment has created a healthy sector producing plastic, textiles and industrial gases and assembling electronic components. There is also a significant construction industry. The main agricultural exports are bananas, coconuts and cocoa.<br /><br />The government is focusing its efforts on further diversification, principally directed towards the creation of a service sector based on tourism and financial services. It has also affected various deregulation measures and privatisation of a number of major state-owned enterprises.<br /><br />St Lucia is a member of the regional trading bloc, CARICOM, and the region's principal political co-operative grouping, the Organisation of Eastern Caribbean States. <br /><br/>A number of hotels offer conference facilities, with seating for up to 200 persons. The St Lucia Tourist Board can provide details (see <em>Important Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A short- or long-sleeved shirt and tie or a lightweight suit are suitable for most business visits.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700, Sat 0830-1230.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Solar Tours and Travel</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 452 5898.
					Website:http://www.solartoursandtravel.com
					Address: ,20 Bridge Street,Castries,PO Box 1519]]><b>St Lucia Chamber of Commerce, Industry and Agriculture</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 452 3165 ,453 1540
					Website:http://www.stluciachamber.org
					Address: Vide Bouteille,PO Box 482,Castries,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>St Lucian food is a combination of Creole with French and West Indian influences. Most hotels have restaurants, in addition to a wide range of eateries in the major towns serving many different types of food. Waiter service is the norm.</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s also a strong British influence in the local cooking with widespread use of cinnamon garlic, nutmeg, cloves, parsley, cocoa and allspice.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Langouste:</strong> Local spiny lobster, cooked in a variety of ways.<br />
<strong>Bouyon:</strong> A thick red beans soup made with meat, ground provision and vegetables. <br />
<strong>Lambi:</strong> Conch. <br />
<strong>Green figs and salt fish:</strong> Unripe bananas and preserved fish, the national dish. <br />
<strong>Callaloo:</strong> Spinach-like soup made from the leaves of the dasheen plant.<br />
<strong>Accra:</strong> Fish fritters made from salted cod, flour and local green seasoning.<br />
<strong>Pepper pots:</strong> Traditional stews made with whatever ingredients &ndash; fish, meat, vegetables &ndash; were at hand that day.<br />
<strong>Green fig salad:</strong> Similar to a potato salad, but made with boiled green bananas.<br />
<strong>Float bakes:</strong> A fried dough mixture similar to donuts, just not as sweet.<br />
<strong>Cocoa tea and bakes:</strong> Traditional St Lucian breakfast and tea made with local cocoa &ndash; said to be the richest in the world &ndash; served with bakes. Breadfruit: This starchy fruit is a staple food in St Lucia, often boiled and eaten with chicken, fish or other meat. It&rsquo;s also widely used in salads.<br />
<strong>Banana cake:</strong> Sponge cake with added mashed bananas, chopped pineapple, orange juice and walnuts.<br />
<strong>Golden apple juice:</strong> A tangy soft drink make from the juice of Golden Apples mixed with sugar.<br />
<strong>Piton:</strong> Locally brewed beer.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>An optional 10% is sometimes added to bills.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>St Lucia's nightlife is based mainly in hotels and restaurants. On Friday nights, the village of Gros Islet hosts a weekly 'jump up', popular with locals and visitors alike; Anse La Raye hold their <em>Friday Night Fish Fry BBQ</em>.<em> Indies</em> and <em>The Late Lime </em>are two of St Lucia's most popular nightclubs, both featuring live entertainment. There is little nightlife during the summer, but during the winter the resorts are lively, with plenty of local music and dance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Special purchases include unique batik and silkscreen designs made into shifts, sports shirts, table mats, cocktail napkins and shopping bags produced at a studio on the road between Castries and La Toc. Other craft outlets sell locally made bowls, beads, straw hats, flour-sack shirts, sisal rugs, bags, sandals and woodwork. Pointe Seraphine features over 30 duty-free shops (open seven days a week), bars and restaurants placed around an open piazza. Another duty-free shopping complex is at La Place Carenage. Duty-free shopping is available to all visitors, provided they present their passport, cruise ship boarding pass or airline ticket when purchasing goods. Purchases of alcohol and tobacco can be sent ahead to the airport  for collection upon departure.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1230 and 1330-1630, Sat 0830-1230 and 0900-2100 in shopping malls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>St Lucia has a range of accommodation to suit every taste and budget, from large luxury resorts hotels to self-catering apartments. All-inclusive holidays are very popular and the big hotels in St Lucia tend to be located to the North around Castries and Gros Islet. If you want to escape the hustle and bustle, head further south on the island, towards Soufri&egrave;re, Vieux Fort and Choiseful for more low-key acommodation. Most hotels provide some form of entertainment in the evening, from calypso music to the ever-popular limbo dancing. A government tax of 8% and service charge of 10 to 15% are added to bills.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A wide range of guesthouses are available; some offer self-catering facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>St Lucia has a range of accommodation to suit every taste and budget, from large luxury resorts hotels to self-catering apartments. All-inclusive holidays are very popular and the big hotels in St Lucia tend to be located to the North around Castries and Gros Islet. If you want to escape the hustle and bustle, head further south on the island, towards Soufri&egrave;re, Vieux Fort and Choiseful for more low-key acommodation. Most hotels provide some form of entertainment in the evening, from calypso music to the ever-popular limbo dancing. A government tax of 8% and service charge of 10 to 15% are added to bills.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>St Lucia has a range of accommodation to suit every taste and budget, from large luxury resorts hotels to self-catering apartments. All-inclusive holidays are very popular and the big hotels in St Lucia tend to be located to the North around Castries and Gros Islet. If you want to escape the hustle and bustle, head further south on the island, towards Soufri&egrave;re, Vieux Fort and Choiseful for more low-key acommodation. Most hotels provide some form of entertainment in the evening, from calypso music to the ever-popular limbo dancing. A government tax of 8% and service charge of 10 to 15% are added to bills.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No**]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Costs of health care are high and payment in cash is usually expected, irrespective of whether you have health insurance. Victoria hospital in Castries is  the main hospital but serious cases will require transfer to a country with greater medical facilities. Full health insurance is essential.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated, and whilst relatively safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is available. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat but take care to ensure that all foods are properly prepared and cooked. Barracuda should not be eaten due to risk of ciguatera poisioning.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Independence Day :
							22 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Corpus Christi :
							31 May </p><p>Emancipation Day :
							06 August </p><p>National Day :
							13 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into St Lucia by travellers over the age of 18 without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 225g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1.2L of alcoholic beverages.<br />
&bull; Other gifts or souvenirs to the value of US$250.</p>
<p>You may only claim this allowance once a year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may not be brought into the St Lucia:</p>
<p>&bull; Counterfeit currency and coins.<br />
&bull; Indecent or obscene photographs, painting or objects.<br />
&bull; Any narcotics including marijuana, morphine, LSD, opium and morphine.<br />
&bull; Flick knives and blades.<br />
&bull; Shaving brushes made in or exported from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan">Japan</a>.<br />
&bull; All  matter associated with black magic and occultism.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may not be exported from St Lucia without the correct consent:</p>
<p>&bull; Narcotic drugs and psychotropic substances. <br />
&bull; Ginger and dry coconuts. <br />
&bull; Any goods that have the coat of arms or the flag of St Lucia.<br />
&bull; Rare or threatened species of animals or plants, their products and derivatives.</p>
<p>For a comprehensive list of prohibited imports and exports see the St Lucia Customs departmental website <a target="_blank" href="http://www.customs.gov.lc">www.customs.gov.lc</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eastern Caribbean Dollar (XCD; symbol EC$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of EC$100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of EC$1, and 50, 25, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents. US Dollars are also accepted as legal tender.<br /><br />The Eastern Caribbean Dollar is tied to the US Dollar at EC$2.7 to US$1.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollars ensure a better exchange rate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are accepted at all large shopping centres, restaurants, hotels etc. Most banks have ATMs.</p><p>Most banks have ATMs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted. However US Dollar cheques are preferred and will help to avoid additional exchange rate charges. Change may be given back in EC$.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally Mon-Thurs 0830-1500, Fri 0830-1700. Some banks at Rodney Bay Marina are open Sat 0800-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter St Lucia, a passport valid for six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry vacation visa: &pound;35; multiple-entry vacation visa: &pound;45;&nbsp;business visa: &pound;40. Costs depend on the nationality of the applicant and the place of application.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The validity of visas is determined by the immigraton department. Single-entry visa: usually up to three months; multiple-entry visa: multiple entries within one year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy or high commission).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow three working days if applying in person and five to seven days if applying by post.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to extend your stay, you must visit the immigration department.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pets must have a microchip, rabies vaccination certificate and veterinary certificate. You must arrange an import permit before you travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[13.909444]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-60.978893]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>616.3 sq km (238 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>186,383 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>266 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Castries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>St Lucia is the second-largest of the Windward Islands. It has some of the finest mountain scenery in the West Indies and is rich with tropical vegetation. For such a small island, 43km (27 miles) by 23km (14 miles), St Lucia has a great variety of plant and animal life. Orchids and exotic plants grow wild in the rainforests, and the roadsides are covered with many colourful tropical flowers. Indigenous wildlife includes a species of ground lizard unique to St Lucia. The Amazona versicolor parrot is another, though more elusive, inhabitant of the deep interior rainforest.</p>
<p>The highest peak is Mount Gimie at 950m (3,117ft). Most spectacular are the twin peaks of Gros Piton and Petit Piton, ancient, volcanic forest-covered cones which rise out of the sea on the west coast. The mountains are intersected by short rivers which in some areas form broad fertile valleys. The island has excellent beaches and is surrounded by a clear, warm sea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Majority Roman Catholic (78%) with some Anglican, Methodist, Seventh Day Adventist and Baptist.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>St Lucians are friendly and hospitable and encourage visitors to relax and enjoy their leisurely lifestyle. The traditional dress of the madras and foulards are not often seen in towns, but are sometimes worn at festivals such as the Feast of St Rose of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lima">Lima</a> in August. Casual wear is acceptable, although some hotels and restaurants encourage guests to dress for dinner. Beachwear should not be worn in towns. It is an offence for anyone, including children, to dress in camouflage clothing. Certain homosexual acts are against the law.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs generally  have three square pins (as in the UK), but some sockets do take American flat-pin plugs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Kenny Anthony since 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor-General Neville Cenac since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fierce resistance from Carib Indians kept British and French colonists away from this Caribbean island in the early-17th century, though the island was not entirely untouched by Europeans &ndash; the notorious French pirate, Fran&ccedil;ois le Clerc, had been a frequent visitor a century before and by 1600 the Dutch had established a camp at what in now Vieux Port.</p>
<p>The Carib Indians could only keep the colonialists at bay for so long, though: between 1660 and 1814, the Old World skirmished over the island and its ownership of St Lucia switched hands no fewer than 14 times.</p>
<p>In 1722 King George I granted the island to the Duke of Montagu, who sent a merchant sea captain with a fleet of seven ships to establish a settlement &ndash; he was promptly seen off by the French. Britain then occupied St Lucia during the Seven Years War, but returned it to France at the Treaty of Paris in 1763.</p>
<p>A revolutionary tribunal was set up on the island after the French Revolution, all slaves were declared free and a guillotine was set up to execute Royalists, but it wasn&rsquo;t long before Britain invaded the island and the tug of war resumed before being finally settled in 1814 at the end of the Napoleonic Wars.</p>
<p>The British abolished slavery in 1836 and all slaves had to serve a four-year apprenticeship working for their former masters as they completed a transition to freedom. A measure of self-government was introduced in 1840 with universal suffrage from 1953, before St Lucia was granted full autonomy in 1979 as an independent state of the Commonwealth of Nations.</p>
<p>HM The Queen remains the head of state and is represented on the island by the Governor-General, currently Dame Pearlette Louisy, who became the first woman to hold the position when she assumed office in 1997. St Lucia has long lobbied for greater regional integration as a unitary Eastern Caribbean state and has formed a more limited union with three other like-minded islands &ndash; Dominica, Grenada and St Vincent.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	A volcanic island, St Lucia&rsquo;s highest point is Mount Gimie at 950m (3,116ft) above sea level.<br />
&bull;	The biggest cultural event of the year is the St Lucia Jazz Festival held in May.<br />
&bull;	Soufriere Volcano is the world&rsquo;s only drive-in volcano. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[St Lucia High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7370 7123</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.stluciahcuk.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7370 7123</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0930-1730, Fri 0930-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1 Collingham Gardens<br/>London<br/>SW5 0HW<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of St Lucia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 364 6792</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 364 6792</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Sun: 1000-1700&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3216 New Mexico Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20016<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in St Lucia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(758) 452 2484/5</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ukinbarbados.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(758) 452 2484/5</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1230 / 1300-1600; Fri 0800-1300. Open to public: Mon-Fri 0800–1230&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Waterfront<br/>Francis Compton Building, 2nd Floor, (PO Box 227)<br/>Castries<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Trade winds keep temperatures on the right side of sizzling in sunny St Lucia, where white sandy beaches, crystalline waters and luscious rainforests paint the quintessential picture of Caribbean island idyll.</p>
<p>St Lucia is in the business of creating lasting first impressions: visitors to the island are greeted by the unforgettable sight of the Piton Mountains, which are fringed by coral reefs, sandy shores and swaying palms as they rise majestically from the rolling surf.</p>
<p>While other Caribbean islands lay claim to equally beautiful beaches, St Lucia will tempt you out of the sun-lounger and into the ocean with its bountiful marine life and exquisite reefs, which are a playground for scuba divers and snorkelers. St Lucia&rsquo;s waters are also prime for kite-boarding and windsurfing, thanks to the aforementioned trade winds.&nbsp;</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s not all about the coast, though. A trip to the island&rsquo;s interior presents the opportunity to hike through verdant mountains, zip-line over forest canopies and watch boiling sulphur springs bubble away atop a volcano, all in a day&rsquo;s work. If you&rsquo;ve still got the energy for a night out, there are regular shindigs in the north of the island. Friday nights get particularly lively. &nbsp;</p>
<p>Here visitors can experience the relaxed flavour of island life, as well as the unique mixture of West African, European and East Indian influences that infuse the local cuisine. St Lucia is also known for its folk music and world-famous Jazz &amp; Arts Festival, which takes place every year amidst much fanfare. &nbsp;</p>
<p>The island carries a unique cultural heritage, having changed hands between Britain and France no fewer than 14 times. The British eventually lost control in 1979, and St Lucia gained its independence. Various cultural legacies linger, from the colonial-style plantations that dot the landscape, to the French-influenced patois spoken throughout the country.</p>
<p>The result is a destination that will captivate visitors long after the emerald-green peaks of the Pitons have disappeared over the horizon.</p><p>Trade winds keep temperatures on the right side of sizzling in sunny St Lucia, where white sandy beaches, crystalline waters and luscious rainforests paint the quintessential picture of Caribbean island idyll.&nbsp;St Lucia is in the business of creating lasting first impressions: visitors to the island are greeted by the unforgettable sight of the Piton Mountains, which are fringed by coral reefs, sandy shores and swaying palms as they rise majestically from the rolling surf.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
