<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="St Maarten" ColCode="stm" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="xs" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[St Maarten]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hot but tempered by cooling trade winds. The annual mean temperature is 27°C (80°F), varying by no more than two or three degrees throughout the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropicals and cottons are worn throughout the year. Umbrellas or light waterproofs are advisable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can charter small boats for fishing trips, scuba-diving, waterskiing or visits to neighbouring islands. There are marinas at Oyster Pond, Philipsburg and Simpson Bay Lagoon.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Most roads are in good condition.</p><p>There are good services on the island running from the airport, main hotels and towns. Taxis do not have meters but fares are fixed. There is a 50% surcharge after midnight. There is a taxi station at Wathey Square. Taxi drivers do not expect a tip.</p><p>A national driving licence is required.</p><p>There are plenty of car hire firms in the city and at the airport. Chauffeur-driven cars are also available.</p><p>TriSport (<a href="http://trisportsxm.com" target="_blank">trisportsxm.com</a>) hires bikes and runs bike tours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The biggest local airline is Winair (<a href="http://www.fly-winair.sx" target="_blank">www.fly-winair.sx</a>), based at Princess Juliana Airport. Other airlines flying to St Maarten include Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>), American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>), Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>), JetBlue (<a href="http://www.jetblue.com" target="_blank">www.jetblue.com</a>) and United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 12 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 4 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For international destinations, there is a departure tax of US$30 for those age two and up. This departure tax might be already included in the airfare of certain airlines. For islands within the Netherlands Antilles, the departure tax is US$10. Again, some include the departure tax in the airline ticket.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Saint-Martin Grand Case Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.saintmartin-airport.com]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Princess Juliana International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.sxmairport.com<p>The airport , 15km (9.5 miles) west of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/philipsburg">Philipsburg</a> (journey time - 15 minutes), receives regular scheduled flights from other Caribbean islands, Europe and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main port:&nbsp;</strong>Philipsburg.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Calls made through the operator are more expensive and include a 15% tax.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Compatible with most US handsets but not with GSM handsets. Phone hire is available. Roaming agreements exist. Most US handsets can be used, and can be activated with a temporary number before or after arrival on the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet access is available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>English-language dailies include the <em>Daily Herald</em>, published on St Maarten. Most other newspapers in the Netherlands Antilles are published in Dutch or Papiamento. The Leeward Broadcasting Corporation is based in St Maarten. The local station is Voice of St Maarten.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes four to six days, surface mail takes four to six weeks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Cross over to Marigot</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tiptoe across the border (no passports are required) into French St Martin and visit the charming market town of Marigot. This is the main town and capital on the French side. Market days are every Wednesday and Saturday morning.</p>]]><p><b>Get on your bike</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cycling and mountain biking can be enjoyed on the coastal road and along the trails around Paradise Peak. There are excellent views and peddling allows you to quietly approach roadside wildlife. There are numerous bike hire and bike tour operators available on the island.</p>]]><p><b>Have a go at deep sea fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Arrange a deep sea fishing expedition, with half- and full-day charters available all year round. Game fish can be found lurking in the deeper waters around the island such as tuna, mahi mahi and wahoo.  What better way to catch you own dinner.</p>]]><p><b>Make some waves and go sailing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The island is one of the Caribbean's leading sailing venues, rent anything from motorboats and yachts to canoes, or charter day trips and "picnic sails" to secluded bays and nearby uninhabited islands. Bareboat charters are also available, which means you can charter a fully equipped yacht without a professional skipper and crew.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the Queen Wilhelmina Golden Jubilee Monument</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a peek inside Philipsburg's nine shingled churches, and visit the Queen Wilhelmina Golden Jubilee Monument. Nearby is Fort Amsterdam, dating from the time of the earliest settlers. Located alongside is a breeding colony of Brown Pelican with over 60 nests.</p>]]><p><b>Set sail for the St Maarten Heineken Regatta</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Founded in 1980, this annual yacht race bears the apt slogan "serious fun". It's intended to represent both sides of the sailing community in the Caribbean – the racing and partying. Growing year on year, the event now attracts over 3,000 sailors from 32 nationalities.</p>]]><p><b>Shop tax-free in Philipsburg</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy the colonial atmosphere and duty-free shopping of St Maarten's principal town, Philipsburg, which is situated on a sandbar that separates Great Salt Pond, a salt marsh, from the ocean. The entire town consists of two streets, <em>Voorstraat</em> (Front Street) and <em>Achterstraat</em> (Back Street), and several short, narrow alleys.</p>]]><p><b>Take a visit to the Border Monument</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Travel inland to see the picturesque ruins of several plantation mansions, set in the wooded hills around Mount Flagstaff, and the Border Monument, which celebrates 300 years of cooperation between the French and the Dutch. This remains the smallest landmass in the world to be shared by two sovereign nations.</p>]]><p><b>Take the plunge at a wreck site</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take advantage of excellent diving conditions, with coral reefs located close to the shore. One of the most popular dive sites is the wreck of HMS Proselyte, a British man-of-war which sank in 1801. There are also many good sites for snorkelling.</p>]]><p><b>Watch the planes at Maho Beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>St Maarten is famed for its runway into Princess Juliana International Airport, where landing aircraft touch down a mere 35m (115km) from Maho Beach. The runway is situated right next to the sea, with hulking jets appearing to land perilously close to sunbathers. Perfect for some quirky holiday snaps or for plane enthusiasts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$3.3 billion (2005).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and electrical equipment, crude oil (for refining and re-export), chemicals and food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Venezuela, Guatemala, Singapore and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourism dominates the economy; 70% of all visitors to the Netherlands Antilles visit St Maarten, which results in around half a million tourists annually. Further investment in the tourism infrastructure is under way, including a new major port.<br /><br />Government service provides one of the few alternative sources of employment, while subsistence farming and fishing meet a fair proportion of the islands' domestic needs. St Maarten is the only island in the Antilles group apart from Curaçao which has achieved some success in developing an 'offshore' financial services industry.<br /><br />The Netherlands Antilles group enjoys Overseas Territory status at the EU and observer status at the Caribbean trading bloc CARICOM.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Formality in business is expected in most of The Netherlands Antilles and lightweight suits should be worn. Appointments should be made in advance and punctuality is taken very seriously. It is customary to shake hands.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1200 and 1330-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>St Maarten Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 542 3590
					Website:http://www.sintmaartenchamber.org
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>St Maarten's cuisine is as varied as its history, combining Creole, Dutch, English, French and, more recently, international influences. For many it is the culinary capital of the Caribbean with a wide choice of excellent restaurants where the chefs combine the island's proud tradition and local ingredients with European savoire faire to produce dishes and menus that rival the best not only in the region but further afield as well.</p><p>Cooking and eating on the island is a reflection of the sunny, relaxed and joyous atmosphere that permeates the place.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>St Maarten's spare ribs:</strong> The locals all have their own recipes for this island favourite – they're all based on racks of pork ribs washed with lime and cider vinegar and marinated in barbecue sauce with onions, garlic and lime juice.</p><p><strong>Saltfish fritters: </strong>Saltfish and chopped vegetables mixed in batter and deep-fried.</p><p><strong>Chiquetaille de morue: </strong>Shredded cod in hot pepper vinaigrette.</p><p><strong>Avocado feroce:</strong> Ripe avocado mashed with manioc flour.</p><p><strong>Meat patties: </strong>Pastry parcels filled with spiced meat, shrimp or fish.</p><p><strong>Pigeon peas soup: </strong>Hearty soup made with ham hock or salt pork and the light brown black eye peas also known as cajanus, gandules or gongo peas.<br/><strong>Guavaberry:</strong> A traditional liqueur made with aged rum, brown sugar and wild guavaberries that grow in the island's interior. It's enjoyed all year round but especially at Christmas.</p><p><strong>Le Planteur: </strong>A local cocktail with as many recipes as there are beaches on St Maarten, but all based on rum (white or old), fruit juice (orange, pineapple and guava), can syrup, Angostura bitters and nutmeg.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tips of 10-15% is acceptable for waiters and bar staff.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many of the restaurants and bars have live entertainment and dancing until the early hours. All the large hotels have casinos.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good range of high quality duty-free shopping available in Philipsburg.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1200 and 1400-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>St Maarten is well-stocked with accommodation, and the island's luxury hotels come fully equipped, from casinos and beauty parlours, to extensive watersports facilities. Even more modest beachside establishments typically have a swimming pool and restaurant. <br /><br />A government tax of 5% is levied on all hotel bills and many hotels add a 10 to 15% service charge. Some even add a further 10% as an energy surcharge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Several guest houses cater for the less demanding; apartments and villas may be rented.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>St Maarten is well-stocked with accommodation, and the island's luxury hotels come fully equipped, from casinos and beauty parlours, to extensive watersports facilities. Even more modest beachside establishments typically have a swimming pool and restaurant. <br /><br />A government tax of 5% is levied on all hotel bills and many hotels add a 10 to 15% service charge. Some even add a further 10% as an energy surcharge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>St Maarten is well-stocked with accommodation, and the island's luxury hotels come fully equipped, from casinos and beauty parlours, to extensive watersports facilities. Even more modest beachside establishments typically have a swimming pool and restaurant. <br /><br />A government tax of 5% is levied on all hotel bills and many hotels add a 10 to 15% service charge. Some even add a further 10% as an energy surcharge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There is a general hospital, the St Maarten Medical Centre in Cayhill. Medical care is good. Medical insurance is advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water on the island is considered safe to drink. Bottled mineral water is widely available. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Queen's Birthday :
							30 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Bastille Day :
							14 July </p><p>Schoelcher Day :
							21 July </p><p>Antillean Day :
							21 October </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>St Maarten Day :
							11 November </p><p>Kingdom Day :
							15 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You don't have to pay duty on any goods brought into St Maarten.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollars are accepted everywhere but at the moment the official currency is the Netherlands Antilles Guilder or Florin (ANG; symbol &fnof;) which is going to soon be phased out and replaced by the Caribbean Guilder (CMg) by 2012-2013. Notes are in denominations of 200, 100, 50, 20 and 10. Coins are in denominations of 1, 5, 10, 25, 50 cents, 1 guilder, and 5 guilder coins. The <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/caribbean">Caribbean</a> guilder will be pegged to the US Dollar (US$ 1 = CMg 1.79).]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major currencies can be exchanged at banks on the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major credit cards are widely accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Widely accepted. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0830-1130 and 1330-1630. Some banks are also open on Saturday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter St Maarten, a passport valid for the duration of the intended stay is required by nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Schengen visa is not valid for travel to St Maarten.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The short-stay Caribbean visa allows nationals who do require a visa to make short visits to Aruba, Bonaire, Cura&ccedil;ao, Saba, St Eustatius and St Maarten for up to 90 days in a 180-day period.</p>
<p>The long-stay Caribbean visa allows nationals who do require a visa and wish visit Aruba, Bonaire, Cura&ccedil;ao, Saba, St Eustatius and St Maarten to apply for a residence permit. A residence permit is required for visits lasting more than 90 days.</p>
<p>The cost of a Caribbean visa is EUR&euro;35.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Caribbean visa is a multiple-entry visa. Visa holders may visit any of the countries included under the scheme for a maximum of 90 days within a 180-day period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Contact your nearest Dutch Embassy to make an appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Applications for the Caribbean visa are usually processed within 15 calendar days, but processing times vary depending on the country. Applications can be made up to 3 months before the intended travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors who do not require a visa can extend their stay at the immigration office, usually up to a maximum of 180 days. You cannot extend the Caribbean visa.</p>
<p>You cannot extend the short-stay Caribbean visa. If you wish to stay for more than 90 days, you must apply for a residence permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing a pet, your animal needs a health certificate issued no more than 10 days before your arrival. You must also bring a list of inoculations, including proof of a rabies vaccination given no more than 30 days before your trip.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[18.030827]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-63.073633]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>34 sq km (13 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>39,538 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,092 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Philipsburg.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kingdom of the Netherlands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Politically, St Maarten is one of three Windward Islands in the former Netherlands Antilles, although geographically it is part of the Leeward Group of the Lesser Antilles, and not strictly an island - it occupies just one-third of an island otherwise under French control (the French sector is called St Martin), lying 8km (5 miles) south of Anguilla, 232km (144 miles) east of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/puerto-rico">Puerto Rico</a> and 56km (35 miles) due north of St Eustatius. St Maarten is the southern sector, an area of wooded mountains rising from white sandy beaches. To the west, the mountains give way to lagoons and salt flats.</p>
<p>St Maarten and Cura&ccedil;ao were granted autonomy as part of the dissolution of the Netherlands Antilles on 10 October 2010, making the islands 'constituent countries' in the Kingdom of the Netherlands.&nbsp;</p>
<p>For information on the French sector (St Martin), see the French Overseas Possessions section.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Protestant, with Roman Catholic and Jewish minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dutch customs are still important throughout the former Netherlands Antilles, but tourism has brought increasing <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> influences and St Maarten is perhaps more easy-going than the southern islands. Dress is casual and lightweight cottons are advised, but it is common to dress up in the evening.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110 volts AC, 60Hz. (Note that St Martin, the French side of the island, uses 220 volts). American-style plugs with two flat pins (and sometimes a third grounding pin) are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Leona Marlin-Romeo since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King Willem-Alexander since 2013, represented locally by Governor Eugene Holiday since 2010.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Occupied since prehistory by Carib Indians, St Maarten was sighted by Christopher Columbus on St Maarten's day in 1493. However, the first European settlers were French and Dutch who, in 1648, partitioned the island. The island has remained under dual sovereignty ever since, the Dutch sector achieving partial independence from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/netherlands">Netherlands</a> in 1954 with the establishment of the Netherlands Antilles. <br />
<br />
At the 2002 general election for the Staten,  the local governing body of the Antilles, the socialist <i>Frente Obrero Liberashon </i>(Workers' Liberation Front) won the largest number of seats but was excluded from office by a four-party centre-right coalition led by the <i>Partido Antia Restruktura </i>(Party for the Restructured Antilles, or PAR). The PAR,&nbsp; based on the island of Cura&ccedil;ao, had dominated Antilles' politics since its formation a decade ago.</p>
<p>After the dissolution of the Netherlands Antilles on 10 October 2010, St Maarten and Cura&ccedil;ao were granted autonomy as 'constituent countries' in the Kingdom of the Netherlands.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Office of the Minister Plenipotentiary of the Netherlands Antilles]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(70) 306 6111.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(70) 306 6111.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>Badhuisweg 173-175<br/>PO Box 90706<br/>The Hague<br/>2597 JP<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Caracas (nearest British Embassy to St Maarten)]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b> (0) 212 267 1275.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinvenezuela.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b> (0) 212 267 1275.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1630, Fri 0800-1315.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>1st Floor<br/>Torre La Castellana<br/>Avenida La Principal de la Castellana<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Diplomatic representation]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sun-lovers, water babies, sailors and divers alike will find St Maarten an alluring Caribbean getaway. This popular destination in the former Netherlands Antilles is lined with delicious coastline, on which to frolic, bake, or get active.</p>
<p>The most prominent physical feature in St Maarten is Mount Flagstaff, an extinct volcano, but the most important for visitors is the excellent beach that follows the south and west coasts; beach activities and shopping at duty-free centres firmly satisfy most tourists.</p>
<p>St Maarten is also popular with sailing enthusiasts and divers. The excellent diving conditions feature striking coral reefs located close to the shore. One of the most popular dive sites is the wreck of HMS Proselyte, a British man-of-war which sank in 1801. Body boarding is increasingly popular way of enjoying the gleaming waters and getting refreshed in the pouring sunshine.</p>Sun-lovers, water babies, sailors and divers alike will find St Maarten an alluring Caribbean getaway.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
