<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="St Vincent and the Grenadines" ColCode="vct" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="vc" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[St Vincent and the Grenadines]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate is tropical, with trade winds tempering the hottest months of June and July. The best time to visit St Vincent and the Grenadines is from December to April, when the nights are cooler and the days hot. The rainy season is from June, with rainfull  heavy in the mountains and short, sharp bursts on the coast.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights and waterproofs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can charter small planes for inter-island travel. Mustique Airways (<a href="http://mustique.com" target="_blank">mustique.com</a>) and SVG Air (<a href="http://www.svgair.com" target="_blank">www.svgair.com</a>) run regular services to the Grenadines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Yacht chartering is easily arranged and is one of the best ways to explore the Grenadines. You can hire yachst locally, with or without crew. Ferries make frequent sailings to Bequia (journey time - 1 hour), Canouan, Mayreau, the Union Islands and Mustique.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[l<p>These are shared and charge standard rates (fixed by the government). Taxi drivers do not expect tips.</p><p>You must bring your valid national licence or International Driving Permit. You need to show this to obtain a temporary local driving licence; these are available at all ports of entry as well as at the police headquarters in Kingstown, St Vincent.</p><p>Easily arranged through a number of national and international firms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travel to St Vincent and the Grenadines is via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/barbados">Barbados</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/grenada">Grenada</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/martinique">Martinique</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/st-lucia">St Lucia</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/trinidad-and-tobago">Trinidad and Tobago</a>, and then on to St Vincent and the Grenadines in a prop plane. LIAT (<a href="http://www.liat.com" target="_blank">www.liat.com</a>) is the main airline serving St Vincent &amp; the Grenadines.</p>
<p>British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) Virgin Atlantic (<a href="http://www.virgin-atlantic.com" target="_blank">www.virgin-atlantic.com</a>) fly to Bridgetown, Barbados, from where it's a short hop with LIAT to St Vincent and the Grenadines.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 11 hours 45 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 8 hours 30 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A new airport, Argyle International Airport (AIA), is expected to open in 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>EC$40 on all international departures; children under 12 years of age and passengers departing on the same day are exempt. This is usually included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A new airport, Argyle International Airport (AIA), is expected to open in 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>E.T. Joshua Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 3km (2 miles) southeast of Kingstown.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>North American mobile phones work on all the islands. Network coverage is good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available in Internet caf&eacute;s and hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All newspapers are in English and most are published weekly.<br />The most popular papers are <em>The News</em>, <em>Searchlight </em>and <em>The Vincentian.</em><br /><em>SVG Television</em> is operated by <em>St Vincent and the Grenadines Broadcasting Corporation</em>.n<em>NBC Radio</em> is a partly government-funded national station.<br /><br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes up to two weeks.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1500, Sat 0830-1130.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bequia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Bequia, an island 14km (9 miles) south of St Vincent and the largest of the Grenadines. Observe Bequia's age-old traditions of boat building and fishing, largely retained due to its seclusion. In the marine park, spearfishing, snares and nets are prohibited. The islanders themselves are the world's last hand-harpooners and their activities do not affect marine stocks.</p>]]><p><b>Boat builders</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Watch men building their boats by hand in Admiralty Bay, Bequia's natural harbour and a favourite anchoring spot for yachtsmen from all over the world. The attractive region around Lower Bay has good opportunities for swimming and other watersports.</p>]]><p><b>Botanical Gardens</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take in the oldest Botanical Gardens in the western hemisphere, which occupy 8.1 hectares (20 acres) to the north of Kingstown, St Vincent, and contain a display of tropical trees, blossoms and plants, including a breadfruit tree descended from the original one brought to the island in 1765 by Captain Bligh.</p>]]><p><b>Canouan beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take in the beautiful beaches on Canouan. The island claims some of the best in the Caribbean with long stretches of powder-white sands, wide shallows and coral.</p>]]><p><b>Falls of Baleine</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a boat trip to the Falls of Baleine, at the northern tip of St Vincent. The 18m (59ft) freshwater falls stream from volcanic slopes and form a series of shallow pools at the base.</p>]]><p><b>Fishing villages</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to the fishing villages of Questelles, Layou, Barrouallie and Châteaubelair, all of which have charming pastel-coloured cottages and excellent black-sand beaches from which fishermen set out daily in small brightly painted boats.</p>]]><p><b>Kingstown</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the lively port and market town of Kingstown; the capital of St Vincent. The town contains 12 small blocks with a variety of shops and a busy dock area, which is the centre of commerce for the islands. The Saturday morning market, comprising many stalls piled high with fresh fruit and vegetables, brings everyone to town.</p>]]><p><b>Luxurious Mustique</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mustique, a gem in the ocean taking up only 4.5 sq km (2 sq miles). Mustique is privately owned, with a landscape as gentle as its lifestyle - verdant hills roll into soft white-sand beaches and turquoise waters. This island has long been a hiding place for the rich and famous, including members of the British Royal Family.</p>]]><p><b>Mount Parnassus</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to Mount Parnassus on Union Island, which soars 275m (900ft) from the sea guarding the entrance to the southern Grenadines. The 850-hectare (2,100-acre) mountainous island is fringed by superb beaches and is the stopping-off point for yachtsmen and visitors heading to some of the smaller Grenadines. Clifton Harbour, the main town, is small and commercial.</p>]]><p><b>St Mary's Roman Catholic Cathedral</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to the centre of Kingstown where you will find St Mary's Roman Catholic Cathedral. Built of grey stone, it is a graceful combination of several European architectural styles displaying Romanesque arches, gothic spires and Moorish ornamentation. Its architecture has led Kingstown to become known as the City of Arches.</p>]]><p><b>Tobago Cays</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to the numerous islets and coves of the Tobago Cays where you can see some of the most spectacular coral reefs in the world. Visitors can sail, snorkel and beachcomb in complete seclusion. The only way to get here is by chartered yacht.</p>]]><p><b>Volcanic hiking</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hike up La Soufrière volcano (1,200m/4,000ft) in the north of St Vincent, which is popular, though strenuous. The 5km (3 mile) journey rewards you with a wonderful bird's-eye view of the crater and its islands, and all of St Vincent.</p>]]><p><b>Watery pursuits</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hit the water and try some sailing, scuba diving or snorkelling on Bequiam which is encircled by gold-sand beaches, many of which disappear into coves. Lodgings vary from luxurious resort cottages to small, simple West Indian inns. Much of the nightlife centres on the hotels and beachside barbecues, invariably accompanied by a steel band.</p>]]><p><b>Young Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Young Island, which is only 180m (590ft) off St Vincent and rises from the sea to form a mountain blanketed with tropical foliage and blossoms. Young Island provides an excellent view of the procession of yachts sailing into the harbour of St Vincent. The entire island comprises one resort called <em>Young Island Resort</em>, which consists of 29 rustic cottages set on the beaches and hillsides.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$632 million (2009).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Bananas, eddoes and dasheen (taro), arrowroot starch and tennis rackets.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, machinery and equipment, chemicals and fertilisers, minerals and fuels.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>EU, Barbados, St Lucia and Trinidad and Tobago.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>St Vincent and the Grenadines is poor by Eastern Caribbean standards, with agriculture the main source of income and export earnings. Bananas are the main crop, but St Vincent is also the world's leading producer of arrowroot and grows other exotic fruit, vegetables and root crops. Fishing has also been revitalised and a processing complex has been built with Japanese assistance. Agriculture is especially vulnerable to the unpredictable, often adverse weather patterns of the Caribbean. <br /><br />Tourism is the other main component of the economy. By regional standards, this was relatively late to evolve and was initially hampered by the lack of a suitable infrastructure. This was addressed with the help of aid from the European Union and the industry is now growing rapidly: the most recent figures record its contribution to the economy at US$90 million. A small manufacturing sector and an embryonic 'offshore' financial services industry complete the country's economic inventory.<br />For information, contact the St Vincent and the Grenadines Tourist Office (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short- or long-sleeved shirt and tie are suitable for most business visits.</p><p><strong>Government office hours:</strong> These vary from department to department but generally Mon-Fri 0800-1615, with some opening for a few hours Saturday morning.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>St Vincent and the Grenadines Chamber of Industry and Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 457 1464
					Website:http://www.svgcic.com
					Address: Coreas Building,PO Box 134,Kingstown,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>St Vincent is one of the few islands where good West Indian cuisine can almost always be enjoyed in hotels. There is also plenty of fresh fruit, vegetables and seafood on offer.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; Red snapper.<br />&bull; Kingfish.<br />&bull; <em>Lambi</em> (conch).<br />&bull; <em>Callalou</em> soup.<br /><em>&bull; Souse</em> (pickled meat or seafood).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10 to 15% service added to the bill.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most evening events take place in hotels and it is best to ask at individual hotels for a calendar of events. Nightclubs include the Aquatic club and the Buccama Club<em> </em>on the Leeward Coast. The Attic in Kingstown features a wide variety of music during the week and live entertainment at weekends. There is one casino on the island, at Peniston, on the Leeward side.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Designs on sea-island cottons can be bought and made up into clothes within a few days at a number of shops. Handicrafts and all varieties of straw-made items, grass rugs and other souvenirs can be bought at a number of workshops and gift shops.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1300-1600, Sat 0800-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From casual and economical to elegant and exclusive, lodgings in St Vincent and the Grenadines offer something for every taste and budget. The choice ranges from a rustic cottage on the beach or a historic country hotel in the mountains, to a luxury resort with an island to itself. All hotels are small and emphasise personal service. A list of rates is available from the St Vincent Department of Tourism and all its overseas offices. All rooms are subject to a 7% hotel tax.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading: </strong>Many hotels in the Caribbean offer accommodation according to one of a number of plans. FAP (Full American Plan): room and all meals supplied (including afternoon tea, supper, etc); AP (American Plan): room and three meals supplied; MAP (Modified American Plan): breakfast and dinner included with the price of the room plus, in some places, British-style afternoon tea; CP (Continental Plan): room and breakfast only; EP (European Plan): room only.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From casual and economical to elegant and exclusive, lodgings in St Vincent and the Grenadines offer something for every taste and budget. The choice ranges from a rustic cottage on the beach or a historic country hotel in the mountains, to a luxury resort with an island to itself. All hotels are small and emphasise personal service. A list of rates is available from the St Vincent Department of Tourism and all its overseas offices. All rooms are subject to a 7% hotel tax.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading: </strong>Many hotels in the Caribbean offer accommodation according to one of a number of plans. FAP (Full American Plan): room and all meals supplied (including afternoon tea, supper, etc); AP (American Plan): room and three meals supplied; MAP (Modified American Plan): breakfast and dinner included with the price of the room plus, in some places, British-style afternoon tea; CP (Continental Plan): room and breakfast only; EP (European Plan): room only.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From casual and economical to elegant and exclusive, lodgings in St Vincent and the Grenadines offer something for every taste and budget. The choice ranges from a rustic cottage on the beach or a historic country hotel in the mountains, to a luxury resort with an island to itself. All hotels are small and emphasise personal service. A list of rates is available from the St Vincent Department of Tourism and all its overseas offices. All rooms are subject to a 7% hotel tax.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading: </strong>Many hotels in the Caribbean offer accommodation according to one of a number of plans. FAP (Full American Plan): room and all meals supplied (including afternoon tea, supper, etc); AP (American Plan): room and three meals supplied; MAP (Modified American Plan): breakfast and dinner included with the price of the room plus, in some places, British-style afternoon tea; CP (Continental Plan): room and breakfast only; EP (European Plan): room only.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There is one large hospital, the Kingstown General Hospital. In addition, there are district rural hospitals, health centres and a medical laboratory. Visitors can get treatment at primary level, but need a referral for access to the main hospital. As facilities are limited, serious medical problems require evacuation to another island or the USA. Visitors would be expected to pay the full costs for services, therefore health insurance with emergency repatriation is recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated, and whilst relatively safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is available. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>National Heroes' Day :
							14 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							07 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Carnival Monday :
							02 July </p><p>Emancipation Day :
							06 August </p><p>Independence Day :
							27 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into St Vincent &amp; the Grenadines without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 225g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 0.95L of wine or spirits.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Drugs, firearms and ammunition, and spear fishing equipment are all restricted imports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eastern Caribbean Dollar (XCD; symbol EC$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of EC$100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of EC$1, 50, 25, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.<br /><br />The Eastern Caribbean Dollar is tied to the US Dollar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major currencies can be exchanged at banks and at the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major credit and debit cards are widely accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1500, Fri 0800-1700. The bank at ET Joshua Airport opens Mon-Sat 0700-1700 with additional extensions during the major festivals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter St Vincent and the Grenadines, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Only nationals of a handful of countries do require a visa; check with the consulate/high commission.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Entry visa: EC$200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Entry visa: validity is determined by the immigration authorities upon application.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals of the few countries who do require a visa should apply to the Ministry of National Security in St Vincent and the Grenadines or the nearest high commission/embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All visitors must be able to provide proof of funds to cover their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is possible to extend a visitor permit each month for up to a year from the date of arrival, but this is at the discretion of the immigration authorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[12.984305]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-61.287228]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>389 sq km (150 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>109,644 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>263.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kingstown.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarachy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>St Vincent &amp; the Grenadines make up part of the Windward Islands and lie south of St Lucia. The highest point on St Vincent is the volcanic peak of <em>La Soufri&egrave;re </em>(1,219m/4,000ft). The 'tail' of the comet of St Vincent (the Grenadines) is a string of islands and cays that splays south from Bequia (pronounced Beck-Way), Petit Nevis, Isle &agrave; Quatre and Pigeon Island to Battowia, Baliceaux, Mustique, Petit Mustique, Savan, Canouan, Petit Canouan, Mayreau and the Tobago Cays, Union Island, Palm Island and Petit St Vincent. All of the Grenadines are famous for their white beaches, clear waters and verdant scenery.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic, Anglican, Methodist and other Christian denominations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Vincentians are fun-loving and easy-going people, and the informal and relaxed lifestyle combines many English influences with West Indian. All visitors are made welcome and casual wear is widely acceptable. Refrain, however, from wearing beachwear or mini shorts on the streets or while shopping.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220/240 volts AC, 50Hz (except Petit St Vincent and Palm Island which use 110 volts AC, 60Hz and American-style plugs with two flat pins). British-style plugs with three square pins are used everywhere else.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Ralph Gonsalves since 2001.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor-General Frederick Ballantyne since 2002.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>By the time St Vincent was discovered by Christopher Columbus in January 1498, the island had been occupied for nearly 200 years  by Carib Indians from South America, who had subjugated the original Arawak Indian inhabitants. The island remained a Spanish possession until 1627, when it was granted to the British Lord Carlisle. However, the Caribs fought furiously to keep possession of it. In 1783, the Treaty of Versailles restored St Vincent to Britain, after the French had temporarily taken it. Carib resistance was finally crushed in 1795, after which the settlement of St Vincent proceeded on more conventional lines. During the late 19th and 20th centuries, St Vincent endured a series of natural disasters: in 1812, the first recorded eruption of the La Soufrière volcano, during which many lives were lost; in 1896, floods; two years later, a hurricane; and in 1902, the second eruption of La Soufrière, killing 2000 inhabitants. <BR/><BR/>The next eruptions, neither of which caused loss of life, occurred in the 1970s. Soon after World War II, the right to vote was extended to the entire adult population, after decades of restriction. This was an essential preparatory move towards independence  the key issue of the day. For small Caribbean islands like St Vincent & the Grenadines, a variety of proposals were studied during the 1960s, leading to St Vincent's adoption of Associate Statehood with the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> in 1969. Under this agreement the island was internally self-governing, while <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> looked after foreign and defence matters. It also gave St Vincent the right to declare full independence at any time, which it finally did in October 1979. The viability of St Vincent as a nation state has been the subject of constant debate ever since.<BR/><BR/>In 1992, the New Democratic Party (NDP) administration of James Mitchell committed itself to the pursuit of a limited political and economic union with three other countries in the region  <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/st-lucia">St Lucia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dominica">Dominica</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/grenada">Grenada</a>. The NDP remained in power for almost two decades. It was finally ousted in March 2001, when the United Labour Party won an absolute parliamentary majority. The new premier was ULP party leader Ralph Gonsalves, a former lawyer known to many as 'Comrade Ralph'. Under the new government, St. Vincent joined the Non-Aligned Movement in February 2003 and, later in the year, introduced anti-money laundering measures which ensured its removal from a 'blacklist' of countries which had failed to take sufficient measures to deal with the problem. Gonsalves won a second term in office in the December 2005 elections.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[High Commission for St Vincent and the Grenadines in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7565 2874.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.svghighcom.co.uk/site/Home.html</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7565 2874.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>10 Kensington Court<br/>London<br/>W8 5DL<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of St Vincent and the Grenadines in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 364 6730.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embsvg.com/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 364 6730.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3216 New Mexico Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20016<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Scattered across the Caribbean Sea like so many emeralds, St Vincent &amp; the Grenadines is a glorious-looking archipelago. The country&rsquo;s name makes it sound like an old soul band, and aptly there&rsquo;s something timeless about the place. Lush mountain peaks, white sands, secluded coves, volcanic landscapes and spectacular coral reefs all go towards making this one of the region&rsquo;s most diverse spots. For hikers, sailors and those who just fancy kicking back in wave-lapped sunshine for a week or two, it&rsquo;s some proposition.</p>
<p>The country, which found Hollywood fame when it was used as a setting for the <em>Pirates of the Caribbean</em> films, is made up of 32 islands and cays. St Vincent itself is by far the largest, and has a laid-back capital city, Kingstown, to show for it. Colonial architecture, botanical gardens and a fish market are among the attractions. The latter hints at the dishes that dominate the archipelago&rsquo;s food scene &ndash; fresh seafood, usually washed down with a cold Hairoun beer, is a speciality. Elsewhere on St Vincent there&rsquo;s some fantastic walking to be had, most notably the trail that leads up to La Soufri&egrave;re volcano.</p>
<p>The smaller islands that make up the Grenadines offer an even quieter pace of life. Among the most appealing spots are Bequia, which has good claim to that overused adage &ldquo;the Caribbean as it used to be,&rdquo; and Mustique, a long-established A-list bolthole that has welcomed the likes of Mick Jagger, Kate Moss and the Duke and Duchess of Cambridge.</p>
<p>The best way to experience the outlying islands is to hop between them by boat, and the country as a whole has near-legendary status in the yachting community. The most obvious focal point on a sailing trip is the stupendously scenic Tobago Cays, which is made up of five uninhabited islands and offers excellent potential for divers and snorkelers.</p><p>Scattered across the Caribbean Sea like so many emeralds, St Vincent &amp; the Grenadines is a glorious-looking archipelago. The country&rsquo;s name makes it sound like an old soul band, and aptly there&rsquo;s something timeless about the place. Lush mountain peaks, white sands, secluded coves, volcanic landscapes and spectacular coral reefs all go towards making this one of the region&rsquo;s most diverse spots. For hikers, sailors and those who just fancy kicking back in wave-lapped sunshine for a week or two, it&rsquo;s some proposition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
