<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Sudan" ColCode="sdn" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="sd" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Sudan]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Extremely hot (less so November to March). Sandstorms blow across the Sahara from April to September. In the extreme north, there is little rain but the central region has some rainfall from July to August. The southern region has much higher rainfall, the wet season lasting May to October. Summers are very hot throughout the country, whilst winters are cooler in the north.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical clothes all year, warmer clothes for cool mornings and evenings (especially in the desert).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sudan Airways (<a href="http://www.sudanair.com" target="_blank">www.sudanair.com</a>) runs services to several airports, including El Obeid, Kasala and Port Sudan. The most reliable route is Port Sudan to Khartoum.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>River steamers serve all towns on the Nile but conditions are mostly unsuitable for tourist travel. Services depend on fluctuating water levels. It's wise to take food and water. Destinations include Dongola, Karima and Kosti.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sudan has an extensive rail network (5,500km/3,418 miles) but the service is in bad repair, extremely slow and uncomfortable. The only remaining service is the Khartoum-Wadi Halfa train. Travelling first class is advisable; second- and third-class compartments can get very crowded.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Only major roads are asphalted. Road conditions are poor outside towns, roads to the north are often closed during the rainy season (July to September) and street lights are non-existent. Owing to the bad conditions, you should carry a full set of spare parts for long journeys. Vehicles must be in good working condition.</p><p>In recent years Sudan&rsquo;s network of paved roads has increased enormously, making bus (and minibus) the easiest way to travel. Asphalt highway now stretches from Khartoum all the way to Wadi Halfa in the north, Port Sudan in the east, and the Ethiopian border.</p><p>You can find taxis at ranks or hail them in the street. Taxis are not metered; you must agree fares in advance.</p><p>A Carnet de Passage, adequate finance and roadworthiness certificate (from the embassy) are all needed. An International Driving Permit is recommended, although not legally required. A temporary driving licence is available from local police on presentation of a valid national driving licence, for a maximum period of three months. Women are allowed to drive in Sudan.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Speed limits are 130kph (81mph) on motorways, 110kph (62mph) on highways, 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas and 90kph (50mph) outside built-up areas. Heavy fines are imposed for speeding. It is compulsory for front and rear passengers to wear seat belts. It is illegal to use a handheld mobile telephone while driving. Headlights should be turned on at all times.</p><p>Available in the main towns and at major hotels but charges are high. It&rsquo;s usual to hire a driver with the car.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Speed limits are 130kph (81mph) on motorways, 110kph (62mph) on highways, 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas and 90kph (50mph) outside built-up areas. Heavy fines are imposed for speeding. It is compulsory for front and rear passengers to wear seat belts. It is illegal to use a handheld mobile telephone while driving. Headlights should be turned on at all times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Private <em>bakassi</em> minibuses (nicknamed <em>boksi</em>) ply the streets of Khartoum and major towns. They pick up and set down with no fixed stops.  These operations are on the fringes of legality and should be used with care.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sudan Airways (<a href="http://www.sudanair.com" target="_blank">www.sudanair.com</a>) is Sudan's main carrier. There are no direct flights from the UK or the USA. Indirect options include flights with Egyptair (<a href="http://www.egyptair.com" target="_blank">www.egyptair.com</a>) via Cairo and Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>) via Istanbul.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To Khartoum: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 9 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 17 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$20 (Sudanese nationals may pay in local currency). Transit passengers (within 24 hours) are exempt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Khartoum International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 4km (2 miles) southeast of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Piracy has been reported in the area. A weekly ferry runs from Wadi Halfa down Lake Aswan to Aswan (Egypt). Irregularly departing barges head up the Nile from Kosti to Malakal in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-sudan">South Sudan</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The only practical land border is with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ethiopia">Ethiopia</a> at Gallabat. The land border with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/egypt">Egypt</a> is periodically closed to foreigners.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Outgoing international calls must go through the operator.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies. Coverage is widespread.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet access is available in main towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Television and radio stations are mostly government-controlled.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International post is slow.</p><p>Sat-Thurs 0830-1200 and 1730-1830.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Discover Khartoum’s hidden gems</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With Omdurman and Bahri, Khartoum forms Sudan's unusual 'three-towns capital'. Among the tourist attractions are Omdurman's camel market and the Arab souk. Particularly noteworthy from a historical and artistic viewpoint is the well-organised National Museum, containing treasures dating back 6,000 years. The Khalifa's House Museum will reward those with an interest in Sudan's more recent history.</p>]]><p><b>Dive into Sudan’s Red Sea marvels</b></p><![CDATA[<p>More widely associated with desert landscapes than coral reefs, Sudan has a burgeoning diving industry centred on the Red Sea's Port Sudan from where scuba expeditions are led to various sites, including Jacque Cousteau's underwater village and Sanganeb reef.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the coastal cities</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Port Sudan, Suakin and the Arous Tourist Village are three of the best centres from which to explore the country's beautiful Red Sea coastline. If you can't handle the heat head to Erkowit, which sits 1,200m (3,930ft) above sea level and is home to a beautiful resort offering exquisite panoramas and evergreen vegetation.</p>]]><p><b>Head south for wildlife viewing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The southern provinces are characterised by green forests, open parkland, waterfalls and treeless swamps. The bird and animal life here flourishes, and includes elephant, black and white rhino, antelope, zebra, crocodile, hippo, and the almost extinct shoebill. The Gemmeiza Tourist Village, situated in the heart of East Equatoria, is considered of special interest, owing to the abundance of game in the area.</p>]]><p><b>Hike through the Jebel Marra mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The extinct volcanoes of Jebel Marra, at more than 3,000m (10,000ft), are the highest point in the vast Darfur region of western Sudan. It is a sparsely populated area of outstanding scenic beauty and small traditional villages, waterfalls, volcanic lakes and a pleasant Mediterranean climate.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the Pyramids of Meroe</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Pyramids of Meroe are Sudan's most iconic tourist site. The product of a culture quite different to that of Egypt, these brick-built and steep-sided pyramids sprout in groups of a dozen at a time, and there's not a tourist tout offering souvenirs or camel rides in sight. Nearby are the archaeological sites of Naqa and Musawarat Es Sufra, which are worthy of a detour.</p>]]><p><b>Travel back in time at Musawarat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the largest ancient temple complexes in Sudan, Musawarat is thought to have been a pilgrimage site. Modern pilgrims can wander the columns of the Great Enclosure to study the carved walls depicting the animals that once inhabited the region. Also worth visiting are the engraving of the marriage room, and the elephant stables.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Dinder National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Covering 6,475 sq km (2,500 sq miles) southeast of Khartoum on the Ethiopian border, Dinder National Park is one of the largest in Africa. Providing homes for 27 species of large mammal including big cats and giraffe, it also provides habitats for a large variety of birdlife flying between Europe and Africa including pelican, kingfisher and the beautiful crown crane.</p>]]><p><b>Wander among the ruins of Old Dongola</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The now deserted Nile city of Old Dongola, which sits 80km (49 miles) from modern Dongola, represents one of Sudan's premier archaeological sites. An important medieval Christian city, the remains include those of a dozen churches, though the most prominent survivor is the large Throne Hall, which was constructed between the 9th and 10th centuries.</p>]]><p><b>Watch the Blue and White Niles converge in Khartoum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The long straight roads of Omdurman lead to Sambat Bridge, a good place to view the sluggish and silt-laden waters of the reddish-brown Blue Nile converge with the clearer, lighter shades of the White Nile. Just south, the manmade wonder of the Gezira irrigation canals cover almost 9,000 sq km (3,500 sq miles) of land for cotton production.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>$65.93 billion (2010 est. prior to South Sudan independence)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude oil and petroleum products, cotton, gold, sorghum, peanuts, gum arabic, sugar, meat, hides, live animals and sesame seeds.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Oil and petroleum products, oil pipeline, pumping and refining equipment, chemical products and equipment, wheat and wheat flour, transport equipment, food, tea, agricultural inputs and machinery, industrial inputs and manufactured goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China, Egypt, Saudi Arabia, India</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Since the late 1990s, the export of oil has transformed Sudan's economic outlook, from basketcase to years of boom. Investment has changed Khartoum through large-scale building projects, while Chinese support has helped with a sizeable road-building scheme as well as the construction of the Merowe hydroelectric dam north of Khartoum. Following the independence of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-sudan">South Sudan</a>, oil revenues are expected to decrease, as many oil fields are in the South. <br/><br/> Agriculture employs most of the workforce however, producing cotton - wheat, groundnuts, sorghum and sugar cane. Production of gum arabic, once an important product, has declined through the introduction of synthetic substitutes and increasing competition, particularly from West Africa. Livestock breeding remains important. <br/><br/> The manufacturing sector concentrates on processing the country's agricultural output (sugar, for example) and the production of textiles, cement and some consumer goods. There are some mineral deposits including marble, mica, chromite, gypsum and gold.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businessmen should wear a lightweight suit. Visiting businesspeople should respect Muslim customs. It should be clearly stated in advance if the visitor is female. English is widely spoken in business circles although knowledge of a few words of Arabic will be well received. Punctuality is less important than patience and politeness. Personal introductions are an advantage; business cards should have an Arabic translation on the reverse.<br /></p><p>Sat-Thurs 0800-1430.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Sudan Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (11) 772 346 ,776 518
					Website:http://www.sudanchamber.org
					Address: Gamhoria Street,PO Box 81,Khartoum 11114,]]><b>Sudan Development Corporation (SDC)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (11) 472 186
					Website:
					Address: 21 al-Amarat,PO Box 710,Khartoum,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Peanuts are an important ingredient in Sudanese cooking, adding both taste and texture, and are frequently used as the underlying flavour. Another important ingredient is the thick porridge-like starch made from millet, wheat or corn flour. Plain in taste, the porridge is used as a vehicle to carry richer sauces of meat or vegetables.</p>
<p>Though it owes much to the indigenous people of the region, Sudanese cuisine has also been influenced by its history and geographic location close to the Middle East, demonstrated by an ingredient list that includes cardamom, cinnamon, green peppers and apricots.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Goraasa be dama</strong>: Beef stew flavoured with tomato, green pepper, cardamom and cinnamon.<br />
<strong>Ful</strong>: Mashed fava beans with a tomato and chilli sauce.<br />
<strong>Tamia</strong>: Sudanese falafel.<br />
<strong>Kisra</strong>: Flatbread made from sorghum flour.<br />
<strong>Jibnasalaata</strong>: Salad of feta-like crumbly cheese, tomato and cucumber.<br />
<strong>Dura</strong>: Cooked maize or millet eaten with various vegetables.<br />
<strong>Basboosa</strong>: Sweet semolina cake.<br />
<strong>Kawari</strong>: Soup comprising boiled-down sheep or cow hooves with vegetables and spices.<br />
<strong>Moukhbaza</strong>: Paste of mashed bananas.<br />
<strong>Fassikh</strong>: Fish with a tomato and onion sauce.<br />
<strong>Black tea: </strong>Usually with sugar.<br />
<strong>Black coffee.</strong> Also served with sugar.<br />
<strong>Karkaday</strong>: Popular tea made from hibiscus flowers.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol is banned in Sudan and strict punishments are given to people caught with alcohol.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Not customary.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol is strictly prohibited.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sudan offers little in the way of nightlife. The best music is to be found at Sudanese weddings. Some entertainment can be found in Khartoum and Omdurman, with the national theatre, music hall, cinemas, open-air and hotel entertainment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The souk has stalls selling food, local crafts, spices, jewellery and silver. Special purchases include basketwork, ebony, gold and silver and assorted handicrafts. Visitors must not buy cheetah skins: the killing of cheetahs is prohibited and they are a protected species under the World Wildlife Act.</p><p>Sat-Thurs 0800-1330 and 1730-2000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Good accommodation is scarce outside Khartoum and Port Sudan. Khartoum has around 10 major hotels, including some of international standard, and Port Sudan also has several. There are a few smaller hotels in the main towns and several hostels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Good accommodation is scarce outside Khartoum and Port Sudan. Khartoum has around 10 major hotels, including some of international standard, and Port Sudan also has several. There are a few smaller hotels in the main towns and several hostels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Good accommodation is scarce outside Khartoum and Port Sudan. Khartoum has around 10 major hotels, including some of international standard, and Port Sudan also has several. There are a few smaller hotels in the main towns and several hostels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical treatment may be free at certain establishments but health insurance is essential and should include cover for emergency repatriation. Medical facilities are very limited, particularly outside Khartoum.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as a potential health risk. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Cholera outbreaks can occur; check the &amp;nbsp;National Travel Health Network and Centre (&lt;a href="http://nathnac.net" target="_blank"&gt;http://nathnac.net&lt;/a&gt;) for updates. Avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water; swimming pools which are well chlorinated and maintained are safe. Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations.<br /><br />During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha (Feast of Sacrifice) may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Independence Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Revolution Day :
							30 June </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Sudan by visitors over 20 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 450g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; A reasonable amount of perfume and eau de toilette for personal use.<br />
&bull; A reasonable amount of gifts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include alcohol, pornographic material, pork meat and goods from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/israel">Israel</a>.</p>
<p>You can only import fruit, vegetables, meat and fish with the approval of the Ministry of Animal and Fish Resources. To import firearms, you must obtain permission from the Ministry of Interior.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Finds from archeological sites, protected plants and animal (including ivory).&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sudanese Pound (SDG) = 100 piasters. Notes are in denominations of SDG50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of 50, 20, 10, 5 and 1 piasters.<br /><br />The Sudanese Pound has replaced the Sudanese Dinar, which was phased out on 30 June 2007. 1 Sudanese Pound = 100 Sudanese Dinars = 1,000 old Sudanese Pounds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency should be exchanged only at official bureaux de change and banks, and receipts should be retained. There are severe penalties for changing money on the black market.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Due to recent conflicts, it is recommended to bring plenty of cash rather than rely on card transactions in Sudan.</p><p>There are limited ATM facilities in Khartoum.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are generally not recommended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sat-Thurs 0830-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Sudan, a passport valid for at least six months is required by nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visit visa (covers all types of visit): &pound;55.   A letter of introduction is required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visit visa: 60 days from the date of issue and valid for a stay of up to 60 days from the date of entry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consular section at embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow four to six weeks for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to extend your visit, you should contact the General Directorate of Passports, Immigration and Nationality, Ministry of Interior, Khartoum.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[13.933033]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[30.151977]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,861,484 sq km (718,723 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>41,175,541 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>19.1 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Khartoum.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Federal republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sudan is bordered by Egypt to the north, the Red Sea to the northeast, Ethiopia and Eritrea to the east, South Sudan to the south, the Central African Republic and Chad to the west, and Libya to the northwest. There is a marked difference between the climate, culture and geography of northern and southern Sudan. The far north consists of the contiguous Libyan and Nubian deserts which extend as far south as the capital, Khartoum, and are barren except for small areas beside the Nile River and a few scattered oases.  This gives way to the central steppes which cover the country between 15&deg;N and 10&deg;N, a region of short, coarse grass and bushes, turning to open savannah towards the south, largely flat to the east but rising to two large plateaux in the west and south, the Janub Darfur (3,088m/10,131ft) and Janub Kordofan (500m/1,640ft) respectively. Most of Sudan's agriculture occurs in these latitudes in a fertile pocket between the Blue and White Niles which meet at Khartoum. South of the steppes is a vast shallow basin traversed by the White Nile, and the border with South Sudan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Muslim in the north; Christian and traditional animist beliefs in the south.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the north, Arab culture predominates, while the people in the more fertile south belong to many diverse tribes, each with their own lifestyle and beliefs. Because Sudan is largely Muslim and operates <em>Sharia</em>, women should not wear revealing clothing., although they are not expected to wear a veil or cover their heads. At official and social functions as well as in some restaurants, formal clothes are expected. The Sudanese have a great reputation for hospitality. A curfew operates in major cities from 0000-0400.<br />
<br />
<strong>Photography: </strong>There are many restrictions on photography: a photography permit can be obtained from the External Information Office at the Ministry of Information in Khartoum.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with two or three round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Motazz Moussa, since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Omar al-Bashir since 1989.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sudan&rsquo;s earliest civilisations sprung up along the Nile, growing into the Kingdom of Kush during the 8th century BC. Kush conquered Egypt and adopted many facets of Egyptian culture, including burying its kings in pyramids found at Meroe. The region converted to Christianity in the AD 6th century, and then to Islam in the 14th century.</p>
<p>Modern Egypt conquered Sudan in the 1820s, turning the country into a slave market, but within 60 years jointly administered it with Britain, which was keen to control the area around the newly-built Suez Canal. Sudanese resistance against foreign rule was led by Mahdi Mohammed Ahmed, a figure revered as both a mystic and a holy warrior.</p>
<p>The Mahdist armies kicked both the Egyptians and British out, holding Khartoum until the British re-conquered the territory in 1898. By the mid-20th century, the Sudanese were once more clamouring for independence, which was granted in 1956.</p>
<p>Resenting the political domination of the north, the mostly Christian and animist southerners launched an insurrection against the Khartoum government. This was the trigger for a conflict that raged on and off for five decades and claimed an estimated two million lives.</p>
<p>President Nimeiri ended the first civil war in 1972, granting the south considerable autonomy. He set about giant infrastructure projects aiming to turn Sudan into Africa&rsquo;s breadbasket, but ended up driving the economy into the buffers. Pressure from northern political parties also meant the rescinding of Southern autonomy, the return of civil war, and an army coup.</p>
<p>A cycle of elections and coups has shaped much of Sudan&rsquo;s post-independence history. In 1989, General Omar al-Bashir seized power. It wasn&rsquo;t until the change of geopolitics brought about by 9/11 that Sudan started to shift from its hard-line Islamist position. Flush with money from its new oilfields it sought peace with the south, which became independent in July 2011, although clashes continue. At the same time, a struggle for resources in Darfur sprang into full rebellion. Repression from Khartoum led to President Bashir becoming the first head of state to be indicted by the International Criminal Court for crimes against humanity.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	There are more pyramids in Sudan than in Egypt.<br />
&bull;	Sudanese weddings can last for up to a week.<br />
&bull;	Sudan dropped from being the largest to third largest country in Africa after the independence of South Sudan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Sudan]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(183) 777105 </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ukinsudan.fco.gov.uk/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(183) 777105 </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Sun-Wed 0800 – 1600, Thurs 0800 – 1430 (embassy); Sun– Thurs 0830 – 1330 (acceptance of applications), 1330 – 1430 for enquiries except Thurs which is 1300 -1400 (visas).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>off Sharia Al Baladia, PO Box No 801<br/>Khartoum East<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Sudan in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 338 8565.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.sudanembassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 338 8565.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0900-1600&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2210 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Sudan in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7839 8080.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.sudan-embassy.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7839 8080.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1600 (general enquiries); Mon-Fri 0930-1230 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>St James's<br/>3 Cleveland Row<br/>London<br/>SW1A 1DD<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sudan is hardly your archetypal tourist destination, but behind the unsavoury headlines is a country of exquisite natural beauty, ancient historical attractions and inhabitants well versed in the art of hospitality.</p>
<p>A vast country, three times the size of Texas, Sudan is as much about people as it is natural or man-made wonders. It is a nation where travellers can learn more drinking freshly prepared smoothies with the residents of Khartoum (Sudan is officially alcohol free) than they can by visiting one of the capital&rsquo;s excellent museums.</p>
<p>A relatively young city, Khartoum was built in 1821 at the confluence of the Blue and White Niles while the country was ruled jointly by Britain and Egypt. History and traditionalism jostle with modernity in the city, where stunning classical Islamic architecture in red ochre hues stands beside modern glass and steel skyscrapers paid for by the country&rsquo;s oilfields (which were mostly lost with the independence of South Sudan in 2011).</p>
<p>Centuries before colonial rule Sudan comprised a series of city-states. One of the longest lasting was Mero&euml;, which sits some 200 km (125 miles) northeast of Khartoum. A UNESCO World Heritage Site, this ancient city features more than 200 steep-sided pyramids, which were built as elaborate royal mausoleums. They rise from the sandy dunes of the Nubian Desert and date from between 300 BC and AD 300, when the kingdom was at its most powerful.</p>
<p>Worth visiting in itself, the Nubian Desert &ndash; in reality part of the Sahara &ndash; offers solitude and unspoiled natural beauty stretching east all the way to the Red Sea and Port Sudan, the centre of Sudan&rsquo;s burgeoning diving scene.</p>
<p>One of the least visited countries in East Africa, but one of the friendliest, Sudan has a magical mix of history, tradition and modernity that belies its status as a pariah state.</p>Sudan is hardly your archetypal tourist destination, but behind the unsavoury headlines is a country of exquisite natural beauty, ancient historical attractions and inhabitants well versed in the art of hospitality.  
<p>A vast country, three times the size of Texas, Sudan is as much about people as it is natural or man-made wonders. It is a nation where travellers can learn more drinking freshly prepared smoothies with the residents of Khartoum (Sudan is officially alcohol free) than they can by visiting one of the capital&rsquo;s excellent museums.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
