<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Sweden" ColCode="swe" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="se" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Sweden]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>During the winter, thick layers are needed, with wind chill proving particularly problematic. Far north, stick to woollen layers closest to your skin, and avoid cotton socks. Sturdy footwear, scarves, hats and gloves will be required regardless of where you are.</p>

<p>During the summer, lighter clothing is all you need. Shorts or jeans and a t-shirt is standard attire, with a light jacket or sweater for the evenings. Cobblestones in the city, and unpaved roads in the countryside, means flat shoes or sandals are best for getting around.</p>

<p>Waterproof clothing is recommended year round.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sweden&rsquo;s vast size means that air is an easy and convenient option when travelling long distances, and the country&rsquo;s 40-plus airports give you plenty of choice.</p>
<p>Airlines running domestic flights include SAS (<a href="http://www.flysas.com" target="_blank">www.flysas.com</a>), BRA (<a href="https://www.flygbra.se" target="_blank">www.flygbra.se</a>) and&nbsp;Norwegian (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.norwegian.com">www.norwegian.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unlike Norway and Finland, there are few domestic ferry services in  Sweden. The various archipelagos on the southeast coast are served by  small ferries, the most comprehensive network being within the Stockholm  archipelago, for which you can buy an island-hopping boat pass.</p>
<p>Discover the archipelago and take a ferry at the boat terminal Saltholmen to get to the southern islands or take a ferry at Lilla Varholmen to see the northern islands.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The  other major link is Destination Gotland (tel: +46 771 223 300;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.destinationgotland.se"> www.destinationgotland.se</a>)  between the Baltic island of Gotland and the mainland at Nyn&auml;shamn and  Oskarshamn. Both are very popular routes in summer; booking ahead is  strongly recommended. There are frequent coastal sailings to all ports  and on the hundreds of lakes throughout the country, especially in the  north. For details contact local authorities.</p>
<p><strong>Canal:</strong> The G&ouml;ta Canal (tel: +46 141 202 050;&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.gotakanal.se" target="_blank">www.gotakanal.se</a>), served by vintage steamer, connects Gothenburg and Stockholm.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The excellent and extensive rail system is run by Swedish State Railways (SJ) (tel: +46 771 757 575; <a href="https://www.sj.se" target="_blank">www.sj.se</a>), Tagkompaniet (TKAB) (<a href="https://www.tagkompaniet.se" target="_blank">www.tagkompaniet.se</a>), Sn&auml;lltaget (<a href="http://www.snalltaget.se" target="_blank">www.snalltaget.se</a>), MTR Express (<a href="https://mtrexpress.se" target="_blank">mtrexpress.se</a>) and Inlandsbanan (<a href="http://inlandsbanan.se" target="_blank">inlandsbanan.se</a>). The network is more concentrated in the south where services run between the main cities, but routes extend to the forested and sparsely populated north, which is a scenic and popular holiday destination. Night trains that connect the north and south are a popular choice for budget travellers and students, as seats are often inexpensive for the long journeys. Restaurant cars and sleepers are provided on many trains. Reservations are essential for most express services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail One-Country Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Sweden. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 28 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 get a discount when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurail Sweden Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, five or eight days in one month within Sweden. Available to non-EU nationals from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sweden has an extensive road network, with over 210,000km (130,000 miles) available for public use. In very rural areas, getting around by car is often the only option available, while in cities, intense rush hour traffic means that cars are usually better avoided. Apart from the &Ouml;resund and Svinesund bridges and the bridges across Sundsvallsfj&auml;rden and Motalaviken, Swedish roads are toll-free. Congestion taxes are due in Stockholm and in Gothenburg.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Road signs usually follow European standards. It's worth watching out for elk, reindeer or deer signs in the country &ndash; these mean that a lot of the animals are around and that a collision is possible. The risk is particularly high early in the morning between 0500 and 1000 and at night, when visibility is poor.</p>r<p>The vast majority of Sweden&rsquo;s roads are well maintained, although quality tends to be less impressive in very rural areas. Outside of city rush hours, traffic is usually minimal.</p><p>The main bus operator is Samtrafiken (tel: +46 771 757 575; <a href="https://samtrafiken.se/tjanster/resplus/" target="_blank">samtrafiken.se/tjanster/resplus/</a>), which operates both city and intercity services. Samtrafiken, along with Swebus Express (tel: +46 771 218 218; <a href="https://www.swebus.se" target="_blank">www.swebus.se</a>), also offers express intercity coach services &ndash; a cheaper, if longer, alternative to air.</p><p>Available in all towns and at airports. Intercity taxis are also available. Taxi drivers should be tipped around 10%.</p><p>A national driving licence is sufficient, but it must include a photo or it will not be recognised. You must carry the car's log book and written permission if driving someone else's car. A Green Card is not required by Swedish authorities but it tops up the cover provided by a domestic policy. It is advisable to check the validity of insurance policies prior to departure.</p><p>The minimum age for car drivers is 18; for motorcyclists it is 17. Speed limits are 110/120kph (68mph / 74mph) on motorways depending on the road quality, 70kph (43mph) on other roads outside urban areas, and 50kph (31mph) in towns and cities. There are on-the-spot fines for traffic offences. The use of dipped headlights is compulsory in the daytime for cars and motorcycles and winter (studded) tyres must be used from the beginning of December until the end of March.</p>
<p>Crash helmets are compulsory for motorcyclists and seat belts must be worn at all times. Children under seven cannot travel in a car if it is not equipped with a special child restraint or a normal seat belt adapted for the child's use. Emergency warning triangles are obligatory.</p><p>Assistancek&aring;ren (tel: 020 912 912, in Sweden only).</p><p>All the main international agencies, such as Avis and Hertz, have offices in Sweden. Special weekend deals are usually available, but given Sweden&rsquo;s long distances, options that include unlimited mileage are usually your best bet.</p><p>In Stockholm, Stockholm City Bike (tel: +46 77 444 2424, <a href="http://www.citybikes.se" target="_blank">www.citybikes.se</a>) is the main source of tourist bikes. Try Styr &amp; St&auml;ll (tel: +46 31 227 227; <a href="http://www.goteborgbikes.se" target="_blank">www.goteborgbikes.se</a>) in Gothenburg and Travelshop Europe (tel: +46 40 330 570; <a href="http://www.travelshop.se" target="_blank">www.travelshop.se</a>) in Malm&ouml;. It&rsquo;s also worth bearing nearby Copenhagen&rsquo;s plethora of bike rental services in mind if you&rsquo;re planning to take to two wheels in Malm&ouml;. Outside of the main cities, you can hire bikes from some campsites, hotels and hostels.</p><p>The minimum age for car drivers is 18; for motorcyclists it is 17. Speed limits are 110/120kph (68mph / 74mph) on motorways depending on the road quality, 70kph (43mph) on other roads outside urban areas, and 50kph (31mph) in towns and cities. There are on-the-spot fines for traffic offences. The use of dipped headlights is compulsory in the daytime for cars and motorcycles and winter (studded) tyres must be used from the beginning of December until the end of March.</p>
<p>Crash helmets are compulsory for motorcyclists and seat belts must be worn at all times. Children under seven cannot travel in a car if it is not equipped with a special child restraint or a normal seat belt adapted for the child's use. Emergency warning triangles are obligatory.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public transport is efficient, comprehensive and well-integrated. Stockholm has bus, trams, metro (T-banan) and local rail services (<a href="http://sl.se" target="_blank">sl.se</a>). Most tickets are loaded on the SL Access smart card, which can also be used on small ferries around the Stockholm islands. V&auml;sttrafik (<a href="http://www.vasttrafik.se" target="_blank">www.vasttrafik.se</a>) runs Gothenburg's buses and trams. Taxis are widely available; large taxi companies are cheaper than independents. Several of the main cities, particularly Stockholm, have boat excursions and services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Sweden</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">mora</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Sweden</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">malmouml</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.05</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">8.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.45</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Sweden</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">lulearing</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">20.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">15.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Sweden</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">gothenburg</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.30</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sweden's national carrier is SAS (<a href="http://www.flysas.com">www.flysas.com</a>). Other airlines operating direct flights to Sweden from the UK include British Airways (<a href="https://www.britishairways.com">www.britishairways.com</a>), Norwegian (<a href="https://www.norwegian.com">www.norwegian.com</a>) and Ryanair (<a href="https://www.ryanair.com">www.ryanair.com</a>). SAS and Norwegian both offer direct flights from the USA.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sweden/gothenburg-landvetter-airport">Gothenburg Landvetter Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sweden/stockholm-arlanda-airport">Stockholm Arlanda Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/stockholm">Stockholm</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours 20 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 8 hours.</p>
<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/gothenburg">Gothenburg</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 1 hour 55 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 9 hours 20 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The cheapest time to fly to Sweden is during the autumn and winter months when the chilly weather and limited hours of daylight put a dampener on seeing the sights and picking up sartorial inspiration from the country&rsquo;s stylistas. However, if you&rsquo;re prepared to brave the cold and dark, it&rsquo;s worth taking a punt on cheaper winter fares for a chance to see the aurora borealis or to take advantage of the short flying times for a weekender in one of the country&rsquo;s numerous de luxe boutique hotels. Peak season fares, from June to August, are usually considerably steeper.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The cheapest time to fly to Sweden is during the autumn and winter months when the chilly weather and limited hours of daylight put a dampener on seeing the sights and picking up sartorial inspiration from the country&rsquo;s stylistas. However, if you&rsquo;re prepared to brave the cold and dark, it&rsquo;s worth taking a punt on cheaper winter fares for a chance to see the aurora borealis or to take advantage of the short flying times for a weekender in one of the country&rsquo;s numerous de luxe boutique hotels. Peak season fares, from June to August, are usually considerably steeper.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Gothenburg-Landvetter Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.swedavia.com/landvetter<p>Gothenburg-Landvetter Airport is located 25km (15.5 miles) east of Gothenburg, in southern Sweden.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+46 10 109 3100</p>]]><b>Stockholm Arlanda Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.swedavia.com/arlanda<p>Stockholm Arlanda Airport is located 43km (27 miles) north of Stockholm.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+46 1 0109 1000.</p>]]><b>Malmö Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.swedavia.com/malmo<p>The airport is 31km (20 miles) east of the city (journey time - 35 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Swedish ports offering marina facilities include Gothenburg (www.goteborgshamn.se), Sundsvalls Hamn (www.sundsvallshamn.se), Hargs Hamn (www.hargshamn.se) and Trelleborg (www.trelleborgshamn.se).</p>
<p><strong>&Ouml;resund Rundt Card:</strong> This pass enables visitors to travel on both sides of the &Ouml;resund sound (Sweden and Denmark) on busses or trains. You can buy the ticket from Skanetrafiken (www.skanetrafiken.se).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Numerous train, or train plus ferry combination routes connect the UK with Sweden. The easiest way is by Eurostar&nbsp;to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brussels">Brussels</a>, followed by high-speed ICE train to Cologne and InterCity train to Hamburg. After an overnight stop in Hamburg, you can catch a ICE-TD train to Copenhagen and then catch a train from Copenhagen to Stockholm, Malm&ouml; or Gothenburg.</p>
<p>The Swedish national rail company SJ (<a href="https://www.sj.se" target="_blank">www.sj.se</a>) run the X2 express trains between Copenhagen and Stockholm, with a travel time of just under 5 hours. A comfortable seat, free WiFi and power sockets are included as standard with your ticket.</p>
<p>Other connections include taking the ferry from Denmark or making use of through rail routes from Norway (Oslo, Narvik and Trondheim). Bicycles can be taken on the trains.&nbsp;</p>
<p>You can check most international timetables on <a href="https://www.bahn.com" target="_blank">www.bahn.com</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 30 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, or 5 days in 15 days or 5, 7, 10 days in a month across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 22 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 5 or 7 days in one month, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sweden is easily accessible by car from Finland and Norway, whose long borders with Sweden have numerous, crossing points. Motorists entering from Denmark can use the beautiful &Ouml;resund Bridge, which connects the Danish capital Copenhagen with Malm&ouml;. On the Swedish side, the toll bridge connects to the E6 motorway.</p>
<p>Motorists moving between the south of Sweden and Finland can use car ferries either by night or day, connecting Stockholm with Turku and Helsinki as well as the island city Mariehamn. The Baltic cities of Riga and Tallinn are also accessible by ferry. Tallink Silja (<a href="https://www.tallinksilja.com" target="_blank">www.tallinksilja.com</a>) and Viking Line (<a href="https://www.vikingline.com" target="_blank">www.vikingline.com</a>)are the main ferry operators.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Due to the ever increasing mobile phone use the last pay phones were dismantled in 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mobile phone coverage is available across most of the country, although it can be sporadic in very isolated or extremely rural areas. Most international networks also have arrangements with local providers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sweden is one of the world's most net-savvy countries, with a very high proportion of the population online. Wi-Fi is widespread in most towns and cities, with many restaurants, hotels and public spaces offering access. Internet cafes can be found in most major urban areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Freedom of the press has been enshrined in Swedish law since 1776. The press is funded by a combination of government cash, private money and taxpayer-provided levies, with public TV stations funded by a license fee in the same way as the UK&rsquo;s BBC. Media organisations are regulated by the Swedish Press Council, which deals with media-related complaints directed to it by the public-facing Press Ombudsman.</p>
<p>The Swedish public enjoys a wide variety of public and commercial broadcast services, although until relatively recently, public TV and radio had a near-monopoly of the airwaves. Digital terrestrial broadcasting was launched by <em>SVT</em> in 1999, in the face of much opposition from critics, including Social Democratic MP Maj Britt Theorin, calling for a prohibition on private ownership of satellite dishes. Swedes are also among the top consumers of newspapers in the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Post boxes are yellow. Stamps and aerograms are on sale at post agencies and also at most bookstalls and stationers. Airmail within Europe usually takes between two to three days, but can take significantly longer if posting to a destination outside of the EU. Swedish post offices were closed down and replaced by postal agencies. Nowadays, postal service counters can be found in grocery stores, supermarkets, newsagents, petrol stations and corner stores.&nbsp;</p><p>Mon-Fri, 0800-1900; Sat, 0800-1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Ancient Swedish civilisation</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For history buffs, the southwestern Bohusl&auml;n province (<a href="http://www.vastsverige.com/bohuslan" target="_blank">www.vastsverige.com/bohuslan</a>), one of the most important centres of ancient Swedish civilisation, is a must-visit. The region is also packed with museums displaying the many archaeological relics found in the area &ndash; many of which date back to the Bronze Age and Viking era.</p>]]><p><b>Astrid Lindgren's World</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Immerse yourself in Astrid Lindgren's fantasy world in Vimmerby in the province of Sm&aring;land: Pippi Longstocking, Ronja the robber's daughter, Emil, Karlsson on the roof and many more of Astrid Lindgren's famous characters gather in Astrid Lindgren's V&auml;rld (<a href="http://www.alv.se/en" target="_blank">alv.se</a>). In summer, there are about 50 different daily theatre performances in the park. Spend the night in one of the houses in <em>Den Lilla Staden</em> (The Tiny Town) and relive the life of the Bullerby children.</p>]]><p><b>Beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In summer, make the most of Sweden's hundreds of miles of beaches, particularly on the west coast, and its 96,000 lakes. The beaches of Gotland are a popular destination, with their blue waters and white sand reminiscent of the Mediterranean. If swimming and sunbathing isn't enough, head to one of the numerous waterskiing and windsurfing centres.</p>]]><p><b>Boat trips</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a boat trip from Stockholm city centre among the islands to Drottningholm Palace (<a href="http://www.kungahuset.se" target="_blank">www.kungahuset.se</a>), where the Palace Theatre opera house has been preserved in its original 18th-century form, and stages productions in period costume and using authentic instruments.</p>]]><p><b>Canal cruises</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If you have a couple of days to spare, take a cruise on the MS Ceres along the historic G&ouml;ta Canal. Constructed in the early 19th century, the canal&rsquo;s 614km (382 miles) stretch from Gothenburg in the west to S&ouml;derk&ouml;ping on the Baltic Sea. Tours start in Stockholm and Gothenburg (<a href="http://www.gotakanal.se" target="_blank">www.gotakanal.se</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Christmas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Finland might be the official home of St.Nick, but Sweden, which also possesses a large chunk of Lapland, has an ultra cool take on Christmas of its own. Take the kids (or just yourself) to Mora in the heart of the Swedish Lakeland region, where you can meet Father Christmas at the Santaworld theme park (<a href="http://www.tomteland.se" target="_blank">www.tomteland.se</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Cycling</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the nicest ways to get to grips with the Swedish capital, seeing the city on two wheels lets you get close to the magnificent Stadhuset (City Hall) and navigate the winding streets of Gamla Stan (The Old Town) with ease. For bike rental, try Stockholm City Bikes (tel: +46 (0) 77 444 2424; <a href="http://www.citybikes.se" target="_blank">www.citybikes.se</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Djurgården</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a ferry to Stockholm's Djurg&aring;rden Island area, to see the world's oldest open-air museum Skansen (<a href="www.skansen.se">www.skansen.se</a>), showcasing historical houses and farmsteads, as well as a zoo of farm animals and wild Nordic animals like wolves, brown bears and the elusive lynx. The fairground Gr&ouml;na Lund (<a href="www.gronalund.com">www.gronalund.com</a>) has its entrance next to the ferry port, and is full of rollercoasters and other rides with a view over the Stockholm islands. You can also head to the Nordic Museum (<a href="https://www.nordiskamuseet.se" target="_blank">www.nordiskamuseet.se</a>), Waldemarsudde House (<a href="https://www.waldemarsudde.se" target="_blank">www.waldemarsudde.se</a>) &ndash; until 1947, the home of royal artist Prince Eugen - and Liljevalchs Konsthall (<a href="http://www.liljevalchs.com" target="_blank">www.liljevalchs.com</a>) art gallery.</p>]]><p><b>Fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Norrbotten is an angler's paradise with plenty of mountain streams and excellent sea fishing. It is situated on the so-called Midnight Sun Coast, which is a 1,500km (900-mile) stretch of Baltic coastline that runs all the way to the Finnish border.</p>]]><p><b>Glassworks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>German immigrants founded Sweden's crystal and glass-making industry in the southern province of Sm&aring;land in the 16th century and 16 glassworks in the area are open to visitors. The Sm&aring;land Museum (<a href="http://www.kulturparkensmaland.se/1.0.1.0/13/2/" target="_blank">www.kulturparkensmaland.se/1.0.1.0/13/2/</a>) in V&auml;xj&ouml; also has permanent exhibitions dedicated to the region&rsquo;s glassmaking past, or why not try making your own glass artwork at the Stockholm Glassworks in Skansen (<a href="http://www.stockholms-glasbruk.se">www.stockholms-glasbruk.se</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Golfing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sweden has more than 400 golf courses: one situated north of the Arctic Circle enjoys 24-hour daylight during the summer months, with the interesting result that many midsummer championships take place at night.</p>]]><p><b>Gothenburg</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gothenburg (G&ouml;teborg) is the home of Volvo cars and they have a museum to prove it (<a href="http://www.volvomuseum.com" target="_blank">www.volvomuseum.com</a>). If cars aren&rsquo;t your thing, relive the city's seafaring past at the Maritime Museum (<em>Sj&ouml;fartsmuseet</em>) (<a href="https://www.sjofartsmuseetakvariet.se" target="_blank">www.sjofartsmuseetakvariet.se</a>) or head to the pretty Nordstaden Kronhuset area, home of the fascinating City Museum (<a href="http://goteborgsstadsmuseum.se" target="_blank">goteborgsstadsmuseum.se</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Island hopping</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head offshore - Gotland and &Ouml;land are Sweden's biggest islands, in the southeast of the country. On Gotland are the Lummelunda Caves (<a href="http://www.lummelundagrottan.se/" target="_blank">www.lummelundagrottan.se</a>) with spectacular stalactites and stalagmites, and a preserved medieval town at Kattlundsg&aring;rd.</p>]]><p><b>Malmö</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Much maligned and unfairly ignored, Sweden&rsquo;s third city, Malm&ouml; (<a href="http://malmo.se" target="_blank">malmo.se</a>), has undergone a renaissance in the years since the construction of the &Ouml;resund Bridge. Key sights include Malm&ouml;hus Castle and the St Petri Church. Also see Konsthallen (<a href="http://www.konsthall.malmo.se" target="_blank">www.konsthall.malmo.se</a>) and the remarkable Turning Torso skyscraper.</p>]]><p><b>Medieval and modern</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Founded by King Sven Tvesk&auml;gg more than 1,000 years ago, the pretty town of Lund is home to a lovely 12th-century cathedral, 14th-century astronomical clock and hordes of 21st century students. The huge open air museum, Kulturen (<a href="https://www.kulturen.com" target="_blank">www.kulturen.com</a>) is in the heart of the city centre, and includes row after row of perfectly preserved mediaeval streets. There is also the spectacular &Ouml;resund Bridge, the world's longest single span bridge, between Denmark and Sweden, close to Malm&ouml;.</p>]]><p><b>National collections</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Historical Museum (<a href="http://historiska.se/home" target="_blank">historiska.se/home</a>) in Gothenburg is home to Sweden&rsquo;s most important historical treasures, including prehistoric artefacts and stunning medieval art. Stockholm&rsquo;s National Museum of Fine Arts (<a href="http://www.nationalmuseum.se" target="_blank">www.nationalmuseum.se</a>) meanwhile, houses the country's stunning collection of fine art.</p>]]><p><b>Naval and folk history</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Delve further into Sweden's history at the Vasa Museum (<a href="http://www.vasamuseet.se" target="_blank">www.vasamuseet.se</a>), which contains a restored 360-year-old wooden warship recovered from Stockholm's harbour in 1961, or head to the Medieval Museum (<a href="http://medeltidsmuseet.stockholm.se/in-english">medeltidsmuseet.stockholm.se</a>) to see Riddarholmsskeppet, a wooden ship dating back to the 1520's.</p>]]><p><b>Sami experience</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Meet the S&aacute;mi people at Jokkmokk (<a href="http://www.jokkmokk.se" target="_blank">www.jokkmokk.se</a>), where you&rsquo;ll find collections of S&aacute;mi art and cultural artefacts along with <em>Lappstaden</em> - an old-fashioned village of 70 cone-shaped traditional huts called <em>Lavvu</em>. Arjeplog also has an interesting S&aacute;mi museum, Silvermuseet (<a href="http://silvermuseet.se" target="_blank">silvermuseet.se</a>), home to an extraordianry collection of S&aacute;mi silver jewellery.</p>]]><p><b>Staying fit</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Whatever you're into, Sweden's many wide open spaces and endless coastline means that sporting activities are on offer just about anywhere you go. Winter sports such as skating, tobogganing, snowmobiling, ice climbing and dog sledding are particularly popular.</p>]]><p><b>Stockholm Old Town</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the historic Gamla Stan (<a href="http://www.visitstockholm.com" target="_blank">www.visitstockholm.com</a>), with its collection of beautifully-preserved historic buildings bisected by winding cobbled streets. Slottsbacken, Gamla Stan&rsquo;s highest hill, is home to the Royal Palace and a jumble of baroque buildings. The suburb&rsquo;s main streets, &Ouml;sterl&aring;nggatan and V&auml;sterl&aring;nggatan, are prime shopping spots with plenty of fashionable boutiques.</p>]]><p><b>The Lakelands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sweden has more than 97,500 lakes to choose from, but the prettiest are to be found in the huge Swedish Lakeland area. Stretching from Gothenburg in the west and taking in large chunks of Uppsala and the Baltic coast; the region is rich in stunning scenery, wonderful old castles and picturesque tiny villages.</p>]]><p><b>Wildlife</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Sweden's prime wildlife watching spots, the H&auml;rjedalen Valley is the home of the country's only herd of musk oxen.</p>

<p>Lapland has abundant reindeer, buzzard and beaver. Lynx, wolves, brown bears and wolverines are around but rarely spotted as they prefer to stay away from humans.</p>

<p>Elk and deer are common around the country, and can be spotted even in urban areas.</p>]]><p><b>Winter refreshment</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Experience the 'ice beds' (thick sleeping bags included) and enjoy a well-earned thirst quencher in the Absolut Icebar at the igloo-esque Ice Hotel (<a href="http://www.icehotel.com" target="_blank">www.icehotel.com</a>) in the small northern village of Jukkasj&auml;rvi in Lapland. Only open during the winter, the hotel has to be rebuilt every year, as it melts during the summer. Or opt for the Ice Hotel 365 which is open year round.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$511 billion (2016)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, motor vehicles, paper products, pulp, wood and chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, petroleum products, chemicals, motor vehicles, iron and steel.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Germany, Denmark, Norway, UK,&nbsp;Finland&nbsp;and the United States of America.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sweden boasts one of Europe's most advanced industrial economies and one of the highest standards of social welfare in the world. It is also the headquarters of a relatively large number of world-class multinational companies (Ericsson, Electrolux, ABB, AstraZeneca, IKEA, H&amp;M and Volvo among them). A prolonged period of peace, which included a policy of neutrality during both World Wars, has contributed much to its economic development.</p>
<p>Well over half of the country is covered by forest, which supplies the raw material for the country&rsquo;s wood-based industries (paper, wood pulp and finished products such as furniture), which account for 20% of Swedish material exports. The agricultural (mainly in the south) and fisheries sector is, however, fairly insignificant today, accounting for just 1.7% of GDP.</p>
<p>Sweden has a strong industrial sector that produces a number of major exports including machinery, vehicles, office and telecommunications equipment, iron and steel, wood products and chemicals. The country is rich in mineral resources, which include 15% of the world's known uranium deposits and large deposits of iron ore, copper, lead and zinc.</p>
<p>The annual GDP growth rate for 2017 was estimated to be 4&percnt;. This shows that Sweden has overcome the effects of the financial and economic crisis in Europe in recent years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Swedes pride themselves on their cooperative, egalitarian spirit in the workplace. In theory at least, issues of status and hierarchy are considered to be of far less importance than in many other countries, with the majority of people using their first names in the work place. Elaborate deference is definitely out of fashion and the management style, in a similar style to Swedish government practice, tends to be consensual rather than authoritarian.</p>
<p>Since Stockholm is the capital, the city sees itself as setting the tone and pace for the rest of the country. Nevertheless, however relaxed Swedes are about power and authority, they are strict timekeepers and punctuality is expected for both work and play. Businesspeople are expected to dress smartly, with suits being the norm, although more casual attire is favoured in industries such as IT, media and internet businesses - here you can generally get away with wearing jeans and a shirt. English is widely - and well - spoken in most circles. Business cards are commonly used.</p>
<p>Swedes also tend to go straight to the point; personal chat is generally put to one side until the real business is done and dusted. Most business socialising is done away from the home, at bars and restaurants. Dinners tend to be quite boozy affairs, although at lunches water is often substituted for alcohol. 'Afterwork' – written and pronounced in English – is the Swedish Happy Hour, and usually starts around 1600. City bars and restaurants fill with crowds who have finished work for the day, to drink beer, wine and cocktails.</p> 
<p>People in Sweden work to live, they don't live to work. Summer vacations are usually four weeks or longer, and to accommodate their employees, entire offices and small companies may shut around July and August. At <em>midsommar</em>, the summer solstice that falls around the end of June, towns and cities will be abandoned as Swedes head to their cottages in the countryside.</p><p>Flexible working hours are a widespread practice with lunch between 1200 and 1300. Normal office hours are 0800-1600, usually with an earlier finish on Fridays. It's not uncommon for parents to leave daily at 1530, to pick up their children from daycare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>The Swedish Exhibition &amp; Congress Centre</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: +46 (31) 708 88 00.
					Website:http://svenskamassan.se/en/contact/
					Address: ,Mässans Gata / Korsvägen,Gothenburg,SE-412 94]]><b>Malmö Tourist Convention Bureau</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: +46 (40) 34 22 24.
					Website:http://www.malmotown.com/moten-kongress/hur-kan-vi-hjalpa-dig/kontakt/
					Address: ,Skeppsbron 2,Malmö,211 20]]><b>Invest Stockholm</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: +46 (8) 508 280 00.
					Website:http://www.investstockholm.com
					Address: ,Drottninggatan 33,Stockholm,10325]]><b>Stockholm Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: +46 (8) 55 51 00 00.
					Website:http://www.chamber.se/
					Address: ,Brunnsgatan 2,Stockholm,SE-103 21]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>While Swedish food isn&rsquo;t known for its sophistication, it does have a simple, wholesome charm all of its own. Locally produced and organic ingredients take pride of place in the kitchen and wild food such as mushrooms, blueberries and cloudberries crop up seasonally. A long coastline and numerous freshwater lakes mean fish is a staple part of the diet along with meat and root vegetables.</p>
<p>Rest assured, travellers will find the meatballs so beloved of the ubiquitous flat pack homewares brand are considerably better in Sweden than in the store canteen. From every day Swedish cuisine, or husmanskost, &auml;rtsoppape (pea soup) is a staple and a heart-warming choice on cold winter days, particularly when followed by pancakes doused in Swedish punch &ndash; a very sweet (and very strong) local liqueur.</p>
<p>Waiter service is common although there are many self-service snack bars.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Sm&ouml;rg&aring;sbord:</strong> The classic Scandinavian cold table includes a starter of pickled herring with boiled potatoes followed by smoked salmon or anchovies, cold meats, p&acirc;t&eacute;, sliced beef, stuffed veal or smoked reindeer.</p>
<p><strong>Jansson&rsquo;s temptation:</strong> Sliced herring, potatoes and onions baked in cream.<br />
<strong>K&ouml;ttbullar:</strong> Small meatballs.</p>
<p><strong>Rotmos med flask: </strong>Pork with potatoes and rutabaga, a root vegetable like turnip.<br />
<strong>Pyttipanna:</strong> A bubble and squeak-style blend of fried diced meat with potatoes and onion, usually served with a fried egg and sliced pickled beetroot.<br />
<strong>Gravlax:</strong> Salmon that has been specially prepared and marinated).<br />
&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Ostkaka: </strong>Swedish cheesecake.</p>
<p><strong>Akvavit:</strong> A Scandinavian spirit traditionally drunk chilled with sm&ouml;rg&aring;sbord. Flavours vary from practically tasteless to sweetly spiced.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Service in restaurants is not generally included in the bill; around 10% is usually expected.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>You must be at least 20 to buy alcohol in shops; 18 in bars, restaurants and nightclubs.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fashion isn&rsquo;t the only element of Swedish culture that has made the world sit up and take notice; its music scene too has come a long way since the days when Abba ruled the airwaves. Today, Swedish music is as richly varied as its nightlife, proving that the Swedish musical milieu is alive and kicking. Out and about in Stockholm, Gothenburg and Malm&ouml;, you&rsquo;ll find plentiful bars, caf&eacute;s and clubs; many of which will be playing some of Sweden&rsquo;s finest tunes.</p>
<p>For a more dedicated musical experience, try Stockholm&rsquo;s Cirkus venue (tel: +46 (08) 5879 8700; <a href="http://www.cirkus.se" target="_blank">www.cirkus.se</a>), which benefits from an enchanting setting in a beautiful baroque building, and has attracted bands from all over the world. For a slightly more highbrow treat, head to a performance from the Royal Ballet (tel: +46 (08) 791 4400; <a href="http://www.operan.se" target="_blank">www.operan.se</a>). Outside of the capital, the country&rsquo;s lyrical approach to nights out continues, with the Court Theatre of the Palace of Drottningholm (<a href="https://dtm.se" target="_blank">dtm.se</a>), which puts on wonderful 18th-century operas.</p>
<p>While the capital&rsquo;s 24/7 approach to parties wins the plaudits, Malm&ouml; is fast building a reputation for its clubs, while Gothenburg offers plenty of options in picturesque surroundings. Nonetheless, Stockholm remains Sweden&rsquo;s number one destination for party people, with the S&ouml;dermalm, Vasastan and Kungsholmen districts topping the charts at night. Clubbing is a big part of the Stockholm experience, with music catering for every possible taste, although be warned: death metal nights enjoy a Teflon-like popularity in the Swedish capital, so double check with the club&rsquo;s website before you go, to avoid a wasted entry fee. Top choices include Berns (tel: +46 (08) 5663 2200; <a href="http://www.berns.se" target="_blank">www.berns.se</a>) - one of Sweden&rsquo;s oldest clubs, Nalen (tel: +46 (08) 5052 9200; <a href="http://www.nalen.com" target="_blank">www.nalen.com</a>), Mosebacke (tel: +46 (08) 531 99490; <a href="http://sodrateatern.com" target="_blank">sodrateatern.com</a>) and Debaser (tel: +46 (08) 462 98 60; <a href="http://debaser.se" target="_blank">debaser.se</a>), which also has a second branch in Stockholm almost next door.</p>
<p>Away from Stockholm, Malm&ouml; has plenty for the hardened night owl to enjoy and as in Gothenburg and the capital, boasts clubs that remain open until three and even five AM. Slagthuset (tel: +46 (040) 611 80 90; <a href="http://slagthus.se" target="_blank">slagthus.se</a>) is Malmo&rsquo;s and Scandinavia&rsquo;s biggest club and offers three floors of party action, with revels lasting until the small hours, seven days a week. Also worth a look is Club Wonk (tel: +46 (04) 023 9303; <a href="http://www.wonk.se" target="_blank">www.wonk.se</a>), Malmo&rsquo;s number one gay nightclub, which offers free entry for drag queens.</p>
<p>Gothenburg, the city that brought Ace of Base to the world, isn&rsquo;t short of party options either, although one must-try are the schlager clubs and bars, which focus on pumping out the sort of tunes most often heard during the Eurovision Song Contest. It&rsquo;s hilariously bad taste but incredibly good fun and creates a really upbeat, cheerful atmosphere. At the other end of the spectrum, cool jazz clubs such as Nefertiti (tel: +46 (03) 1711 40 76; <a href="http://www.nefertiti.se" target="_blank">www.nefertiti.se</a>) have plenty for hipsters to love.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not for nothing has Sweden, its capital Stockholm in particular, built up a reputation as one of the world&rsquo;s top destinations for all things fashionable. Cult label Monki stands for popular Swedish fashion, while its denim-focused sister label, Cheap Monday, and Gothenburg brand Dr. Denim, do some of the best jeans on the planet. Other brands to look out for include Fillipa K, Whyred, Acne and Minimarket. Sweden&rsquo;s flair for design doesn&rsquo;t stop at fashion either. IKEA is one of the country&rsquo;s better known exports but rather than heading to one of its stores, hunt down hip locally designed homeware at leading department store, <em>Nordiska Kompaniet</em> or NK (tel: +46 8 762 8000;&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nk.se/stockholm/" target="_blank">www.nk.se/stockholm/</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Purchases</strong><br />
Sweden is justly famous for its fashion and very few places are without at least one branch of H&amp;M. While H&amp;M might be the best known of the Swedish fashion brands, it&rsquo;s also one of the least special and its ubiquity means giving it a miss won&rsquo;t leave you missing out. Instead, focus on the higher end labels, which not only are cheaper in Sweden, but also of significantly better quality. Key stops should be at Acne, Fillipa K and Whyred, as well as the boutique shopping centre Mood (<a href="http://www.moodstockholm.se" target="_blank">www.moodstockholm.se</a>). Cameras, mobile phones and glassware are all excellent quality and cheaper in Sweden than elsewhere in Europe. Also worth looking for are the traditional, brightly coloured Dala horse wooden toys, Sami handicrafts, traditional handknitted Nordic sweaters and Swedish aquavit (schnaps). It&rsquo;s also easy to find brands originating in other Scandinavian countries, so if you aren&rsquo;t travelling on to Finland or Denmark, don&rsquo;t leave without picking up some bold printed clothes and bags from Finnish fabric designer Marimekko (<a href="http://www.marimekko.com" target="_blank">www.marimekko.com</a>) or fabulous minimalist pieces by Danish jewellery designer Georg Jensen (<a href="https://www.georgjensen.com" target="_blank">www.georgjensen.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Key areas</strong><br />
In Stockholm, bypass Drottninggatan &ndash; the city&rsquo;s main pedestrian shopping street, which is packed with international high street brands - and head to G&ouml;tgatan in Gamla Stan, where you&rsquo;ll find a throng of tiny boutiques selling some of Sweden&rsquo;s edgiest labels and wonderful homeware.</p> 
<p>In Gothenburg, make Nordstan (<a href="http://nordstan.se/en/" target="_blank">nordstan.se/en/</a>), Scandinavia&rsquo;s largest shopping centre &ndash; your first stop. Away from the shopping centre, try Magasinsgatan in the Innerstaden district, which is home to an eclectic mix of shops selling everything from fashion to food.&nbsp;</p><p>Mon-Fri 0930-1800; Sat 0930-1400/1600. Some department stores stay open until 1900 or later. In larger towns, some shops have longer opening hours and are also open Sundays 1200-1600. In rural areas, shops and petrol stations close by 1800.</p><p>VAT (Moms) is refundable to visitors who are resident in non-EU countries on goods bought at shops participating in the Tax-Free Shopping scheme. The refund is payable to the customer when departing from Sweden at either airports or customs offices at ports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sweden boasts an excellent range of hotels, covering the full spectrum of prices and standards with many offering discounted rates throughout the summer and at weekends during the winter. Details of these offers and other (including family) discount schemes are available from VisitSweden. Unsurprisingly, the Swedish capital (and elsewhere) does a good line in boutique hotels, with fabulous spots such as Sweden&rsquo;s oldest inn - the quirky Stallmastaregarden Hotel (tel: (08) 610 1300; <a href="http://www.stallmastaregarden.se" target="_blank">www.stallmastaregarden.se</a>) &ndash; among the best. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars. An <em>SHR </em>sign indicates that the establishment belongs to the Swedish Hotel &amp; Restaurant Association.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>One of the nicest (and cheapest) sleeping options Sweden has to offer, bed and breakfasts tend to be small and cosy but vary hugely in terms of facilities. Some of the more rural operations can be very basic affairs, with washing water provided in buckets. Happily, this type is a rarity and modern versions complete with hot water and proper bathrooms are to be found practically anywhere.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sweden boasts an excellent range of hotels, covering the full spectrum of prices and standards with many offering discounted rates throughout the summer and at weekends during the winter. Details of these offers and other (including family) discount schemes are available from VisitSweden. Unsurprisingly, the Swedish capital (and elsewhere) does a good line in boutique hotels, with fabulous spots such as Sweden&rsquo;s oldest inn - the quirky Stallmastaregarden Hotel (tel: (08) 610 1300; <a href="http://www.stallmastaregarden.se" target="_blank">www.stallmastaregarden.se</a>) &ndash; among the best. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars. An <em>SHR </em>sign indicates that the establishment belongs to the Swedish Hotel &amp; Restaurant Association.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sweden boasts an excellent range of hotels, covering the full spectrum of prices and standards with many offering discounted rates throughout the summer and at weekends during the winter. Details of these offers and other (including family) discount schemes are available from VisitSweden. Unsurprisingly, the Swedish capital (and elsewhere) does a good line in boutique hotels, with fabulous spots such as Sweden&rsquo;s oldest inn - the quirky Stallmastaregarden Hotel (tel: (08) 610 1300; <a href="http://www.stallmastaregarden.se" target="_blank">www.stallmastaregarden.se</a>) &ndash; among the best. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars. An <em>SHR </em>sign indicates that the establishment belongs to the Swedish Hotel &amp; Restaurant Association.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Sweden, like the rest of the Scandinavian bloc, benefits from excellent public healthcare programmes. Clinics and hospitals are clean and safe, and the quality of care provided is usually exemplary. Urgent cases (emergencies) are prioritised and are usually treated immediately, while the Swedish national guarantee of care states that patients with non-urgent health concerns should be able to get an appointment with a GP within three days of contacting the clinic.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As in the UK and other European countries with a nationalised healthcare system, not everything is free and prescriptions can be extremely expensive. EU nationals are charged between 100 and SEK 300 for a doctor's visit. American and Canadian citizens will find it especially steep with most prescriptions coming in at around SEK500 (80 US dollars). While British and other European travellers will also have to meet these prescription costs, if you are suddenly taken ill or involved in an accident during a visit to Sweden, free or reduced-cost necessary treatment is available, EEA and Swiss citizens are entitled to free medical care (prescriptions apart), but proof of entitlement is usually required. Such proof takes the form of the European Health Insurance Card (EHIC), which replaced the E111 form in 2006. Travellers from other countries should find out if they are covered by other reciprocal arrangements. Australia, for example, has such an agreement as long as long as citizens carry their Medicare card. Comprehensive insurance is advised for all other nationals.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Food in Sweden is safe to eat although care should be taken when purchasing food from roadside stalls. In most cases, Swedish food tends to be safer than that produced in other countries, thanks to the Swedish National Food Administration&amp;rsquo;s tough rules on pesticides and additives. Sweden also enforces tough rules on misleading food marketing claims, which means &amp;ndash; provided you can translate the Swedish text &amp;ndash; that you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t get any nasty surprises when picking up food in supermarkets.&amp;nbsp;Tap water is also safe, although drinking from streams, lakes and rivers &amp;ndash; however clean they look &amp;ndash; isn&amp;rsquo;t recommended as even the most inviting-looking water can harbour parasites. Water that has been boiled or treated with iodine or chlorine tablets is usually safe to drink.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organisation recommends vaccination for tick-borne encephalitis regardless of the destination. If you intend to participate in winter sports, make sure your travel insurance policy covers it as many will refuse to pay out should you take &amp;lsquo;unnecessary risks&amp;rsquo; &amp;ndash; under which heading come many of the country&amp;rsquo;s most popular winter sports; skiing and snowboarding included.&amp;nbsp;While Sweden&amp;rsquo;s mild summers pose little risk for outdoor adventure enthusiasts, its arctic winters are a different story. With temperatures regularly dipping below zero (to as low as -30&amp;ordm;C/-22&amp;ordm;F in northern regions), care needs to be taken when participating in outdoor sports during the colder months. Extra layers, including thick woollen hats and gloves, are essential and it&amp;rsquo;s also worth carrying a small supply of food and fluids should you get into trouble.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Easter Sunday :
							01 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Sunday :
							20 May </p><p>National Day :
							06 June </p><p>Midsummer's Day :
							23 June </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p><p>New Year's Eve :
							31 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sweden is within the European Union. If you are travelling from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, you are entitled to buy fragance, skincare, cosmetics, champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices.</p>
<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22%, 20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22%, 90L of wine (no more than 60L of sparkling wine) and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Sweden without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of Kr4,300 for air and sea travellers and Kr3,000 for other travellers.</p>
<p>You must be at least 20 years old to import alcohol and 18 years old to import tobacco.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unlicensed firearms and ammunition, meat and dairy products from outside the EEA, and medicines and narcotics (unless prescribed).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unlicensed firearms and ammunition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Swedish Krona (SEK; symbol kr) = 100 &ouml;re. Notes are in denominations of kr1,000, 500, 200, 100, 50 and 20. Coins are in denominations of kr10, 5, 2 and 1.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency can be converted at FOREX foreign exchange agencies; these are found in major cities, airports and ferry terminals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are all widely accepted, although it should be noted that most shops and restaurants require ID when paying with a credit card. ATMs are widely available and can be used with most international bank cards, although it&rsquo;s worth bearing in mind that you may incur a small charge. Personal cheques are no longer used, while traveller's cheques can be cashed at most banks.</p><p>ATMs are widely available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller&rsquo;s cheques are accepted at some banks. To avoid unfavourable exchange rate charges, visitors are advised to rely on credit or debit cards instead.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Banks are open Mon-Wed and Fri 9000-1500. On Thursdays, banking hours are slightly longer, running from 9000-1800. In larger cities such as <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/gothenburg">Gothenburg</a>, Malmo and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/stockholm">Stockholm</a>, some banks have longer opening hours and are open at weekends.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A transit visa is required for nationals of just a handful of countries; check with the consulate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sweden is part of the Schengen area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Citizens of EU countries including the UK and Ireland can live and work freely in any Schengen or EU country, which includes Sweden, so do not require any type of visa to visit the country. A small number of non-EU countries have also negotiated visa-free travel with Sweden, including the USA, Canada, Japan, New Zealand and Australia. For citizens of other non-EU countries, Swedish visas available include the standard 90-day visitor&rsquo;s visa, along with work, student, family, medical, performing artists visas and a visa for exceptional circumstances, including for emergency purposes or on humanitarian grounds. Citizens from countries that have negotiated visa exemption agreements with Sweden still require a visa for stays of more than 90 days. See <a target="_blank" href="http://www.swedenabroad.com">www.swedenabroad.com</a> for more information.</p>
<p>Schengen visa: &euro;60/&pound;50. This is reduced to &euro;35/&pound;30 for children under 12 and nationals of some countries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). UK residents who wish to apply for a Schengen visa should apply through VFS Global (<a href="http://www.vfsglobal.se/uk">www.vfsglobal.se/uk</a>) in London or Edinburgh, with whom the Swedish Embassy has an agreement. A non-refundable service charge of &pound;24 applies in addition to the cost of the visa. All visa applicants aged 12 or over must submit biometric data at their visa appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow seven to 60 days for visa processing.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If applying for a Schengen visa, you must show you have at least kr370 (around &pound;30) per day, per person to cover your stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can only extend Schengen visas in exceptional circumstances, such as <em>force majeure</em> or for humanitarian reasons.</p>
<p>If you're an EU/EEA national and plan to stay longer than 90 days to live in Sweden, you must register with the Swedish Migration Agency within 90 days of arrival (<a href="https://www.migrationsverket.se" target="_blank">www.migrationsverket.se</a>). You must also apply for a Swedish ID number from your local tax office.</p>
<p>Non-EU/EEA nationals must apply for a residence permit if staying beyond 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing a pet from another EU country, your animal must have a microchip, pet passport and rabies vaccination certificate. Animals arriving from outside the EU must have a microchip, rabies vaccination certificate and veterinary certificate issued by an official veterinarian.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[62.915003]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[16.236982]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>449,964 sq km (173,732 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>9,851,852 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>21.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Stockholm.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With a land mass totalling around 449,964 sq km (173,732 sq miles), Sweden is the fifth largest country in Europe and the largest of the Scandinavian bloc. Sharing land borders with Norway to the west and Finland to the northeast, the country also has 3,218km (2,000 miles) of coastline, much of it on the Baltic Sea. What remains faces the Gulf of Bothnia &ndash; a chilly stretch of sea, shared with Finland. To the south, Denmark is another near neighbour and is directly linked to the southern Swedish port of Malm&ouml; via the &Ouml;resund Bridge. Along with Denmark, Sweden has maritime borders with Germany, Poland, Russia, Lithuania, Latvia and Estonia.</p>
<p>With a population of over 9 million, most of whom inhabit the cities and the south, the vast majority (78%) of Sweden&rsquo;s enormous tracts of land are forested, while another 8% is covered in water. The largest lake is V&auml;nern, with an area of 5,655 sq km (2,140 sq miles) and the highest peak is Kebnekaise, which stands 2,104m (6,903ft) above sea level and is part of the Scandinavian mountain chain on the Norwegian border. In the far north, Sweden&rsquo;s portion of Lapland extends well into the Arctic Circle, with the northernmost outpost of Swedish civilisation to be found in the tiny Lappish town of Treriksr&ouml;set on the three way border between Finland, Norway and Sweden. The country&rsquo;s southernmost point is the small fishing village of Smygehuk on the Baltic coast, close to the tiny city of Trelleborg in Sk&aring;ne County.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Around 65% of the population belong to the Church of Sweden (Evangelical Lutheran), which separated from the state in January 2000. The remainder belong to minority Protestant denominations although the country also has significant numbers of Catholics, Eastern Orthodox Christians and Muslims.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normal courtesies should be observed. It is customary for the guest to refrain from drinking until the host makes a toast. The guest should also thank the host for the meal by saying <em>tack f&ouml;r maten</em> (thank you for the food). Casual dress is acceptable for everyday occasions; smarter threads are worn for social occasions, exclusive restaurants and clubs. Evening wear (black tie) will usually be specified when required. Smoking is prohibited on public transport and in most public buildings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Stefan L&ouml;fven since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King Carl XVI Gustaf since 1973.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Described as &lsquo;a land of frozen seas and the midnight sun&rsquo; by Greek explorer and trader Phytheas of Massilia in AD550, by the time of the ninth century, Sweden&rsquo;s icy waters were proving an outlet for explorers of its own. From 800 until the mid-11th century, Sweden's Vikings took eastern Europe and Byzantium by storm; sacking monasteries, carrying off shiploads of plunder and providing some of the most memorably monikered characters to walk the Earth, including Ingvar the Far-Travelled and Eric the Victorious.<br />
<br />
Towards the end of this period, the modern kingdom of Sweden came into being and some sense of order followed the accession of Margaret &ndash; Regent of Denmark and ruler of Norway &ndash; in 1387. She attempted to establish a united Scandinavia, but this did not last long and during the 15th century the nobility was able to do much as it pleased.<br />
&nbsp;</p>
<p>The most significant event of this period was the Massacre of Stockholm in 1520, occasioned by Christian of Denmark&rsquo;s attempt to reassert his authority in Sweden. During the resulting revolt, headed by Gustav Ericksson Vasa, the Danes were defeated and Gustav established the House of Vasa as monarchs. Much of the foreign policy of the 17th century was expansionist and despite his Protestantism, Gustav II allied with Catholic France as Sweden won the last remaining Baltic territories not under its control &ndash; Prussia and Pomerania.</p>
<p>The next couple of centuries saw the country lose the majority of its territory outside of Scandinavia as a succession of royal dynasties playing a gilded sort of musical chairs with the throne. By 1818, the Bernadotte family (which still rules) had taken control, but while the country&rsquo;s political leadership was assured, its overseas territories remained in a state of flux thanks to the emergence of Norwegian nationalism, which culminated in Norway&rsquo;s declaration of full independence in 1905.</p>
<p>By this time, parliamentary government had emerged in Sweden. The Social Democrats first gained power in the early 1920s and rule almost continuously from 1932 until 1976. Since the end of World War 2, in which Sweden remained neutral (as it had done in World War 1), the country has enjoyed growing economic prosperity with continued investment in, and expansion of, the welfare state.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; The Roman historian Tacitus was the first to write about Sweden in the <em>Germania</em>.</p>
<p>&bull; Sweden has not been at war since it allied with Napoleon against Norway in 1814.</p>
<p>&bull; On 6 June 2016, to mark the 50th anniversary of the day they first met, ABBA&rsquo;s Benny Andersson and Bjorn Ulvaeus, were joined by fellow members Agnetha F&auml;ltskog and Anni-Frid Lyngstad to perform at a private party.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Sweden in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 467 2600.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.swedenabroad.se</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 467 2600.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0830-1200, 1300-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2900 K Street<br/>Washington<br/>20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Sweden in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7917 6400.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.swedenabroad.com/london</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7917 6400.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1200 and 1400-1600 (general enquiries); Mon, Tues, Thurs and Fri 0900-1100 (visa applications).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>11 Montagu Place<br/>London<br/>W1H 2AL<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sweden is a land of incredible contrasts, from the dense pine forests and craggy mountains of the north, to the rolling hills and glossy golden beaches of the south. But the diversity doesn't stop at the suburbs, with each of Sweden's seven major cities boasting its own character, history and unique architectural style.</p>
<p>Bordered by Denmark to the south, Norway to the west and Finland to the east, Sweden, the largest of the Scandinavian countries, boasts a long mercantile history that has made it one of the most culturally open and welcoming in Europe.</p>
<p>The instantly likeable capital Stockholm has long been synonymous with style and its sharply tailored brand of chic has percolated throughout the wardrobes of the world. Hipsters notwithstanding, Stockholm, with its 14 islands and medieval beauty, has much to offer those in search of culture, art and historical treasures. However, perhaps the most surprising city is Malmö, which has belied its unfairly grim reputation to become one of the country's liveliest destinations.</p>
<p>Beyond the cities, Sweden's countryside has a gentler charm than the rugged landscapes of neighbouring Norway. Much of Sweden is forested and there are thousands of lakes, including the large stretches of water between Gothenburg and Stockholm. The border with Norway is home to the spectacular Skanderna (Scandinavian) mountain chain, while in the far north you'll find wonderfully bleak Arctic tundra, where you can see the Northern Lights. 
The south is dominated by emerald forests, the cerulean waters of the Gulf of Bothnia and the jagged Baltic coastline. Of all the lovely spots in Sweden though, the awe-inspiring panoramas of the Stora Sj&ouml;fallet National Park take some beating. Part of the UNESCO-listed Laponian region of northern Sweden, the park's majestic waterfalls, soaring peaks and crowded clumps of fir trees make it one of the country's greatest natural treasures.</p> 
<p>The Swedes are proud of their green country and believe the great outdoors should be available to everyone. <em>Allemansr&auml;tten</em> – the everyman's right – is a constitutional right that allows the public access to public and privately owned land for recreation. As long as you do not disturb or destroy nature, or infringe on the privacy of others (such as by walking too close to their house), you are free to roam the countryside. This right even allows people to pick wildflowers, berries and mushrooms – unless they are endangered.</p><p>Sweden is a land of incredible contrasts, from the dense pine forests and craggy mountains of the north, to the rolling hills and glossy golden beaches of the south. But the diversity doesn&rsquo;t stop at the suburbs, with each of Sweden&rsquo;s seven major cities boasting its own character, history and unique architectural style.</p>
<p>Bordered by Denmark to the south, Norway to the west and Finland to the east, Sweden, the largest of the Scandinavian countries, boasts a long mercantile history that has made it one of the most culturally open and welcoming in Europe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
