<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Switzerland" ColCode="che" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ch" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Switzerland]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate is moderate but the Alps cause many climatic variations throughout Switzerland. In the higher Alpine regions temperatures tend to be low, while the lower land of the northern area has higher temperatures and warm summers. Overall the hottest months are July and August, though these are also the busiest. Those looking to ski should visit Switzerland between December and April, when snow is most likely to be good in the Alps. If the winter weather is too warm for skiing, which is more and more the case, most ski resorts reach into their bag of tricks and pull out artificial snow. The months of May and September are great times to visit for those looking for sunny and mild days, but without the throngs of tourists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Warm clothes and rainwear; lightweights for summer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can book internal flights&nbsp;in Switzerland through Swiss (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.swiss.com/">www.swiss.com</a>). Domestic air travel is fast but expensive, and with the exception of the Geneva to Z&uuml;rich flight (journey time - 45 minutes), many businesspeople prefer to travel by rail or road.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rail transport is particularly well developed in Switzerland, with excellent services provided by Schweizerische Bundesbahnen (SBB) (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.sbb.ch/">www.sbb.ch</a>) and many other operators. Using a Swiss Pass is a superb way to view the scenery, although mainline services are geared to the needs of the hurried business traveller.</p>
<p>Trains run at least hourly from the major centres, and there is a country-wide timetable of regular services. There are dining cars on many trains and snacks and refreshments are widely available. Independent railways, such as the Rh&auml;tische Bahn in the Grisons and the Berner-Oberland-Bahn, provide services in certain parts of the country. The SBB has introduced specialised cars for travellers using wheelchairs.</p>
<p>There are also a large number of mountain railways which are sometimes the only means of access to winter resorts. Some of these are attractions in their own right: the Gornergrat-Bahn in Zermatt is one of the oldest mountain railways and climbs to a height of over 3,000m (over 9,800ft) above sea level, offering a spectacular panorama of the Matterhorn and surrounding mountains. The panoramic train Gotthard Panorama Express connects Fl&uuml;elen with Lugano. Starting from Lucerne you can reach Fl&uuml;elen by ship while enjoying the wonderfuls sights on Lake Lucerne.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Swiss Travel Pass:</strong> valid for three, four, eight or 15 consecutive days on rail, bus and boat services across Switzerland. Passes also allow free entry to more than 480 museums and offer 50% discount on most mountain railways. Children under 16 travel free when accompanied by at least one parent. Available from SBB (<a href="http://www.swisstravelsystem.com/">www.swisstravelsystem.com/</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Swiss Travel Pass Flex:</strong>&nbsp;similar to the Swiss Travel Pass, but the lexi pass is valid for three, four, eight or 15 non-consecutive days in one month.</p>
<p><strong>Swiss Transfer Ticket:</strong> allows return travel from a Swiss border or airport to a selected destination.</p>
<p><strong>InterRail One-Country Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Switzerland. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurail Austria-Switzerland Pass:</strong> offers travel for four, five, six, eight or ten days in two months within Austria and Switzerland. Available to non-EU nationals from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Road quality is generally good.  Many mountain roads are winding and narrow, and often closed in heavy winter conditions; otherwise chains and snow tyres may be necessary.  Rail is often more efficient than driving.</p>r<p>Swiss Post (tel: +41 848 888 888; <a href="http://www.postauto.ch" target="_blank">www.postauto.ch</a>) runs regular PostBus services to much of rural Switzerland.</p><p>Registered taxis are available in most major towns and cities in Switzerland. All taxis have meters for short and long trips, although it is advisable to agree the fare for longer distances out of town.</p><p>A national driving licence is sufficient. Green Card insurance is advised; ordinary domestic insurance policies are valid but do not provide full cover. The Green Card tops the cover up to the level provided by your domestic policy.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Seat belts are obligatory and children under 12 years must travel in the back of the car. Dipped headlights are compulsory at all times.</p>
<p>Speed limits are 120kph (75mph) on motorways, 100kph (62mph) on dual carriageways, 80kph (50mph) on main roads and 50kph (31mph) in towns.</p>
<p>On minor roads, traffic going up a mountain has priority. Road numbers on green signs indicate toll expressways, where a toll vignette (sticker) (Autobahn-Vignette) must be displayed. You can order one online before you travel (<a href="http://rail.myswitzerland.com" target="_blank">http://rail.myswitzerland.com</a>). Stickers are valid for one calendar year.</p><p>Emergency breakdown&nbsp;help can be arranged through the Swiss Touring Club (tel: 0800 140 140, in Switzerland only; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.tcs.ch/">www.tcs.ch</a>).</p><p>Car hire is&nbsp;available in all towns from hotels and airports and at all manned rail stations. All major European companies are represented, including Alamo, Sixt and Hertz.</p><p>You can rent bikes at numerous railway stations through Rent a Bike (<a href="http://www.rentabike.ch" target="_blank">www.rentabike.ch</a>).</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Seat belts are obligatory and children under 12 years must travel in the back of the car. Dipped headlights are compulsory at all times.</p>
<p>Speed limits are 120kph (75mph) on motorways, 100kph (62mph) on dual carriageways, 80kph (50mph) on main roads and 50kph (31mph) in towns.</p>
<p>On minor roads, traffic going up a mountain has priority. Road numbers on green signs indicate toll expressways, where a toll vignette (sticker) (Autobahn-Vignette) must be displayed. You can order one online before you travel (<a href="http://rail.myswitzerland.com" target="_blank">http://rail.myswitzerland.com</a>). Stickers are valid for one calendar year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Highly efficient and integrated urban public transport systems serve as a model for other countries. There are tramways and light rail services in Basel, Bern, Geneva, Neuch&acirc;tel and Zurich. These and a further dozen cities also have trolleybuses.</p>
<p>Fare systems are generally automated with machines issuing single or multiple tickets at the roadside. Tickets are also available at enquiry offices. Fares are generally zonal. There is a day ticket for travel in one or more Swiss cities on any given day at a standard fare. Taxis are widely available and drivers expect a 15% tip.</p>
<p>Visitors can use public transport for free with mobility tickets, if they stay in hotels, youth hostels or on camping sites in Berne and in Basel and in the canton of Ticino.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Switzerland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">lugano</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Switzerland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">geneva</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.55</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Switzerland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">bern</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.10</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Switzerland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">basle</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.05</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Switzerland's national airline is Swiss (<a href="http://www.swiss.com" target="_blank">www.swiss.com</a>). Other airlines operating flights to Switzerland from the UK include&nbsp;British Airways (<a href="http://www.britishairways.com/">www.britishairways.com/</a>) and&nbsp;easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>). There is also a good selection of flights to Switzerland from other countries, including direct flights with American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>), Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>), Swiss and United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>) from the USA.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/switzerland/euroairport-basel-mulhouse-freiburg">EuroAirport Basel-Mulhouse-Freiburg Airport</a>, Bern-Belp Airport, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/switzerland/geneva-international-airport">Geneva International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/switzerland/zurich-international-airport">Zurich Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/geneva">Geneva</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 1 hour 35 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 7 hours 50 minutes.</p>
<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/z%C3%BCrich">Zurich</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 1 hour 40 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 7 hours 40 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>EuroAirport Basel-Mulhouse-Freiburg</b><![CDATA[http://www.euroairport.com<p>EuroAirport Basel-Mulhouse-Freiburg is situated 8km (5 miles) northwest of Basel (in Switzerland), 25km (15.5 miles) south of Mulhouse (in France) and 70km (43 miles) south of Freiburg (in Germany). The airport is wholly within France, but is close to the Swiss and German borders.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+33 3 8990 3111</p>]]><b>Geneva International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.gva.ch<p>Geneva International Airport is located 4km (2.5 miles) northwest of Geneva city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+41 22 717 7111</p>]]><b>Zurich Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.zurich-airport.com<p>Zurich Airport is located 12km (7.5 miles) north of Zurich.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+41 43 816 2211</p>]]><b>Bern-Belp Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.flughafenbern.ch<p>The airport is located within Belp&rsquo;s city limits.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+41 31 960 2111</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travelling from the UK, the quickest way to get to Switzerland by rail&nbsp;is to travel by Eurostar through the Channel Tunnel to Paris (journey time - 2 hours 15 minutes) and, from there, to Switzerland. The TGV (<a href="http://www.sncf.com/en/trains/tgv-lyria">www.sncf.com/en/trains/tgv-lyria</a>) connects Paris with Switzerland. For further information and reservations contact Eurostar (tel: 03432 186 186, in the UK or +44 1233 617 575, outside the UK; <a href="http://www.eurostar.com" target="_blank">www.eurostar.com</a>) or Voyages SNCF (tel: +44 844 848 5848;&nbsp;<a href="http://uk.voyages-sncf.com/en/#/">uk.voyages-sncf.com/en/#/</a>).&nbsp;There are also through trains from Spain, Italy and Germany.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://uk.voyages-sncf.com/en/pass/interrail-passes">uk.voyages-sncf.com/en/pass/interrail-passes</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Payphones can be found in towns and cities throughout Switzerland. Domestic and international calls from public phones are made using phonecards, which can be purchased in newsagents, Swisscom Shops, post offices and at petrol stations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies and coverage is good across Switzerland. Local SIM cards are readily available in newsagents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are more than 1,700 public Wireless LAN hotspots in Switzerland. Wi-Fi is ubiquitous in Switzerland with most hotels, restaurants, several train stations and companies as well as public spaces offering free access. Internet providers like Swisscom and Monzoon offer paid wireless internet access.</p>
<p>Connections are also available in Internet caf&eacute;s and phone booths, which are found in most major town and cities. In the case of phone booths,&nbsp;charges are payable by phonecard or credit card.&nbsp;The airports in Zurich and Geneva also offer Wi-Fi-access, the first one hour is free of charge.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Tourists can purchase a Travelers Wifi Mobile Hotspot (<a href="http://travelerswifi.com">travelerswifi.com</a>) which gives unlimited 4G LTE data internet access in all of Switzerland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main broadcaster in Switzerland is the public Swiss Broadcasting Corporation. It operates seven TV networks (three in German, two in Italian and two in French) and 18 radio stations. Most of its funding comes from licence fee revenues, while a smaller proportion comes from TV advertising. Private TV and radio stations operate in the regions. TV stations from France, Germany and Italy are widely available, thanks in part to the very high take-up of multichannel cable and satellite TV. Some German commercial broadcasters provide tailored versions of their channels for the Swiss market.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail within Europe takes three days.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1200 and 1345-1830. Saturday closing is at 1100 except in major cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire Switzerland's traditional Appenzell villages</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the Switzerland of old with a drive through rustic Appenzell, the most traditional canton, with its picturesque villages of ornately painted houses set in lush, rolling landscapes. S&auml;ntis is Appenzell's most famous peak, with memorable views over six nations: Austria, France, Germany, Italy, Liechtenstein and Switzerland. The mountain Hoher Kasten (1795m/ 5889ft) is also worth a visit.</p>]]><p><b>Basler Fasnacht carnival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go to Basel for the Basler Fasnacht (a pre-Lenten carnival), with three days of grand masked parties and street parades with fancy costumes. One of the highlights is the impressive lantern display, which is even more illuminating with the city's lights switched off. In front of the City Theatre there is a fabulous Fasnacht Fountain.</p>]]><p><b>Book a date with the medieval library at St Gallen</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Elegant and ancient, St Gallen is blessed with a baroque cathedral whose famous Abbey Library is a UNESCO World Heritage treasure. Today the library is open to the public and also functions as a museum. St Gallen's old town is pretty with decorative town houses from the 16th until 18th centuries.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]><p><b>Brave the bear pits of Bern</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the capital city of Bern, a UNESCO World Cultural Heritage Site, on the Aare River with its medieval heart of unique 11th-century arcaded streets. It&rsquo;s also famed for its 13th-century clock tower and ancient bear pits, which are found at the eastern edge of the old city. A reminder of the capital&rsquo;s ursine emblem can be seen throughout Bern on flags, statues, stained-glass windows and souvenirs.</p>]]><p><b>Capture history at Chillon Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Chillon Castle is the most famous castle in Switzerland. It enjoys a spectacular location on the eastern edge of Lake Geneva, near Montreux, with the Dents du Midi mountain in the background. Built in the 13th century, visitors can see the famous jail and learn of Fran&ccedil;ois de Bonivard, the castle's most famous prisoner.</p>]]><p><b>Climb Little Matterhorn in a cablecar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Make your trip a memory of lifetime and take Europe's highest aerial cable car up the Little Matterhorn at Zermatt, then ski back to the car-free village on one of the longest ski runs in Europe. Or head to the small town of Engelberg, where the world's first revolving cable car ascends Mount Titlis, the highest lookout-point in central Switzerland.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the beautiful Berner Oberland landscape</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the Berner Oberland, a major tourist area that flourishes with spectacular scenery including famous peaks (Jungfrau, M&ouml;nch and Eiger), mountain lakes, alpine streams and wild flowers. As well as the Brienz-Rothorn-railway, which is over 125 years old, the region is home to such celebrated resorts as Adelboden, Grindelwald and Interlaken.</p>]]><p><b>Fall for rail travel on the Glacier Express</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Travel by train through stunning Alpine scenery on the Glacier Express. At the very heart of Switzerland, one of Europe's greatest rail journeys winds over arching viaducts and through the Rhine gorge. Ride it from St Moritz to Zermatt (or vice versa) and don't forget your camera.</p>]]><p><b>Feel rejuvenated and rested at Graubünden</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For a virtuous holiday health kick, spend time at one of Switzerland's many climatic health resorts. The Graubünden resorts of Arosa, Davos, Klosters and St Moritz are renowned the world over. Interlaken, near Bern, is another celebrated health resort and the gateway to the Berner Oberland.</p>]]><p><b>Lace up your hiking boots</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Join the Swiss in their favourite pastime: hiking. There are over 65,000km (40,389 miles) of marked trails to explore, with hiking times marked on signposts, and colour-coding according to difficulty.</p>]]><p><b>Make a beeline for Basel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover the ancient university and trading city of Basel. Straddling the Rhine between the Jura region, Alsace in France and Germany's Black Forest, it is a centre of art and research. Don't miss the Art Museum, the ancient red sandstone M&uuml;nster or the kinetic wonderment at the Jean Tinguely museum. Learn about papermaking and book printing at the Basel Paper Mill.</p>]]><p><b>Make the most of the many Mountain sports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The mountains are the perfect place to get active, with ice climbing, ski touring, snowboarding, deep-snow skiing, heli-skiing and glacier walking. Top ski areas include Portes du Soleil, Klosters, Zermatt, Saas Fee and glamorous St Moritz, which also offers snow-polo, the Olympic Bob run and the Cresta run. In 2017 St Moritz is host city of the Ski World Cup for the fifth time.</p>]]><p><b>See both sides of Lausanne</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lausanne's highlights include the Cath&eacute;drale Notre-Dame, the Mus&eacute;e Olympic (Olympic Museum) and the Musee de l&rsquo;Art brut which exhibits outsider art. While a stroll along the promenade of the old Port d'Ouchy reveals a slower pace of life, the city&rsquo;s vibrant side can be found among the contemporary architecture of Flon, where boutique shops, cinemas and evening entertainment has replaced derelict warehouses, buoyed by the town&rsquo;s two universities.</p>]]><p><b>Tackle Switzerland's cycling trails</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cycling is not necessarily as strenuous as the mountainous terrain might suggest, but those with the leg power will want to ride the trails around the Matterhorn. There are 9,000km (5,592 miles) of well-marked interlinked trails, and most of them offer easy cycling. Many railway stations offer bike hire.</p>]]><p><b>Take a scenic trip to Ticino</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the southernmost tip of Switzerland, the lovely, Italian-speaking region of Ticino. Follow the road from the Alpine valleys through Bellinzona with its three medieval castles, past the sweeping Contra Dam (the site of the James Bond Golden Eye bungee jump) to the Locarno and Lugano, the celebrated lake resorts of Southern Ticino. Or take the panoramic train Gotthard Panorama Express&nbsp;to Ticino through the Gotthard base tunnel.</p>]]><p><b>Take to the water on the splendid Swiss Lakes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy a lake cruise or ferry trip on the likes of Lake Geneva, Lake Zurich, Lake Brienz, Lake Constance (with visits to towns in Germany and Austria) and the picturesque Vierwaldst&auml;ttersee at Luzern, where paddle steamers link up with various mountain railways and cableways. For a little more adventure, take a kayak out on Lake Z&uuml;rich.</p>]]><p><b>Take your pick of Valais's peaks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Whether you climb up them, ski down or just capture them on camera, the Valais region (the valley) possesses such lofty glacial peaks as the Dufourspitze (4,634m/15,217ft), Dom (4,545m/14,917ft), Weisshorn (4,509m/14,793ft) and the Matterhorn (4,478m/14,698ft). Popular resorts here include Saas Fee, Verbier and Zermatt.</p>]]><p><b>Tour Geneva on two feet</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover Geneva's ancient city centre on foot, especially its crowning glory, the Cath&eacute;drale de St Pierre; a magnificent example of Romanesque architecture. Near Lake Geneva, the flower clock in the Jardin Anglais, with over 6,500 blooms, pays homage to Geneva's watch industry. You can also choose from guided tours that focus on themes like Geneva's beautiful parks and gardens, buildings of the UN and the International Organizations or on Geneva's old town with its long history.</p>]]><p><b>Unearth the old and the zany in Zurich</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Zurich, Switzerland's largest city. The old town, Altstadt, is especially picturesque. See the gothic Fraum&uuml;nster, with its stained-glass windows by Chagall; the imposing twin-towered Grossm&uuml;nster cathedral; the Swiss National Museum; and the modern art collections at the Kunsthaus Zurich. The Dada artistic movement began in Zurich, enjoy its quirky output at Cabaret Voltaire.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Switzerland's tastiest village, Gruyères</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit one of Switzerland's most photogenic medieval villages, Gruy&egrave;res, home to the nation's most famous cheese, to explore its castle, Ch&acirc;teau de Gruy&egrave;res, three museums and various cheese factories. Nearby, take a barge to the medieval ruins on the Isle of Ogoz.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$522 billion (2009).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Chocolate, watches, pharmaceuticals, machinery, metals, chemicals and agricultural products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Chemicals, textiles, electronics, vehicles, machinery and argricultural products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Germany, Austria, France, Italy, USA and UK.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Switzerland has a typical West European mixed economy with a bias towards light and craft-based industries: Swiss precision manufacturing such as watch-making is renowned throughout the world. The country is highly industrialised and heavily dependent on exports of finished goods (including machine tools, printing and photographic equipments, electronics and medical equipment). There is also a substantial chemical industry, employing 15% of the workforce, which continues to grow steadily. In total, exports are equivalent to just under half of Swiss GDP. Switzerland lacks raw materials, so most of these must be imported.<br /><br />Although half of the country's food is imported, the agricultural sector is a strong and major employer. The processed foods industry has a high international profile, particularly in such products as chocolate, cheese and baby foods.<br /><br />The service sector is dominated by banking, where the particular reputation of the Swiss banking community for discretion has attracted large deposits. Switzerland is one of Europe's major financial centres, with Zürich home to the world's fourth-ranked stock market (after New York, London and Tokyo). Among other service industries, tourism is of major importance.<br /><br />Switzerland is not a member of the European Union, although nearly two-thirds of its exports are sold to EU countries.<br />The neutrality, stability and conveniently central location of Switzerland make the country a favourite meeting place for conventions and international organisations. It has an extensive and highly developed network of conference destinations with all the major cities and many of the smaller alpine and lake resorts offering fully equipped business facilities.<br /><br />Each of Switzerland's main cities has its own Convention Bureau, whilst the Association of Swiss Convention Centres, Swiss Congress, oversees meetings activity throughout the country. The organisation is made up of the 19 leading congress locations in Switzerland and can help with the organisation of a meeting in any region of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businesspeople are expected to wear suits. Punctuality is important and business cards are essential when visiting firms. During meetings, humour is considered inappropriate and does not cross cultural barriers easily and business relationships and negotiations tend to develop slowly and visitors should adopt the local pace. A little introductory chit-chat is usually expected but overly personal topics are best avoided.</p>
<p>Although English is widely spoken, it is always appreciated if a visitor attempts to say a few words in the language of the host and the usual form of greeting in both business and social settings is a firm handshake.</p>
<p>On first meeting itis always important to address Swiss colleagues by their surnames (including any academic or honorary titles) prefixed by Herr (for a man) or Frau (for a woman) and to use the polite Sie form, rather than the informal du, until familiarity has been established.</p>
<p>If invited to a colleague's home, you should bring a small gift of flowers (these should be unwrapped) or chocolates.<br />
In Geneva, company structures remain hierarchical, particularly within the financial sector. It is therefore wise to approach those at the top.</p>
<p>Meetings are commonly held over lunch and dinner &ndash; rarely breakfast &ndash; and Genevois appreciate an invitation to a top restaurant. Suits should be worn but without ostentation.<br />
In Zurich, do not be surprised by Z&uuml;rchers' apparent brusqueness - they believe in speaking the truth, even if it is not always pleasant.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p>Business hours are typically Monday to Friday 0800-1200 and 1400-1700, while in Geneva the business day can start 30 minutes earlier.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Switzerland Global Enterprise</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (44) 365 51 51
					Website:http://www.s-ge.com/en
					Address: Zürich,Stampfenbachstrasse 85,Switzerland,CH-8021]]><b>Economiesuisse Swiss Business Federation</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (44) 421 35 35
					Website:http://www.economiesuisse.ch/
					Address: ,Hegibachstrasse 47,CH-Zürich ,8032]]><b>Switzerland Convention and Incentive Bureau (SCIB)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (44) 288 13 73
					Website:http://www.myswitzerland.com/de-de/dienstleistungen.html
					Address: ,Tödistrasse 7,CH-Zürich,8027]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Swiss cuisine is hearty, filling fare with different regions bearing various degrees of influence from their German, French and Italian neighbours. With wheat farming less suited to higher altitudes, Swiss farmers have instead focused on dairy, hence the large number of Swiss cheeses.</p>
<p>Though not native to Europe (they were introduced by the Spaniards returning from Latin America), potatoes are now a Swiss staple, as are cured sausages and air-dried meats, while lake fish such as trout and char are commonly found on menus.</p>
<p>Those with a sweet tooth will be in heaven; Switzerland is, of course, at the forefront of chocolate manufacturing, producing some of the best sweet stuff on the planet. The little-exported Swiss wine, in particular whites, are excellent, and domestic beer, both lager and dark ales, are also widely available.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Fondue:</strong> A delicious concoction of Gruy&egrave;re and Vacherin cheese, melted and mixed with white wine, flour, Kirsch and a little garlic.<br />
<strong>Raclette:</strong> Cheese melted over a fire or grill and served with onions, pickles and bread or jacket potatoes.<br />
<strong>Berner platte:</strong> A selection of meats and sausages cooked with sauerkraut, beans and boiled potatoes.<br />
<strong>Viande s&egrave;ch&eacute;e:</strong> Dried beef or pork from Valais and the Grisons (where it is called <em>b&uuml;ndnerfleisch),</em> served with pickled onions.<br />
<strong>Pieds de porc:</strong> Pigs' trotters.<br />
<strong>R&ouml;sti:</strong> A flat, round hot cake made with shredded fried potatoes.<br />
<strong>Fondue bourguignonne:</strong> Cubes of seasoned meat cooked in oil or butter and served with various sauces.<br />
<strong>Leckerli:</strong> Spiced honey cakes topped with icing sugar, decorated in Bern with a white sugar bear.<br />
<strong>Kirsch:</strong> A clear hard spirit made from sour cherries.<br />
<strong>Chasselas:</strong> A grape widely used to produce dry and delicate Swiss white wines.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tips are already included within hotel and restaurant bills, but it is customary to tip a little extra for good service.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>The legal drinking age is 16 for beer and wine and 18 for spirits.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major towns and resorts have nightclubs. There is a symphony orchestra in every main city, and some bars and restaurants have local folk entertainment. Z&uuml;rich is the country's top nightspot, with an array of trendy bars and a flourishing avant-garde club scene, closely followed by Lausanne and Geneva. During winter months, many ski resorts (including Verbier and Zermatt) offer a lively apr&egrave;s-ski party atmosphere.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Special purchases include embroidery and linen, Bernese woodcarving, chocolate, cheese, Swiss army knives and luxury handmade clocks and watches. Z&uuml;rich is the shopping capital, centred on the luxury boutiques and department stores of the celebrated Bahnhofstrasse.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800/0830 or 0900-1200 and 1400-1830 or 1900, Sat 0800-1600/1700. Many shops (especially in rural areas) are closed on Monday mornings. Shops in smaller cities are closed for 1 to 2 hours around noon.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>High quality hotels in Switzerland range from luxury to family to simple pensions. A service charge of 15% is included in hotel bills, and an additional local tax may be payable (depending on the location).</p>
<p><strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Note: </strong>Most hotels in Switzerland are affiliated to the Schweizer Hotelier Verein (SHV or Swiss Hotel Association). Hotelleriesuisse is responsible for hotel classification and guides. Membership of the SHV is voluntary, and there may be some first-class hotels which do not have a star rating. There are many hotels with no actual star classification that are recognised by, and members of, the SHV as well as Country Inns, Unique hotels, Aparthotels, Mountain Inns/Traveller's Lodges and Low Service hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are extensive bed and breakfast hotels in Switzerland, information on these can be found from Bed and Breakfast Switzerland (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.bnb.ch/">www.bnb.ch</a>). A service charge of 15% is included in bills, and an additional local tax may be payable (depending on the location).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>High quality hotels in Switzerland range from luxury to family to simple pensions. A service charge of 15% is included in hotel bills, and an additional local tax may be payable (depending on the location).</p>
<p><strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Note: </strong>Most hotels in Switzerland are affiliated to the Schweizer Hotelier Verein (SHV or Swiss Hotel Association). Hotelleriesuisse is responsible for hotel classification and guides. Membership of the SHV is voluntary, and there may be some first-class hotels which do not have a star rating. There are many hotels with no actual star classification that are recognised by, and members of, the SHV as well as Country Inns, Unique hotels, Aparthotels, Mountain Inns/Traveller's Lodges and Low Service hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>High quality hotels in Switzerland range from luxury to family to simple pensions. A service charge of 15% is included in hotel bills, and an additional local tax may be payable (depending on the location).</p>
<p><strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Note: </strong>Most hotels in Switzerland are affiliated to the Schweizer Hotelier Verein (SHV or Swiss Hotel Association). Hotelleriesuisse is responsible for hotel classification and guides. Membership of the SHV is voluntary, and there may be some first-class hotels which do not have a star rating. There are many hotels with no actual star classification that are recognised by, and members of, the SHV as well as Country Inns, Unique hotels, Aparthotels, Mountain Inns/Traveller's Lodges and Low Service hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;If European visitors or any of their dependants are suddenly taken ill or have an accident during a visit to Switzerland, free or reduced-cost necessary treatment is available; in most cases on production of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). Full travel insurance is advised for all travellers.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;There's nothing to mark out Switzerland produce as particularly risky to general health, in fact food hygiene standards are very high across the country. The tap water is also safe to drink. However, resist the temptation to drink from streams or lakes, no matter how clean they look, as they may contain pollutants.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;No immunisations are required to enter Switzerland, although it is advisable to make sure your standard vaccinations like tetanus, diphtheria, mumps, measels, rubella and polio are up to date before travelling.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>There are additional regional holidays which are observed in certain cantons only.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Berchtold's Day :
							2018<br/>02 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>National Day :
							01 August </p><p>Christmas Eve :
							24 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Switzerland by travellers with a minimum age of 17 years without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 250 pieces /gr/ cigarettes / other tobacco products.<br />
&bull; 5L of alcoholic drinks up to 18% volume and 1L of alcoholic drinks over 18% volume.<br />
&bull; Goods to a value of SFr300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited or restricted goods include endangered species, narcotics, counterfeit goods, cultural property, medicines, plants, radar warning devices, animals and animal products, and weapons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unlicensed firearms, counterfeit goods and narcotics. You must declare any cultural property.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Swiss Franc (CHF; symbol SFr) = 100 centimes (called <em>centimes</em> in French, <em>rappen</em> in German and <em>centesimi</em> in Italian). Notes are in denominations of SFr1,000, 200, 100, 50, 20 and 10. Coins are in denominations of SFr5, 2, 1, 1/2 and &nbsp;20, 10 and 5 centimes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are bureaux de change at train stations, airports, major hotels and banks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit and debit cards are accepted at most places throughout Switzerland, including American Express, Diners Club, Mastercard and Visa.</p><p>ATMs are widely available throughout Switzerland, especially in the major cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pound Sterling, US Dollar or Euro cheques are accepted at airports, railway stations and banks. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, visitors are advised to take traveller's cheques in Pounds Sterling, Euros or US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0830-1630 in bigger cities. Mon-Fri 0830-1200 and 1400-1700 in rural areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay (or for the duration of stay for EU/EEA nationals) and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above, except (<strong>1</strong>) EU&nbsp;nationals holding a valid national identity card.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Switzerland is part of the Schengen area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: &euro;60/&pound;51.72. Reductions are available for some nationalities and for children.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). UK residents requiring a Schengen visa should apply to the Swiss Visa Application Centre (<a href="https://www.vfsglobal.ch/switzerland/uk">www.vfsglobal.ch/switzerland/uk</a>); a service charge of &pound;22.10 applies. All visa applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at their visa appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>EU/EEA residents planning on staying in Switzerland for more than three months to work must register with the local authorities and apply for a residence permit. The length of the permit depends on the duration of the work. Slightly different rules apply to nationals of Bulgaria and Romania. Contact the State Secretariat for Migration (<a href="http://www.sem.admin.ch" target="_blank">www.sem.admin.ch</a>) for details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow at least seven days for visa processing. For some nationalities, it may take at least 14 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa applicants must provide bank statements from the previous three months with their application.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa holders can only extend their stay in exceptional circumstances, such as <em>force majeure</em>, or for humanitarian reasons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[46.806016]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[8.225971]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>41,284 sq km (15,940 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>8,379,477 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>196.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Federal City Bern.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Federal republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Landlocked Switzerland shares borders with France to the west, Germany to the north, Austria and Liechtenstein to the east and Italy to the south. It has the highest mountains in Europe, together with waterfalls, rivers and lakes set amid green pastures. The highest peaks are Dufourspitze, 4,634m (15,203ft), on the Italian border; the Dom, 4,545m (14,911ft); the Matterhorn, 4,478m (14,691ft); and the Weisshorn, 4,506m (14,793ft).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic (38%), Protestant (27%), others (6%), atheist (21.4%).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is customary to give flowers to the hostess when invited for a meal, but never give chrysanthemums or white asters as they are considered funeral flowers. Informal wear is widely acceptable. First-class restaurants, hotel dining rooms and important social occasions may warrant jackets and ties. Black tie is usually specified when required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Standard European plugs with two round pins and Swiss plugs with three round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Alain Berset since January 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Alain Berset since January 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Neutrality is a key part of the Swiss national identity. While the conflicting forces of the world have squared up to each other time and time again, Switzerland has steered clear of global clashes since it first adopted a neutral stance in 1815. Though peace and stability have characterised the last two centuries, the country&rsquo;s earlier years were more turbulent.</p>
<p>Like most of its southern European neighbours, Switzerland was invaded by the Romans in the 1st century BC. As the Roman Empire began to decline in the 4th and 5th centuries, Germanic and Burgundian tribes arrived, effectively carving up the country between them &ndash; a division that is still evident today in the French and German-speaking areas of the nation.</p>
<p>In the 9th century, Switzerland came under the dominion of the Holy Roman Emperor. To begin with, the Swiss were allowed to do mostly as they pleased, but by the 13th century, the Romans had tightened the reins. Resentment soon bubbled among the population, culminating in the founding of the autonomous Swiss Confederation (of three cantons) in 1291. The country gained full independence in the late 15th century and was replaced by a sovereign government in the late 19th century, relying on a unique hands-on system, which allows its citizens to vote regularly on various matters, both large and small.</p>
<p>Nowadays, Switzerland is one of the world&rsquo;s major financial hubs, with a flourishing banking industry. Despite being surrounded by EU states, Switzerland itself is not a member, with the independent-minded citizens rejecting accession in a 2001 referendum. It wasn&rsquo;t the first time the Swiss refused to go with the herd; nine years earlier, membership of the European Economic Area was also rejected by referendum. Switzerland did, however, join the United Nations in 2002, and relations with the EU are now based on a wide range of bilateral agreements.</p>
<p>As a result of a popular vote, Switzerland joined the Schengen treaty and Dublin Convention in 2005, bringing the country into Europe's passport-free zone. In 2014, the Swiss voted to curb mass immigration with quotas in an initiative presented by the populist Swiss People&rsquo;s Party, a move that would violate the country&rsquo;s prior agreement with the EU regarding the free movement of persons. The government has yet to implement immigration limits, but the results have nevertheless put a strain on EU-Swiss relations.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Women weren&rsquo;t given the right to vote until 1971. <br />
&bull;	In Switzerland, it&rsquo;s against the law to keep a lone guinea pig; these sociable rodents must have a companion.<br />
&bull;	Switzerland has enough nuclear bunkers to shelter every citizen. Geneva city authorities often use them as homeless shelters during winter. <br />
&bull;	Bern is home to a disturbing 500-year old sculpture, which depicts an ogre-like man eating a baby mid-bite. Oddly, nobody is sure exactly why it is there.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Switzerland in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 745 7900.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.eda.admin.ch/washington</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 745 7900.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1200.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2900 Cathedral Avenue N.W.<br/>Washington<br/>20008-3499<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Switzerland in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7616 6000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.eda.admin.ch/london</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7616 6000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1200.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>16-18 Montagu Place<br/>London<br/>W1H 2BQ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Switzerland]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(31) 359 7700</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-embassy-berne</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(31) 359 7700</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0900-1230 and 1330-1630; 0900-1200 (consular).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Thunstrasse 50<br/>Berne<br/>3005<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Combining expansive greenery, slick cities and bucketfuls of fresh air, Switzerland is a stylish tourist destination offering countless outdoor adventures and contemporary urban breaks.</p>
<p>Switzerland&rsquo;s Alpine vistas are so picture perfect, they can appear plucked from the pages of a storybook. But these disarming landscapes are alive and kicking, as a spot of skiing, hiking or mountain biking will attest. Ski resorts like Zermatt (home to the lofty Matterhorn), Verbier and celebrity-studded St Moritz provide everything from big, bad Olympic runs to encouragingly gentle novice slopes. And when the snow melts at low altitudes, the white-tipped mountain peaks remain against a backdrop of blue skies, providing a superb setting for summertime hiking.</p>
<p>The ancient capital Berne provides almost endless opportunities for sightseeing, shopping and traditional folk entertainment, while Zurich leads the way in art, design and nightlife; from opera and world-class theatre to stylish bars and nightclubs. Geneva is the sleekest and most upscale of Switzerland's cities, acting as home to a thriving community of expats, many of whom work for the numerous international organisations that are headquartered there.</p>
<p>Yet Switzerland&rsquo;s cultural offerings don&rsquo;t stop there. When it comes to contemporary art, polished Basel reigns supreme, with more than 40 museums and galleries packed into this compact city. For a few days every year, it takes centre stage for the eminent Art Basel fair. French-flavoured Montreux also steals a moment in the cultural spotlight when it becomes the centre of focus for the jazz world during the Montreux Jazz Festival. Elsewhere, dotted around green foothills, are countless spruce towns and folkloric villages, where ancient farm culture survives and cattle still loiter amid flower-filled pastures.</p>
<p>Small, mountainous and wealthy, Switzerland is renowned for its enviable quality of life, with public services ticking along like clockwork. Come for the pungent cheese, smooth chocolate and luxury watches; stay for the exquisite culture, incredible scenery and sheer sense of fun.</p><p>Combining expansive greenery, slick cities and bucketfuls of fresh air, Switzerland is a stylish tourist destination offering countless outdoor adventures and contemporary urban breaks.&nbsp;<span style="line-height: 20.3999996185303px;">Switzerland&rsquo;s Alpine vistas are so picture perfect, they can appear plucked from the pages of a storybook. But these disarming landscapes are alive and kicking, as a spot of skiing, hiking or mountain biking will attest. Ski resorts like Zermatt (home to the lofty Matterhorn), Verbier and celebrity-studded St Moritz provide everything from big, bad Olympic runs to encouragingly gentle novice slopes. And when the snow melts at low altitudes, the white-tipped mountain peaks remain against a backdrop of blue skies, providing a superb setting for summertime hiking.</span></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
