<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Syrian Arab Republic" ColCode="syr" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="sy" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Syrian Arab Republic]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Syrian Arab Republic's climate is characterised by hot, dry summers and fairly cold winters. Nights are often cool.

<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights are essential in summer with protective headwear. Heavy winter clothing is advisable from November to March.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>SyrianAir<em>&nbsp;</em>flies to Aleppo, Deir ez Zor, Latakia, Palmyra and Qamishli.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The railway extends 2,200km (1,364 miles). A service operates between Damascas-Aleppo-Deirez-Zar-Hassakeh-Kamechli. A second line runs between Aleppo-Latakia-Banias-Tartous-Homs-Damascas-Deraa. First-class carriages are air conditioned.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are 25,887km (16,086 miles) of roads. Traffic systems are poor and there are numerous accidents. Second-class roads are unreliable during the wet season. The principal route is Aleppo to Damascus and Dar'a (north-south axis).</p>r<p>Shared taxis are available to all parts of the country. Service taxis (old limousines) run on major routes and cost 50 to 70% more than Karnak buses.</p><p>International Driving Permit required. Green Cards are not yet accepted in the Syrian Arab Republic. Insurance is required by law and a customs certificate is needed. These are available from touring and automobile clubs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Publicly-owned bus services operate in all major towns and cities. Most buses outside the capital, however, have no signs in a European script to indicate destination or stops, which can make travelling rather difficult. Taxis are widely available. Fares should be agreed in advance and according to the meter in the cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Syrian Arab Republic</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">latakia</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Syrian Arab Republic</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">deirez_zor</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">8.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Syrian Arab Republic</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">aleppo</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Syrian Arab Republic</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">al_hasakah</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">8.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Syrian Arab Republic's national airline is SyrianAir<em>&nbsp;</em>(<a href="http://www.syriaair.com" target="_blank">www.syriaair.com</a>). However, due to ongoing conflict in the country, buying tickets from Syrian Arab Airlines to fly to Syria is now illegal for EU citizens; they are only allowed to buy tickets that depart from Syria from this airline.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To Damascus: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 6 hours.</p>
<p>To Aleppo: from London - 4 to 5 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>S&pound;200. Children under 10 years of age and transit passengers (continuing their journey within 24 hours and not leaving the customs zone) are exempt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Aleppo International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport, 10km (6.5 miles) from the city (journey time - 20 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Latakia Bassel al-Assad International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is situated 25km (16 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Damascus International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.scaa.sy<p>The airport is located 30km (18 miles) south of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/damascus">Damascus</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(011) 444 3400</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports</strong><strong>:</strong> Latakia and Tartus.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Links go via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ankara">Ankara</a> (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkey">Turkey</a>) and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/istanbul">Istanbul</a>. Change at Ankara for the <em>Taurus Express </em>to Aleppo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Public telephones are available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International roaming agreements have been established. Coverage is good, covering 95% of the populated areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Access to Internet services is available in universities and public offices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The government and Baath Party own and control much of the Syrian media. Criticism of the president and his family is not permitted and the domestic and foreign press are censored. Press freedom swelled after Bashar al-Assad became president in 2000, overseeing the licensing of the first private publications in almost 40 years. However, a subsequent press law imposed a range of restrictions. Publications had to obtain licences from the prime minister and could be suspended for violating content bans. Websites deemed to be offensive or anti-Syrian are banned by the government.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes up to 10 days. Parcels sent from the Syrian Arab Republic should be packed at the post office. There are post offices in virtually all towns.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1400; larger branches are open longer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>A quick update</b></p><![CDATA[<p>As Syria's civil war continues to rage, the country remains a no-go for tourists. Updates on the attractions below, which once lured millions of tourists to this country, were added to this guide in 2015 and will be reviewed by our foreign correspondents when the war has finished and the dust has settled – whenever that may be.</p>]]><p><b>The Crac des Chevaliers</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Crac des Chevaliers is the most famous crusader castle in the world and was a stronghold of the Hospitallers during the days of the Latin Kingdom of Jerusalem (1100-1290). The castle, rising from an altitude of 670m (2,200ft), was protected by watchtowers and supplied with food from the surrounding fertile countryside. The castle fared well during previous military campaigns, but is sadly being destroyed during the current conflict.</p>]]><p><b>The River Orontes in Hama</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Situated on the River Orontes, 45km (28 miles) from Homs, Hama has fared better than most in the civil war. Dating back to around 5,000BC, Hams is famed for its <em>norias</em>, gigantic wooden waterwheels, which are still used to provide water for the city and to irrigate the many public gardens. The orchards, the Great Mosque and the Al Azem Palace's Museum are also of interest.</p>]]><p><b>The Royal Palace in Mari</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mari's Royal Palace was built by Zimrilim, the ruler of this important city-state some 2,000 years ago, and boasts 300 rooms and hallways. It was rediscovered in the course of excavations during the 1930s, but has been systematically looted by IS militants. Mari itself was built at a strategic point on the trade routes from the Syrian Arab Republic to Mesopotamia. The town's oldest ruins date back 5,000 years, but are currently a no go area.</p>]]><p><b>The ancient city of Aleppo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A high-profile victim of the civil war, fierce fighting has taken place in the city of Aleppo, much of which has been reduced to rubble. The city contains a massive citadel, which stands on the site of a Hittite acropolis. This UNESCO World Heritage Site is one of the most magnificent examples of Islamic military architecture in Syria, but it's future is decidedly uncertain.</p>]]><p><b>The ancient city of Damascus</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the world's oldest inhabited cities, the Syrian capital has fared much better than other parts of the country during the civil war, but the security situation there is precarious. In more peaceful times, visitors flocked to the city to admire attractions such as Ummayyad Mosque, the 16th-century Tikiyeh Mosque and Al Azem Palace, which houses Islamic art and ancient copies of the Koran. Sadly, it will be a case of seeing what's left after the civil war.</p>]]><p><b>The ancient city of Palmyra</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Famed for its ancient Byzantine ruins, Palmyra has been plundered of its ancient treasures by IS militants and its temples (most famously that of Baalshamin) have fallen victim of the group's campaign of iconoclasm. Satellite images suggest much of this ancient city has fallen, but the true extent of the damage will not be known until the end of the war.</p>]]><p><b>The minarets of Mecca</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Home to some of the oldest minarets in the world, Bosra has become a battlefield in recent years. The first city in Syria to become Muslim, it was used as a stopover on the pilgrimage route to Mecca and prospered until the 17th century. By then the region, as it is today, was becoming unsafe and the pilgrims began to take a less dangerous route further west.</p>]]><p><b>The seaside town of Latakia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A stronghold for president Assad, Latakia is located on Syria's Mediterranean coast. Once a major holiday resort, the town stands at the foot of forested mountains overlooking the beach and the edge of the Fertile Plains (also known as the 'Cradle of Civilisation'). There are a number of antiquities, including the ruined Temple of Bacchus and a triumphal arch.</p>]]><p><b>The souks of Syria</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Before the civil war broke out, visitors came to Syria in their droves and one of the many highlights for sightseers was to explore one of the country's many souks (markets). Particularly recommended was the one at Aleppo, made up of 16km (10 miles) of meandering low corridors lined with shops and bustling with activity, but that city has been a high-profile casualty of the war. Damascus' Long Souk was also wonderful.</p>]]><p><b>The steamy hammams</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Though the country is in a mess, parts of Syria try to cling on to some semblance of normal life. One facet of local life is to kick back and relax in one of Syria's well-preserved <em>hammams</em> (public baths).</p>]]><p><b>The ‘Pear of the Euphrates’</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sadly the city of Deir ez Zor, once known as the 'Pearl of the Euphrates,' has been the scene of fierce fighting during the civil war. Neighbourhoods have been reduced to rubble and much of the population has been displaced. Located on the bank of the Euphrates, the city was revered for its manicured gardens and orchards, which contrasted beautifully with the golden desert hues and the silver thread of the river.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$26.3 billion (2005).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum, textiles, phosphates, antiques, fruit and vegetables, and cotton.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, metal and metal products, machinery, textiles and petroleum.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Germany, Italy, France, Lebanon and Saudi Arabia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main components of the Syrian economy are agriculture and oil. In the agricultural sector, cotton is the principal commodity and a key export. Wheat, barley, fruit and vegetables are the other main products, the bulk of which are grown for domestic consumption.<br /><br />Oil is the main industry and provides two-thirds of Syrian export earnings, although the future of the sector is limited by the relatively small size of the Syrian Arab Republic's reserves (which are already over half-exhausted). There are also reserves of phosphates (another export earner), iron ore and natural gas.<br /><br />The rest of the industrial economy is divided roughly between three areas: chemicals, rubber and plastics; textiles and leather goods; and food and drink. The service economy is relatively under-developed but expanding rapidly: tourism especially has seen exceptional growth to the extent that the Syrian Arab Republic now receives over 1 million visitors annually.<br /><br />A particular problem for the Syrian economy in a very arid region is the availability of water. The Syrians have concluded a long-term agreement with Turkey over use of the northern part of Tigris/Euphrates river system (which also serves Iraq), but this is still a highly sensitive issue. <br /><br />The government has set a high priority on economic reform. Much of the economy is still state-owned and highly regulated. Some measures have been introduced to promote private enterprise and attract foreign investment; fiscal policy has focused on an overhaul and simplification of the convoluted tax system. The cabinet has been tasked to accelerate the economic reform process, although it is likely to encounter many of the same obstacles as its predecessors in the form of well-entrenched vested interests and monopolies.<br /><br />The Syrian Arab Republic's trade patterns have shifted since the demise of the Soviet bloc, with which it traded extensively. It is now more vulnerable to attitudes in Washington: under the Bush administration, the Syrian Arab Republic is classed as a 'rogue state' and since November 2003 has been subject to partial economic sanctions. This has a knock-on effect on trade with other countries.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Formal suits are necessary for business. Businesspeople generally speak English and French. Appointments are necessary and business cards are widely used. Arabs often discuss business with more than one person at a time. A list of notarised translators is available from the British Embassy. Hotels with conference facilities can be found in Damascus (Cham Palace, Ebla-Cham, Omayyad and The Sheraton), in Aleppo (Shahba-Cham), in Latakia (the Cote d'Azure) and in Hama (Apamee-Cham).<br /></p><p>Sat-Thurs 0800-1400. All government offices, banks and Muslim firms close on Fridays and remain open on Sundays; Christian firms are generally open on Fridays and closed on Sundays. During the month of Ramadan, government offices start work one hour later than usual.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Damascus Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (11) 211 339
					Website:http://www.dcc-sy.com
					Address: 126 rue Mou'awiah,PO Box 1040,Damascus,]]><b>Federation of Syrian Chambers of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (11) 337 344
					Website:http://www.fedcommsyr.org
					Address: rue Mousa Ben Nousair,PO Box 5909,Damascus,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Clearly things have changed greatly in Syria with the on-going civil war, but traditionally there were numerous restaurants in Aleppo and Damascus that served a variety of Oriental and European dishes.</p><p>Syria has a rich and ancient food culture and was once considered the bread basket of the Middle East, but the years of conflict have all but destroyed farming and cut off food supplies to many areas.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Kibbeh bil sanieh:</strong> The national dish of minced meat and bulgur wheat baked with a filling of spiced meat and pine nuts.</p><p><strong>Fatteh</strong>: Crumbs of fresh or stale breads toasted and served with meat or vegetables and sauce. <br/><strong>Yabrak:</strong> Vine leaves stuffed with rice and minced meat.</p><p><strong>Ouzi:</strong> Pastry stuffed with rice and minced meat. <br/><strong>Mensaf:</strong> Pieces of lamb on rice and pine nuts.</p><p><strong>Riz a'djaj: </strong>Poaxched chicken with rice.</p><p><strong>Freekeh with chicken:</strong> Oached chicken with slow cooked freekeh wheat served with Syrian truffle, pine nuts and almonds.</p><p><strong>Muhammara: </strong>A hot pepper dip, originally fron Aleppo.</p><p><strong>Mahshi: </strong>Courgettes or aubergines stuffed with minced beef or lamb, nuts and rice.</p><p><strong>Tabbouleh: </strong>Bulgur (or couscous) with parsley, mint, onion, seasoned with olive oil and lemon juice.</p><p><strong>Fattoush: </strong>Salad with tomato, cucumber and radish in a dressing made with sumac spice.</p><p><strong>Malukhiyya: </strong>Vegetable dish made with jute leaves chopped a cooked in meat stock with garlic and coriander.</p><p><strong>Manoushi bread: </strong>A popular snack, like a pizza only softer and chewier.<br/><strong>Baklava:</strong> A favourite dessert made from flaky pastry filled with honey and nuts.</p><p><strong>Cigar nut pastries: </strong>Chopped almonds, pistachios and walnuts rolled with brown sugar and filo pastry.</p><p><strong>Ma'amoul: </strong>date, pistachio or walnut filled biscuits.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Often expected, especially in more expensive establishments; traditionally 10% is generally acceptable.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Souks (markets) are the best places for shopping, notably those in Aleppo. Local handicrafts in the Syrian Arab Republic are numerous and precious, including mother-of-pearl items (such as backgammon boards), olive-wood carvings, weaving and embroidery, leather goods and gold and silver jewellery.</p><p>Sat-Thurs 0930-1400 and 1630-2200 (summer); Sat-Thurs 0930-1400 and 1600-2000 (winter).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While accommodation can generally be arranged on arrival from November to March, reservations are highly recommended throughout the year. Particularly during exhibitions, upmarket hotels in Aleppo and Damascus are often fully booked. Tariffs are the same throughout the year. All rates are subject to a 15% service charge. Hotels range from fairly low grade to luxurious 5-star accommodation. The best-quality hotels are found in Damascus, though Aleppo, Hama, Homs, Latakia and Palmyra also have luxury hotels. For further information, contact the Ministry of Tourism.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available in Aleppo, Bosra, Damascus, Dar'a, Idlib and Zabadani. <em>Cités Universitaires </em>offer summer accommodation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While accommodation can generally be arranged on arrival from November to March, reservations are highly recommended throughout the year. Particularly during exhibitions, upmarket hotels in Aleppo and Damascus are often fully booked. Tariffs are the same throughout the year. All rates are subject to a 15% service charge. Hotels range from fairly low grade to luxurious 5-star accommodation. The best-quality hotels are found in Damascus, though Aleppo, Hama, Homs, Latakia and Palmyra also have luxury hotels. For further information, contact the Ministry of Tourism.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While accommodation can generally be arranged on arrival from November to March, reservations are highly recommended throughout the year. Particularly during exhibitions, upmarket hotels in Aleppo and Damascus are often fully booked. Tariffs are the same throughout the year. All rates are subject to a 15% service charge. Hotels range from fairly low grade to luxurious 5-star accommodation. The best-quality hotels are found in Damascus, though Aleppo, Hama, Homs, Latakia and Palmyra also have luxury hotels. For further information, contact the Ministry of Tourism.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health insurance is recommended. Basic medical facilities exist in main cities but there are few outside them. Medical care is provided free of charge to those who cannot afford to pay.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and relatively safe. Bottled water is available. Drinking water outside main cities and towns is likely to be contaminated and sterilisation is considered essential. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water; swimming pools which are well chlorinated and maintained are safe. Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Revolution Day :
							08 March </p><p>Easter Sunday :
							01 April </p><p>Orthodox Easter Sunday :
							08 April </p><p>Independence Day :
							17 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Martyrs' Day :
							06 May </p><p>Anniversary of October Liberation War :
							06 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into the Syrian Arab Republic without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigarillos or 25 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 30ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; 570ml of spirits.<br />
&bull; 500ml of lotion and 500ml of eau de cologne.<br />
&bull; Gifts worth up to S&pound;250.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Firearms and ammunition, and live, frozen or stuffed birds, or any bird-derived products.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Syrian Pound (SYP; symbol S£) = 100 piastres. Notes are in denominations of S£1,000, 500, 200, 100, 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1. Coins are in denominations of S£25, 10, 5, 2 and 1.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Syrian currency cannot generally be reconverted to hard currency. The country's banking system is state-owned, and there is at least one branch of the Commercial Bank of Syria in every main town. Hard currency can be exchanged for local currency in these branches.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express and Diners Club are most readily accepted; some hotels will accept MasterCard. Tickets may be bought with credit cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Can be difficult to exchange and are not generally recommended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normally Sat-Thurs 0800-1400 (banks tend to close early on Thursdays).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry: &pound;30; multiple-entry: &pound;50. These fees are only for nationals of the UK. The cost of visas for other nationalities varies; consult the embassy for further information.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry: three months from the date of issue; multiple-entry: six months from the date of issue. Entry visas initially allow stays of up to 14 days. Extensions for up to three months are possible; apply at the Department of Immigration.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at the embassy). Application forms must be completed online.</p>
<p>In countries where the Syrian Arab Republic does not have diplomatic representation, visitors can either apply by post to the nearest Syrian Embassy or can apply at the Syrian border. Note the Syrian Embassy in the USA was closed by the US government in 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow six days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For stays of over 15 days, visitors should report to the immigration office.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[34.802075]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[38.996815]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>185,180 sq km (71,498 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>18,563,595 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>92.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Damascus.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The country can be divided geographically into four main areas: the fertile plain in the northeast, the plateau, coastal and mountain areas in the west, the central plains, and the desert and steppe region in the central and southeastern areas. The Euphrates flows from Turkey in the north, through the Syrian Arab Republic, down to Iraq in the southeast. It is the longest river in the Syrian Arab Republic, the total length being 2,330km (1,450 miles), of which 600km (370 miles) pass through the Syrian Arab Republic. The Khabur River supports the al-Khabur Basin in the northeast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Over 80% Muslim (mostly Sunni), with sizeable Christian (mostly Orthodox and Catholic) groups and Jewish minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Syrians take as much pride in their modern amenities as in their unique heritage and in the tradition of exquisite craftsmanship, and both should be appreciated. Visitors will enjoy the hospitality that is a deep-rooted Arab tradition and sharing the pleasures of an attractive Oriental way of life. It is customary to shake hands on meeting and on departure. A visitor will be treated with great courtesy and will frequently be offered refreshment, usually coffee. As a guest in someone's home or, more usually, in a restaurant, visitors should respect Arab customs and traditions. A souvenir from the visitor's home or company is well received. Conservative casual wear is suitable. Beachwear or shorts should not be worn away from the beach or poolside. Smoking follows Western habits and in most cases it is obvious where not to smoke. Smoking is prohibited in public from dawn to dusk during Ramadan.<br /><br /><strong>Photography: </strong>No attempt should be made to photograph anything remotely connected with the armed forces or in the vicinity of defence installations, which even includes radio transmission aerials. It is wise to take a good look at what will be appearing in the background before pointing the camera.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins and Italian-style plugs with three round pins in a row are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Wael al-Halqi since 2012.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Bashar al-Assad since 2000.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Syrian Arab Republic has been inhabited for tens of thousands of years and, as a result, has a rich cultural history. The area that is now the Syrian Arab Republic was part of the Empire of Mesopotamia around 2300 BC, during which time the cities of Ugarit (where the oldest written alphabet in the world is believed to have been developed) and Byblos grew to become powerful commercial centres. By about 500 BC, southern Syria had fallen under the control of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/egypt">Egypt</a>, while the northern principalities had been welded into the Mitanni Empire. Within a few centuries, however, the Hittites from the north had overrun all of Syria, an empire that in turn collapsed in the face of invasions by the Mediterranean Sea peoples. The history of the following centuries, until the eventual destruction of the Kingdom of Judah in 539 BC, is one of a struggle by Babylonians, Canaanites, Assyrians, Phoenicians and many other tribes and empires for control of Syrian trade. Alexander the Great absorbed Syria into his empire in 333 BC; however, control of the region was disputed for the following two centuries  on this occasion, between the various people trying to gain control of his inheritance. <BR/><BR/>For several centuries, the Province of Syria enjoyed the mixed blessings of the Pax Romana and was a province of the Eastern (Byzantine) Empire after the division of the Roman Empire. But even then, Syria was regarded as a frontier region, bordered to the east by the Arabs and Persians. The Persian invasions were repulsed but Syria eventually fell to the Muslims in the mid-seventh century. From then on, Syria was to be firmly part of the Muslim world, although retaining Christian and Jewish populations. Muslim control of Syria was vital to the defeat of the Christians and their expulsion from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jerusalem">Jerusalem</a>. However, during the 13th century, a far greater threat was the terrifying force of the Mongols. In the space of 50 years, they swept through Asia, creating an empire that stretched from Korea to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a>. By 1260, they had overrun Syria and deposed the Abbasid Khalif. The Muslim world  and, indeed, the Christian one  seemed doomed. But in that year, the Mamluk General Baybars defeated the massive army of Hulagu at the Battle of Goliath's Well  a victory that, in retrospect, must be seen as one of the world's most decisive military engagements. By 1520, the region had fallen under the sway of the Ottoman Turks and, as a result, Syria prospered once  for the most part. <BR/><BR/>The 19th century was a period of increasing restlessness in the area  Napoleon's campaign in 1799/1800, the Egyptian invasion in the 1830s and the insurrection in 1860-61 are three instances of this. The Turks were defeated in World War I and Syria was occupied by the French for a short time, before Syria was granted full independence in 1946. Three years later, the country came under the first of a series of military dictatorships that have governed the country for most of the subsequent period. As in the rest of the Middle East, Arab nationalism became a major political force during the 1950s  indeed, the influence of Nasser's revolution in Egypt on the Syrians was so strong that Syria joined Egypt in forming the United Arab Republic in 1958. The alliance was short-lived, Syria seceding in 1961, to form the Syrian Arab Republic. The most powerful political force in Syria since then has been the Ba'ath Party or Arab Socialist Renaissance (see <I><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iraq">Iraq</a></I>), which seized power in 1971, under the leadership of General Hafez al-Assad, who ruled at the head of a tightly controlled dictatorship, until his death in June 2000. Assad's main power base was the Alawite group, a Muslim sect to which 10 per cent of the Syrian population is affiliated. With the tactical and strategic skill that was his trademark, Assad comfortably dealt with the challenges to his supremacy  largely through his control of the army and the country's myriad intelligence organisations. <BR/><BR/>The major exception occurred in February 1982, when the Muslim Brotherhood  the principal opposition group confronting the Assad regime  launched a rebellion from the town of Hama. The rebellion was crushed, with several thousand deaths, by military forces led by Assad's brother Rifaat who then controlled the country's security forces. A few months afterwards, Assad then faced his most serious foreign policy challenge since the loss of the Golan Heights (an area bordering the Syrian Arab Republic and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/israel">Israel</a>) in the 1973 Arab-Israeli war, the Israeli invasion of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lebanon">Lebanon</a>. The Syrian Arab Republic perceived Israel's strategy as establishing a Christian-dominated client state, underpinned by Israeli military power. The Syrian Arab Republic could not hope to match the Israelis militarily but Assad nonetheless managed to manoeuvre the Syrian Arab Republic into a dominant position in Lebanon. This he achieved by supporting the main Lebanese Muslim militias, Amal and Hezbollah, and then introducing a substantial military presence of its own, remaining careful to avoid direct confrontation with the Israelis (see <I>Israel</I> and <I>Lebanon</I>). In 1984, the Israelis moved into a self-styled 'security zone' south of the Litani River and in 1999, after a decade and a half of attritional guerrilla warfare with the Syrian-backed Hezbollah, the Israelis pulled out altogether. The Syrian Arab Republic, meanwhile, had established a political and military dominance over Lebanon, which continues to this day, although events in early 2005 - such as the assassination of the former Lebanese prime minister, Hariri, the UN Security Council and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>'s increasing pressure on Syria, and rallies on both sides - have prompted Syria to begin the process of withdrawing its troops, although it is not know how quickly or how thoroughly this process will be undertaken. Apart from anything else, their presence in Lebanon served to confirm that the Syrian Arab Republic was indispensable to a comprehensive settlement in the Middle East. The Syrian Arab Republic has yet to secure its main objective  the return of the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights  and has made clear that unless the issue is settled, the Syrian Arab Republic will not follow Egypt and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jordan">Jordan</a> in reaching a formal peace with the Jewish state. It is therefore uncertain whether Syria will be prepared to exit Lebanon entirely, when it is so key to their objective in Israel. There have been some discreet contacts between the Syrian Arab Republic and Israel in the last few years, most recently in early 2004. Israeli premier Ariel Sharon has invited President Bashar Assad to visit Israel, an offer which so far has not been accepted. The relationship between the two countries took a turn for the worse in 2005 over an alleged deal Syria was making with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a> to acquire missiles. <BR/><BR/>The Syrian Arab Republic's relations with the West reached a nadir during the late-1980s, but the 1991 Gulf War came as an unexpected blessing, with the USA eager to attract Arab states into the anti-Iraqi coalition. Assad had been an implacable opponent of Saddam Hussein's Iraq from the beginning: the pan-Arab Ba'athist movement had suffered a fatal ideological split in the 1960s which has never been healed. The Syrians were happy to back the UN coalition and as part of the deal, they also secured substantial financial support and the guarantee of a free hand in Lebanon (which they still have, although, as aforementioned, this is subject to increasing contention and it is possible Syria may withdraw completely by later within the tear). <BR/><BR/>In June 2000, after years of failing health, President Assad died. Having fallen out with his brother, Rifaat, some years earlier, and with the accidental death of his eldest son, Basil, in 1994, Assad had selected his second son, Bashar, as heir. While domestic policy has seen something of a relaxation under Bashar, Western hopes that the Syrian Arab Republic would pursue a more pro-Western line have proved misguided  in the vocabulary of the US Bush administration, the Syrian Arab Republic is a 'state of concern' (one level below the 'axis of evil'). The Syrians have provided some assistance to the Western 'War Against Terror' but were strongly opposed to the Anglo-American invasion of Iraq in 2003. Syria pulled its forces out of Lebanon in 2005, after coming under intense international pressure after being implicated by a UN report for the assassination of former premier of Lebanon, Rafik Hariri. Both Syria and Pro Syria Lebanese officials were thought to be involved although this has been strongly denied by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/damascus">Damascus</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Syrian Arab Republic in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 232 6313.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 232 6313.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2215 Wyoming Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Syrian Arab Republic in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7245 9012 or 7201 8830/1 (consular).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.syrianembassy.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7245 9012 or 7201 8830/1 (consular).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon- Fri 1000-1200 (visa applications); 1300-1400 (enquiries); 1400-1500 (visa collection).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>8 Belgrave Square<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8PH<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Until the recent civil war, Syria was a diverse destination that revelled in its antiquity. Inhabited for tens of thousands of years, the country accumulated all the cultural riches afforded by such a long history and was rightly considered one of the Middle East&rsquo;s top destinations. Sadly, the war-ravaged nation is now struggling to preserve its ancient relics, which document the rise and fall of myriad civilisations.</p>
<p>Like its history, Syria&rsquo;s landscapes are varied. Vast steppes cover much of the country, but mountains soar in the west, deserts stretch in the east and volcanic fields spread across the south. Meandering through this dusty land is the great Euphrates River, which also flows through neighbouring Iraq.</p>
<p>Syria was once regarded as a frontier region, bordered to the east by Persians and west by the Arabs. The country fell to the Persians in the sixth century and though it retained Christian and Jewish populations, Syria was from then on a Muslim nation.</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s story is littered with dramatic episodes. Syria was subsumed by empires from Babylon to Canaan, Assyria to Phoenicia; it was conquered by the Ottomans, endured a campaign by Napoleon and was invaded by the Egyptians. During the height of pan-Arabism in the 1950s, the country briefly joined with Egypt in the United Arab Republic, but seceded to form the Syrian Arab Republic in 1961.</p>
<p>The battles and territorial scrambles of the past have translated into a catalogue of staggering cities, such as Damascus and Aleppo, which are chock-full of stunning monuments and ancient mosques.</p>
<p>The uprising against the ruling Baath Party in 2011 gave way to a civil war, which continues to rage and is further complicated by the formidable presence of the jihadist militant group Islamic State. Travel to Syria is ill-advised (it is probably the most dangerous country on the planet right now) and the future remains uncertain.</p><p>Until the recent civil war, Syria was a diverse destination that revelled in its antiquity. Inhabited for tens of thousands of years, the country accumulated all the cultural riches afforded by such a long history and was rightly considered one of the Middle East&rsquo;s top destinations. Sadly, the war-ravaged nation is now struggling to preserve its ancient relics, which document the rise and fall of myriad civilisations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
