<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Tahiti and her Islands" ColCode="tah" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="pf" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Tahiti and her Islands]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Temperate, but cooled by sea breezes. Two main seasons: humid (hot and wet) from November to March, cool and dry from April to October.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens are worn, with a warm layer for cooler evenings. Rainwear is advisable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Domestic flights run by Air Tahiti&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.airtahiti.com" target="_blank">www.airtahiti.com</a>) connect Tahiti with neighbouring islands (Bora Bora, Huahine, Maupiti, Moorea and Raiatea) and remote archipelagos (Tuamotu East and North with Manihi, Rangiroa, Takapoto and Tikehau; Austral Islands of Rurutu and Tubuai; Marquesas Islands of Hiva Oa and Nuku Hiva).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are inter-island connections on the many ferries, catamarans, copra boats and schooners that make regular trips throughout the islands. Daily connections exist between Bora Bora, Huahine, Moorea, Papeete and Raiatea. Yacht and sailboat charter is available at most of the major islands. Some come complete with a captain and crew.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Available in Bora Bora, Huahine, Moorea, Raiatea and Tahiti.</p><p>A national driving licence is sufficient.</p><p>Major and local agencies hire out cars on the main islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Tahiti Nui<em> </em>(<a href="http://www.airtahitinui.com" target="_blank">www.airtahitinui.com</a>) is the only Tahiti-based international carrier. Its routes include direct flights between Papeete and Los Angeles.<strong><br />
</strong></p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 24 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 16 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/los-angeles">Los Angeles</a> - 8 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Faa’a International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airtahitinui-usa.com/airports/papeete.asp<p>The airport, on <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tahiti-and-her-islands">Tahiti</a>, is 6km (4 miles) from the city (journey time - 15 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main port</strong><strong>:</strong> Papeete. The port is served by cruise lines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Operator assistance may be required for international calls. There are many phone booths which operate using cards (<em>Telecarte</em>) that can be purchased at the airport, bars, magazine stands and the post office. Hotel telephone charges are extremely high.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The GSM 900 network is not compatible with US mobile phones. Mobile phones are available to rent, which offer better rates than roaming fees.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are Internet caf&eacute;s in Papeete and Moorea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes around six to eight days.</p><p>(central office in Papeete) Mon-Fri 0700-1800, Sat-Sun 0800-1100 (outside Papeete, there is a restricted service in the afternoons and at weekends).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bask on beautiful beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If you know a place where there are better beaches than Tahiti and Her Islands, we want to know about it. With white sand as pure as the driven snow, limpid lagoons and volcanic vistas, the islands are nirvana for sun seekers. But which are the best? Tough call, but it's hard to beat the sandy shores of Moorea.</p>]]><p><b>Come face to face with sharks and whales</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Come across some of the amazing life that lurks beneath the lovely waters of Tahiti and Her Islands. There are shark and ray feeding demonstrations on Moorea and Bora Bora, and humpback whale watching is possible between July and October in the waters of Rurutu.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the arts heritage of the Marquesas Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the burial spots of both Paul Gauguin and Jacques Brel on the Marquesas Islands, both of whom are buried on Hiva Oa. For greater insight into the life of Gauguin, the famous French Post-Impressionist painter of the 19th century, visit the Paul Gauguin Museum on Tahiti.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Fatu Hiva island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cherish one of Tahiti and Her Islands' most beautiful locations: the island of Fatu Hiva, with its valley of Hanavare, hidden between volcanic rock on the Bay of Virgins. This also contains the important archaeological site of Puamau, with its ancient statue of a <em>tiki</em> (a male figure in Polynesian myth).</p>]]><p><b>Get showered by the Blowhole of Arahoho</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See some of Tahiti's impressive watery wonders, from the Blowhole of Arahoho, which throws water skywards, to the Faarumai and Vaipahi waterfalls. It may be worth finding out beforehand if the sea swell is large enough that day to force water through the blowhole.</p>]]><p><b>Mountain climb on Bora Bora</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ascend the two mountains of Otemanu and Pahia on the island of Bora Bora, and find yourself a wonderful lookout point across this most famous of the Leeward Islands, still only 45 minutes from Tahiti by plane. Club Alpin in Arue also provides information and assistance for climbing Mount Aorai and Mount Diademe.</p>]]><p><b>Saddle up for horse riding</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go horse riding between the numerous valleys of Ua Huka. Hourly and day-long horse riding tours can be arranged through Club Equestre de Tahiti and Centre de Tourisme Equestre de Tahiti, both at the Hippodrome, Pirae, Tahiti. For more equine-related fun, Tahitian-style horse racing can be seen at the Hippodrome in Pirae.</p>]]><p><b>Set sail for adventure</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There's plenty of opportunity to go deep-sea fishing, scuba diving, snorkelling or swimming on a nearby <em>motu</em> (small sandy atoll within a reef), or take a trip by glass-bottomed boat around the lagoons of Bora Bora. The sea around the South Pacific islands is excellent for scuba diving and other popular watersports include windsurfing, waterskiing, surfing and kite-surfing.</p>]]><p><b>Walk through the Opunohu Valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the beautiful Opunohu Valley on Moorea, an ancient dwelling place, uninhabited for 150 years, with 500 ancient structures including temples, some of which have been restored. The <em>marae</em> (open-air temple) of Mahaiatea, on Tahiti, is also worth a visit.</p>]]><p><b>Wander around Papeete market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get to know the locals at Papeete's public market, Le Marché. The bazaar is open all week but really comes to life on Sunday mornings when out-of-town merchants come to sell their wares. Flowers, spices, fabrics and fresh produce are all on offer.</p>]]><p><b>Wander around the enchanting Tahaa island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Inhale the faintly sweet aroma that lingers on the "Vanilla Island" of Tahaa. The breeze constantly carries the aroma of vanilla, from the island's numerous vanilla plantations. Tahaa also shares a coral reef with the island of Raiatea, and offers a tranquil and relaxed lifestyle.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$4.6 billion (2003).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Cultured black pearls, fish and coconut products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Fuels, food, machinery and equipment.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, USA, Japan, Australia and New Zealand.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The traditional Polynesian economy was agricultural, but that sector now accounts for less than 5% of total output and employment. Coconuts are the principal cash crop and vanilla, coffee and citrus fruit are also produced in quantity. There is a substantial fishing industry, based on tuna, most of the income of which is derived from licences granted to foreign fleets. Manufacturing is mainly devoted to processing agricultural products and a small mining industry has evolved following the recent discovery of phosphate and cobalt deposits. <br /><br />French Polynesia as a whole has suffered from a serious unemployment problem since the end of French nuclear testing in the mid 1990s; although much disliked by local governments and the majority of their peoples, the tests provided many construction and service jobs. As a result, Tahiti now depends heavily on remittances from migrant workers.<br /><br />The government believes that tourism offers the best, and perhaps the only, prospect for a self-supporting economy. At present, French Polynesia as a whole receives around 230,000 visitors annually, and the industry is worth over US$400 million annually.<br /><br />The territory suffers from a serious trade deficit (imports exceed exports by a factor of 10) so that considerable aid is needed from the French to balance the country's finances. <br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Informal in atmosphere. Literature will be in French, but English is understood in some business circles, particularly those connected with tourism.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1330-1730, Sat 0800-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre de Commerce, d'Industrie, des Services et des Métiers Polynésie Française (CCISM)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 472 700
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>All the classified hotels have good restaurants where visitors will find Chinese, French, Italian, Japanese and Vietnamese food being served, as well as the Polynesian specialities. Tahitian food can be found in some hotels, while Les Roulottes – trucks or lunch wagons parked on the waterfront at Papeete – sell steak, chips, chicken and shish kebabs. Red meat and poultry is typically imported from New Zealand, but many local dishes make good use of the abundant seafood and exotic fruits and local cooks are famed for their delicate sauces, often made with homegrown vanilla and coconut. A full range of alcoholic drinks is available.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Poisson cru, or iaota:</strong> Marinated fish, for example raw tuna served with coconut cream and limes. The national dish.</p><p><strong>Tamaaraa: </strong>A Tahitian feast with lots of singing and dancing. Roast chicken and pork are cooked then served from 'ahima'a' underground ovens.</p><p><strong>Fafa:</strong> Spinach-like taro leaves, often served with young suckling pig.</p><p><strong>Pouletfafa: </strong>Chicken with taro leaves and coconut cream.</p><p><strong>Fafaru: </strong>Sliced tuna or parrotfish macerated in sea water with crushed shrimps.</p><p><strong>Chevrettes: </strong>Freshwater shrimp.</p><p><strong>Uru: </strong>Breadfruit, eaten as a side dish.</p><p><strong>Casse-croute: </strong>Tahitian sandwich, as popular with locals and tourists.</p><p><strong>Po'e:</strong> A sweet, starchy pudding made of taro roots flavoured with papaya, mango and banana, topped in a rich coconut sauce.</p><p><strong>Kato:</strong> Biscuits made with coconut milk.</p><p><strong>Pineapples: </strong>There's no shortage of beautiful fruit on the islands but Tahiti's pineapples are reputed to be the sweetest in the world.</p><p><strong>Firifiri: </strong>Figure of eight-shaped doughnuts dipped in coffee.</p><p><strong>Noni Juice:</strong> Comes from the Noni tree and is famous for its health-enhancing effects.</p><p><strong>Hinano:</strong> Tahitian beer.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>In general tipping is tolerated but not practised, since it is contrary to the Tahitian idea of hospitality.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Papeete is full of life in the evenings with many restaurants and nightclubs. Most hotels feature Tahitian dance shows, bands and other traditional entertainment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Facilities are concentrated in Papeete. Special purchases include Marquesan woodcarvings, dancing costumes, shell jewellery, Tahitian perfumes, <em>Monoi Tiare Tahiti</em> (coconut oil scented with Tahiti's national flower), vanilla beans and brightly patterned <em>pareu fabrics that make the traditional Tahitian <em>pareo</em>.</em></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1330-1700/1730, Sat 0800-1100. Shops sometimes close for lunch, anytime between 1100-1400. Some shopping centres in the suburbs of Tahiti are open 0730-2200</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation varies from air-conditioned, carpeted, deluxe rooms with telephones and room service, to thatched-roofed bungalows (Tahitian <em>pensions</em> where the bathroom is shared and may be outdoors with cold showers). In the outer islands, resort hotels normally have individual gardens and over-water bungalows and rooms, many built of bamboo; shows and dance bands are often laid on in the evening. A tax of 7% tax is added to the cost of all hotel rooms, but this does not apply to pensions or family lodgings.<br />
<br />
There is a youth hostel in Papeete. It is possible to rent a room in a family home through Tahiti Tourisme for a more genuine experience. There are two campsites on Tahiti; camping is also possible in the grounds of some pensions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation varies from air-conditioned, carpeted, deluxe rooms with telephones and room service, to thatched-roofed bungalows (Tahitian <em>pensions</em> where the bathroom is shared and may be outdoors with cold showers). In the outer islands, resort hotels normally have individual gardens and over-water bungalows and rooms, many built of bamboo; shows and dance bands are often laid on in the evening. A tax of 7% tax is added to the cost of all hotel rooms, but this does not apply to pensions or family lodgings.<br />
<br />
There is a youth hostel in Papeete. It is possible to rent a room in a family home through Tahiti Tourisme for a more genuine experience. There are two campsites on Tahiti; camping is also possible in the grounds of some pensions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation varies from air-conditioned, carpeted, deluxe rooms with telephones and room service, to thatched-roofed bungalows (Tahitian <em>pensions</em> where the bathroom is shared and may be outdoors with cold showers). In the outer islands, resort hotels normally have individual gardens and over-water bungalows and rooms, many built of bamboo; shows and dance bands are often laid on in the evening. A tax of 7% tax is added to the cost of all hotel rooms, but this does not apply to pensions or family lodgings.<br />
<br />
There is a youth hostel in Papeete. It is possible to rent a room in a family home through Tahiti Tourisme for a more genuine experience. There are two campsites on Tahiti; camping is also possible in the grounds of some pensions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical facilites are good on the major islands. Private medical insurance is recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and, whilst relatively safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is available. Drinking water outside main cities and towns may be contaminated and sterilisation is advisable. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Gospel Day :
							05 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Victory Day :
							08 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Internal Autonomy Day :
							29 June </p><p>Bastille Day :
							14 July </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Armistice Day :
							11 November </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Tahiti by passengers 18 years and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2L of wine, sparkling wine, beer and cider and 2L of other alcoholic drinks.<br />
&bull; Goods up to a value of XPF30,000 (XPF15,000 for passengers up to 15 years of age).</p>
<p>There is no duty-free allowance for perfume, eau de toilette, tea or coffee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics, counterfeit goods, unlicensed firearms and ammunition, cultured pearls from outside Tahiti, endangered species, domestic pets, art and antiquities (unless you have a permit), and medicines (other than for personal use).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>French Pacific Franc (XPF) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of XPF10,000, 5,000, 1,000 and 500. Coins are in denominations of XPF100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. The French Pacific Franc is tied to the Euro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Exchange facilities are available at the airport, major banks and at authorised hotels and shops in Papeete.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are all accepted. ATMs are common on Tahiti, with a few on the smaller islands.</p><p>ATMs are common on Tahiti, with a few on the smaller islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The recommended means of importing foreign currency. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars or Euros.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0745-1530. Some are open Saturday 0745-1130.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Tahiti, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by EU nationals and for three months by all other nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tahiti is not part of the Schengen area. You can only visit on a Schengen visa if French Polynesia is clearly marked on your visa sticker, so be sure to advise the consulate in advance. You should only apply for this visa if visiting France <em>and</em> Tahiti.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay overseas territory visa: &euro;9; short-stay&nbsp;Schengen visa: &euro;60; long-stay visa: &euro;99.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay visa: up to three months; long-stay visa: valid for stays of over three months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals who require visas should obtain them from the French Embassy/Consulate in their place of residence. In the UK, the consulate has outsourced the visa application process to TLScontact (<a href="http://www.tlscontact.com/gb2fr" target="_blank">www.tlscontact.com/gb2fr</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow 15 working days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-17.650920]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-149.426042]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>4,167 sq km (1,609 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>285,753 (UN estimate 2016)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>67.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Papeete (Tahiti Island).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>French Overseas Collectivity.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>French Polynesia comprises 120 islands divided into five archipelagos: the Society Archipelago, Tuamotu Archipelago, Marquesas Islands, Austral Islands and Mangreva Islands. The Windward and Leeward Islands, collectively called the Society Archipelago, are mountainous with coastal plains. Tahiti, the largest of the Windward group, is dominated by Mount Orohena at 2,236m (7,337ft) and Mount Aorai at 2,068m (6,786ft). Moorea lies next to Tahiti, a picturesque volcanic island with white sand beaches. The Leeward Islands to the west are generally lower in altitude. The largest islands are Raiatea and Bora Bora. Tuamotu Archipelago comprises 80 coral atolls, located 298km (185 miles) east of Tahiti. The Marquesas Islands lie 1,497km (930 miles) northeast of Tahiti and are made up of two clusters of volcanic islands divided into a southern and northern group. The grass-covered Austral Islands south of Tahiti are scattered in a chain from east to west over a distance of 499km (310 miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Approximately 55% Protestant and 34% Catholic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The basic lifestyle of the islands is represented by the simple Tahitian fares built of bamboo with <em>pandanus</em> roofs. Local women dress in bright <em>pareos</em> and men in the male equivalent, but casual dress is expected of the visitor (except in Papeete, where bathing suits and shorts are not considered suitable dress). Traditional dances are still performed mostly in hotels, with Western dance styles mainly in tourist centres. Normal social courtesies are important.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110/220 volts AC (depending on the location), 60Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins and American-style plugs with two flat pins are in use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President of the Council of Ministers Edouard Fritch since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Fran&ccedil;ois Hollande since 2012, represented locally by  High Commissioner Lionel Beffre since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The first Europeans to arrive on the island groups were 16th-century Spanish and Portuguese explorers. The British, notably Captain Cook and later Captain Bligh (of 'HMS Bounty' notoriety), and then the French, took control of the islands in the 18th century. Tahiti, the largest island in French Polynesia, was made a French protectorate in 1842 and a colony in 1880. The other islands were annexed by the turn of the century. This status quo remained until 1957, when Polynesia was made an Overseas Territory. A revised constitution, introduced in 1977, ceded greater autonomy. For the next 20 years, the islands' politics were dominated by the French nuclear testing programme. <BR/><BR/>By the time the programme ended in 1996, 150 separate explosions had been detonated, mainly on the atoll of Mururoa. In general, the French government was able to rely on the firm backing of most of French public opinion and an often ambivalent attitude on the part of the inhabitants of French Polynesia, who were well aware of the considerable benefits of the test programme to the otherwise threadbare local economy. The tests had begun in 1966, but it was not until the 1980s that opposition to them began to assume significant proportions, following the terrorist attack by French special forces on the Greenpeace vessel <I>Rainbow Warrior</I>. <BR/><BR/>By the time of the final series of tests in 1995/6, Tahiti had become the focus of opposition from throughout the South Pacific, and several riots occurred. Although the protesters failed to stop the tests, their campaign had an important political effect by linking the anti-nuclear movement and the burgeoning pro-independence movement which had so far been largely unrepresented in any political forum, despite the support of a large proportion (possibly the majority) of the population. The politics of the territory had been dominated for the previous decade by the centre-right <I>Tahoeraa Huiratira</I> (TH) party, led by Gaston Flosse, allied to the <I>French Gaullist Rassemblement pour la République</I> (RPR), which backed French rule and nuclear testing. <BR/><BR/>Pro-Independence leader Oscar Temaru was elected by the territory's assembly in March 2005. It was the third change in leadership n 12 months and followed months of wrangling between Mr Temaru and the Pro France rival, Gaston Flosse. Mr Flosse's Government lost a vote of confidence on February 2005, precipitation the poll in which Mr Temaru defeated the pro-France candidate, Gaston Tang Sang by 29 votes to 26. <BR/><BR/>Tahiti and her Islands gained <I>Overseas Country</I> status in 2004.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[French Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7073 1000. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ambafrance-uk.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7073 1000. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>58 Knightsbridge<br/>London<br/>SW1X 7JT<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[French Embassy in the USA ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 944 6000. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ambafrance-us.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 944 6000. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Visa appointments are available Mon-Fri 0845-1200. Appointments can be booked online.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>4101 Reservoir Road NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tahiti and Her Islands are known for their laid-back vibes. Expect romantic sunsets and giant curls of turquoise breaking over reefs. Remote and pristine, the islands give you a glimpse of paradise on Earth.</p><p>The first Europeans to arrive on the islands were 16th-century Spanish and Portuguese explorers. After them, the British and French took control in the 18th century. Tahiti, the largest island in French Polynesia is characterised by its spectacular tropical scenery, banana groves, plantations and flowers. The isle is dominated by Mount Orohena at 2,236m (7,337ft) and Mount Aorai at 2,068m (6,786ft).</p><p>You'll find plenty of colonial history on Tahiti, which became a French protectorate in 1842, and was by 1880 a full colony. The other islands were annexed by the turn of the century. This status quo remained until 1957, when Polynesia was made an Overseas Territory. A revised constitution, introduced in 1977, ceded greater autonomy to the islands.</p><p>For the next 20 years, Tahiti and Her Islands' politics were dominated by the French nuclear testing programme. By the time the programme ended in 1996, 150 separate explosions had been detonated, and Tahiti had become the focus of opposition throughout the South Pacific, with plenty of protesting and riots. Although the protesters failed to stop the tests, their campaign had an important political effect by linking the anti-nuclear movement and the burgeoning pro-independence movement, which had up until then been largely unrepresented in any political forum, despite the support of a large proportion of the population.</p><p>In recent years, changes have been afoot: Tahiti and Her Islands gained Overseas Country status in 2004, and pro-independence leader Oscar Temaru was elected in 2005. It only remains to be seen whether these changes result in imminent and full independence.</p><p>Beyond the political questions, Tahiti and Her Islands offer an idyllic getaway for holidaymakers keen on sun, sand and tranquillity. And let's be honest, who isn't keen on those things?</p><p>Tahiti and Her Islands exude a laid-back tranquillity, as romantic sunsets send giant curls of turquoise breaking over reefs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
