<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Taiwan" ColCode="twn" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="tw" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Taiwan]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Despite the island&rsquo;s relatively small size, the fact that Taiwan is bisected by the Tropic of Cancer means weather conditions can vary considerably from the north to the south. There&rsquo;s a subtropical climate with moderate temperatures in the north, where rain is common in the winter months. The southern areas, where temperatures are higher on average, are less prone to rain.</p>
<p>Summer can be uncomfortably hot across the island, making autumn and spring great times to come calling. The typhoon season usually comes into effect in late summer and makes itself felt most forcefully on the east coast, although in some years the phenomenon is far more active than in others. </p>
<p>It might sound tempting to visit during the Chinese New Year celebrations, but while you&rsquo;re likely to experience some spectacular revelry, you should be aware that accommodation prices always sky-rocket and many businesses and service providers shut down for the period.   </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Light- to mediumweights, with rainwear advised. It&rsquo;s a good idea not to wear overly skimpy clothing when visiting some of the stricter Buddhist temples, although light trousers and a t-shirt will always be considered perfectly acceptable for both sexes. It&rsquo;s a wise idea to pack swimwear for the hot springs, although some single-sex bathing areas require no costume to be worn. Bring a pair of sturdy shoes too &ndash; even if you&rsquo;re not intending to go trekking, there are some enjoyable short walks to be had at natural attractions like Taroko Gorge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mandarin Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.mandarin-airlines.com">www.mandarin-airlines.com</a>), TransAsia Airways (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.tna.com.tw">www.tna.com.tw</a>) and Uni Air (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.uniair.com.tw">www.uniair.com.tw</a>) are among the domestic airlines that run services to local destinations from Songshan Airport, Taipei.</p><p>The increase in high-speed rail services has meant there are fewer domestic flights on offer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Various services are available between Taiwan and its islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>THSR (<a href="http://www.thsrc.com.tw" target="_blank">www.thsrc.com.tw</a>) runs high-speed rail services down the west coast of Taiwan from Taipei to Zuoying. Services are also provided to destinations all over the island by the Taiwan Railways Administration (tel: +886 2 2381 5226;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.railway.gov.tw" target="_blank">www.railway.gov.tw</a>).</p>
<p>The main tourist routes are Taipei-Taichung-Chiayi-Tainan-Kaohsiung (a top-class service), Taipei-Taichung-Sun Moon Lake (with the last leg of the journey by bus), Chiayi-Alishan (with spectacular mountain scenery) and Taipei-New Hualian-Taitung (scenic coastal route). Air-conditioned electric trains run at least hourly from Taipei to Kaohsiung; some trains have restaurant cars. Children under three travel free; children aged three to 13 pay half fare. You can buy train tickets at many major hotels in Taipei, as well as at the main railway station.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>THSR Pass:</strong> valid for unlimited travel on THSR trains for&nbsp;three consecutive days or three days within a week.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Joint Pass:</strong> valid for five days of unlimited travel on THSR and Taiway Railways trains (including up to two days on THSR trains).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An adequate road system joins major cities. A highway links Taipei and Kaohsiung. Some main streets have English signs. Congestion can be a problem, and mudslides may block mountain roads. Traffic accidents account for the highest number of deaths to international visitors, many involving scooters.</p>r<p>Bus and coach services between main centres are regular and cost-effective, often cheaper than trains. Leading companies include Free Go Bus (<a href="http://www.freego.com.tw" target="_blank">www.freego.com.tw</a>), Kuo-Kuang (<a href="http://www.kingbus.com.tw" target="_blank">www.kingbus.com.tw</a>) and Ho-Hsin Bus (<a href="http://www.ebus.com.tw" target="_blank">www.ebus.com.tw</a>). The Taiwan Tour Bus programme (<a href="http://www.taiwantourbus.com.tw" target="_blank">www.taiwantourbus.com.tw</a>) offers sightseeing tours. The Taiwan Tourist Shuttle (<a href="http://www.taiwantrip.com.tw" target="_blank">www.taiwantrip.com.tw</a>) is a similar initiative.</p><p>These are plentiful and inexpensive (metered). A 20% surcharge is charged between 2300-0600. An extra charge is made for a taxi ordered over the phone and for luggage put in the trunk. The destination may have to be written in Chinese for the driver to understand it. It is not customary to tip taxi drivers.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required.</p><p>Seat belts must be worn by the driver and the front seat passenger.</p><p>Third-party insurance is generally included on all insurance policies. Numbers to be aware of are the Police (110) and Fire Services (119). Car hire companies often provide roadside service island-wide, as well as replacement vehicles within 24 hours.</p><p>This is available in major towns. Most hire fees do not include insurance. The tourist board advises travellers to hire a car with a driver. Different rental companies have different minimum-age requirements, generally ranging from 20 to 25.</p><p>Designated cycle paths have appeared all over the country, usually of a good quality, although in many cases they&rsquo;ve been designed with &lsquo;pleasure rides&rsquo; in mind rather than as a means of getting from A to B. Longer-distance touring is perfectly possible though, with the quieter East Coast particularly popular.</p><p>Seat belts must be worn by the driver and the front seat passenger.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Private and public bus companies provide extensive services in Taipei. The MRT Mass Rapid Transit System (<a href="http://www.metro.taipei" target="_blank">www.metro.taipei</a>), Taipei's metro system, covers the major areas of the city. Trains are frequent and run all day until midnight. Metered taxis are available in Taipei; tipping is not expected, but it is starting to come into practice.</p>
<p>For those confident on two wheels, meanwhile, scooters are convenient ways to explore smaller cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Taiwan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">taitung</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">10.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Taiwan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">tainan</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.10</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Taiwan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">makung</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Taiwan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">kaohsiung</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.40</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is China Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.china-airlines.com">www.china-airlines.com</a>). The other major Taiwanese carrier offering international flights to Taiwan is EVA Air (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.evaair.com">www.evaair.com</a>). Other airlines servicing Taiwan include&nbsp;Emirates (<a href="http://www.emirates.com" target="_blank">www.emirates.com</a>), KLM (<a href="http://www.klm.com" target="_blank">www.klm.com</a>) and Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>).</p>
<p>Expect prices to rise in the run-up to peak holiday times, particularly Chinese New Year. Fares can often be cheaper in the summer months.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/taiwan/taiwan-taoyuan-international-airport">Taiwan Taoyuan International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 14 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 16 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/taiwan/taiwan-taoyuan-international-airportn">Taiwan Taoyuan International Airport</a> (TPE) (<a href="http://www.taoyuan-airport.com/english" target="_blank">www.taoyuan-airport.com/english</a>); Kaohsiung International Airport (KHH) (<a href="http://www.kia.gov.tw" target="_blank">www.kia.gov.tw</a>).</p>]]><b>Taiwan Taoyuan International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.taoyuan-airport.com/english<p>Taiwan Taoyuan International Airport is situated 40km (25 miles) west of Taipei, in Taoyuan County.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+886 3 273 3728</p>]]><b>Kaohsiung International Airport </b><![CDATA[<p>The airport  is 9km (4 miles) from the town centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Keelung (<a href="http://kl.twport.com.tw" target="_blank">kl.twport.com.tw</a>), Taichung (<a href="http://tc.twport.com.tw" target="_blank">tc.twport.com.tw</a>) and Kaohsiung (<a href="http://kh.twport.com.tw" target="_blank">kh.twport.com.tw</a>) are the three key ports. There are three ways of arriving from mainland <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> &ndash; a two-stage journey from Fuzhou in China to Taiwan&rsquo;s Matsu Islands, then from there to Keelung; a direct ferry service from Xiamen to Keelung; or a fast ferry from the Chinese island of Pingtan to Taichung.</p><p>The long-running service from Taiwan to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan">Japan</a> run by Arimura Sangyo Lines has been discontinued. The ferry from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/macau">Macau</a> to Taiwan has also been suspended indefinitely.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There is an extensive telephone system across the island, including a large number of public card phones which can be used for overseas calls. Prepaid cards can be bought from 7-Eleven and other convenience stores.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone companies, meaning the vast majority of phones will be compatible with local networks once you arrive.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet caf&eacute;s aren&rsquo;t quite as simple to find as you might expect from such a tech-savvy destination. They&rsquo;re certainly out there, however, found everywhere from gaming centres to local libraries, and connections are usually good. Most hotels have Wi-Fi internet access, which is often free but may come with a surcharge.</p>
<p>The Taiwan tourist office offers free internet access for tourists from abroad. Tourists can register here: <a href="http://itaiwan.taiwan.net.tw" target="_blank">http://itaiwan.taiwan.net.tw</a></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are good levels of freedom of press in Taiwan. Daily Chinese-language papers include the <em>United Daily News</em>, the <em>Central Daily News </em>(online only), <em>China Times&nbsp;</em>and <em>Liberty Times</em>. English-language dailies include <em>The China Post</em>, <em>Taipei Times</em> and <em>Taiwan News</em>. On TV, <em>Public Television Service</em> <em>(PTS)</em> is the only non-profit public broadcaster. Commercial networks include <em>China Television Company</em> <em>(CTV)</em>, <em>Chinese Television System</em> <em>(CTS)</em>, <em>Taiwan Television Enterprise</em> <em>(TTV)</em> and <em>Formosa Television</em> <em>(FTV)</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The domestic postal service is quick and dependable. Airmail to Western Europe takes up to 10 days.</p><p>Varied &ndash; usually 8.00-17.00 Monday to Friday and 8.30-12.00 on Saturdays. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the artefacts at the National Palace Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A few hours in Taipei's National Palace Museum should be essential for anyone with even a remote interest in the region's cultural heritage. It showcases the world's largest and most exquisite collection of Chinese artefacts, the majority of which came over with Chiang Kai-Shek's supporters, much to the continued chagrin of Beijing. Truly unmissable.</p>]]><p><b>Bring out the binoculars for a spot of birdwatching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Taiwan is home to about 460 different species of birds, including rare endemic species such as the brilliantly vibrant Formosan blue magpie, the orange punk-haired flamecrest and the Mikado and Swinhoe's Pheasants. Other wildlife includes the famous fanged Formosan rock-monkey, and about 400 species of butterflies.</p>]]><p><b>Dive the corals of Ludao (Green Island)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dive or snorkel in the waters around Ludao (Green Island), off the southeast coast: there are splendid forests of corals to admire, and, what's more, visibility is good all-year-round. The island is accessible by boat from Taitung and is famous for the political prisoners that were exiled here in the 20th century.</p>]]><p><b>Drive the outstanding northeast coastal road</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a memorable drive along the northeast coastal road, which gives spectacular panoramas of the foothills of the Central Mountain Range and the blue expanse of the East China Sea and Pacific Ocean. The route passes through a large number of small villages, many of them little changed since the advent of high technology.</p>]]><p><b>Feast on the delectable sites at Taroko Gorge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take time to marvel at the scale of Taroko Gorge, Taiwan's most iconic natural attraction and a worthy inclusion on any itinerary. The ravine's towering cliffs are shot through with extensive marble deposits, contributing to the overall beauty of one of the Far East's most striking sights.</p>]]><p><b>Hike Taiwain's jewel, Yushan (Jade Mountain)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Many of Taiwan's national parks offer top-notch hiking, but dramatic Yushan is the pick of the bunch. This is largely thanks to Mount Yushan (Jade Mountain) itself; at 3,952m (12,966ft) it is the highest peak in North East Asia. It's an important symbol of Taiwan's identity and a favourite target for mountain climbers.</p>]]><p><b>Join in the Chinese New Year celebrations</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Join in the celebrations for one of many festivals taking place in the capital, and gain an insight into the island's culture. The Dragon Boat Festival and the Mid-Autumn Moon Festival are both colourful affairs but it is the lanterns and fireworks of the Chinese New Year that really bring the streets to life.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the massive, Chung Tai Chan Monastery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The world's tallest Buddhist temple, this epic feat of architecture took more than 10 years to construct and was designed by C.Y. Lee, the man behind Taipei 101. It's best accessed from the town of Puli in central Taiwan, and is notable among other things for its impressive blend of modernist techniques and old-world traditions.</p>]]><p><b>Raft down the East Rift Valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover the East Rift Valley, Taiwan's largest fault line. Known locally as "the land of milk and honey", the rich sediment makes it a geologist's paradise. With stunning scenery featuring clear streams, lakes and verdant valleys, the area is popular for adventurers. Raft down the Xiuguluan River for unforgettable views.</p>]]><p><b>Relax in a Taian hot spring</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Taiwan's volcanic past has left abundant reserves of geothermal energy all over the island, and there are well over 100 hot mineral springs scattered around the country. They're hugely popular with both locals and tourists, and offer an indulgent way of soothing tired muscles. Arguably the best are in Taian in the north of the island.</p>]]><p><b>Relax with a recreational visit to Kenting National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Chill out for a day or two in Kenting National Park, a much-visited forest recreation area boasting glorious beaches, coral lakes and a bird sanctuary, as well as facilities for watersports and golf, all set amidst tropical coastal forest. The park occupies the extreme southern tip of Taiwan.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the wind at the Penghu archipelago</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Admire the astonishing basalt rock formations of the Penghu archipelago, a group of islands in the middle of the Taiwan Straits. The columns were formed when lava erupting from deep into the earth cooled and contracted, and were then carved by wave and wind erosion. The breeze almost makes Penghu a popular windsurfing destination.</p>]]><p><b>Soar above Luye Plateau</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Taiwan's precipitous terrain and steady winds offer perfect opportunities for hang-gliding and paragliding. Green Bay on the North Shore and the Luye Plateau in Taitung County in the southeast offer inspiring scenery for gliders to soar over. Tandem glides are ideal for all skill levels.</p>]]><p><b>Spot a pickled python at Snake Alley (Taipei)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gawp at live snakes, pickled pythons and other oddities at Taipei's Huahsi Night Market. Known locally as Snake Alley, this is more than just a gimmick for tourists – the various products, including snake testicles and turtle penises, are believed to promote virility and are available to buy.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the vistas atop Taipei 101</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Admire the view from the top of Taipei 101, which until 2010 was the world's tallest building. You can take a lift (the fastest of its kind in the world) up to The Observatory on the top floor for the ultimate city vista. It's more than twice the size of the next tallest building in Taipei.</p>]]><p><b>Tour the temples of Tainan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Tainan, the oldest city on the island and the former capital. It's known as the "City of 100 Temples", but there are in fact 220, including some of the best examples of Confucian temple architecture in Taiwan. Expect ancient monuments, lip-smacking food and a packed calendar of celebrations including the Yenshui Firework Festival.</p>]]><p><b>Uncover the Yami tribe of Lanyu (Orchid Island)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Learn about the aboriginal Yami, one of the world's last surviving hunter-gatherer tribes, on their island, Lanyu (Orchid Island). Off the southeast coast, the volcanic island is also home to some of the finest coral reef in the region and offers a peaceful taste of the tropics, even in peak season.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the imposing Chiang Kai-Shek Memorial Hall</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Climb one of the two staircases to the Chiang Kai-Shek Memorial Hall, an imposing tomb and shrine to Taipei's most famous leader.  A national landmark, the monument also houses Taipei's main venues for the performing arts, the National Theatre and National Opera House, in its large grounds.</p>]]><p><b>Walk behind the ramparts at Kinmen</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An archipelago of islands located just 2km (1.2 miles) off the coast of mainland China (but still under Taiwanese rule), Kinmen represents one of the most fascinating – and little-known – options of a trip to Taiwan. As a pivotal strategic base during the unrest of the 20th century, it remains heavily fortified.</p>]]><p><b>Wander through the traditional town of Lugang (Lukang)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A character-rich old port town in central Taiwan, Lugang is home to a wealth of traditional buildings and great places to pick up authentic local crafts.  The historic centre is an enjoyable spot through which to wander but make sure not to miss three of the country's most atmospheric temples, Longshan, Matsu and Glass Matsu.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$474 billion (2012).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Electronics, metals, plastic and rubber products, machinery and chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, electronics, crude petroleum, minerals and precision instruments.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China (PR), the European Union, the USA, Hong Kong (SAR) and Japan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Taiwan was one of the first 'tiger economies' of the Pacific basin, enjoying phenomenal growth from the 1950s onwards.</p>
<p>Its success was built on a policy of rapid industrialisation coupled with low overheads and labour costs &ndash; as opposed to relying on raw materials, of which there is a dearth. Massive foreign currency reserves accumulated over the years have since helped Taiwan to minimise the effects of turbulence in the world economy.</p>
<p>After a brief recession in 2000/01, the economy is growing at a healthy rate. The performance of the Taiwanese economy is significantly affected by external political and economic conditions, especially in China (PR). In January 2002, Taiwan was admitted to the World Trade Organisation. It is also a member of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum and the Asian Development Bank. The International Monetary Fund has listed it as the world&rsquo;s 15th largest economy and Asia's 5th largest.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Taiwan is certainly underpinned by Chinese traditions, but it has also been shaped by Western values and customs. A heavy Japanese influence is also evident. International business visitors, therefore, will generally find themselves easily accommodated &ndash; this is a functional society used to dealing with Westerners. A lightweight suit is suitable business wear, and shaking hands is the usual form of greeting. Business cards (ideally printed in both Chinese and English) should be both given and received with two hands. Take a moment to study any business card you receive &ndash; it&rsquo;s a sign of respect.</p>
<p>When addressing people, the family or surname comes first. Punctuality is important and appointments should, where possible, be made in advance. The Taiwanese have an instilled work ethic and are often highly educated, although even if business is being conducted in English, a translator may be necessary. As in all Asian countries, not &ldquo;losing face&rdquo; is important. It might not be wise to talk about Chinese politics or international recognition of Taiwan, unless someone else brings the subject up.</p><p>Office hours are Monday to Friday 0900-1700 and Saturday 0900-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Ministry of Economic Affairs (ROC)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 2321 2200
					Website:http://isc01.moea.gov.tw
					Address: ,15 Fu Chou Street,Taipei 100,]]><b>Taiwan Convention Association (TCA)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 2725 5200.
					Website:http://www.ticc.com.tw
					Address: ,1 Hsin-Yi Road,Taipei 110,]]><b>Taiwan External Trade Development Council (TAITRA)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 2725 5200
					Website:http://www.taiwantrade.com/tw
					Address: Section 1,333 Keelung Road,Taipei 110,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Much of Taiwan&rsquo;s culinary heritage comes directly from China so is carefully prepared, easy on the eye and frequently delicious. Culinary styles come from all over China including Canton, Hunan, Mongolia, Peking, Shanghai and Szechuan, as well as Taiwan itself. Fujian, the mainland Chinese province closest to Taiwan, has had the broadest effect on the overall food culture.</p>
<p>Taiwanese staples include spring rolls with peanut satay, sweet-and-sour spare ribs, bean curd in red sauce, oyster omelette, steamed pork dumplings and numerous excellent seafood dishes.</p>
<p>Tea is a major component of Taiwanese culture, with the island producing many acclaimed varieties &ndash; oolong being the most famous. Teahouses are found in great numbers, ranging from the traditional to the contemporary.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Xiaochi:</strong> Little eats, in effect are a Taiwanese version of tapas.</p>
<p><strong>Lurou fan: </strong>Braised pork with rice.</p>
<p><strong>Ningpo:</strong> Fried eel.</p>
<p><strong>Beef noodle soup: </strong>Local chefs compete to produce the best.</p>
<p><strong>Milkfish: </strong>Bony but very popular, served pan-fried, braised or as fish ball soup.</p>
<p><strong>Bun: </strong>Spongy white bread filled with meat then pan-fried.</p>
<p><strong>Pepper cakes: </strong>Pastry pockets filled with peppered pork baked on the wall of a clay oven.</p>
<p><strong>Gun boa: </strong> Steamed bun sandwiches filled with pork, pickled cabbage and powdered peanuts.</p>
<p><strong>Tian bu la: </strong>Fish paste moulded then deep-fried and boiled in broth.</p>
<p><strong>Bu wan: </strong>Large dumpling filled with pork and vegetables.</p>
<p><strong>Iron egg: </strong>Chewy little eggs braised in soy sauce.</p>
<p><strong>Pineapple cake: </strong>Mini pies filled with candied pineapple.</p>
<p><strong>Bubble tea:</strong> A cooled tea-based drink with tapioca pearls drunk through a straw.</p>
<p><strong>Gaoliang jiu:</strong> Local spirit distilled from sorghum.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tipping is not an established custom, although it is on the increase. Taipei hotels and restaurants add 10% service charge and extra tipping is not expected.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Taiwan has an abundance of nightlife, and Taipei in particular is lively at night. Western-style entertainment can be found in various international hotels, and in the many discos, clubs, restaurants and cinemas around the city. Popular amongst local people are KTVs, a type of sing-along club modelled on Japanese karaoke bars; and beer houses, which sell draught beer and snacks. The northern district of Tienmu contains a street of open-air beer houses.</p>
<p>Kaohsiung and Taichung are also renowned for their after-dark entertainment. In both these cities, as in Taipei, you&rsquo;ll find a decent spectrum of late-night venues, from swish hotel lounges to unfussy beer joints. In smaller cities, however, drinking holes tend to be thinner on the ground, so it&rsquo;s advisable to seek prior information rather than just wandering the streets in the expectation of chancing on a bar.   </p>
<p>As an aside, it&rsquo;s worth mentioning that all recreational drugs (including marijuana) are illegal, so dabbling is strongly unadvised. There have even been reports of police turning up at venues and subjecting clubbers to on-the-spot urine tests.</p>
<p>The visitor can also sample both traditional and modern tea houses, open all day and in the evening. In the tea-growing countryside around Mucha, it is possible to visit all-night tea houses and sip locally produced teas such as 'iron Buddha' <em>tiehkuanyin</em> tea. High-quality meals and snacks are also provided. These tea houses are popular with local families, particularly on special occasions.</p>
<p>Back in Taipei, there are night markets selling a variety of items, both modern and traditional. These are bustling with browsers and bargain hunters, whose persistence can be spectacularly rewarded. It is advisable to take a pen and paper to assist in the bargaining process, as most vendors speak only Chinese. Taipei's largest night market is probably the aforementioned Shilin, famous for its good-value clothing and food. Many shops are open at night.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>One of the best ways to shop is to visit the island&rsquo;s famous night markets, which you&rsquo;ll find located everywhere from Taipei to Taitung. A lively atmosphere of steaming food carts, thumping music and strolling families make them hugely enjoyable places to spend time. What&rsquo;s more, if you keep your eyes peeled, you&rsquo;ll be able to hunt down some serious bargains. Purchases include: Formosan sea-grass mats, hats, handbags and slippers, bamboo items, Chinese musical instruments, various dolls in costume, handpainted palace lanterns made from silk, lacquerware, ceramics, teak furniture, coral, veinstone and jade items, <em>ramie</em> fibre rugs, brassware, handmade shoes, fabrics and chopsticks (decorated, personalised sticks of wood or marble).</p><p>Mon-Sat 1000-2200. Some convenience stores are open 24 hours per day.</p><p>Night markets often stay open later than regular shops, and the Shilin Night Market in Taipei stays packed well into the evening on Sundays. It&rsquo;s worthwhile setting aside at least a couple of hours for a visit - find everything from dumpling stalls and reflexology parlours to knock-off watches and designer clothes, and it&rsquo;s normally possible to pick up decent souvenirs at a reasonable price.   </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You&rsquo;ll find a wide scope of different accommodation options in Taiwan, with standard mid-price hotels at one end of the market and a raft of big-name international chains and chic design properties at the top end. Taipei in particular has a good number of all-out luxury properties. For full details, contact the Taiwan Visitors Bureau. Prices can fluctuate according to peak seasons, weekends and public holidays, with the period around Chinese New Year the most expensive time.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Since 2007, hotels have been rated on a scale of 1 to 5 stars. However, the old system of 1 to 5 'Plum Blossoms' is still used by many establishments.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The homestay concept has taken off in a big way in Taiwan, with all manner of family-run establishments opening their doors to visitors. While some are downright fantastic, offering enough charm and hospitality to make them a trip highlight in their own right, others are more basic. Breakfast is often provided, although it&rsquo;s not often eaten with the family. Costs tend to be comparable to mid-range hotels, although a homestay is far more likely to give you an insight into Taiwanese life.    </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You&rsquo;ll find a wide scope of different accommodation options in Taiwan, with standard mid-price hotels at one end of the market and a raft of big-name international chains and chic design properties at the top end. Taipei in particular has a good number of all-out luxury properties. For full details, contact the Taiwan Visitors Bureau. Prices can fluctuate according to peak seasons, weekends and public holidays, with the period around Chinese New Year the most expensive time.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Since 2007, hotels have been rated on a scale of 1 to 5 stars. However, the old system of 1 to 5 'Plum Blossoms' is still used by many establishments.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You&rsquo;ll find a wide scope of different accommodation options in Taiwan, with standard mid-price hotels at one end of the market and a raft of big-name international chains and chic design properties at the top end. Taipei in particular has a good number of all-out luxury properties. For full details, contact the Taiwan Visitors Bureau. Prices can fluctuate according to peak seasons, weekends and public holidays, with the period around Chinese New Year the most expensive time.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Since 2007, hotels have been rated on a scale of 1 to 5 stars. However, the old system of 1 to 5 'Plum Blossoms' is still used by many establishments.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Healthcare facilities are good and doctors are well-trained, although English isn&amp;rsquo;t always widely spoken, so it may be wise to enrol the services of someone who can translate for you. Imported medicines are expensive, but locally produced and manufactured medicines are plentiful. Dental treatment is adequate too, should emergency treatment be necessary on your travels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health insurance is highly recommended &amp;ndash; you&amp;rsquo;ll be expected to pay upfront for treatment at hospitals and public health clinics then claim back on your insurance afterwards. The good news is that medical costs are reasonable. Private clinics are more costly, particularly in Taipei. In all cases, make sure you hang on to receipts for medicine and treatment to help with any claim, and ideally get hold of a signed medical form detailing your diagnosis &amp;ndash; in English if at all possible, although this isn&amp;rsquo;t always essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find well stocked pharmacies in all Taiwanese towns, many of them selling a similar range of products to Western chemists. Staff are generally very helpful towards visitors &amp;ndash; if there&amp;rsquo;s a language barrier, don&amp;rsquo;t be shy about using sign language to ask for a particular product, even if it seems embarrassing!  &lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Bottled water is widely available and usually well priced &amp;ndash; a great number of hotels provide water for guests as a matter of course. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Taiwan being the developed nation that it is, the vast majority of visitors will find that by taking sensible precautions, health concerns remain comfortingly low. As with most Asian destinations, things like dehydration and sunstroke are the cause of the most common ailments, so be sure to drink plenty of bottled water and take sun protection seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where more serious illnesses are concerned, vaccination is sometimes required for Japanese B encephalitis and there have been sporadic dengue fever outbreaks in recent years, most commonly in the south. Taiwan is not malarial. Likewise, there have been no cases of SARS since the 2003 outbreak, although the practice of locals wearing facemasks when suffering from a cold or virus is still commonplace. Avian influenza (bird flu) is still a slight issue, although its extremely low levels mean it is highly unlikely to affect travellers. The risk only really applies to those who spend significant time around poultry farms or bird markets. The H1N1 virus, otherwise known as swine flu, reached Taiwan in 2009, although its impact was comparatively low when compared with the worst affected Western nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If walking in secluded rural areas, keep an eye out for poisonous snakes &amp;ndash; attacks are rare but can be serious.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Founding Day of the Republic of China :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Peace Memorial Day :
							28 February </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>National Day :
							10 October </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported by persons over 20 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 25 cigars or 454g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of alcoholic beverages.</p>
<p>﻿&bull; Other&nbsp;<a id="fck_paste_padding">﻿personal goods owned and used by passenger up to the value of NT$10,000 per piece.</a></p>
<p>&bull; Other goods for personal use up to the total value of NT$20,000.<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fruit, live animals (other than pets with permits), plants and their products, narcotics, arms and ammunition, endangered species (unless you have a permit), and articles infringing upon the rights of patents, trademarks and copyrights.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Taiwan Dollar (TWD; symbol NT$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of NT$TWD2,000, 1,000, 500, 200 and 100. Coins are in denominations of NT$50, 20, 10, 5 and 1.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All travellers are required to make a currency declaration in writing together with the baggage declaration. Unused currency can be reconverted on departure, on production of exchange receipts. Various bureaux de change are on hand to convert international currency into New Taiwan Dollars, although the rate of exchange offered by ATMs is generally more attractive. If you do need to change notes, you&rsquo;ll generally have no problem if you&rsquo;re holding <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars, British pounds, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a> dollars or Japanese yen. As a rule, Taiwan is pricier day-to-day than the likes of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cambodia">Cambodia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/thailand">Thailand</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vietnam">Vietnam</a>, but compares favourably to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan">Japan</a> and Hong Kong.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, MasterCard, Visa and Diners Club are accepted in most hotels, restaurants and shops.</p><p>ATMs are found in all major towns, cities and airports and &ndash; with a few exceptions that only handle domestic accounts &ndash; are mostly compatible with international debit and credit cards. A lot of 7Eleven stores have cashpoints inside, which tend to be a safe bet for withdrawing with an international card. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cashed in most hotels, restaurants and shops. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1530.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Taiwan, a passport valid for at least six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above, except for Japan (three months) and the USA (passport only needs to be valid for the duration of the stay). Always double-check with your embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As long as children have valid passports, there are no special requirements.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A visa is not required by travellers continuing their journey by the same or connecting aircraft on the same day, provided holding confirmed onward tickets and the necessary travel documentation and provided not departing from the transit lounge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: usually valid for three months to one year for stays of 14, 30, 60 or 90 days; multiple-entry (business purposes only): usually six months from the date of issue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors who do require a visa in advance should apply to their nearest Taipei Representative Office.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign nationals who intend to stay for longer than six months can apply for resident visas, whether staying for family purposes, employment purposes, study, official work, missionary work, an international exchange programme or other approved reasons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa processing usually takes two working days. A next-day service is available for an additional fee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas may be denied to those applicants who appear unable to cover their expenses for the duration of their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa holders with 'no extension' marked on their visa may not apply for an extension of stay. If this has not been marked on the visa, it's possible to apply for an extension at a local immigration office in Taiwan.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Visa-exempt visitors cannot extend their stay. The exception is British and Canadian visitors, who may extend their stay by an additional 90 days to a maximum of 180 days; you must apply for your extension 30 days before your initial 90-day stay expires.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pets must have a 15-digit ISO 11784 compliant pet microchip. They should also have been vaccinated against rabies when at the age of at least 90 days. The period between the day of vaccination and the day of shipment should be no less than 30 days and no more than one year. You should apply for an import permit well in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[23.685972]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[120.897041]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>36,188 sq km (13,972 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>23,395,600 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>647 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Taipei.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Though Taiwanese territory includes dozens of small islands in the Taiwan Strait and the Pacific, the main island known as Taiwan covers the vast majority of the land area under Taiwanese administration. Almost two-thirds of Taiwan is covered by mountains, with 258 peaks over 3,000m (9,850ft), most of them heavily forested. The highest of these, Yushan (Jade Mountain), is northeast Asia's tallest mountain at 3,952m (13,042ft). This mountainous terrain is the result of the island&rsquo;s location &ndash; it sits on the fault line of two tectonic plates, and was formed after a dramatic geological upheaval between four and five million years ago. It also sits on the Tropic of Cancer, putting it on the same line of latitude as Hawaii in the North Pacific.</p>
<p>But while mountains dominate Taiwan's centre and rugged east coast, the island's western third is mostly alluvial plain and is host to most of the population. The two Pacific islands, Lyudao (Green Island) and Lanyu (Orchid Island), are popular holiday destinations, while the Taiwan Strait archipelagos of Penghu and Matzu hold historic and cultural appeal. And just a few kilometres off mainland China's Fujian coast, the tiny islands of Kinmen and Lieyu remain under Taiwanese control.</p>
<p>The combination of climate, terrain and topography also makes the main island of Taiwan ripe for endemic flora and fauna, particularly in the diverse mountain forests. The Taiwan fir tree and Formosan black bear are two key examples. There&rsquo;s also a rich bird life to enjoy, with various specialist tours available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>'Folk religion' - a blend of ancient animist beliefs with the traditions of Taoism, Buddhism and Confucianism - forms the core beliefs of most Taiwanese. Purer forms of Buddhism are also on the rise, along with Christianity. Due to the work of Western missionaries in centuries gone by, many aboriginal Taiwanese are Christians.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Despite Taiwan's complex ethnic and cultural mix, its way of life is predominantly Chinese, steeped in tradition and marked by superstition. As such, ancient customs and festivals are celebrated with fervour, and traditional holidays are closely observed. Taiwanese people are on the whole extremely friendly, and standards of hospitality are high. Entertainment is more commonly offered in restaurants than in private homes, and visitors are not usually expected to entertain. Handshaking is common, and casual wear is widely acceptable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110 volts AC, 60Hz. American-style plugs with two flat pins (and sometimes a third grounding pin) are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Premier Lai Ching-te since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Tsai Ing-wen since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Indigenous tribes have inhabited the region for some 4,000 years, with Chinese settlements springing up in the 16th century. It subsequently attracted European colonists, with the Dutch and Spanish both putting down roots. In 1684, Taiwan was taken over by the deposed Ming Dynasty, before becoming completely controlled by the Qing Dynasty and made a province in its own right.</p>
<p>In the 1890s, Chinese defeat in the first Sino-Japanese War (1894-1895) brought the first occupation of Chinese territory by the Japanese and Taiwan was ceded to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan">Japan</a>, in perpetuity, in the Treaty of Shimonoseki. Although it was fiercely resented and resisted by the population, Taiwan remained under Japanese rule from 1895 until the end of WWII.</p>
<p>The Chinese Civil War (1927-1950), which had already been in progress for some years, came to a head in 1948 as Mao's Communists defeated Chiang Kai-Shek and his nationalist forces. The nationalist leadership, along with thousands of supporters, fled to Taiwan where their political vehicle, the Kuo Min-Tang (KMT) rapidly came to dominate.</p>
<p>Having ensured its own survival, the KMT set about developing Taiwan&rsquo;s economy with spectacular success, helping the small island nation become one of the fast developing 'tiger economies' of the Pacific Rim. Politically, Taiwan relied for a long time upon the support of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> until the early 1970s, when a rapprochement between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/washington-state">Washington</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/beijing">Beijing</a> took place, the USA effectively shifting its allegiance from Taiwan to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a>.</p>
<p>The Chinese still consider Taiwan to be part of their national territory and continue to harbour the long-term objective of reunifying Taiwan with the mainland. International recognition of Taiwan by the United Nations is therefore unacceptable to Beijing, but for all their political disagreements, extensive trade, travel and communications links have built up between Taiwan and China since the early 1970s.</p>
<p>Taiwan continues to call itself the Republic of China, a name the People&rsquo;s Republic of China finds more acceptable than official recognition of an independent Taiwan.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Although official People&rsquo;s Republic of China policy is to reunify China, in recent years it has pursued a form of unification through Deng Xiaoping&rsquo;s principle of &lsquo;One Country, Two Systems&rsquo;.<br />
&bull;	Taiwan uses two official calendars &ndash; the Gregorian and the Minguo, which began in 1911 with the founding of the Republic of China.<br />
&bull;	Taiwan competes as Chinese Taipei at the Olympic Games and the FIFA World Cup.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office (TECRO) in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 895 1800.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.taiwanembassy.org/uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 895 1800.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Washington<br/>4201 Wisconsin Avenue NW<br/>DC 20016<br/>20016<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Taipei Representative Office in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7881 2650 or 2654 (visa section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.taiwanembassy.org/uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7881 2650 or 2654 (visa section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1230 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>50 Grosvenor Gardens<br/>London<br/>SW1W 0EB<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Trade & Cultural Office]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+886 2 8758 2088.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukintaiwan.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+886 2 8758 2088.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>Xin Yi District<br/>26th Floor, President International Tower, Number 9-11 Song Gao Road<br/>Taipei 11073<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sitting pretty as one of Asia&rsquo;s best-kept travel secrets, the spicy, scenic island of Taiwan makes a habit of smashing visitor preconceptions.</p>
<p>Outsiders tend to see this country as notable only for its technological prowess &ndash; an image reinforced by the global prominence of &lsquo;Made in Taiwan&rsquo; stickers &ndash; but in reality this is a destination that serves up awe-inspiring panoramas, a rainbow of different cultures and a startlingly rich history.</p>
<p>Alongside night markets, cycle trails and hot springs, there are gleaming skyscrapers, hulking mountains and sparkling lakes. When you factor in the manageable size of the island, which is less than half the size of Scotland, the appeal becomes even more significant.</p>
<p>Taiwan is one of the few places on Earth where ancient religious and cultural practices still thrive in an overwhelmingly modernist landscape. This juxtaposition is expressed most clearly in Taipei, where futuristic marvels like Taipei 101 &ndash; one of the tallest buildings in the world &ndash; share the city with incense-fogged temples and indigenous communities.</p>
<p>This mix of different influences is wonderfully showcased by the island&rsquo;s cuisine &ndash; a lip-smacking blend of Chinese, Japanese and aboriginal fare.</p>
<p>Like many aspects of life in Taiwan, its diverse cuisine makes sense when you look at the island&rsquo;s history. Following five decades of Japanese rule, in 1949 a liberated Taiwan became a refuge for the Chinese Nationalist Party and their supporters, who fled here during the Chinese Civil War. To this day, Taiwan remains a product of this period &ndash; a maverick sovereign state still viewed with uneasiness by Beijing.</p>
<p>History buff or not, there&rsquo;s much to enjoy in Taiwan. Away from the sleek towers of the cities, it&rsquo;s the valleys, lakes and gorges of the countryside that tend to leave the greatest impression. The fact that comparatively few tourists make it here is more to do with a lack of awareness than a lack of things to do &ndash; hikers, cyclists, divers, surfers, pilgrims and gourmands will all find a little slice of heaven in this corner of Asia.</p><p>Sitting pretty as one of Asia&rsquo;s best-kept travel secrets, the spicy, scenic island of Taiwan makes a habit of smashing visitor preconceptions.&nbsp;Outsiders tend to see this country as notable only for its technological prowess &ndash; an image reinforced by the global prominence of &lsquo;Made in Taiwan&rsquo; stickers &ndash; but in reality this is a destination that serves up awe-inspiring panoramas, a rainbow of different cultures and a startlingly rich history.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Alongside night markets, cycle trails and hot springs, there are gleaming skyscrapers, hulking mountains and sparkling lakes. When you factor in the manageable size of the island, which is less than half the size of Scotland, its appeal becomes even more significant.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
