<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Tajikistan" ColCode="tjk" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="tj" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Tajikistan]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Dushanbe, temperatures vary between a minimum -13°C (8°F) in December/January to a maximum 33°C (91°F) in July/August. Humidity is generally low. In the mountains, it can reach -45°C (-49°F) when the wind chill factor is taken into consideration, and rise to 20°C (68°F) in summer. In the Pamir Mountains, the climate is semi-arid to polar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Warm clothing should be taken by anyone intending to visit the<br />mountains. Those intending to visit the southwest in summer should<br />bring light, loose clothing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Somon Air (<a href="http://www.somonair.com" target="_blank">www.somonair.com</a>) operates domestic flights between Dushanbe and Khujand.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tajikistan&rsquo;s railroad network totals just 680km (420 miles) and train travel can be unreliable. There are services running between Dushanbe and Iski-Guzar, Denov and Kulob, as well as routes between other cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To really appreciate the scenic beauty of Tajikistan most travellers take to the roads, journeying through epic landscapes, while adjusting to the bone-riveting drive.</p>
<p>Most travel on the Pamir Highway, which offers one of the best road trips in the world. The direct route from Dushanbe via Khorog and Murghab to Osh is 1,260km (783 miles), but more adventurous motorists detour via the stunning Wakhan Corridor. Routes here are more like off-road tracks than roads and can be difficult to navigate without local knowledge or a driver.</p>
<p>The weather in Tajikistan varies dramatically by season and region, so study weather forecasts before you set off.</p>r<p>The quality of the roads in Tajikistan is very variable and can swiftly change from good to terrible. This makes driving at speed extremely hazardous and you can usually expect to hit deep potholes and bumps anywhere in the country.</p>
<p>The Pamir Highway was a phenomenal construction endeavour built in the 1930s but hasn&rsquo;t seen much maintenance since. Heavy snowfall, intense winter cold and Chinese lorries have all taken their toll and the route is more &lsquo;off-road&rsquo; in the high altitude and ravine sections.</p><p>Major cities have extensive trolleybuses and bus networks, but intercity services are virtually non existent.</p><p>Most Tajiks don&rsquo;t own a car so private taxis and shared taxis are ubiquitous in Dushanbe. Options are reduced in remote districts.</p><p>Foreign drivers require an International Driving Permit along with their original national driving licence. Drivers should also carry a vehicle registration document, car tax receipt and proof of international insurance documents from the country of the vehicle&rsquo;s origin.</p><p>There is a wide variety of regulations regarding the use and driving of vehicles in Tajikistan. These range from the mandatory use of seat belts and adherence to speed limits, to the more unusual rules including maintaining the cleanliness of the vehicle when in the city.</p><p>In the event of breakdown, flag down other vehicles. Tajiks are very friendly and are willing to help, particularly in the more remote regions. You can quickly find yourself overrun with helpers.</p><p>Traditional car hire is almost impossible to find in Tajikistan due to the lack of car insurance schemes and the potential for car damage due to the poor road quality. A few tour operators in Dushanbe do offer car rental.</p><p>Bike hire in Dushanbe and Khujand is relatively straightforward. Bike hire shops have now also appeared in a number of towns and it is even possible to hire bikes in Murghab.</p><p>There is a wide variety of regulations regarding the use and driving of vehicles in Tajikistan. These range from the mandatory use of seat belts and adherence to speed limits, to the more unusual rules including maintaining the cleanliness of the vehicle when in the city.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Buses, trolleybuses and taxis are all great experiences. Tajikistan&rsquo;s cities are all fairly small and walking is the most pleasant way to get around them.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dushanbe International Airport is the main hub for air travel within Tajikistan. The main carriers into and out of Dushanbe are flydubai (<a href="http://www.flydubai.com" target="_blank">www.flydubai.com</a>), Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>) and Ural Airlines (<a href="http://www.uralairlines.com" target="_blank">www.uralairlines.com</a>)</p>
<p>The peak times for travelling to Tajikistan are during March, April, September and October, when temperatures are neither scorching hot or bitterly cold. To keep costs down, travel on the edge of these seasons and book in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London - 11 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a> - 20 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air travel into and out of Tajikistan remains disproportionately expensive compared to other Central Asian destinations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All taxes are included in ticket prices for international flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air travel into and out of Tajikistan remains disproportionately expensive compared to other Central Asian destinations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Dushanbe International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://airport.tj<p>The airport is 1 mile (2km) south of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no legitimate entry points into Tajikistan by water.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International connections include a train from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a> to Dushanbe, but this isn't recommended for foreign travellers, as you need visas for <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kazakhstan">Kazakhstan</a>, Uzbekistan and Tajikistan.</p>
<p>There's also a service from Saratov, Russia to Dushanbe via Samarkand, Uzbekistan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are three main road routes into Tajikistan. The highway between Mazar-i-Sharif in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/afghanistan">Afghanistan</a> and Dushanbe is pretty straightforward, although it is mainly used by locals rather than international travellers.</p>
<p>The route via Tursunzoda offers trouble-free travel from Samarkand in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/uzbekistan">Uzbekistan</a> to Dushanbe. The best option for travelling between Tajikistan and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kyrgyzstan">Kyrgyzstan</a> is on the &lsquo;Pamir Highway&rsquo; &ndash; a bone-jarring six-day (minimum) adventure through one of the most remote and awe-inspiring regions in the world.</p><p>The route between Tajikistan and Kyrgyzstan, via the Garm valley, remains closed to international travellers.</p>
<p>The Kulmar Pass into <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> remains closed to international travellers. The direct route between Penjikent and Samarkand also remains closed due to an ongoing dispute between Uzbekistan and Tajikistan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Services can be unreliable. International telephone calls can be made from telephone offices which are usually found attached to a post office (in Dushanbe, on Prospekt Rudaki). There are now also some new, private telephone offices in Dushanbe. International, operator-routed calls can also be ordered from some hotels such as the Hotel Tajikistan and the Hotel Independence. Direct-dial calls within the CIS are obtained by dialling 8 and waiting for another dial tone and then dialling the city code. Calls within the city limits are free of charge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is limited to urban areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are Internet caf&eacute;s in the main cities. Some will allow you to plug in your own computer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Press freedom is provided for in the constitution, but is not widely respected; independent journalists are said to come under huge pressure from the state. The Government controls the editorial policy of the state-owned media and state-operated radio and TV dominate broadcasting. There are over 30 local and regional private TV stations and more than 200 registered newspapers. Some are government-owned; others are connected to political parties and movements. There are no dailies. A few private radio stations exist. Dushanbe's first private station opened in September 2002, after waiting four years for a licence. <strong></strong></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mail to Western Europe and the USA can take between two weeks and two months. Stamped envelopes can be bought from post offices. Addresses should be laid out in the following order: country, postcode, city, street, house number and, lastly, the person's name. Postal services available include registered mail, restricted delivery, special delivery and Express mail (in Dushanbe only). Both surface and air mail are available for parcels.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1800, Sat: 0900-1700. Visitors can also use the post offices located within the major hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Amble around leafy Dushanbe</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There is a genteel ambiance along the boulevards of Dushanbe that is more akin to a French town than a Soviet era city. Yes, ugly concrete tenements can be found in the suburbs, but the city centre is home to a pretty collection of neo-classical buildings and leafy parks, which offer vistas of snow-capped mountains.</p>]]><p><b>Call in at the National Museum of Antiques</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Although not the prettiest of buildings, the Museum of National Antiquities (<a href="http://www.afc.ryukoku.ac.jp/tj/tajikistanEnglish/index.html" target="_blank">www.afcryukoku.ac.jp</a>) has an excellent collection of archaeology exhibits. However, the highlight of any visit is the huge statue of a sleeping Buddha, which was excavated in 1966 and then relocated to the museum. Also on offer are several artefacts of Sogdian and Persian origin.</p>]]><p><b>Check out ancient cave art</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located some 40km (25 miles) south of Murghab is the most important archaeological site in Tajikistan, Shakhty Cave. Its walls are adorned with decorative cave paintings dating back to 6500BC, depicting life in the Neolithic period. To find the cave, contact the Murghab Ecotourism Association, 102 Osh Street, Murghab (<a href="http://www.meta.tj" target="_blank">www.meta.tj</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Disapprove of Dushanbe’s ‘dictator chic’</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The new 'Dictator chic' buildings in the city centre are outrageously opulent; visitors can only wonder how the government can justify building the highest flagpole in the world, the largest chaihana in the world and the glittering Palace of Nations when most of its rural population are without running water or a reliable quality of electricity supply. These edifices serve only to impress the tourist and are testament to the remarkable tolerance of the Tajik people.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the natural beauty of Rangkul</b></p><![CDATA[<p>To the north and east of Murghab lies the lake and village of Rangkul. The lake is particularly beautiful because of the shades of rock on the opposite shore and the lake is also an important transit location for bird migration. Rangkul village has a deep Kyrgyz heritage and tourists can pre-arrange through META a cultural performance of dance, poetry and music.</p>]]><p><b>Drive the Pamir Highway</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the greatest road trips in Asia, a drive down the Pamir Highway promises the full gamut of vistas; soaring mountains, desert plateaus and shimmering lakes. The highway goes through neighbouring Afghanistan, Uzbekistan and Kyrgyzstan, but some of the best sights can be seen along the Tajikistan section; Karakul Lake, a meteorite crater filled with water, and the snow-capped Peak Lenin are amongst the highlights.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Hissor Fort</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located 20km (13 miles) to the west of Dushanbe, Hissor Fort is built on a promontory overlooking the valley. The reconstructed stone gateway is the only present-day remnant of the buildings that stood on this site, but the earthworks tell a story of a once impressive structure that began construction in the Neolithic era and then saw destruction and reconstruction with the advent of every successive invasion. The 16C Madrassa opposite is also worthy of investigation.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the Panj valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Panj River cuts a deep gorge for approximately 300km (186 miles) along the border between Tajikistan and Afghanistan. On the Tajik side of the river valley the Pamir Highway forges a precipitous route from village to village, but on the Afghan side an even more gut-wrenching path navigates sheer cliffs above foaming rapids – local Afghans steer this path with the seeming footwork of mountain goats.</p>]]><p><b>Hike to the largest glacier in the world</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Fedchenko glacier – the longest glacier in the world outside of the polar regions – is located in the Pamir Mountains. The glacier covers approximately 700 sq km (270 sq miles) and specialist tour operators do offers treks to see it.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Zorkul Lake</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the far south east of the Eastern Pamir lies the stunning Zorkul Lake. Christened 'Lake Victoria' by British military explorers in the 18th century, Zorkul is significantly smaller than its African equivalent, albeit just as scenic. Accessed via and off-road track, visitors must purchase a Zorkul National Park permit which can be bought in Murghab. Speak to Murghab Ecotourism Association, 102 Osh Street, Murghab for more information.</p>]]><p><b>Stay in a Kyrgyz yurt</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For an authentic Tajikistan experience, adventurous tourists can stay in yurts with hospitable Kyrgyz nomads. The Murghab Ecotourism Association, 102 Osh Street, Murghab (<a href="http://www.meta.tj" target="_blank">www.meta.tj</a>) work with local Kyrgyz people and offer a range of homestays in the area.</p>]]><p><b>Swim in the ‘Tajik Riviera’</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Kairakhum reservoir is Tajikistan's closest approximation to a coastline. Located 20km (13 miles) west of Khujand, the manmade lake is home to a few sanatoriums and pensions where visitors can relax in the sunshine and swim in the lake. The area is also popular with birdwatchers, having been identified as an Important Bird Area by BirdLife International.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the Wakhan valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the 18th century, the Wakhan Valley became one of the most obscure geopolitical boundaries in the world as the British and the Tsarist colonial powers turned it into a no-man's land and passed it into Afghan territorial ownership.</p><p>Known as the Wakhan Corridor this wide and fertile valley runs for approximately 200km (130 miles) between Afghanistan and China, passing through Tajikistan. The Tajikistan stretch of the valley provides stunning views and the locals are used to visitors and welcome them with open arms.</p>]]><p><b>Trek the Fann Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Kissing the sky at 5,000m (16,404ft), the Fann Mountain are home to some of the highest peaks in Tajikistan, not to mention the beautiful Marguzor Lakes. Also known as the Seven Lakes, these turquoise lagoons are popular with hikers and photographers alike.</p><p>Iskanderkul (Alexander's Lake) is a particularly stunning lake, which, according to folklore, is where Alexander the Great lost his favourite warhorse – Bucephalus – which drowned in the lake. Locals say that on clear, summer nights the horse surfaces again to graze on the shoreline.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US $8.5 billion (2013)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Aluminium, electricity, cotton, fruit, textiles</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum products, aluminium oxide, foodstuffs, electrical goods and machinery</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Russia, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkey">Turkey</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iran">Iran</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kazakhstan">Kazakhstan</a></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Since the collapse of the Soviet Union and the ensuing civil war, Tajikistan has struggled to find investment in infrastructure or the economy.</p><p>Mining and cotton product remain the single largest earners in export revenues. However, environmental disputes, often instigated by local greed and corrupt officials, frequently disturb or deter further mining exploration and investment from international mining companies.</p><p>More than a third of the population remain below the poverty line. Small family businesses employ approximately 85% of Tajikistan's workforce, but unemployment is rising in both the cities and rural districts. Economic migration is very high as disaffected Tajiks seek work in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a> or further afield.</p><p>In the World Bank's 2013 'Ease of Doing Business Ranking' Tajikistan came 141 out of 185 countries. The challenges for any prospective investor are substantial and there are few external enterprises willing to take on the long journey to profitability in Tajikistan. Nevertheless, there have been business sectors that have succeeded most notably the telecoms and banking sectors.</p><p>The main problems in doing business are trading across borders, payment of taxes, electricity supply and obtaining appropriate permits. Corruption is rife and the lack of administrative clarity leads one to wonder if bribery is actually the only viable route for businesses that wish to be successful.</p><p>Central government pricing control distorts the real inflation affecting the economy and there are growing serious issues in the lack of maintenance of infrastructure and international debt dependence. With all the above facts, it remains unclear how Tajikistan can ever become a truly viable economy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Tajik's have hospitality at their heart and usually most business meetings begin with a sharing of friendly pleasantries and some food with tea. This can often go on for some time adding to the Central Asian propensity for lateness, which is also well exhibited in Tajiks. As a result, meetings often overrun unless they are held at the end of the day. Don't plan meetings back to back or expect to be on-time after your first morning meeting.</p><p>Business attire is formal for all meetings. The trading of business cards is usual.</p><p>Typically Mon-Sat 0800-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Ministry of Economy and Foreign Economic Relations</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (372) 232 944,(372) 210 404
					Website:
					Address: ,42 Rudaki Street,Dushanbe 734002,]]><b>Business Information Service for the Newly Independent States</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (202) 482 4655
					Website:
					Address: Stop R-Binis,USA Trade Center,1401 Constitution Avenue,]]><b>US Department of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Over the last few years, dining options have improved substantially in the cities and it is now possible to find most culinary forms somewhere in Dushanbe. However, the quality is variable and once out into the countryside options rapidly shrink to Central Asian staples.</p><p>In a country where most farmers are operating at subsistence level, the volume of production always beats quality. Furthermore, food sellers are prone to display their best wares on the surface and if you dig deeper you'll usually find poorer quality goods awaiting the unwary buyer.</p><p>If you are invited into a house as a guest you will insult the local person if you don't stay at least for tea and many will instantly commence cooking for you.</p><p>You will be invited to sit on tushucks (thin pallets) around a tablecloth on the floor upon which the meal will be served. You should never touch the tablecloth with your feet.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Plov</strong>: A hearty one-pot dish of rich, lamb fat and root vegetables.</p><p><strong>Lagman</strong>: Meat soup with noodles and vegetables.</p><p><strong>Mante</strong>: Steamed meat dumplings that may be served with a spicy dip.</p><p><strong>Beshbarmak</strong>: The Tajik/Kyrgyz of the Eastern Pamir frequently serve this tasty dish involving large pieces of mutton in a broth with noodles or potatoes.</p><p><strong>Non</strong>: Flat bread served with every meal. Custom dictates that diners should never turn their bread upside down or throw their bread away.</p><p><strong>Apricots</strong>: Apricot jam and dried apricots appear on most Tajik tables.</p><p><strong>Zeliony, or chorny chai</strong>: Green, or black tea.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>It's normal to tip 10%. If you've had a guest meal in a homestay you should repay that hospitality with a gift or payment that does not insult the owner – up to $5 should be fine.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>21.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nightlife in Tajikistan is decidedly quiet in comparison to most other countries and generally there is insufficient disposable income to warrant merriment of this kind.  With the exception of Khujand and Dushanbe, essentially you have to make it happen for yourself – particularly in rural districts.</p><p>This may not be too bad if you can find a local group or band to perform but don't expect this every night and with electricity in short supply, take plenty of batteries for your torch and reading.</p><p>In Dushanbe, there are plenty of bars and clubs that you can visit but heavy drinking can be expected in most and some of the clientele work in a professional capacity – be wary of your bags and overly friendly advances.</p><p>The Aini Opera and Ballet Theatre is an impressive building towards the southern end of Rudaki and you should book in advance. There is also a water and light show in the fountains up on Karamov.</p><p>In Khujand, the story is very similar to Dushanbe, but with fewer options. However, their water and light show (near the Somoni statue on the north side of the river) is more entertaining and usually attended by hundreds of locals and their families – worth experiencing just to see the crowds of happy faces having fun together in the evening.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tajikistan relies heavily on imported goods, most of which are of Turkish, Russian or Chinese origin and those goods usually reflect only the low quality end of the range, including various obvious attempts at fake branding of western goods. In the cities, 'supermarket' retailing is emerging but the majority of locals still buy from traditional bazaars which exist in most villages and are worth experiencing even if you have no plans to buy anything at all.</p><p>In Dushanbe, there are several bazaars worth visiting, most notably the Zelenny (green) Bazaar where the vegetable and fruit market is particularly colourful. Barakat Bazaar is the better option for clothing but Tsum is good for a range of consumables and souvenirs.</p><p>Around Khujand, from June to September, it is worth inquiring about dried apricot bazaars, which are held fortnightly in remote locations in the countryside. They begin very early in the day to avoid too much sunshine on the products. Selling starts at sunrise and it is usually all over by 9am.</p><p>In a small district called Chkalovsk, near Khujand, there is a market held on Saturdays in the local park where the remaining local ethnic Russian community sells items of soviet memorabilia. In the soviet era this was a 'closed city' as there was a uranium enrichment plant here. The city appeared on no maps and was populated only by ethnic Russians, many of whom have now departed and their memorabilia are all that remain of that bygone era.</p><p>Probably the most unusual bazaar experience can be found in Murghab where old transport containers have been cut up to make a variety of small booths and shops. The significant absence of many commodities adds to the flavour of this retail graveyard.</p><p>The most popular souvenirs involve traditional needlework and patchwork designs on felt, cotton and wool handicrafts. Some development efforts have been made to try and stimulate local production of handicrafts for tourist purchase. However, poor quality designs, materials and workmanship all compound to reduce this trade to not much more than a 'pity purchase'.</p><p>In the Eastern Pamir you can find traditional Kyrgyz headwear – the kalpak.</p><p>Mon-Sat 10.00-18.00</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tajikistan is not well supplied with hotels. Although there are no restrictions on where visitors may stay, hotels other than the main hotels are unused to accommodating foreigners and all but the most insistent visitors may find it difficult to obtain a room. The main hotels are clean and friendly, although it is difficult to get a room in the Oktyabrskaya, which houses both the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> and Russian embassies. Outside the capital, accommodation is very hard to find. For further information, contact the State National Tourism Company of the Republic of Tajikistan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tajikistan is not well supplied with hotels. Although there are no restrictions on where visitors may stay, hotels other than the main hotels are unused to accommodating foreigners and all but the most insistent visitors may find it difficult to obtain a room. The main hotels are clean and friendly, although it is difficult to get a room in the Oktyabrskaya, which houses both the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> and Russian embassies. Outside the capital, accommodation is very hard to find. For further information, contact the State National Tourism Company of the Republic of Tajikistan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tajikistan is not well supplied with hotels. Although there are no restrictions on where visitors may stay, hotels other than the main hotels are unused to accommodating foreigners and all but the most insistent visitors may find it difficult to obtain a room. The main hotels are clean and friendly, although it is difficult to get a room in the Oktyabrskaya, which houses both the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> and Russian embassies. Outside the capital, accommodation is very hard to find. For further information, contact the State National Tourism Company of the Republic of Tajikistan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Standards of health care are low. As the domestic health service is plagued by shortages of medicines and drugs, travellers are advised to take antibiotics and any prescription medicines, contact lens solutions and a first-aid kit containing basic medicines and water treatment tablets. Although fees for health services are low, health insurance is recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being a potential health risk. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccination sometimes required for tick-borne encephalitis.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Victory Day :
							09 May </p><p>National Unity Day :
							27 June </p><p>Independence Day :
							09 September </p><p>Constitution Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Tajikistan by persons of 18 years of age or older without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigars or 500g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2L of spirits.<br />
&bull; Perfume for personal use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Firearms and weapons, pharmaceuticals, narcotics and live animals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tajik Somoni (TJS) = 100 diram. Notes are in denominations of TJS100, 50, 20, 10, 5 and 1, and 50, 20, 5 and 1 diram.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The preferred hard currency is the US Dollar, although other hard currencies are in theory also acceptable. All bills are normally settled in cash, and tourists must pay in hard currency for accommodation in hotels, although these are normally included in the price of organised tours. Owing to a shortage of change, a supply of small notes should be carried. International banking services are not available. All money should be changed at the official bureaux de change and the receipts should be kept. However, this law is not rigidly enforced.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Limited acceptance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Tajikistan, a passport valid for at least six months longer than the validity of the requested visa is required by the nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>e-Visa: US$50.</p>
<p>Tourist visa from the embassy: &pound;20.</p>
<p>The costs for all other types of visa are as follows:</p>
<p>Single-entry visa: &pound;60 (up to 14 days), &pound;80 (up to 30 days), &pound;90 (up to 60 days), &pound;150 (up to 90 days), &pound;200 (up to 180 days).</p>
<p>Double-entry visa: &pound;65 (up to 14 days), &pound;90 (up to 30 days), &pound;100 (up to 60 days), &pound;160 (up to 90 days), &pound;220 (up to 180 days).</p>
<p>Multiple-entry visa: &pound;70 (up to 14 days), &pound;100 (up to 30 days), &pound;150 (up to 60 days), &pound;200 (up to 90 days), &pound;250 (up to 180 days).</p>
<p>Permit for the Gorno Babakhshan Autonomous Region: &pound;50.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dependent on purpose of trip. Tourist visas and e-Visas are usually valid for up to 45 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section of embassy) or, if eligible, on arrival at the Dushanbe Airport or via <a href="http://evisa.tj" target="_blank">evisa.tj</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow three to five working days for embassy visa processing. There is also an express service available for double the usual fee.</p>
<p>e-Visas are usually processed immediately.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to extend your visa, contact the consular department of the Tajik Ministry of Foreign Affairs. You cannot usually extend tourist visas however.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[38.813982]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[71.478951]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>143,100 sq km (55,251 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>8,669,464 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>57.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dushanbe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tajikistan is bordered by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kyrgyzstan">Kyrgyzstan</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/uzbekistan">Uzbekistan</a> to the north, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/afghanistan">Afghanistan</a> to the south and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> (PR) to the east. 93% of the republic is occupied by mountains, most notably by the sparsely populated Pamir Mountains, which include Mount Garmo (formerly Pik Kommunizma; 7,495m/24,590ft), the highest point of the former Soviet Union. The mountainous terrain means that in winter it is impossible to reach the east or the north of the country by road without taking a detour through Uzbekistan and Kyrgyzstan. In the fertile plains of the southwest, cotton dominates the agriculture. In the north, in the Khudzand (formerly Leninabad) region, cotton and silk are the main crops.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Predominantly Sunni Muslim (80%) with a small Shi'ite Muslim minority (5%). A large Ishmaeli minority exists in the Pamirs. There is also a smaller and shrinking Russian Orthodox minority and a small Jewish community.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><em>Lipioshka</em> (bread) should never be laid upside down, and it is normal to remove shoes, but not socks, when entering someone's house. Shorts are rarely seen in Tajikistan and, if worn by females, are likely to provoke unwelcome attention from the local male population.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Qohir Rasulzoda since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Emomali Rahmon since 1994.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Strictly speaking, the history of Tajikistan as a nation begins as recently as 1991, when the Tajik Soviet Socialist Republic (part of the former USSR) became an independent country. Sadly the new country immediately fell into civil war &ndash; a bloody and unpleasant conflict involving divided ethnic factions, regions and ideologies.</p>
<p>The war ended with the signing of a peace accord in 1997 and the appointment of President Emomalii Rahmon. The topic of the civil war is still simmering under the surface in Tajikistan in some quarters and relics of those times do still remain.</p>
<p>Human activity in Tajikistan can be traced back as far as 6500BC, when Neolithic cave dwellers settled in the mountains. All the communities that have subsequently attempted habitation of the region &ndash; which is characterised by its remoteness and harsh climate &ndash; have endured tough conditions and, consequently, only the hardy few have made it their home.</p>
<p>The first traveller of global consequence to the region was Alexander the Great. He travelled through present day western Tajikistan, marrying the infamous Roxana to cement local relations. His army made a number of forays into the Fann Mountains and Western Pamir, chasing down local marauders and searching for an eastward route through those ranges towards present day <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a>.</p>
<p>Various myths abound regarding how far the scouting parties got in their search beyond the then &lsquo;known&rsquo; world. There are fables suggesting that some garrisons remained in the valleys of the Western Pamir, which might attempt to explain the real and obvious ethnic diversity of these present day communities &ndash; to this day you can see European faces with blond or red hair colour in isolated valleys.</p>
<p>In the 8th Century the region was conquered by the Umayyad Empire, hailing from Mecca. The incursion first introduced the Islamic religion to the region &ndash; a heritage that has survived waves of successive empires from Mongol, Timurid, Persian, Tsarist and, lastly, Soviet origin.</p>
<p>Another globally renowned traveller, Marco Polo, made a dent in Tajik history in successfully establishing an international trade connection through the Pamir. That embryonic &lsquo;Silk Road&rsquo; would actually become a network of routes through the region and Polo was able to document and reveal the scale of the geographic barrier that was the Pamir range, which had defeated Alexander over 1500 years before.</p>
<p>His exploration was subsequently followed five more centuries later by Russian and British military expeditions to the region that came again under the guise of explorers. During the period referred to as &lsquo;The Great Game&rsquo;, the British and Tsarist empires vied for control of the region, beginning the process of establishing the first geopolitical boundaries.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong> <br />
&bull;	There are more than 900 rivers in Tajikistan that are longer than 10km (6 miles).<br />
&bull;	Russian soldiers reported seeing a Yeti in the Pamir Mountains. Like the Loch Ness Monster, the legend of the Tajikistan yeti still persists today. <br />
&bull;	There are thought to be as few as 3,500 snow leopards left in the wild &ndash; 300 are thought to live in the Tajik Pamirs.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Tajikistan Republic in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 223 6090.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.tjus.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 223 6090.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0800-1700, Mon-Tues and Thurs-Fri 0900-1200 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1005 New Hampshire Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20037<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Tajikistan Republic in Germany]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(30) 347 9300.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.botschaft-tadschikistan.de</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(30) 347 9300.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0900-1300&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Otto-Suhr-Allee 84<br/>Berlin<br/>10585<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Following in the footsteps of ancient Silk Road traders, modern travellers come to Tajikistan to experience a magical journey across the &lsquo;Roof of the World,&rsquo; a land of soaring mountain ranges, deep ravines and high-altitude deserts.</p>
<p>Although Tajikistan is one of the most remote countries in the world, even its most inaccessible nooks host life; the mountains and deserts are home to Kyrgyz nomads, who eke out simple, self-sufficient lives as they have done for generations. Intrepid travellers will endure some of the coldest temperatures on the planet to visit them, but these chilly conditions are tempered by the Kyrgyz&rsquo;s warm hospitality.</p>
<p>An independent state since 1991, Tajikistan spent much of the last two centuries under Tsarist and Soviet rule. Ethnic Tajiks form the majority of the population, but there are also minority ethnic groups of Russian, Uzbek and Kyrgyz origin &ndash; a mix brought about by Stalin&rsquo;s &ldquo;divide and conquer&rdquo; strategy.</p>
<p>Tajikistan&rsquo;s landscapes are just as dramatic as its political history. In the mountainous west, lofty peaks plunge into deep valleys where villages cling precariously to the cliffs-side above fast flowing rivers. In these settlements, where most of the population are subsidence farmers, any available patch of land is terraced and cultivated with potatoes, cabbage and wheat.</p>
<p>Over in the east, the mountains plateau into a vast, high-altitude desert that looks like the surface of the moon. This is a hostile part of the&nbsp;world, as Marco Polo noted when he travelled through the region. &ldquo;No birds fly here because of the height and the cold,&rdquo; he wrote.</p>
<p>Most arrive in Tajikistan via its capital, Dushanbe, one of the prettier cities in Central Asia with its gilded palaces, leafy parks and neoclassical facades. Emerging from the shadows of Soviet rule, Dushanbe is desperate to impress; it boasts the largest teahouse and tallest flagpole in the world, which are, aside from a few museums and markets, about the extent of its attractions.</p>
<p>But Tajikistan isn&rsquo;t about the destination, it&rsquo;s about the journey; a journey through history and geography, where warm a welcome awaits those intrepid enough to visit.</p><p>Following in the footsteps of ancient Silk Road traders, modern travellers come to Tajikistan to experience a magical journey across the &lsquo;Roof of the World,&rsquo; a land of soaring mountain ranges, deep ravines and high-altitude deserts. Although Tajikistan is one of the most remote countries in the world, even its most inaccessible nooks host life; the mountains and deserts are home to Kyrgyz nomads, who eke out simple, self-sufficient lives as they have done for generations. Intrepid travellers will endure some of the coldest temperatures on the planet to visit them, but these chilly conditions are tempered by the Kyrgyz&rsquo;s warm hospitality.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
