<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Tanzania" ColCode="tza" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="tz" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Tanzania]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate is tropical and coastal areas are hot and humid, while the northwestern highlands are cool and temperate. There are two rainy seasons; the short rains are generally from October to December, while the long rains last from March to June. The central plateau tends to be dry and arid throughout the year.<br /><br />Tanzania can be visited year-round, although the best time for travelling is outside of the rainy season between June and October, when temperatures stay well below their summer peaks. Beach side locations like Zanzibar can be fine to visit during the hotter months of December to January, when ocean breezes make the high temperatures bearable (though humidity can still be high). However, this is also the time popular for typical beach holidays, especially for those travelling from Europe wanting some winter sunshine, and hotels can book up early especially for the Christmas and New Year period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical clothing is worn throughout the year, but in the cooler season, from June to September, jackets and sweaters may be needed, especially in the evenings. Clothing appropriate to temperatures below zero is required on the higher slopes of Kilimanjaro and Meru. Also note that it can get very cold at night on the rim of the Ngorongoro Crater and early morning game drives may be chilly before the sun comes up.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Precision Air (<a href="http://www.precisionairtz.com" target="_blank">www.precisionairtz.com</a>) runs regular services, mostly via Dar es Salaam, Kilimanjaro or Zanzibar, to main towns and other destinations in the region. Air Tanzania (<a href="http://www.airtanzania.co.tz" target="_blank">www.airtanzania.co.tz</a>) also has a limited network of domestic routes.</p>
<p>All national parks and some of the top-end luxury lodges have airstrips and Coastal Air (<a href="http://www.coastal.cc" target="_blank">www.coastal.cc</a>) operates between these and the main airports on the mainland and the islands of Zanzibar, Pemba and Mafia. ZanAir (<a href="http://www.zanair.com" target="_blank">www.zanair.com</a>) has frequent connections between Zanzibar, Pemba and the mainland.</p>
<p>Flying between destinations saves a lot of time, particularly on a short holiday, and flights are affordable and run reasonably efficiently. The most popular route by air in Tanzania is between the northern circuit parks (the Serengeti, Ngorongoro Crater etc.) and Zanzibar. For some destinations, Gombe Stream or Mahale on Lake Tanganyika for example, flying is the preferable option and saves days by road or rail journey.</p><p>Many of the smaller airlines run services in circuits and flights may involve several stops as the plane drops passengers at different airstrips on each circuit. For example, a flight to the Serengeti may pick up and drop off passengers at several safari lodges on the same circuit. They generally use small six- or 12-seater planes, and while they have frequent scheduled flights, will only fly with the required minimum of passengers, though sometimes this is only two people. Note that on the smaller aircraft, the baggage allowance is 15kg, so you may have to leave luggage at hotels in Dar es Salaam or Arusha (or other major departure points).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Azam Marine (<a href="http://www.azammarine.com" target="_blank">www.azammarine.com</a>), among other companies, runs comfortable, air-conditioned ferry services several times a day between Dar es Salaam and Zanzibar by hydrofoil (journey time - 90 minutes). Some of the services also continue on from Zanzibar to Pemba Island. You can obtain timetables and tickets at the booking offices at the main passenger port on Sokoine Drive adjacent to the jetty. Payment for ferry tickets is in US Dollars (cash) only.</p>
<p>There is a basic overnight steamer service on Lake Victoria that runs between the ports of Bukoba and Mwanza.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tanzania's railways are in feeble condition, with breakdowns and cancellations of already infrequent services all too common. Tanzania Railways Corporation (TRC) (<a href="http://www.trctz.com" target="_blank">www.trctz.com</a>) operates the Central Line, which runs between Dar es Salaam and western Tanzania. The line splits at Tabora in the middle of the country and one branch continues to Kigoma on the shores of Lake Tanganyika, while the second branch goes north to Mwanza on Lake Victoria.</p>
<p>The route between Dar es Salaam and Mbeya in the southwest and on to Kapiri Moshi in Zambia is run by the Tanzania and Zambia Railway Authority (Tazara) (<a href="http://www.tazarasite.com" target="_blank">www.tazarasite.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[l<p>Tanzania has a decent network of tarmac and all-weather roads connecting the major towns. Away from the main highways, however, the majority of roads are bad and hazardous. Most of the minor roads are unmade gravel with potholes: there are many rough stretches and they deteriorate further in the rainy season. While there is a tarred road from Arusha to the Ngorongoro Crater, beyond there (and in other parts of the country) road conditions in the parks and reserves of Tanzania are extremely rough, and during the rainy season, many are passable only with high clearance 4-wheel drive vehicles.</p>
<p>Fuel is available along the main highways and in towns, but if you&rsquo;re going way off the beaten track, consider taking a couple of jerry cans of extra fuel. Also ensure the vehicle has a jack and possibly take a shovel to dig it out of mud or sand.</p>
<p>It is not advisable to drive at night because of wild animals, cattle and goats on the road. Also be wary of driving behind public transport vehicles (buses and mini-buses), which can break sharply to pick up passengers.</p><p>There are numerous private bus companies operating in Tanzania. However, most vehicles are old and basic and depart when full, which means there are no set timetables and they can be uncomfortable. Petty theft on the vehicles and at bus stations can also be a problem. Nevertheless, fares are cheap and they link all long-distance destinations.</p>
<p>As for the cross-border routes, Scandinavia Express (<a href="http://www.scandinaviagroup.com" target="_blank">www.scandinaviagroup.com</a>) is the best bet for city-to-city long-distance routes as its coaches are modern, have air-conditioning and onboard toilets and run to fixed schedules. Smaller vehicles known as <em>dala-dalas</em> (minibuses) link the smaller towns over short distances and can be flagged down from the side of the road, but they are crowded and can be driven erratically.</p><p>You can't hail taxis in the street, but you can find them parked up at transport hubs like airports, rail and bus stations, and at major intersections in the cities and towns. Most hotels and restaurants can find one for you. They are not metered and you have to negotiate the fare before you get in. This can be tricky as it&rsquo;s not uncommon for taxi drivers to charge tourists overinflated prices &ndash; but conversely a taxi driver simply will not take you if you bargain a fare that&rsquo;s too low.</p>
<p>At the airports in Dar es Salaam and Zanzibar there are well-organised taxi associations who have desks outside the arrivals terminals with a list of fares to various destinations. You should organise a taxi at these.</p><p>You either need an International Driving Permit, or can pay a small fee to have your own country licence endorsed in Tanzania by the police (the car hire company organises this). Third-party insurance is mandatory and it&rsquo;s recommended to take out the additional collision damage waiver. A credit card is also needed.</p><p>In non-residential areas, speed limits are 120kph (75mph) and 60kph (35mph) in built-up areas. It is compulsory to wear a seat belt and obligatory that all vehicles carry two red triangles to be placed 20m (66ft) in front and behind the vehicle in the event of a breakdown.</p><p>There is no formal breakdown service, so ensure whoever you hire a car from can provide sufficient back-up service in the event of an emergency.</p><p>Car hire can be expensive, and rates (particularly the mileage charges) can vary a good deal. Most companies insist that only 4-wheel-drive vehicles should be hired if going into the parks and reserves or off the beaten track. Vehicles with drivers are also available.</p>
<p>International car hire companies are represented in Dar es Salaam, but elsewhere the only option is to go through a tour operator. Hiring a jeep for a day or two on Zanzibar is a popular way to explore the island and this can be arranged through any tour operator or large hotel. To hire a car you generally need to be over 23 and you'll need an International Driving Permit (in Zanzibar, you'll need a Zanzibari Driving Permit, available from your car hire company).</p><p>The most popular place to hire a bike is on Zanzibar, and any hotel can organise this. Note though that bicycles are the old-fashioned and heavy type and cycling during the day can be hot. Additionally, watch out for motorists, as they generally have little respect for cyclists and expect them to get out of the way or leave the road when they pass.</p><p>In non-residential areas, speed limits are 120kph (75mph) and 60kph (35mph) in built-up areas. It is compulsory to wear a seat belt and obligatory that all vehicles carry two red triangles to be placed 20m (66ft) in front and behind the vehicle in the event of a breakdown.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><em>Dala-dalas</em> are local passenger vehicles using minibuses (on Zanzibar they are also small trucks with open backs and bench-like seating). They are by the far largest method of urban and rural transport and are cheap, but services are often crowded and pickpockets are common. They depart and arrive from various terminals around urban centres and can also be flagged down in the street. As well as regular taxis, the three-wheel tuk-tuks of South-East Asia are also popular in town centres and take three passengers behind the driver.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Tanzania</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">moshi</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.25</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">8.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Tanzania</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">morgoro</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Tanzania</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">mbeya</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">11.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">21.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Tanzania</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">arusha</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">8.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are frequent direct and indirect flights to Tanzania by numerous international airlines. Local airlines Air Tanzania (<a href="http://www.airtanzania.co.tz" target="_blank">www.airtanzania.co.tz</a>) and Precision Air (<a href="http://www.precisionairtz.com" target="_blank">www.precisionairtz.com</a>) serve regional and domestic destinations only. International carriers flying to Tanzania include Emirates (<a href="http://www.emirates.com" target="_blank">www.emirates.com</a>), Etihad Airways (<a href="http://www.etihad.com" target="_blank">www.etihad.com</a>), Kenya Airways (<a href="http://www.kenya-airways.com" target="_blank">www.kenya-airways.com</a>), KLM (<a href="http://www.klm.com" target="_blank">www.klm.com</a>) and&nbsp;Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>) among others.</p>
<p>Airline fare prices to Tanzania stay pretty consistent around the year.</p>
<p>The major aiprot is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tanzania/dar-es-salaam-julius-nyerere-international-airport">Dar Es Salaam Nyerere International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 11 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 19 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Julius Nyerere International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://jnia.taa.go.tz/<p>Julius Nyerere International Airport is situated 12km (8 miles) southwest of Dar es Salaam.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+255 22 284 4324</p>]]><b>Kilimanjaro International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.kilimanjaroairport.co.tz<p>The airport  is 50km (31 miles) from Arusha (journey time - 1 hour).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Mwanza Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.taa.go.tz<p>The airport  is 10km (6.2 miles) from Mwanza (journey time 25 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Zanzibar International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.zanzibar-airport.com<p>The airport  is 4km (2.5 miles) from Stone Town (journey time 15 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main port is Dar es Salaam (<a href="http://www.tanzaniaports.com" target="_blank">www.tanzaniaports.com</a>) which is served by commercial ships but no passenger services from other countries. It does however serve as the departure point for ferry services to Zanzibar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The route between Dar es Salaam and Kapiri Moshi in Zambia is run by the Tanzania and Zambia Railway Authority (Tazara) (<a href="http://www.tazarasite.com" target="_blank">www.tazarasite.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main international road crossings into Tanzania are from Kenya. The most used is the border crossing at Namanga, about halfway between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/nairobi">Nairobi</a> and Arusha. The other principal border crossing is south of Mombasa on the coast at Lunga Lunga, from where the nearest large Tanzanian town is Tanga. There are quieter border crossings at Taveta, between Voi and Moshi, and Isebania on the main road between Kisumu and Mwanza.</p>
<p>Border crossings from other neighbouring countries include the Songwe border with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/malawi">Malawi</a> and the Tunduma border with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/zambia">Zambia</a>, both of which are in the southwestern corner of Tanzania and are reached by a good (but long) road from Dar es Salaam. There is a crossing with <a href="http://i/uganda">Uganda</a> at Mutukulu, northwest of Bukoba, but this is a rough road and a remote region to get to. The easiest way to get to Uganda from Tanzania is via Nairobi in Kenya, from where there are daily bus services to Kampala.</p>
<p>There is a border crossing with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/rwanda">Rwanda</a> at Rusomo, although again this is in the remote northwestern part of Tanzania although there are bus services between Mwanza and Kigali. Tanzania does share a border with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mozambique">Mozambique</a> to the south, but road access between the two countries is very limited.</p><p>There are many local bus companies that ply the main routes over the borders. Several companies run comfortable shuttle bus services between Nairobi and Arusha and Moshi in Tanzania. These are aimed at tourists who fly into Nairobi and are visiting the game parks in Tanzania&rsquo;s northern circuit region from Arusha, or are climbing Mt Kilimanjaro from Moshi. The buses take about 5-6 hours in either direction, and drivers assist passengers with border procedures. Riverside Shuttles (<a href="http://www.riverside-shuttle.com" target="_blank">www.riverside-shuttle.com</a>) offers a reliable daily service.</p>
<p>For long-distance cross-border bus travel, recommended for visitors is Scandinavia Express (<a href="http://www.scandinaviagroup.com" target="_blank">www.scandinaviagroup.com</a>), which has frequent daily departures to and from Nairobi and Arusha, Moshi and Dar es Salaam, Nairobi and Mwanza, and Mombasa and Dar es Salaam. It also offers daily services between Nairobi and Kampala in Uganda, and from Dar es Salaam to Lusaka in Zambia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>In most towns there is an efficient local and international service from public coin and card phone boxes operated by the Tanzania Telecommunications Company Ltd. (TTCL) (<a href="http://www.ttcl.co.tz" target="_blank">www.ttcl.co.tz</a>). These are usually outside or within the post office and in the cities there are separate TTCL offices for phone, fax and Internet. Connections are quick and about a third of the price of a call through hotels, which are expensive for phone calls and faxes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Tanzania's many cellular networks cover almost all towns, the urban sections of the coast, Zanzibar and the tourist areas, but not some of the parks and reserves or the southwest of Tanzania away from the towns and the main road. SIM and top-up cards for the pay-as-you-go mobile providers are available just about everywhere; in the towns and cities they often have their own shops, but you can buy cards from roadside vendors anywhere, even in the smallest of settlements.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Email can be accessed in internet cafés in main urban areas, which are affordable and efficient. Even smaller towns have at least one, usually on the main street. In the more remote towns, where a satellite connection is used, costs can be a little higher. Tourists can also access the internet in many hotels; the more upmarket and business orientated ones have in-room Wi-Fi. Accommodation in parks and reserves generally don't have internet.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Until the 1990s, Tanzania's media was largely state controlled. Founding president Julius Nyerere believed TV would increase the divide between rich and poor and Tanzania is considered to have been one of the last countries in the world to broadcast TV – which it did in 1994. Today, the number of Tanzanians with TVs has risen at a swift rate and most 'middle class' urban Tanzanians own a television. Tanzanians are avid radio listeners with an estimated 60% of the population having access to radio. Tanzania enjoys a good level of freedom of press, though there is some bias depending on the ownership of the media.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are post offices even in the smallest of towns (<a href="http://www.posta.co.tz" target="_blank">www.posta.co.tz</a>). Airmail to Europe takes about 5-7 days and to the US about 10 days. EMS is a registered postal service available at all post offices. Courier services take three working days and the major international courier companies such as DHL (<a href="http://www.dhl.co.tz" target="_blank">www.dhl.co.tz</a>) are represented in the cities and Zanzibar.</p><p>Generally Mon-Fri 0800-1630; Sat 0900-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Safari in the Serengeti</p><![CDATA[<p>The most famous national park in all of Africa is found in Tanzania, and a safari through the Serengeti (<a href="http://www.serengeti.org" target="_blank">www.serengeti.org</a>) is a must-do on any visit to Tanzania - especially during the famed wildebeest migration (November to May). Close sightings of the 'big five' (lion, elephant, buffalo, leopard and rhino) are almost guaranteed. Safaris can be arranged all over Tanzania, particularly in nearby Arusha, which is the springboard town for safaris to all the parks in Tanzania&rsquo;s northern circuit.</p>]]><br/><p>Stone Town</p><![CDATA[<p>Zanzibar's Stone Town was the hub of the ancient spice trade, and once served as the maritime metropolis of East Africa, variously ruled by Shirazi Persians, the Portuguese, the Omani Arabs and British colonials. Today, this UNESCO World Heritage Site remains a labyrinth of narrow, winding streets lined with exotic shops, bazaars, colonial mansions, mosques and squares.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Conquer Mount Kilimanjaro</b></p><![CDATA[<p>As the highest mountain in Africa at 5,895m (19,341 ft), Kilimanjaro has tempted avid explorers with its snow-capped peak for decades. Reaching the top is no walk in the park, but anyone of reasonable fitness can do it. Well-organised six-, seven- or eight-day climbs include guides, porters, food and equipment. Watching the sunrise from the summit is an indescribable spectacle.</p>]]><p><b>Experience wilderness seclusion at Selous Game Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For a truly remote wildlife adventure, head to an isolated lodge in the Selous Game Reserve. This UNESCO World Heritage Site covers an area larger than Switzerland (about one-sixth of Tanzania's land surface), making it one of the biggest reserves in the world. It is home to a plethora of African animals, and is renowned for its exceptionally large elephant herds.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Lake Manyara National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lake Manyara is easily seen from the road that climbs up the Rift Valley, where safari vehicles stop to gawk at the pink flamingos. Once inside the park, there are tracks through the oasis of lush greenery, with the algae-streaked lake on one side and baobab-strewn cliffs on the other. Manyara is famous for its tree-climbing lions, and elephant are easily spotted too.</p>]]><p><b>Feel the beautiful isolation of Lake Natron</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The isolated and beautiful Lake Natron is a lesser-known gem on Tanzania's feted Northern Circuit. The shallow moon-like surface of this salt and soda lake is home to more than two million lesser flamingos, while the surrounding Rift Valley escarpment lends itself to dramatic vistas. Tourism remains delightfully underdeveloped here, though you're just a few hours from Arusha.</p>]]><p><b>Have a history lesson at the National Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located next to the Botanical Gardens in Dar es Salaam, the National Museum reveals the fascinating history and culture of this ancient region, and features the 1.7-million-year-old skull of Nutcracker Man. Peacocks stroll the gardens, where there is a striking sculpture in memory of victims of the 1998 Dar es Salaam US Embassy bombing.</p>]]><p><b>Meander around Moshi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Beneath the snow-capped peak of Kilimanjaro sits the small, charming and verdant town of Moshi, worth exploring either before or after conquering Africa's highest mountain. Unfailingly laidback, Moshi has some good restaurants and a colourful market; it's also the centre of one of Tanzania's major coffee-growing regions, with coffee tours available run by many local operators.</p>]]><p><b>Peruse Mwenge Carvers' Market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located 8km (5 miles) north of Dar es Salaam on the way to the northern beaches, this fascinating market has vendors selling their beautiful handmade wares. This is the place to buy famous Makonde woodcarvings – the Makonde people are considered to be some of the finest carvers in East Africa.</p>]]><p><b>Reach the summit of Mount Meru</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The lower slopes of Mount Meru (4566m/14980ft) in Arusha National Park are one of the most easily accessible places to spot buffalo, giraffe, black and white colobus monkey and warthog. The three-day trek to the summit of the striking mountain is an equally challenging and cheaper option than climbing Kilimanjaro, though far less popular.</p>]]><p><b>Relax on Zanzibar's beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Zanzibar's magnificent swathes of palm-backed white sandy beaches make for a wonderful beach getaway. The many resorts (from simple beach cottages to 5-star luxury) offer a range of activities, such as diving, snorkelling and sunset cruises on white-sailed <em>dhows. </em>Fine seafood and a cold sundowner are never far away.</p>]]><p><b>Safari in the Serengeti</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Serengeti is undoubtedly the most iconic national park in all of Africa, and a safari through the astonishing endless plains is an absolute must on any visit to Tanzania, especially during the famed wildebeest migration (roughly November to May). Close sightings of the Big Five (lion, elephant, buffalo, leopard and rhino) are almost guaranteed.</p>]]><p><b>Scuba dive off the Swahili Coast</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The technicolour marine life surrounding the idyllic coral islands of Zanzibar and Pemba makes them a hotspot for scuba diving. There are countless dive sites around the islands, which are protected as marine national parks and reserves. The warm Indian Ocean has clear visibility to see all kinds of coral, brightly coloured fish, dolphins, manta rays, turtles and sharks.</p>]]><p><b>See the Great Migration from the air</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The endless plains of the Serengeti come to life in the early hours of dawn. Seeing the park wake with the rising sun from a hot air balloon is one of the world's great natural spectacles. The annual migration of some two million wildebeest followed by their predators, roughly from November to May, is the best time to hitch a ride.</p>]]><p><b>Spot the Big Five in Ngorongoro Crater</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At 610m (2,000 ft) deep, 20km (12.5 miles) wide, the Ngorongoro Crater is the largest intact caldera in the world. Another of Tanzania's UNESCO World Heritage Sites, the crater is packed with almost every species of African plains mammal including the densest lion population in Africa.</p>]]><p><b>Stroll through Stone Town</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Zanzibar's Stone Town was the hub of the ancient spice trade, and once served as the maritime metropolis of East Africa, variously ruled by Shirazi Persians, the Portuguese, the Omani Arabs and British. Today, this UNESCO World Heritage Site remains a labyrinth of narrow, winding streets lined with exotic shops, bazaars, colonial mansions, mosques and squares.</p>]]><p><b>Take a trip back in time at Bagamoyo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The ancient town of Bagamoyo was a one-time slave port and terminus for the trade caravans. The town mosque and Arab tombs date from the 18th century, while there are a number of churches and mission buildings dating from the 19th century and later buildings from when the Germans occupied the town. Pick up a guide for a walk around the town, which is an easy day excursion from Dar es Salaam.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the beauty of Tarangire National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Tarangire National Park, only 130km (80 miles) from Arusha is easily accessible but often overlooked in favour of the better-known Northern Circuit parks. However, a game drive here rewards with unusual scenery of giant silver-trunked baobab trees, and the Tarangire River is a favourite haunt for wildebeest, zebra, eland and elephant.</p>]]><p><b>Track chimpanzees on Lake Tanganyika</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Troops of wild chimpanzees thrive in the Gombe Stream and Mahale national parks on the shores of Lake Tanganyika. Both parks have spectacular scenery with mountains and forested valleys plunging into the lake, and both are among just a small handful of places in Africa to see chimps in their natural habitat. Treks can be arranged to follow the troops, with sightings almost guaranteed.</p>]]><p><b>Walk on the wild side in Ruaha National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of only a handful of parks in Tanzania that allows walking safaris, Ruaha National Park boasts unparalleled scenery. It's Tanzania's second-largest park, and it's also one of its wildest. Ruaha is known for its exceptionally large herds of elephant and buffalo and is also one of the best places in Tanzania to see the critically-endangered African wild dog.</p>]]><p><b>Watch bull fighting on Pemba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The pretty and pristine island of Pemba is famed for its own traditional brand of bull fighting. Unlike its Spanish counterpart, this hangover from the days of Portuguese rule in the 16th and 17th centuries does not involve killing the bulls, and is a test of bravery for local livestock farmers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$23.06 billion (estimate 2010).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Gold, cotton, coffee, cashew nuts and sisal.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Industrial raw materials, consumer goods, machinery and transport equipment, chemicals and crude oil.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China, India, Japan, United Arab Emirates and Germany.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tanzania&rsquo;s economy relies heavily on agriculture; the sector employs around 80% of the working population and cash crops are one of the country's main export earners, which accounts for nearly half of the country&rsquo;s GDP. Mineral production (gold, diamonds and tanzanite) has grown significantly in the last decade, and mining represents Tanzania's biggest source of economic growth, provides over 3% of the GDP and accounts for half of Tanzania's exports.</p>
<p>Coal, phosphates, gypsum, tin and other ores are also extracted. Reserves of uranium, nickel, silver and natural gas have been located and the mining sector is expected to be developed further to capitalise on these resources. The industrial sector is one of the smallest in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/africa">Africa</a>, concentrated in agricultural processing and light consumer goods such as sugar processing, brewing and textiles. Tourism is thought to be worth around US$950 million annually to the Tanzanian economy and ranks as the second foreign exchange earner after agriculture.</p>
<p>On the whole, the economy has improved steadily since the mid-1990s. In 2006, Tanzania signed economic agreements with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> for development assistance in the communications, transport and health sectors and saw the African Development Bank write off US$640 million of Tanzania's foreign debt. More recently, with continued help from donor assistance and a boost from an increase in gold exports, Tanzania's economy has picked up the pace. GDP was a healthy 6.5% in 2010, with inflation estimated to be around 7.2%.</p>
<p>Many of the large hotels in Dar es Salaam and Arusha can accommodate conferences. The Arusha International Conference Centre (AICC) (<a href="http://www.aicc.co.tz" target="_blank">www.aicc.co.tz</a>) is the largest conference facility in the country and has several rooms that can cater for 20-1,000 people, and this has been the site of some historic events of East Africa's modern history including the Rwandan War Tribunals and Burundi peace negotiations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normal courtesies should be shown when visiting local businesspeople. English is the language used for business. Lightweight suits are usually expected to be worn for meetings. Appointments are generally necessary.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1400-1630; Sat 0800-1230.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Tanzania Chamber of Commerce, Industry and Agriculture</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (22) 211 9436
					Website:http://www.tccia.com/
					Address: ,PO Box 9713,Dar es Salaam,]]><b>Arusha International Conference Centre (AICC)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (27) 250 2953
					Website:http://www.aicc.co.tz/
					Address: ,PO Box 3081,Arusha,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Food in Tanzania varies greatly depending on where you are in the country. On the mainland and away from the coast, most restaurants serve Tanzanian dishes that usually consist of meat stews or grilled chicken, accompanied by staples including chips, green bananas or <em>ugali </em>(maize meal porridge eaten all over Africa).</p>
<p>Dar es Salaam is a fairly cosmopolitan city with a good choice of local and international restaurants. Many Tanzanian towns, including the capital, have a significant population of second-generation immigrants from the Indian sub-continent, and restaurants serving Indian dishes are not uncommon.</p>
<p>On the coast, the Indian Ocean provides a full range of seafood, and the Swahili culinary style is delicately flavoured by spices and coconut milk and features fragrant rice, grilled fish and prawn curries. Tropical fruits are abundant here, as are the delicious fresh juices made from them.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Nyama choma:</strong> Barbecued meat.<br />
<strong>Ugali:</strong> Maize meal porridge, a staple usually served with stews or meat.<br />
<strong>Mandazi:</strong> A fried dough ball that resembles a savoury doughnut.<br />
<strong>Kachumbari:</strong> Spicy tomato relish served with meat.<br />
<strong>Wali wa nazi:</strong> Rice cooked with coconut milk.<br />
<strong>Mchuzi wa Kamba:</strong> Prawn curry with tomatoes.<br />
<strong>Matoke:</strong> Plantains, generally boiled and served with stews.<br />
<strong>Mishkaki:</strong> Spicy barbecued beef kebabs.<br />
<strong>Konyagi:</strong> A popular, cheap, and frightfully strong gin.<br />
<strong>Duckling Dar es Salaam:</strong> A Tanzanian delicacy, made from duckling cooked with tomatoes, red peppers and onions.<br />
<strong>Chai:</strong> Tanzanian tea, usually served sweet, milky and very hot in small glasses.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>In Tanzania tipping is not expected, but a tip of around 10% for good service is greatly appreciated by restaurant and hotel staff, who generally receive very low pay.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nightlife is limited in Tanzania, but Dar es Salaam does have several nightclubs, cabaret venues and cinemas. Generally, nightlife is centred on the top tourist hotels and restaurants. All along the coast, and particularly on Zanzibar, hotels and beach bars often feature bands at the weekends and dance floors right on the beach. Quite often, traditional tribal dancing and drumming is performed in the safari lodges and beach resorts. Rowdy full moon parties have become popular on Zanzibar's backpacker-focused northern beaches.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pick up African crafts and curios at most popular tourist centres. Dar es Salaam, Arusha and Stone Town on Zanzibar are dotted with curio shops, markets and bazaars, and main roads near parks and reserves, and the coast roads behind beach resorts, all have plenty of roadside stalls. Items to buy include African drums, batiks, basket-ware, soapstone knick-knacks, handmade chess sets, paintings of Masai tribes and Serengeti landscapes in the popular <em>Tingatinga</em> style, and large wooden carvings of animals or salad bowls fashioned from a single piece of teak, mninga or ebony. <br /><br />Masai items such as beaded jewellery, decorated gourds and the distinctive red-checked blankets worn by all Masai men make good souvenirs. <em>Kangas</em> and <em>kikois</em> are sarongs worn by women and men respectively and are often in bright colours and patterns. These are made into other items including clothes, cushion covers and bags. In Zanzibar, find old tiles, antique bowls and the famous carved wooden Zanzibar chests (once used by the Sultans to store their possessions, but today ornate replicas), and pick up packets of Zanzibar's famous spices in Stone Town, as well as on a spice tour. <br /><br />A Tanzanian speciality is the semi-precious stone called tanzanite, which ranges from deep blue to light purple and is only found around Arusha. Tanzanite jewellery can be seen in upmarket curio and jewellers shops in Arusha, Dar es Salaam and Zanzibar's Stone Town.<br /><br />Whilst most prices in shops are set, the exception are curio shops where a little good-natured bargaining is possible, especially if it's quiet or you are buying a number of things. Bargaining is very much expected in the street markets.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1730; Sat 0830-1230. Some tourist shops open on Sunday, while some Muslim-owned supermarkets and other businesses close on Friday afternoons but may also be open on Sunday. On Zanzibar, some shops close for a siesta from around 1200-1500 but stay open later until around 1900. In the larger cities markets are open daily 0800-1800.</p><p>CITES (Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora) was established to prevent trade in endangered species. Attempts to smuggle controlled products can result in confiscation, fines and even imprisonment. International trade in elephant ivory, rhino horn, sea turtle products and the skins of wild cats, such as leopard, is illegal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tanzania has a vast spread of accommodation options, ranging from luxurious game lodges in game-filled national parks, heritage buildings in the winding alleys of Stone Town, sprawling resorts and rustic beach huts lining Zanzibar's beaches, and extending down-budget all the way to a plethora of middling mid-range hotels and the cheap, rough-around-the-edges guest houses.</p>
<p>Hotels in Tanzania vary from superbly finished, expensive luxury hotels with all the trimmings found in the cities and popular tourist areas, to mid-range generic hotels favoured by local business people, and cheap board and lodgings in the regional towns, which, although sometimes adequate, have little atmosphere and can have security issues.</p>
<p>The island of Zanzibar has probably the best assortment of accommodation choices, from luxury resorts to beach bungalows and budget hotels. On the beach are large and modern, fully-contained resorts aimed at package holidaymakers, while the capital of Stone Town boasts many hotels housed in converted, atmospheric heritage buildings, often with ornate four-poster beds and decorated with antiques and Persian carpets. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Referred to locally as 'board and lodgings', these are often offshoots of local bars and provide very cheap accommodation, but offer little more than a bed in a bare room with a door that may or may not lock. At these you will want to ensure rooms are clean, there is water in the bathrooms and special attention to possessions should be paid while staying there. These cannot be booked in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tanzania has a vast spread of accommodation options, ranging from luxurious game lodges in game-filled national parks, heritage buildings in the winding alleys of Stone Town, sprawling resorts and rustic beach huts lining Zanzibar's beaches, and extending down-budget all the way to a plethora of middling mid-range hotels and the cheap, rough-around-the-edges guest houses.</p>
<p>Hotels in Tanzania vary from superbly finished, expensive luxury hotels with all the trimmings found in the cities and popular tourist areas, to mid-range generic hotels favoured by local business people, and cheap board and lodgings in the regional towns, which, although sometimes adequate, have little atmosphere and can have security issues.</p>
<p>The island of Zanzibar has probably the best assortment of accommodation choices, from luxury resorts to beach bungalows and budget hotels. On the beach are large and modern, fully-contained resorts aimed at package holidaymakers, while the capital of Stone Town boasts many hotels housed in converted, atmospheric heritage buildings, often with ornate four-poster beds and decorated with antiques and Persian carpets. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tanzania has a vast spread of accommodation options, ranging from luxurious game lodges in game-filled national parks, heritage buildings in the winding alleys of Stone Town, sprawling resorts and rustic beach huts lining Zanzibar's beaches, and extending down-budget all the way to a plethora of middling mid-range hotels and the cheap, rough-around-the-edges guest houses.</p>
<p>Hotels in Tanzania vary from superbly finished, expensive luxury hotels with all the trimmings found in the cities and popular tourist areas, to mid-range generic hotels favoured by local business people, and cheap board and lodgings in the regional towns, which, although sometimes adequate, have little atmosphere and can have security issues.</p>
<p>The island of Zanzibar has probably the best assortment of accommodation choices, from luxury resorts to beach bungalows and budget hotels. On the beach are large and modern, fully-contained resorts aimed at package holidaymakers, while the capital of Stone Town boasts many hotels housed in converted, atmospheric heritage buildings, often with ornate four-poster beds and decorated with antiques and Persian carpets. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Before leaving home, visit the doctor or a travel clinic for advice on vaccinations, malaria prophylactics and general advice. Basic traveller vaccinations recommended include yellow fever, tetanus, typhoid and hepatitis A. It is vital to take out comprehensive travel medical insurance, and it is essential that is should include repatriation to your home country in the event of an emergency. There are a wide variety of policies to choose from, so shop around. If you are going to be active in Tanzania (mountain climbing or scuba-diving for example), ensure the policy has adequate provision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some good private hospitals in Dar es Salaam, Arusha and Stone Town on Zanzibar, but facilities are rudimentary outside of these and medicines are often unavailable. All treatment must be paid for in advance. Tanzania&amp;rsquo;s emergency telephone number (ambulance, fire and police) is 111. The best private hospital in the country is the Aga Khan Hospital, Ocean Road, Dar es Salaam, (tel: (022) 211 5151; &lt;a href="http://www.agakhanhospitals.org" target="_blank"&gt;www.agakhanhospitals.org&lt;/a&gt;). However, for cases of extreme emergencies or surgery, visitors with adequate health insurance will be transferred to a private hospital in Nairobi, Kenya which has the best medical facilities in East Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malaria: The risk of contracting malaria is prevalent throughout Tanzania and prophylactics should be taken (take expert advice before you leave home). Symptoms can start as something resembling a severe attack of flu. If you develop any symptoms even after several weeks after your return home, seek medical advice. Travellers should take precautions against mosquito bites &amp;ndash; cover-up at dusk and use insect repellent. Almost all hotels in Tanzania have air-conditioning and/or fans which help ward off mosquitoes and most tourist-class hotels have mosquito nets over the beds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Altitude sickness: This can strike from about 3,000m (9,800ft) and is caused by lack of oxygen and should be a consideration for anyone climbing Mt Kilimanjaro. Symptoms include heart pounding, shortness of breath and dizziness. The best way of preventing it is a relatively slow ascent - some time spent walking at medium altitude, getting fit and acclimatizing is helpful. To decrease the symptoms, an immediate descent is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Travellers should use bottled water for drinking, brushing teeth, washing vegetables and reconstituting powdered milk. Ice should be avoided. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Other food hygiene precautions should be strictly observed if eating in a local restaurant, but visitors should encounter few problems if eating in upmarket restaurants and hotels. Eating snacks from street stalls (common in Tanzania) is not advised, but if items are fresh and cooked well (and the same could be said about buffets in tourist hotels) then you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t encounter any problems. If you get traveller&amp;rsquo;s diarrhoea, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t usually last more than 48 hours, the key treatment is rehydration. If it is more persistent, then seek medical advice.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Rabies is prevalent in Tanzania (in monkeys as well as domestic animals). There is a high incidence of HIV/AIDS. Avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water as there is a risk of bilharzia (prevalent in both lakes Victoria and Tanganyika); swimming pools that are well chlorinated and maintained are safe. On the coast and islands, there are sea urchins so take care when snorkelling and diving – if possible wear plastic shoes. If diving, ensure you are fit to do so. Be aware that serious diving injuries may require time in a decompression chamber and the nearest one is in Kenya – check that your medical insurance covers this eventuality.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Zanzibar Revolution Day :
							2018<br/>12 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Union Day :
							26 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Saba Saba (Dar es salaam International Trade Fair Day) :
							07 July </p><p>Nane Nane (Farmers' Day) :
							08 August </p><p>Nyerere Day :
							14 October </p><p>Independence and Republic Day :
							09 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Tanzania by travellers over 17 without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 250g of cigarettes, cigars and tobacco (combined weight).<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits or wine.<br />
&bull; 500ml of perfume and eau de toilette, of which no more than a quarter may be perfume.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unlicensed firearms and ammunition.</p>
<p>Plants and plant products require a phytosanitary certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The export of gold, diamonds and tanzanite unless bought from a licensed jeweller is prohibited. Exporting souvenirs made from wildlife skins (this includes reptiles), shells and coral is forbidden.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tanzanian Shilling (TZS; symbol TSh). Notes are in denominations of TSh10,000, 5000, 2,000, 1,000 and 500. Coins are in denominations of TSh200, 100, 50, 20 and 10 but these are worth very little and are rarely used. In Kiswahili, it is <em>shilingi</em> and written prices are often denoted with the symbol /=; i.e. 100/= is the same as TSh100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US dollars, Pound sterling and Euros may be changed at banks and bureaux de change. However, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars are the best currency to take to Tanzania as it is widely accepted alongside TSh to pay for hotel bills, souvenirs and flights, and is needed to purchase visas on arrival and pay for park entry fees. Bring newer notes – because of the prevalence of forgery, many places (including banks and bureaux de change) do not accept US dollar bills printed before 2005. Large dollar bills (such as US$50 and US$100) command a better exchange rate than smaller ones. Ensure bills are not torn or damaged.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most top-end hotels, safari lodges, airlines and tour operators accept Visa and MasterCard (American Express and Diners Club less so), though a commission of 2-5% is usually charged. Budget hotels and most restaurants and shops do not accept credit cards, and they are rarely accepted for payment outside the main tourist areas.</p><p>Cash easily can be withdrawn from ATMs using Visa or MasterCard. Any sizeable town has at least one bank with an ATM, and there are ATMs at the larger airports. ATMs generally only dispense notes in increments of TSh 10,000 and these larger notes are often hard for people to change – hoard smaller change whenever possible to pay for taxi fares, snacks, souvenirs and the like.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>May be cashed in some banks (try Barclays) or bureaux de change in Tanzania's major cities and Zanzibar, but they are less common as they once used to be, attract a hefty commission and the process is time consuming. Additionally, some places may ask to see original purchase receipts for traveller's cheques. If you are nervous about travelling with lots of hard cash, bring enough to get you started then use ATMs to withdraw local currency off a credit card.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0830-1530; Sat 0830-1300. Bureaux de change have longer hours and in the cities and in Stone Town on Zanzibar are open on Sundays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for at least six months beyond the date of entry to Tanzania is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>
<p>While still part of Tanzania, Zanzibar and other islands are administered autonomously; they have their own immigration procedures and you will be asked to show your passport on entry and exit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visas costing US$30 are available for those travelling through Tanzania to other destinations within a 14-day period. An onward ticket or tour itinerary/confirmation and sufficient funds for transit are required.</p>
<p>Please note that you can only obtain a transit visa to Tanzania at the point of entry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry tourist visa on arrival: US$50 (the exception is US citizens who must pay US$100). For British, the fee is &pound;40 if applying in advance. Please see the different visa types and costs below.</p>
<p><strong>If applying for a Tanzania visa in America</strong> <br />
Please note that Americans can only obtain a tourist visa to Tanzania at US$100 <br />
Single-entry (other nationals) US$50 <br />
Multiple-entry US$100 <br />
Business visa US$250 <br />
Transit visa &ndash; please see the information in the Transit section below. <br />
Please note that the Tanzania Embassy in the United States only accepts visa fees in credit cards except American Express, money order or a company check only.</p>
<p><strong>If applying for a Tanzania visa in the UK</strong> <br />
Single-entry &pound;40 (&pound;60 for same-day service) <br />
Double-entry &pound;70 (&pound;90 for same-day service) <br />
6-month Multiple-entry &pound;80 (&pound;100 for same-day service) <br />
1-year Multiple-entry &pound;100 (&pound;120 for same-day service) <br />
Business Single-entry &pound;180 (&pound;200 for same-day service) <br />
Transit visa &ndash; please see the information in the Transit section below.<br />
Please note that the Tanzania High Commission in the UK only accepts visa fees in credit or debit cards except American Express, bank transfer or banker's draft only.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry (business and tourist) visa is valid for three months from the date of issue. Multiple-entry visa is valid for either six or 12 months from the date of issue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can obtain visas from the embassy or high commission before you travel. You can also obtain them at any point of entry (airports and land borders) on arrival. This is a much easier option but you will need to pay for them in cash in US Dollars. Ensure that you have sufficient blank pages in your passport (the minimum for entry into Tanzania is two).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Residence permits are granted to foreign nationals if they are employed by a Tanzanian company, or working long-term as missionaries or volunteers. You must apply for these through the Immigration Services Department (<a href="http://www.immigration.go.tz">www.immigration.go.tz</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow three working days (applications in person) or 10 days (postal applications)&nbsp;for visa processing if applying in advance. You can pay an additional fee for a 24-hour or same-day service.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Onward ticket or tour itinerary/confirmation, or proof of funds eg credit card, is required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can extend your visas for three months at a time up to a maximum of six months at the immigration office in Dar es Salaam.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-6.306987]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[34.854000]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>945,087 sq km (364,900 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>55,155,473 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>54 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dodoma.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Federal republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The United Republic of Tanzania lies on the east coast of Africa and is bordered by Kenya and Uganda to the north; by Burundi, Rwanda and the Democratic Republic of Congo to the west; by the Indian Ocean to the east; and by Zambia, Malawi and Mozambique to the south. The Tanzanian mainland is divided into several clearly defined regions: the coastal plains, which vary in width from 16 to 64km (10 to 39 miles) and have lush, tropical vegetation; the Masai Steppe in the north, 213 to 1,067m (698 to 3,500ft) above sea level, which gives rise to two prominent mountains, Kilimanjaro, 5,895m (19,341ft) above sea level and Africa's highest peak, and Mount Meru, 4,565m (14,973ft); and there's a high plateau known as the Southern Highlands in the southern area towards Zambia and Lake Malawi.</p>
<p>Savannah and bush cover over half the country, and semi-desert accounts for the remaining land area, with the exception of the coastal plains. Over 53,000 sq km (20,463 sq miles) is inland water, mostly lakes formed in the Rift Valley and Tanzania's share of Lake Victoria and Lake Tanganyika, both on its western border. Lake Victoria covers 69,490 sq km (26,832 sq miles), which is Africa's largest lake and 49% of it lies in Tanzania. With maximum depths of 1,470m (4,821ft), Lake Tanganyika is estimated to be the deepest lake in Africa and is 673km (420 miles) long and averages 50km (31 miles) across; 41% of its area lies in Tanzania. The United Republic of Tanzania includes the islands of Zanzibar and Pemba, about 45km (28 miles) off the coast to the northeast of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>About 40-45% of Tanzania's population is Christian and about 35-40% are Muslim (most of which live along the coast and Zanzibar and the other islands). A small number follow traditional religions and there are some Asian communities including Sikhs and Hindus.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>When meeting and parting, hands are always shaken; this applies throughout the country in both rural and urban areas. It is the convention to use the right hand, not the left, to shake hands or pass or receive anything. The standard greeting of 'hello' is <em>jambo</em>. People are delighted if visitors can greet them in Kiswahili. Dress is on the whole casual but a smart appearance for formal occasions such as a business meeting or upmarket restaurant is always appreciated.</p>
<p>Because of its Muslim influence, the coast is a little more conservative, and away from the beach it is advised to dress respectably and cover up bare arms and legs. Alcohol is only available in the tourist areas on Zanzibar, where it is also considered highly impolite to eat, drink or smoke in public during daylight hours when people are fasting during Ramadan (the exception to this is in the tourist hotels and restaurants).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are mostly used, but plugs with three round pins are also in use. Power cuts are common in the rainy season, though most large hotels and businesses have back-up generators.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President John Magufuli since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President John Magufuli since 2015. Zanzibar is semi-autonomous and has its own parliament and president (President Ali Mohamed Shein since 2010).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are over 120 ethnic groups on the Tanzanian mainland, most of whom migrated from other parts of Africa over the millennia, whilst on the coast, the Swahili people originated from an eclectic mix of traders &ndash; Arabic, Persian and Chinese among others &ndash; who arrived from as early as the 8th century.</p>
<p>The first European arrival was the Portuguese explorer, Vasco da Gama, who visited the coast in the late-15th century, after which most of the littoral region came under Portuguese control. The Portuguese also controlled Zanzibar until 1699, when they were ousted from the island by Omani Arabs.</p>
<p>In the late-19th century, along with Rwanda and Burundi, Tanganyika was absorbed into the colony of German East Africa until the end of WWI. Then, following the German defeat, it was administered by the British under successive League of Nations and United Nations mandates.</p>
<p>Tanganyika became independent in 1961, under charismatic socialist leader, Julius Nyerere, who was President until 1985. In 1964, Tanganyika joined with Zanzibar and became Tanzania. Since independence, Chama Cha Mapinduzi (CCM), has remained the ruling party.</p>
<p>Tanzania proved itself an active player in regional politics, by giving support to anti-apartheid movements in South Africa, and it intervened militarily in Uganda in 1979, to overthrow the Amin regime.&nbsp;In 1985, Nyerere retired and was replaced by Ali Hassan Mwinyi, who introduced market forces into the economy and on the political front, amendments to the constitution allowing for the introduction of a multiparty system.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the CCM comfortably won the 1995 elections, when Benjamin Mkapa became president. In August 1998, Tanzania was the scene of a major terrorist incident when the US embassy in Dar es Salaam was bombed. October 1999 was marked by the death of ex-president Julius Nyerere.</p>
<p>Mkapa won a further term of office in 2000 amid vote rigging and intimidation allegations, particularly on Zanzibar. Again in the 2005 election, Zanzibar experienced tension and some violence when the CCM candidate Jakaya Kikwete was declared the winner, a result disputed by the Civic United Front (CUF), which claimed they&rsquo;d won the majority of votes. However, negotiations between the two parties in 2009 ushered in peaceful elections in 2010 following a power-sharing agreement.</p>
<p>In 2015, John Magufuli became Tanzania&rsquo;s new president and has been praised for his no-nonsense approach and zero tolerance towards corruption and frivolous government expenditure.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Tanzania gained world fame when the celebrated American author Ernest Hemingway wrote about his time in the country in &lsquo;The Green Hills of Africa&rsquo;.<br />
&bull; Some of the earliest remains of humans were recovered in Olduvai Gorge in Tanzania.<br />
&bull; Tanzania shares a national anthem with South Africa and Zimbabwe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the United Republic of Tanzania in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 884 1080.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.tanzaniaembassy-us.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 884 1080.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1232 22nd St NW<br/>Washington<br/>20037<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[High Commission for the United Republic of Tanzania in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7569 1470.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://tanzaniahighcommission.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7569 1470.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1230 (visa applications) and 1400-1530 (visa collection only).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Tanzania House, 3 Stratford Place<br/>London <br/>WC1 1AS<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Tanzania]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(022) 229 0000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukintanzania.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(022) 229 0000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thu 0730-1530; Fri 0730-1330.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Kivukoni<br/>Umoja House, Garden Ave<br/>Tanzania<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you close your eyes and conjure up the quintessential romantic image of Africa, what you&rsquo;ll most likely imagine is Tanzania: the drama of the wildebeest migration along a seemingly-endless savannah; the incongruous snow and glaciers of Mt Kilimanjaro; the iconic and statuesque Maasai warriors; the exotic palm-fringed beaches on the spice islands of Zanzibar. It&rsquo;s all here.</p>
<p>Tanzania boasts some of the most impressive national parks and game reserves in Africa. The Serengeti National Park is considered the continent&rsquo;s premier spot to see wildlife roam unheeded across vast open plains.</p>
<p>Nearby, within the steep walls of the Ngorongoro Crater lies the most densely concentrated population of African mammals on earth. Not to be forgotten, the Selous Game Reserve is larger than Switzerland, and is wild, remote and still virtually untouched by humans.</p>
<p>Even further from the beaten path are parks in the extreme west of the country which offer the unique opportunity to track chimpanzees in their natural habitat on the fringes of Lake Tanganyika, one of Africa&rsquo;s Great Lakes.</p>
<p>Beyond its safari stalwarts, Tanzania has no less than 804km (503 miles) of sublime coastline and pearly-white beaches with some magnificent islands offshore. Known as the Swahili Coast, this was a favoured stop on ancient trading routes between the Indian sub-continent and the Middle East. Spices, jewels and slaves once passed through, bringing with them a m&eacute;lange of cultural riches that remain today.</p>
<p>Tanzania&rsquo;s not short on mountains either. The striking and snow-capped Mt Kilimanjaro is Africa's tallest at 5,895m (19,341ft) and climbing it is an unforgettable experience. Its slightly smaller sister Mt Meru is arguably even prettier, and a quicker climb.</p>
<p>Tanzania is home to more than 120 different ethnic groups and cultures, but it has seen little of the ethnic or religious-based violence that has afflicted certain other nations in the region. In fact the country is an inherently peaceful place and embraces its multicultural heritage, which adds to its broad appeal.</p><p>If you close your eyes and conjure up the quintessential romantic image of Africa, what you&rsquo;ll most likely imagine is Tanzania: the drama of the wildebeest migration along a seemingly-endless savannah; the incongruous snow and glaciers of Mt Kilimanjaro; the iconic and statuesque Maasai warriors; the exotic palm-fringed beaches on the spice islands of Zanzibar. It&rsquo;s all here.&nbsp;Tanzania boasts some of the most impressive national parks and game reserves in Africa. The Serengeti National Park is considered the continent&rsquo;s premier spot to see wildlife roam unheeded across vast open plains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
