<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Tibet" ColCode="" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Tibet]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>High altitude and strong sun mean that Tibet generally has warm days and cool nights. That said temperatures can fluctuate dramatically and you should bring warm clothing even in summer. Despite being called the 'Land of Snows,' there's actually not that much snowfall, even in winter! Rainfall is minimal and occurs mostly in July and August.  The best time to visit Tibet is between April and October. High season is considered to be July, August and the weeks following the national holidays of May 1 and October 1. The shoulder season months of April and May are good times to visit if you want to avoid the crowds. The best months for trekking are July, August and September. Winter is very cold and accommodation and eating options are limited but if you are well equipped, it can be a spectacular time to visit Tibet.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flights to Tibet are operated by Air China (<a href="http://www.airchina.com" target="_blank">www.airchina.com</a>), China Eastern (<a href="http://www.ceair.com">www.ceair.com</a>), China Southern (<a href="http://www.csair.com" target="_blank">www.csair.com</a>), Shenzhen Airlines (<a href="http://www.shenzhenair.com">www.shenzhenair.com</a>), Sichuan Airlines (<a href="http://www.sichuanair.com">www.sichuanair.com</a>) and other domestic airlines which fly into Lhasa from Chinese cities and from <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/nepal/kathmandu/">Kathmandu</a> in <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/nepal/">Nepal</a>. High season is June to October, with demand spiking during national holidays in early May and early October.</p>
<p>There are only a couple of domestic flights inside Tibet and very few travelers use them to get around the country. Weekly flights run from Lhasa to Qamdo (Changdu) in the east and to Ngari (Ali) in the far west. In general it's better to travel overland in order to help with acclimatisation.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/europe/united-kingdom/england/london/">London</a> - 19 hours 30 minutes (including stopovers); <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/north-america/united-states-of-america/new-york-state/new-york-city/">New York</a> - 24 hours (including stopovers).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the price of the air ticket.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The remarkable but controversial Qinghai-Tibet railway line is the world's highest, complete with piped oxygen in the cabins to guard against altitude sickness. Trains run to Lhasa from Xining (21 hours), Lanzhou (24 hours), <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/beijing/">Beijing</a> (40 hours), <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/shanghai/">Shanghai</a>&nbsp;(47 hours) and several other Chinese cities. An extension to Tibet's second city, Xigaz&ecirc;, opened in 2014 and is 3 hours by train.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Road is the primary way to get around Tibet. Main roads are paved and in good condition and a modern tarmac road now reaches as far as Mt Kailash in the far west. Roads to the east are rougher and are affected by annual monsoon landslides.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Lhasa and several other cities have public telephone booths where you can make fairly cheap international phone calls (around £0.35 per minute to the UK). The cheapest way to make calls is through Skype, though not all Internet cafés are equipped with the software. Another way to call internationally is to buy a pre-paid calling card, available from most convenience stores in units of ¥20, 50, 100 and 200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tibet's mobile phone coverage is good and you can even make phone calls from Everest Base Camp! Roaming agreements exist with most major international mobile phone companies. Alternatively, you can buy a prepaid GSM SIM card (from China Mobile) that allows you to use your mobile like a local phone with a new number. You'll need your passport to register. Buy scratch cards to top up your balance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafés can be found in most towns, and Wi-Fi is increasingly available at hotels and cafés in Lhasa. Access is cheap and usually reliable but you may need to present your passport to gain internet access. The state routinely blocks access to sites run by the exiled Tibetan government, human rights groups and some foreign news organisations such as the BBC. Postings by bloggers are closely monitored.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>China and Tibet's media is tightly controlled by the national and provincial leadership. Access to foreign news providers is limited and re-broadcasting and the use of satellite receivers is restricted; shortwave radio broadcasts are jammed and websites are blocked. The only English language magazines or newspapers available in Lhasa are of the Chinese propaganda variety.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Changtang</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Home to herds of wild ass, dramatic grasslands and turquoise salt lakes, Tibet's remotest, emptiest and most beautiful corner is its northwestern wilderness.  Unless you are mounting a full-on expedition, the best way is to pass through along the northern route to Mt Kailash, preferably camping at the lovely lakes en route.</p>]]><p><b>Everest Base Camp</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Don't tell the Nepalese, but the views of Everest from the northern Tibetan side are much more dramatic than from its southern neighbour. Bed down at Base Camp, visit Tibet's highest monastery or just stare at the North Face of the world's highest peak. Adventurers can trek in from Tingri or Kharta.</p>]]><p><b>Ganden Monastery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The spectacularly situated monastery at Ganden offers perhaps the best day trip from Lhasa. Almost completely destroyed in the 1950s the complex has been largely restored, though political tensions remain. A lovely <em>kora</em> (pilgrim circuit) that offers incredible views only adds to the site's charm.</p>]]><p><b>Guge Kingdom</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Amateur archaeologists will feel their pulse quicken at this forgotten centre of Buddhist culture hidden in Tibet's remote far west. Underground staircases and tunnels link halls of spectacular Kashmiri-influenced Buddhist art, while the surrounding hillsides of cave complexes and crumbling ruins offer some genuine exploration.</p>]]><p><b>Gyantse Kumbum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This unique eight-storied stupa is one of Tibet's architectural masterpieces. Paths wind around and up through the stupa, passing dozens of niches filled with impressive Buddhist art and iconography. Views from the roof look towards Gyantse fort, taken by the British army under Francis Younghusband in 1904.</p>]]><p><b>Jokhang Temple, Lhasa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The sacred Jokhang complex is Tibet's spiritual heart. Join the awed Tibetan pilgrims as they spin prayer wheels and shuffle silently around medieval chapels thick with the smell of yak butter and juniper incense.</p>]]><p><b>Mount Kailash</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sacred to over a billion people, iconic Mt Kailash is perhaps Asia's most enigmatic mountain, drawing pilgrims from across the world on a rugged but stunning overland trip to Tibet's far west. Join pilgrims on the three or four-day trek around the mountain before relaxing on the spectacular shores of Lake Manasarovar.</p>]]><p><b>Nam-tso</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Tibet's most spectacular natural sights, this huge salt lake sits like a chunk of turquoise beneath a line of snow-capped 7000m peaks. Dotted with black yak-hair nomads' tents and pilgrim paths it's a great opportunity to taste the rugged beauty of wild northern Tibet.</p>]]><p><b>Sakya Monastery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An easy detour off the Friendship Highway leads to this towering, brooding 13th-century monastery. Politically important for centuries, the monastery still contains towering Buddhist statues, a deeply atmospheric main prayer hall and plenty of surrounding chapels to explore.</p>]]><p><b>Samye Monastery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Situated between the mountains and the sandy banks of the Yarlung Tsangpo River, the uniquely circular walls of Tibet's oldest monastery enjoy one of the loveliest locations in Tibet. The fact that Samye lies at the end point of Tibet's most popular trek (four days from Ganden) just adds to the magic.</p>]]><p><b>Sera and Drepung Monasteries, Lhasa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tibet's two largest monasteries are almost miniature towns in themselves, complete with colleges, prayer halls, kitchens and debating halls. Don't miss the debating monks of Sera or the pilgrim circuit at Drepung.</p>]]><p><b>Sichuan-Tibet Highway</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The remote mountain roads through the Kham region of eastern Tibet are some of the world's wildest and most beautiful. The overland trip takes you through another Tibet; of forested alpine valleys and lush meadows, deep canyons and rich biodiversity. Neither easy nor cheap, this is an adventure of a lifetime.</p>]]><p><b>Take a trip along Friendship Highway</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The ancient 870km (541 miles) trade route between Lhasa and&nbsp;Zhangmu  ranks as one of the world's great road trips. The rollercoaster ride takes you over prayer-flag-strewn high passes and past huge lakes before dropping into the spicy lushness of the Indian subcontinent. Take a week and savour the many monastery sights en route.</p>]]><p><b>Tashilhunpo Monastery, Shigatse</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Shigatse has long been political and religious rival to Lhasa, so it's not surprising that the seat of Tibet's number two religious leader, the Panchen Lama, is a monastic town of huge golden stupas and a colourful annual ceremony that sees the hanging of a colossal&nbsp;<em>thangka</em> (religious painting).</p>]]><p><b>Visit Potala Palace, Lhasa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The breathtaking former abode of the Dalai Lamas towers like a fortress above Lhasa, while the labyrinthine monastery-like interior below houses some of Tibet's great treasures. Crowds can be thick so you need to book in advance a time to visit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US $20.5 billion (2017)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Livestock, traditional medicine, borax and other minerals, lumber, carpets</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Processed foods, building materials, electronics, mechanical products, motor vehicles</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Suits should be worn for business visits. Appointments should be made in advance and punctuality is expected. Business cards should be printed with a Chinese translation on the reverse and should be presented with both hands, while cards received should be studied and perhaps commented on. It is rude to put a business card directly into a pocket without giving it due attention, and a cardinal sin to put it in a back pocket. Business meals can last for several hours, and international visitors may well be expected to drink numerous toasts. A tolerance for tobacco smoke is an advantage.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800, midday break of one hour.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tibet&rsquo;s harsh mountain environment has led to a fairly simple cuisine. The staple foods for most Tibetans are dumplings and noodles, with a big meal out extending to fried yak dishes. Chinese restaurants are omnipresent and mostly offer spicy Szechuanese dishes or pork-free Muslim food from Gansu province. Backpacker-friendly restaurants in the main towns offer variants of western cuisine, from yakburgers to yak cheesecake.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Momos:</strong> Dumplings, steamed or sometimes fried, and filled with pockets of ground vegetables or yak meat. The classic Himalayan dish.<br />
<strong>Thukba:</strong> Thick noodle soup, one of several variants on noodle stew &ndash; depending on the shape of the noodles you may also find &lsquo;thanthuk&rsquo;and &lsquo;hipthuk&rsquo;.<br />
<strong>B&ouml; cha:</strong> Yak butter tea, the quintessential Tibetan drink. Tea leaves, boiling water, yak butter, salt and soda are churned up in a long tube to create a greasy, soupy consistency.<br />
&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Shrabtra: </strong>Stir fired meat with celery, carrots and green chilli.</p>
<p><strong>Gyurma: </strong>Sausage of yak or sheep&rsquo;s bood and roasted barley flour or rice.</p>
<p><strong>SokhamBexe: </strong>Fried dough with butter and minced meat &ndash; said to be a favourite of the Dalai Lama.<br />
<strong>Tsampa:</strong> Ground roasted barley is a staple in rural or nomad areas, often mixed with butter tea to make a filling gruel. Add sugar and milk or yoghurt for breakfast.</p>
<p><strong>ShaPhaley: </strong>Bread stuffed with seasoned beef and cabbage.</p>
<p><strong>Balepkorkun: </strong>Flatbread cooked on a skillet.</p>
<p><strong>Lunggoikatsa: </strong>Stewed sheep&rsquo;s head with curry and fennel.</p>
<p><strong>Gundain:</strong> Pastry made with barley grain and yeast, roasted flour, dry curd cheese, wild ginseng and brown sugar.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s generally not expected but 10% is appreciated in tourist restaurants.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;There is no minimum drinking age in China, but you must be 18 to buy it.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lhasa is the only Tibetan town that can claim any real nightlife. Most bars cater to Chinese karaoke but a few offer live blues and pop music. Several restaurants and cafes near the old town offer cheap backpacker hangouts where you can swap travellers tales until the wee hours. Most interesting are the nangma clubs, which feature a uniquely Tibetan mix of karaoke, live music and line dancing. Traditional music and dance is generally limited to festivals, though a couple of places in Lhasa offer staged floor shows aimed at tourists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tibet offers some unusual souvenirs. Essential pilgrim supplies such as prayer flags, hand-held prayer wheels and brass butter lamps are available at most monasteries and pilgrimage sites and make for quintessential souvenirs. Handicrafts include hand-painted <em>thangkas</em> (religious paintings) and cast metal statues of Buddhas and protector gods. Hand-woven carpets are making a comeback in Lhasa and Shigatse. Clothes like sheepskin-lined <em>chuba</em> (cloaks) and Tibetan-style cowboy hats, worn by nomads, are a good buy as are the stylish dresses worn by Tibetan women. Take care when shopping for turquoise jewellery, as much of it is fake. Lhasa has easily the best shopping selection, especially at the Barkhor Circuit and Lhasa Village Handicrafts, though you should definitely haggle at the former. Chinese-made trekking gear (some fake, some genuine) can be another good buy, with the selection now rivalling <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kathmandu">Kathmandu</a>. Note that antiques made before 1949 need a certificate before they can be taken out of the country. Don't buy skins or furs made from endangered animals such as leopard.</p><p>Daily 1000-2000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Tibet are mainly focussed upon Lhasa. Lhasa has a wide range of hotels ranging from youth hostels to stylish boutique guesthouses and top-end chains like Sheraton and St Regis. Outside of the main cities you'll likely find simple Chinese-style hotels, while out in remote areas you may find yourself in dormitory-style truck stops lacking running water or indoor toilets. In general standards are perfectly acceptable if somewhat uninspiring. A sleeping bag can be useful if you are heading off the beaten track.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Tibet are mainly focussed upon Lhasa. Lhasa has a wide range of hotels ranging from youth hostels to stylish boutique guesthouses and top-end chains like Sheraton and St Regis. Outside of the main cities you'll likely find simple Chinese-style hotels, while out in remote areas you may find yourself in dormitory-style truck stops lacking running water or indoor toilets. In general standards are perfectly acceptable if somewhat uninspiring. A sleeping bag can be useful if you are heading off the beaten track.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Tibet are mainly focussed upon Lhasa. Lhasa has a wide range of hotels ranging from youth hostels to stylish boutique guesthouses and top-end chains like Sheraton and St Regis. Outside of the main cities you'll likely find simple Chinese-style hotels, while out in remote areas you may find yourself in dormitory-style truck stops lacking running water or indoor toilets. In general standards are perfectly acceptable if somewhat uninspiring. A sleeping bag can be useful if you are heading off the beaten track.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical infrastructure is poor in Tibet and services are almost non-existent in rural areas outside of Lhasa. Medical insurance is strongly advised and should include evacuation insurance. The nearest recommended medical facilities are in Chengdu and &lt;a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/nepal/kathmandu/"&gt;Kathmandu&lt;/a&gt;. Traditional Tibetan medicinal treatments are available in Lhasa.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water used for drinking, brushing teeth or freezing should first be boiled or otherwise sterilised. Bottled water is widely and cheaply available. Be especially careful when eating at small street-side stalls or restaurants where standards of hygiene may not be high. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Altitude sickness is a serious risk in Tibet. Symptoms range from breathlessness and headaches to lack of coordination and vomiting and can occur at any elevation over around 3000m (almost everywhere in Tibet). It is extremely important to allow several days in Lhasa to acclimatise. For travel outside Lhasa arrange your itinerary so that you don't gain more than 500m of altitude per day.  As with other parts of &lt;a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt; hepatitis B is endemic. Sporadic outbreaks of avian influenza (bird flu) have resulted in a small number of human deaths. Rabies is present and a concern if travelling or trekking through rural parts of Tibet. If bitten, medical advice should be sought immediately.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Birthday of His Holiness the Dalai Lama :
							06 July </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For duty-free allowances for Tibet, see the <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/">China</a> section.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>See <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/">China</a> section for a full list. Additionally, you may not import pictures of the Dalai Lama, political or other publications by either the Dalai Lama or the exiled government in Dharamsala or even travel guidebooks that obliquely refer to Tibetan independence.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1 Renminbi Yuan (CNY; symbol ¥) = 10 jiao/mao. Notes are in denominations of ¥100, 50, 20, 10, 5, and 1. Coins are in denominations of Y1, 0.5 and 1 jiao/mao. Counterfeit ¥100 notes are commonplace. The Yuan is often referred to as the 'kuai' in street slang.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit/debit cards (Visa, Diners Club, MasterCard, American Express etc) are accepted in top-end hotels in Lhasa but are of very limited use elsewhere.</p><p>ATMs are available in many towns, though those in Lhasa and Shigatse are most reliable. Cash advances from a credit card are available in Lhasa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chinese banks give a slightly higher rate for travellers cheques compared to cash but charge a small commission (around 0.75%). <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars and Euros are the easiest denominations to change. Cashing travellers cheques is difficult outside of Lhasa and Shigatse, so bring a combination of cheques, cash and a credit/debit card.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1300, 1530-1800, Sat & Sun 1000-1600 in Lhasa</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Tibet Autonomous Region is a province of <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/">China</a> and so Chinese visas are required. For regulations and fees, please see the <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/passport-visa/">China passport &amp; visa section</a>.</p>
<p>To enter Tibet, you must also obtain a Tibet travel permit. The easiest way to do this is to join a tour group. Your agency will usually be able to arrange your permit within around seven days, although it can take longer if you're visiting restricted areas, which require additional permits. There are currently no restrictions on group size or nationality. Please note, the Tibet Tourism Bureau often puts a hold on issuing permits during times of political tensions and demonstrations and regulations are subject to change at short notice. Since 2008, no permits have been issued during the month of March each year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[29.647951]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[91.117006]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,228,400 sq km (474,288 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>3.3 million (2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>People's Republic of China comprises 23 provinces (China considers Taiwan its 23rd province), five autonomous regions, two special administrative regions and four municipalities directly under central government.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Almost all Tibetans are Tibetan Buddhists, a form of Tantric Mahayana Buddhism called Vajrayana. Popular Tibetan folk religion is heavily influenced by the pre-Buddhist Bon religion, a shamanic belief system in spirits, spells and exorcism.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tibetans are generally very easy to get along with. Always walk clockwise around a stupa, religious statue or a mani wall (wall made from stones engraved with religious mantras) and spin prayer wheels clockwise. Don't smoke or talk loudly in a monastery. Don't attend sky burials if uninvited and even then never take photographs. Tibetans will often present an honoured guest or visitor with a white silk scarf known as a <em>kathak</em>.</p>
<p>Avoid discussing politics with your guide or monks as you can never be sure who is listening or watching. Don't take photographs of bridges, military installations or the army and avoid getting caught up in political disturbances.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. However, most 4 and 5-star hotels are also wired for the use of 110-volt appliances. Plugs with two flat pins, two round pins, or three flat, angled pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The early Tibetan Empire was one of Asia's largest, even seizing the Chinese capital Xian in CE 763, before the arrival of Buddhism in the 8th and 9th centuries reshaped the nation's psyche, transforming it into one of the world's most spiritually advanced centres.</p>
<p>Up until the 20th century Tibet was essentially a medieval theocracy under the leadership of the reincarnated Dalai Lamas, where wealth, education and political power were vested in the hands of powerful monasteries.</p>
<p>During much of the 19th and early-20th centuries, Tibet cut itself off, retreating behind its Himalayan ramparts and closing the doors to foreign travellers, which was a policy that only added to its mystique.</p>
<p>The Communist Chinese invasion of Tibet in 1950, shattered this isolation, ushering in four decades of political upheaval. The litany of sorrows included the flight of the Dalai Lama in 1959, the destruction of thousands of monasteries and the detention of countless political prisoners, many of them monks and nuns.</p>
<p>Since the late 1980s many religious freedoms have returned although violent demonstrations rocked the region in 1987, 1989 and 2008 and the Chinese occupation of Tibet continues to be a contentious issue.</p>
<p>Today the economy is booming with more than two million tourists a year, most of them Chinese. The communist leadership points to huge investment in infrastructure, airports and the controversial railway line as proof of its commitment, but frustrated Tibetans lament the country&rsquo;s mass immigration, limited employment and state interference in religious affairs.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Butter tea, or <em>po cha</em>, is made from tealeaves, yak butter, water and salt.<br />
&bull;	The Tibetan dzo is a hybrid of yak and domestic cattle, larger and stronger than both and more productive in milk and meat.<br />
&bull;	Nangma dance music is popular in karaoke bars in Lhasa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[China National Tourist Office (CNTO) in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 212 760 8218.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.cnto.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 212 760 8218.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Suite 912, 370 Lexington Ave<br/>New York<br/> 10017<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the People's Republic of China in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 337 1956.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.china-embassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 337 1956.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0900-1730, 0930-1230 and 1330-1500 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Suite 100, 3505 International Place NW<br/>Washington DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the People's Republic of China in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 20 7631 1430</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.chinese-embassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 20 7631 1430</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>31 Portland Place<br/>London<br/>W1B 1QD<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Consulate-General in Chongqing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+86 23 6369 1400</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/world/organisations/british-consulate-general-chongqing</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+86 23 6369 1400</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1200, 1300-1700&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>68 Zourong Lu<br/>68 Zourong Road, Suite 2801, Metropolitan Oriental Plaza<br/>Yu Zhong District<br/>400010<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hidden high on the roof of the world, Tibet is a land of golden monasteries, spectacular mountain scenery and a deep spiritual heritage that lives as much in our imagination as it does in the remote Himalayas.</p>
<p>Of course, it&rsquo;s hard to ignore the complex political situation, with Tibet seen both as occupied territory and an integral part of <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/">China</a> for the best part of a century depending on who you talk to. This contentious situation can affect your freedom of movement in the country, and so it&rsquo;s wise to plan your itinerary and do your research well in advance.</p>
<p>Once you&rsquo;ve crossed these barriers, however, an enthralling, unique realm awaits.</p>
<p>Many travellers will be drawn to Tibet by the spectacular Buddhist temples, ageless monasteries perched on cliff edges and robed monks chanting peacefully. With the amount of reverence and faith among Tibetans, Tibet truly feels like one of the most spiritual places on Earth.</p>
<p>Beyond the zen vibes, Tibet&rsquo;s nature is also life-affirming. Stunning high-altitude scenery and huge blue salt lakes borne on high towards the heavens are the highlights, while epic journeys beckon. Try the world's highest railway trip, for example, or take the classic overland drive across the Himalayas to <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/nepal/kathmandu/">Kathmandu</a> in <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/nepal/">Nepal</a>.</p>
<p>A recurring highlight wherever you go is the Tibetan people, always quick with a smile, from visiting bands of pilgrims to nomads in their yak-hair tents. Be sure to try beer in a Lhasa teahouse, or to accept a monk&rsquo;s offer of yak-butter tea. The Tibetans&rsquo; openness and warmth in the face of political oppression is remarkable.</p>
<p>Once the very definition of remote, arduous and forbidden travel, Tibet is now surprisingly well connected by road, plane and even rail links. Massive change is reshaping the politically troubled plateau but complicated travel restrictions make independent travel tricky, so do plan ahead.</p><p>Hidden high on the roof of the world, Tibet is a land of golden monasteries, spectacular mountain scenery and a deep spiritual heritage that lives as much in our imagination as it does in the remote Himalayas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
