<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Togo" ColCode="tgo" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="tg" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Togo]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From December to January, the <em>Harmattan</em> wind blows from the north. The rainy season lasts from April to July. Short rains occur from October to November. The driest and hottest months are February and March, which are also the best months to visit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical lightweights. Rainwear for the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ferries run along the coast. For details, contact the port authorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no passenger rail services on Togo's dilapidated network.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tarred roads run to the border countries and the major northern route is called 'The Highway of Unity'.&nbsp;There are roads linking most settlements, but these are largely impassable during the rainy season.&nbsp;Police checkpoints are frequent and may cause delays.&nbsp;It's advisable to keep windows rolled up and doors locked.</p>r<p>National bus, minibus and taxi systems are reasonably efficient and cheap. Taxis and minibuses are widely available in Lom&eacute; and shared taxis are available between towns. There is a surcharge for luggage. Drivers do not expect a tip.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required.</p><p>This is available in Lom&eacute;; elsewhere the cost of car hire is very high and it's usually better to hire a taxi.</p><p>You can hire bikes in large towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main airline running services to Togo is Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>) from Paris. Other options include Brussels Airlines (<a href="http://www.brusselsairlines.com" target="_blank">www.brusselsairlines.com</a>) from Brussels and Royal Air Maroc (<a href="http://www.royalairmaroc.com" target="_blank">www.royalairmaroc.com</a>) from Casablanca. All offer connecting flights from the UK.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 10 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 19 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main port:</strong>&nbsp;Lom&eacute;.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are no area codes. IDD is available to main cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good around urban areas and patchy elsewhere.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public access is available in Internet caf&eacute;s all over the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Freedom of the press is provided for in the constitution, but is not respected in practice. The major television channel is government-owned, as is the only daily newspaper and some of the private radio stations. Journalists writing for the private weeklies are subject to harassment and legal action. Several private radio and TV stations which had criticised the military-backed succession of Faure Gnassingbe as president were closed in 2005. Press offences cannot be punished by imprisonment. The main newspaper is the government-owned <em>Togo-Presse</em>, published in French, <em>Ewe </em>and <em>Kabiyé</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Postal facilities are limited to main towns. Airmail to Western Europe takes at least two weeks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be at the centre of it all in Lomé</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Togo's capital is a mixture of the traditional and the modern. Its old heart is centred on the Grand Marché, a vibrant mishmash of stalls and people selling everything under the sun. A few streets away, the Akodessewa voodoo market is possibly the largest in Africa and welcoming of tourists.</p>]]><p><b>Discover where modern Togo was born in Togoville</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In this picturesque location on Lake Togo in 1884 Germany signed a colonial treaty with the Ewe king Mlapa III, making his land a German protectorate. The modern-day chief still shows copies of the treaty to visitors. In the village itself there are numerous voodoo shrines as well as a colonial-era Roman Catholic cathedral.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Aného’s colonial past</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Formerly known as Little Popo, this town developed from a slave port and is a place where fisherman in colourful canoes ply the Atlantic waves. Aného became Togo's capital for a brief period in the 19th century and the town preserves a distinctively colonial air reflected in its churches and German cemetery.</p>]]><p><b>Get wet whale watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go whale watching in the Gulf of Benin, where humpback whales can be seen breaching the Atlantic surf and thrashing their huge tails every October. Though best observed on an organised boat tour, they can sometimes be witnessed from dry land.</p>]]><p><b>Head north to Koutammakou’s traditional dwellings</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the traditional mud tower-houses of Koutammakou, home to the Batammariba and a UNESCO World Heritage Site since 2004. Though basic, the predominately two-storey structures are unique, built to designs handed down unchanged for generations to include space for animals on the ground floor and near-spherical granaries.</p>]]><p><b>Relax in sleepy fishing villages</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the country's short coastline, home to several small fishing villages, many of which are home to examples of colonial-era architecture. Head out into the Atlantic on a traditional canoe to catch some fish before having them grilled back on land, or soak up the atmosphere of these welcoming tightknit communities.</p>]]><p><b>Spot wildlife in national parks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fazao Mafakassa National Park in the semi-mountainous wetland outside Sokodé is Togo's largest and home to 300 species including primates and elephant. Kéran National Park near Kara and the Fosse aux Lions (Lions' Den) southwest of Dapaong are also major drawers for wildlife enthusiasts, while exotic butterflies abound in the lush forests around Kapilmé.</p>]]><p><b>Stretch your legs hiking in Kapilmé</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Not only does the hill country surrounding Kapilmé offer a range of hiking opportunities, it also offers rewarding views of the lush countryside while you climb. The walk to Togo's highest peak, Mount Agou, which kisses the sky at 1,000m (3,280ft), takes you through mountain villages and promises views of Ghana on clear days.</p>]]><p><b>Take to the water</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy watersports at Lake Togo's premier resort, the palm-lined Hotel le Lac at Agbodrafo (also called Porto Seguro), which has water-skiing and sailing facilities. For a swim, you can do worse than West Africa's largest pool, the Olympic-sized pool at the Hotel Sarkawa in Lomé.</p>]]><p><b>Unwind on the beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Togo has many miles of secluded clean sandy beaches lined with coconut palms on its Atlantic coast. Many of the most popular, including Le Ramatou and Robinson Plage, are easily reached from Lomé. The resorts at these beaches also offer the chance to head into the waves, with diving and snorkelling equipment for hire.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$2.7 billion (2009).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Cocoa, phosphate, coffee and cotton.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Consumer goods including food, fabrics, clothes, vehicles and equipment.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>EU (mainly France and The Netherlands), China (PR), Ghana and other francophone West African countries (Benin and Burkina Faso).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>About two-thirds of the working population is employed in agriculture: a wide range of crops are produced, including cotton, cocoa and coffee (the main cash crops) and basic foodstuffs including cassava, maize, yams and sorghum.<br /><br />Togo's other major principal exports are the ores from the country's phosphate mines, although revenues have been hit recently by slack demand and low world prices. Limestone and marble deposits have also been exploited. Togo's mines contain some of the world's richest calcium deposits.<br /><br />Most of Togo's other industry is based on the processing of these agricultural and mineral products, apart from a handful of factories engaged in the production of textiles and consumer goods for domestic consumption. A successful export processing zone, now entering its second decade of operation, has attracted numerous manufacturers from across the world. The service sector is small and tourism negligible. <br /><br />The country's main economic problems are a huge foreign debt and declining revenues due to low world commodity prices. A typical programme of structural adjustment has been undertaken under the supervision of the IMF and World Bank. In 2009, annual GDP growth was 1.8% while inflation was 3.3%.<br /><br />Togo is a member of the CFA Franc Zone, the West African trading bloc ECOWAS and various international commodity organisations.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suits are advised. Business is conducted in French - only a few executives speak English. Appointments should be made and business cards should be carried. <br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0700-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre de Commerce et d'Industrie du Togo (CCAIT)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 221 7065
					Website:
					Address: avenue Georges Pompidou,BP 360,Lomé,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Though the national staple is undoubtedly maize (sweetcorn), eaten on the cob or ground to create a filling savoury porridge, Togolese cuisine also displays the country's German and French colonial legacies in its love of beer and baguettes.</p><p>Meat and poultry are plentiful and well prepared, while fish and shellfish are popular choices on the Atlantic coast. Bush meat including agouti (bush rat) remains popular, but is unlikely to be found on many menus. Local fruit and vegetables, particularly tomatoes, okra and spinach, are also readily available.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Akume</strong>: Savoury porridge made from maize flour and Togo&rsquo;s staple foodstuff when served with one of a variety of sauces.<br />
<strong>P&acirc;tes</strong>: Sauces that accompany akume, generally made from aubergine (eggplant), tomato, spinach or fish.<br />
<strong>Fufu</strong>: Mashed yam eaten with sauces made from peanut, goat or palm nut.<br />
<strong>Riz sauce d&rsquo;arachide</strong>: Rice with peanut sauce.<br />
<strong>Brochettes</strong>: Skewers of meat more often than not with a chilli marinade.<br />
<strong>Yassa</strong>: Chicken in a spicy and tangy sauce.<br />
<strong>Gbomo dessi</strong>: Spicy beef and spinach stew.<br />
<strong>Djenkoume</strong>: Tomato cornmeal fritters served as a side to many dishes.<br />
<strong>Koklo meme</strong>: Grilled chicken in a chilli sauce.<br />
<strong>Grilled prawns</strong>: From the fisherman to your plate in a couple of hours.<br />
<strong>Palm wine: </strong>Potent liquor made from the sap of palm trees.<br />
<strong>Tchakpallo</strong>: Brewed from fermented millet.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>When not included, a tip of about 10% is customary.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>21.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are numerous nightclubs, particularly in Lomé. Most serve food and are open until the early hours for dancing to a mixture of West African and Western popular music. There are also cinemas showing French and English-language films.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Market purchases include wax prints, indigo cloth, Kente and dye-stamped Adinkira cloth from Ghana, embroideries, batik and lace from The Netherlands, locally made heavy marble ashtrays, gold and silver jewellery, traditional masks, wood sculpture and religious statuettes. Voodoo stalls display an extraordinary range of items used in magic, among them, cowrie shells.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1730, Sat 0730-1230.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Only Lama-Kara and Lom&eacute; have international-class accommodation but there are hotels in all the main towns. There is a severe shortage of accommodation, so it is advisable to book in advance. For further information, contact the Office National Togolais du Tourisme.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Only Lama-Kara and Lom&eacute; have international-class accommodation but there are hotels in all the main towns. There is a severe shortage of accommodation, so it is advisable to book in advance. For further information, contact the Office National Togolais du Tourisme.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Only Lama-Kara and Lom&eacute; have international-class accommodation but there are hotels in all the main towns. There is a severe shortage of accommodation, so it is advisable to book in advance. For further information, contact the Office National Togolais du Tourisme.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Limited medical services are provided by the state. Most towns have either a hospital or a dispensary, but these are usually overcrowded and lack adequate supplies. Visitors who get seriously ill are advised to contact their embassy, which can refer them to a specialist or arrange evacuation. Health insurance and a good supply of personal medical provisions are recommended. It is important to carry a basic first aid kit.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as a potential health risk. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water; swimming pools which are well chlorinated and maintained are safe. Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Tabaski (Feast of Sacrifice) may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Liberation Day :
							2018<br/>13 January </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Independence Day :
							27 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Martyrs' Day :
							21 June </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Anniversary of the Failed Attack on Lom̩ :
							23 September </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Togo without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 10 packs of cigarettes or 50 cigarillos or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1 bottle of spirits and 1 bottle of wine.<br />
&bull; 1 bottle of eau de toilette and 1 bottle of perfume.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include obscene or subversive publications, and drugs.</p>
<p>Restricted imports include arms and ammunition, medicines (unless for personal use), meat and endangered species.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>CFA (Communauté Financière Africaine) Franc (XOF) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of XOF10,000, 5,000, 2,500, 2,000, 1,000 and 500. Coins are in denominations of XOF250, 100, 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1.<br /><br />Togo is part of the French Monetary Area. Only currency issued by the Banque des Etats de l'Afrique de l'Ouest (Bank of West African States) is valid; currency issued by the Banque des Etats de l'Afrique Centrale (Bank of Central African States) is not. The CFA Franc is tied to the Euro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies can be exchanged at banks and bureaux de change in Lomé and other major cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express is widely accepted, with more limited use of Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa. The main branch of the Togolese Central Bank in Lomé (BTCI) can give cash withdrawals against a Visa card.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International traveller's cheques are accepted in Lomé and other major cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Togo, a passport valid for one year from the date of departure is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa on arrival: approximately US$30 (passport photo required).</p>
<p>Single-entry tourist visa in advance: &pound;55 (30 days) or &pound;75 (90 days); multiple-entry tourist visa in advance: &pound;65 (30 days) or &pound;85 (90 days).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa on arrival: seven days; visa in advance: 30 or 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>On arrival or in advance from the consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas are usually issued the following day if you apply in person.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to extend your visa, you must contact the Ministry of Interior before your current visa expires, but be prepared for delays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[8.513029]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[0.980026]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>56,785 sq km (21,925 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>7,496,833 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>133 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lom&eacute;.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Togo shares borders with Burkina Faso to the north, Benin to the east and Ghana to the west, with a short coast on the Atlantic in the south. The country is a narrow strip, rising behind coastal lagoons and swampy plains to an undulating plateau. Northwards, the plateau descends to a wide plain irrigated by the River Oti. The central area is covered by deciduous forest, while savannah stretches to the north and south. In the east, the River Mono runs to the sea; long sandy beaches shaded by palms characterise the coastline between Lom&eacute; and Cotonou in Benin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>50% traditional or animist, 35% Christian and 15% Muslim.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Music and dance are the most popular forms of culture. The Togolese have had a varied colonial heritage which has resulted in the variety of Christian denominations and European languages; the voodoo religion is a strong influence in the country and many young girls, after fulfilling an initiation period, will devote their lives to serving the religion and the voodoo village priest. Practical, casual clothes are suitable. Beachwear should not be worn away from the beach or poolside.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Komi Klassou since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Faure Gnassingb&eacute; since 2005.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>At the turn of the 15th century, Togo was populated by Kwa people and tribes from along the River Volta. Over the next 200 years, they were joined by Ewe people from Nigeria and Ane from Ghana and C&ocirc;te d'Ivoire.</p>
<p>During the 18th century the coast was occupied by Danish colonialists, but by the late 19th century Denmark had been replaced by Germany, which established the Togoland protectorate. The administration was overthrown by a joint Anglo-French force early in WWI. Then, in 1922, the country was divided into a French-controlled eastern region and a British-controlled western sector, both governed under a League of Nations mandate. After an UN-sponsored referendum in 1956, the British sector merged with the neighbouring colony of Gold Coast (Ghana), while the French sector became the Republic of Togo.</p>
<p>Civilian government lasted just a few years before a military coup brought Lieutenant-Colonel Etienne Eyad&eacute;ma to power in 1967. Eyad&eacute;ma's authoritarian style spawned several coup attempts, though he remained in office until his death in February 2005.</p>
<p>Earlier, in August 1991, Togo had been at the vanguard of a democratic revolution sweeping Africa, with a national conference convened to chart a path to democracy. The conference stripped Eyad&eacute;ma of executive powers and installed a transitional administration. In November, the administration made a serious tactical error by banning Eyad&eacute;ma's party, the RPT. The army mutinied, and only the arrival of French paratroopers brought the violence to a halt.</p>
<p>When elections were eventually held in 1993, after multiple postponements, opposition parties boycotted or were disqualified. Tension only eased when the RPT lost power in 1994, although Eyad&eacute;ma was convincingly re-elected president in 1998, and then again in 2003.</p>
<p>On his death, the constitution was hastily changed and Eyad&eacute;ma's son, Faure, assumed power. International condemnation forced him to resign just 20 days later until elections were held.</p>
<p>Against a backdrop of violence and accusations of vote rigging and intimidation, Faure won the election with 60% of the vote. As president he oversaw the formation of a transitional unity government to prepare the country for benchmark elections in 2007 that were considered largely free by international observers.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	At the time of his death Eyad&eacute;ma was the longest-serving leader in modern African history, having held the presidency for 38 years.<br />
&bull;	After WWI it was considered that the then German colony should instead be administered by Czechoslovakia.<br />
&bull;	The name Togo means &lsquo;water shore&rsquo; in Ewe. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Togo in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 234 4212.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.togoleseembassy.com/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 234 4212.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2208 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Togo in France]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(01) 4380 1213.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.consulatogo.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(01) 4380 1213.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>8 rue Alfred Roll<br/>Paris<br/>75017<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A great introduction to Africa, ever smiling Togo is a melting pot of more than 40 tribes that together have managed to create a relaxed yet offhand charm in a country so small you can drive across it in under an hour.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Even its biggest city, the capital, Lom&eacute;, feels more like a town and is small enough to comfortably traverse on foot. Experience Togolese <em>joie de vivre</em> at the Grand Marche, which occupies an entire city block and sells everything from artisan products to fresh fruit. Better yet head to the Fetish Market, where fetish priests will fix you up with your own protective charm.</p>
<p>Voodoo and other animist beliefs are not just for tourists, with half the population following such practices. Togoville, on the banks of Lac Togo, is the historic home of voodoo in the country, and is a great place to learn more about religious customs and the meaning of shrines. Meanwhile, the lake itself is becoming something of a weekend retreat for the burgeoning middle-class and its desire for fine food and exciting nightlife.</p>
<p>Few leave the palm-fringed Atlantic beaches of Lom&eacute; and Aneho, but those who do head off the beaten track and into the hills or savannah will be richly rewarded. The hills offer superb hiking among the dense green foliage of coffee and cocoa plantations, and are where you can find the Kloto carvers, famed for creating multiple connected rings from a single piece of wood.</p>
<p>The savannahs of the north, by contrast, offer the chance to witness a more traditional way of life. Considered a symbol of Togo itself, Koutammakou is home to the remarkable <em>takienta</em> mud houses of the Batammariba people, structures that need to be seen to be believed.</p>
<p>Togo has a peaceful nonchalance that makes a quick conversation in Lom&eacute;&rsquo;s Grand Marche as much of a highlight as any attraction, while its small size makes travel a relaxed and stress-free experience.</p><p>A great introduction to Africa, ever smiling Togo is a melting pot of more than 40 tribes that together have managed to create a relaxed yet offhand charm in a country so small you can drive across it in under an hour.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Even its biggest city, the capital, Lom&eacute;, feels more like a town and is small enough to comfortably traverse on foot. Experience Togolese <em>joie de vivre</em> at the Grand Marche, which occupies an entire city block and sells everything from artisan products to fresh fruit. Better yet head to the Fetish Market, where fetish priests will fix you up with your own protective charm.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
