<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Tonga" ColCode="ton" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="to" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Tonga]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tonga's climate is marginally cooler than most tropical areas. The best time to visit is from May to November. Heavy rains occur from December to March.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>REALtonga (<a href="http://realtonga.to" target="_blank">realtonga.to</a>) runs domestic flights across Tonga.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local ferries sail between all the island groups. There are regular sailings from Faua Wharf in Nuku'alofa to Ha'apai and Vava'u. Ferry schedules are subject to change according to demand or the weather.</p>
<p>Water taxis also sail between islands, and private yacht charters are available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[l<p>There is a good network of metalled roads, although with some potholes. Speed limits are low compared to Europe and North America and are generally observed.</p><p>Saloon-car taxis, minimokes and minibuses are available. Taxis may not be marked, but you can identify them by the letter 'T' at the beginning of the number plate. They aren't metered, so make sure you agree the fare before departure.</p><p>A Tongan visitor driver's licence is required, available from the Ministry of Transport in Nuku'alofa on production of a valid national or international licence.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Speed limits are 30kph (19mph) on roads around schools and pedestrian areas, 50kph (31mph) on main roads and 70kph (43mph) in quieter rural areas.</p><p>May be arranged through various agencies. Self-drive or chauffeur-driven cars are available.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Speed limits are 30kph (19mph) on roads around schools and pedestrian areas, 50kph (31mph) on main roads and 70kph (43mph) in quieter rural areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Used mainly by visitors, buses can be a fun way to get around the island. If you see one passing, you can wave it down.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Tonga</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">pangai_harsquoapai</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Tonga</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">neiafu_vavarsquou</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Tonga</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">rsquo_eua</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines operating flights to Tonga include Air New Zealand (<a href="http://www.airnewzealand.com" target="_blank">www.airnewzealand.com</a>), Fiji Airways (<a href="http://www.fijiairways.com" target="_blank">www.fijiairways.com</a>) and Virgin Australia (<a href="http://www.virginaustralia.com" target="_blank">www.virginaustralia.com</a>). Air New Zealand offers connecting flights from the UK via Los Angeles.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/auckland">Auckland</a> - 3 hours.</p>
<p>To Auckland: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 24 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 22 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/los-angeles">Los Angeles</a> - 13 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Fuaʻamotu International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.tongaairports.com<p>The airport is 13km (8 miles) from Nuku'alofa.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong> Neiafu, Niuatoputapu, Nuku'alofa and Pangai.</p>
<p>There are no regular passenger services, but berths may be available on cruise ships.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are no area codes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Coverage is limited to Nuku'alofa. No roaming agreements exist.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are Internet caf&eacute;s in Nuku'alofa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The state's control of the media increased following an amendment to the constitution in 2003 which limited the right of the courts to review royal decisions. State-owned radio and TV are usually biased towards government policy, while private broadcasters offer little independent coverage. Although some privately-owned newspapers carry opposition views, journalists have been known to face harassment and threats of criminal charges. The <em>Matangi Tonga</em>, <em>The Times of Tonga</em> (New Zealand-based) and <em>Tonga Chronicle</em> are English-language newspapers. Television Tonga is state run; private TV networks include TV7 and Friendly Island Broadcasting Network (Vava'u). Tonfon TV is a pay-TV service.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All mail must be collected from the post office. Airmail to Europe takes approximately 10 days. There are branch offices on Ha'apai and Vava'u.</p><p>(main office located in the centre of Nuku'alofa) Mon-Fri 0830-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be amazed by Ha'amonga Trilithon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ha'amonga Trilithon is a massive stone arch possibly used as a seasonal calendar, erected at the same time as the Terraced Tombs and again made from coral. The Anahulu Cave is an underground cavern of stalactites and stalagmites near the beach of the same name, about 24km (15 miles) from the capital.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the Ha'apai Group</b></p><![CDATA[<p>These 68 small islands form the geological and geographical centre of Tonga, and are characterised by white sandy beaches, pristine waters and spectacular coral reefs. The main island, also named Ha'apai, features the quaint old town of Pangai. The famous mutiny on the HMS Bounty in 1789 is said to have taken place in the waters surrounding these islands.</p>]]><p><b>Grab your binoculars and go whale watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Humpback whales arrive in Tongan waters June to November, to calf and to mate. Special speakers for whale watching are plugged into a hydrophone installed on board the Phoenix catamaran based at Neiafu; only the male whales sing. You can find many reputable whale watching tours that will give you the best possible chance of seeing whales.</p>]]><p><b>Make a royal appointment with the Tongatapu Group</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In Nuku'alofa, the capital, sightseeing itineraries should include the white Victorian Royal Palace on the waterfront. When the king is in residence, the royal standard flies from the palace. While visitors are not allowed to enter the palace or gardens, there are good views from the low surrounding walls. The Mala'ekula (Royal Tombs) are situated along Taufa'ahau Road.</p>]]><p><b>Make a splash with the many watersports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tonga's coral reefs provide great beauty and variety for scuba diving and snorkelling; fully equipped boats and equipment can be hired. There are sandy beaches and excellent swimming throughout the islands, with pools at some hotels. There is a world-standard surfing beach on the island of 'Eua. Niutoua Beach, on the main island, and Ha'apai and Vava'u islands are also good for surfing.</p>]]><p><b>Pay your respects at Langi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>On the eastern end of the island are the Langi (Terraced Tombs), 9.5km (6 miles) from the Ha'amonga Trilithon towards Nuku'alofa. The tombs form quadrilateral mounds with huge blocks of stone rising in terraces to heights of 4m (13ft), built for the old <em>Tu'itonga</em> (Spiritual Kings). The stones are of coral, built around AD1200, possibly carried from Wallis Island on large canoes known as <em>lomipeau</em>.</p>]]><p><b>Roam free on 'Eua island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The island of 'Eua is a 10-minute flight away from Tongatapu and has a blend of modern comfort (the island has one hotel and a motel) and traditional island lifestyle. Many species of exotic bird live on the island. ʻEua also counts many huge caves and holes, not all of which have yet been explored.</p>]]><p><b>See the flying foxes of Kolovai</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At Kolovai, 18km (11 miles) west of Nuku'alofa, visitors can find the rare flying foxes, dark brown fruit bats, some with wingspans of up to 1m (3ft). The Ha'atafu and Monotapu beaches are also situated at the western end of the island; they are easily accessible and well protected.</p>]]><p><b>See the spectacle of the blowholes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the most impressive sights in Tonga are the blowholes, which can be found along the coastline at Houma, 14.5km (9 miles) from Nuku'alofa. Waves send seawater spurting some 18m (60ft) into the air through holes in the coral reef. This stretch of coastline is known as the Mapu 'a Vaea ("the chief's whistle") by Tongans because of the whistling sound made by the spouts.</p>]]><p><b>Set sail for the Vava'u Group</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lying north of Tongatapu, this cluster of 50 or so thickly wooded islands has one hotel, one motel, one beach resort and four guesthouses. There is a daily one-hour flight from the capital and a weekly ferry service; charters also operate from the harbour at Neiafu, the main town. Attractions include diving, the Fangatongo Royal Residence, Mount Talau and Sailoame Market in Neiafu.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$298 million (2008).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Squash, fish, vanilla beans and root crops.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, machinery and transport equipment, fuels and chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Japan, USA, New Zealand and Australia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Agriculture is the strongest part of Tonga's economy, producing coconuts, vanilla and pumpkins as cash crops, and a variety of fruit, vegetables and nuts for domestic consumption. The fishing industry was relatively underdeveloped and has been a focus of government plans to expand the economy.<br /><br />Industrial activity is mostly light and small-scale: textiles, handicrafts, brewing and the production of furniture and construction materials predominate. More recently, these have been joined by enterprises engaged in small manufacturing operations and food processing. The search for oil, which has been licensed to foreign consortia, continues offshore despite lack of success so far. Tonga's own energy requirements are met from renewable sources, principally wave and solar power.<br /><br />Most of the growth in the economy and the best immediate prospect for Tonga's economic future lie in tourism which has been expanded under a recently completed 10-year development programme. The industry is now worth US$10 million annually to the Tongan economy. Nonetheless, the government is constantly looking for other projects to diversify the island's economy.<br /><br />A further vital source of revenue is remittances from the many thousands of Tongans working abroad, mainly in New Zealand and Australia.<br /><br />Tonga is a member of the South Pacific Forum and the South Pacific Commission. A regional free-trade accord, known as the Pacific Island Countries Trade Agreement, was signed among a group of Pacific governments in 2002.<br />For advice, contact the Tonga Visitors' Bureau (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shirts and ties will suffice for business visits. English is widely spoken followed by French.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Ministry of Labour, Commerce and Industries</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Tonga Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Restaurants have table service, and are found mainly in hotels. Apart from hotel dining rooms, there are restaurants featuring Tongan, French, German, Italian, Japanese and Taiwanese cuisine.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; <em>Ufi</em> (a large white yam).<br />
&bull; <em>Lu pulu</em> (meat and onions, marinated in coconut milk, baked in taro leaves in an underground oven).<br />
&bull; <em>Feke</em> (grilled octopus or squid in coconut sauce).<br />
&bull; Devilled clams, <em>ota</em> (raw fish marinated in lemon juice) and lobster. <br />
&bull; Feasts play a major role in the Tongan lifestyle. Up to 30 different dishes may be served on a <em>pola</em> (a long tray of plaited coconut fronds), and will typically include suckling pig, crayfish, chicken, octopus, pork and vegetables steamed in an <em>umu</em> (underground oven), with a variety of tropical fruits.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Not encouraged, but no offence is caused if services are rewarded in this way.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nightlife is sedate, limited to music and dancing in the hotels, clubs and occasionally at the Yacht Club. Floorshows are held on some nights in the main hotels and the Tongan National Centre. Tongan feasts and entertainment are also organised.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Special purchases are hand-decorated and woven <em>tapa</em> cloth, woven floor coverings, <em>Ta'ovala pandanus</em> mats, woven <em>pandanus</em> baskets, 'Ali Baba' laundry baskets, polished coconut-shell goblets and ashtrays, model outrigger canoes, ornaments, brooches, earrings, rings and silver-inlaid knives. Tongan stamps and coins are collectors' items; complete sets are on sale at the philatelic section of the Tongan Treasury. There are duty-free shops on Tongatapu and Vava'u. A government tax of 5% is added to all bills for goods and services.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700, Sat 0800-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are excellent hotels, guest houses, and island and beach resorts made up of Tongan-style houses. Traditional boarding houses are also very popular with tourists. A government tax of 7.5% plus service charge is added to hotel bills. For a complete list of available accommodation, contact the Tonga Visitors' Bureau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are excellent hotels, guest houses, and island and beach resorts made up of Tongan-style houses. Traditional boarding houses are also very popular with tourists. A government tax of 7.5% plus service charge is added to hotel bills. For a complete list of available accommodation, contact the Tonga Visitors' Bureau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are excellent hotels, guest houses, and island and beach resorts made up of Tongan-style houses. Traditional boarding houses are also very popular with tourists. A government tax of 7.5% plus service charge is added to hotel bills. For a complete list of available accommodation, contact the Tonga Visitors' Bureau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;The government provides comprehensive medical and dental facilities for residents and visitors. There are hospitals in Vaiola (Tongatapu), Hihifo (Ha'apai) and Neiafu (Vava'u), which will treat minor ailments and dispense medicines. There are also clinics, dispensaries, chemists and pharmacies. However, serious medical problems should be taken to Australia, Hawaii, New Zealand or Pago Pago (American Samoa). Visitors only pay a token fee for medicines. There are also competent private medical practitioners. Health insurance is recommended. For emergency services, dial 911.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is chlorinated and safe to drink in the main towns. Elsewhere, drinking water should be considered a potential health risk and sterilisation is advisable. Bottled water is available. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry and seafood are generally considered safe to eat. It is advised to wash vegetables and fruit with boiled water and boil any questionable drinking water before use.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>ANZAC Day :
							25 April </p><p>Emancipation Day :
							04 June </p><p>Crown Prince's Birthday :
							12 July </p><p>King George Tupou V's Birthday :
							01 August </p><p>Constitution Day :
							04 November </p><p>King George Tupou I Day :
							04 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Tonga by travellers aged 18 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 250 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2.25L of spirits or 4.5L of wine or 4.5L of beer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted items include weapons, indecent goods, illicit drugs and endangered species.</p>
<p>You must declare all meat and animal products, plants and plant products, and equipment which may have come into contact with soil such as tents, riding gear or farm clothing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pa'anga (TOP) = 100 seniti. Notes are in denominations of TOP50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 seniti.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign exchange is available at banks and at major hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Limited use of both Diners Club and Visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted at banks and at some hotels and tourist shops. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Australian Dollars or Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1600, Sat 0830-1130.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Tonga, a passport valid for a minimum of six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitor's visa: TON46, to be paid on arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy/high commission).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow five working days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors who do require a visa must be able to provide proof of sufficient funds to cover their stay when applying for a visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to extend your stay, you should contact the Immigration Department in Nuku'alofa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-18.984973]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-174.585980]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>748 sq km (289 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>106,915 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>142.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nuku'alofa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tonga is an archipelago of 176 islands in the South Pacific - most of which are uninhabited - covering an area of 7,700 sq km (3,000 sq miles). The major island groups are 'Eua, Ha'apai, the Niuas, Tongatapu and Vava'u. Tonga's high volcanic and low coral forms give the islands a unique character. Some volcanoes are still active and Falcon Island in the Vava'u group is a submerged volcano that erupts periodically, its lava and ash rising above sea level forming a visible island which disappears when the eruption is over.</p>
<p>Nuku'alofa, on Tongatapu Island, has a reef-protected harbour lined with palms. The island is flat with a large lagoon, but no running streams, and many surrounding smaller islands. 'Eua Island is hilly and forested with high cliffs and beautiful beaches. The Ha'apai Islands, a curving archipelago 160km (100 miles) north of Tongatapu, have excellent beaches. Tofua, the largest island in the group, is an active volcano with a hot steaming lake in its crater. The Vava'u Islands, 90km (50 miles) north of Ha'apai, are hilly, densely wooded and interspersed with a maze of narrow channels. They are known for their stalagmite-filled caves.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wesleyan Church, Roman Catholic and Anglican. Small denominations of Muslim, Baha'i and Mormon faiths.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shaking hands is a suitable form of greeting. Although by Western standards Tongan people are by no means rich, meals served to visitors will usually be memorable. A token of appreciation, while not expected, is always welcome, especially gifts from the visitor's homeland. Casual wear is acceptable, but beachwear should be confined to the beach. It is illegal for both men and women to go shirtless in public. Sunday is regarded as a sacred day, an aspect of Tongan life thrown into sharp relief by the controversy surrounding the so-called 'Tongan loop'. <br /><br />The International Date Line forms a loop around the islands, thereby making them a day ahead of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/samoa">Samoa</a>, even though Samoa is almost due north of Tonga. Members of the Seventh Day Adventist Church therefore maintain that a Tongan Sunday is really a Saturday, and are unwilling to attend church on a day which is only a Sunday because of an apparently arbitrary manifestation of international law. This complex and almost insoluble problem may cause visitors a certain amount of confusion, but travellers to Tonga are advised to respect the religious beliefs of the islanders.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>240 volts AC, 50Hz. Australian-style plugs with three flat, angled pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister 'Akilisi Pōhiva since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King George Tupou VI since 2012.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The ruling family of Tonga, the last remaining Polynesian kingdom, can be traced back more than 1000 years, but human habitation of the islands is thought to dates back as far as 1500BC. The first European explorers were Dutch and arrived in 1616 becoming frequent visitors by the time the British seafarer Captain Cook dubbed the archipelago the Friendly Islands in 1773. The adoption of Christianity by the ruling family which followed the arrival of Methodist missionaries in the 1820s and an overall policy of accommodation with the British – then the principal imperial power in the area – meant that the islands were not formally colonised. King Taufa'ahau Tupou I, from whom the present ruler is descended, was the first chief to rule over all of Tonga when he united the islands in 1831. He also introduced representative government to the islands during his reign. A Treaty of Friendship was signed with the British in 1879 affording Tonga the unique status of a 'protected state' (as distinct from a Protectorate, which allowed for less autonomy in government). However, although Tonga never surrendered its sovereignty, a Treaty of Friendship with the British subsequently determined its status as a protectorate in 1900. A flu pandemic killed some 1800 Tongans in 1918. King Tupou IV, the grandfather of the current king, presided over the greatest change in Tonga's constitutional status in 1968 when the islands assumed complete responsibility for internal affairs, before being granted full independence in 1970. The king pursued a uniformly pro-Western foreign policy, including (unusually for the region) expression of support for French nuclear testing in the Pacific.</p><p>The legislative reforms of 2010 paved the way for Tonga to become a recognised constitutional monarchy with free elections and the pro-democracy movement campaigns for a more representative Parliament though, telling, not for the abolition of the monarchy. Tongans enjoy free education for all and access to a system of national health care. Land ownership is protected in law and sale of land to foreigners is forbidden, although it can be leased.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>• Of Tonga's 169 islands, 36 are inhabited.</p><p>• In 2014, luger Bruno Banani became the first athlete to represent Tonga at the Olympic Olympics in Sochi. He came 32nd in the men's luge.</p><p>• Each day Radio Tonga begins broadcasting with a recording by the Tongan nobleman Ve'ehala, a celebrated virtuoso of the nose flute.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Tonga Consulate General in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(415) 781 0365.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.tongaconsul.com/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(415) 781 0365.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0900-1700&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Suite 604<br/>360 Post Street<br/>San Francisco<br/>94108<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Tonga High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7724 5828.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7724 5828.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>36 Molyneux Street<br/>London<br/>W1H 5BQ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Fiji]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(679) 3229100.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinfiji.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(679) 3229100.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs:0800-12:40, 13:00-1600; Fri: 0800-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>PO Box 1355<br/>Victoria House,47 Gladstone Road<br/>Suva<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From steep, active volcanoes, to low coral atolls, Tonga's 176 islands offer a truly diverse array of backdrops for those seeking a Pacific getaway.</p>
<p>Tonga enjoys a laidback pace of life which visitors find easy to adopt, whether relaxing on one of the magnificent white sand beaches, first-class diving amid the stunning coral reefs or watching the migratory whales return to their breeding grounds (June to November). Many of the islands are uninhabited, and have much emerald flora and secluded coves to explore.</p>
<p>Sightseeing highlights include the Royal Palace on the waterfront in Nuku'alofa, the Mala'ekula (Royal Tombs), and the Anahulu Cave: an underground cavern of stalactites and stalagmites. Tonga is ruled by the last remaining Kingdom of Polynesia. The ruling family of Tonga, the last remaining Polynesian Kingdom, can be traced back more than 1,000 years.</p>From steep, active volcanoes, to low coral atolls, Tonga's 176 islands offer a truly diverse array of backdrops for those seeking a Pacific getaway.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
