<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Trinidad and Tobago" ColCode="tto" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="tt" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Trinidad and Tobago]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The tropical climate is tempered by northeast trade winds. The dry season is from November to May, but it is hottest between June and October. The climate in Tobago is pleasant most of the year and although May, June and July can be wet at times, the differentiation between the wet and dry seasons is much less acute.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical lightweights are required. Rainwear is advisable, especially for the wet season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Caribbean Airlines<em> </em>(<a target="_blank" href="http://www.caribbean-airlines.com/">www.caribbean-airlines.com</a>) runs regular flights between Piarco (Port of Spain) and Crown Point (Tobago). During peak seasons (especially Carnival time), these are often heavily booked.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are two options for the crossing between Trinidad (Port of Spain) and Tobago (Scarborough), both run by the Port Authority of Trinidad and Tobago<em> </em>(<a target="_blank" href="http://www.patnt.com/">www.patnt.com</a>). The slow car ferry/passenger service takes approximately 6 hours and the fast catamaran crossing is 2 hours 30 minutes (two to three daily).</p>
<p>A regular water taxi service run by NIDCO (<a href="http://www.nidco.co.tt" target="_blank">www.nidco.co.tt</a>)  also links Port of Spain with San Fernando, Trinidad&rsquo;s other major city. If you are arriving by private boat, a clearance certificate from the last port of call and the vessel&rsquo;s registration certificate are essential requirements.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The road network in Trinidad between major towns is good, but traffic around Port of Spain can be difficult during rush hour and around Independence Square at any time. Two major highways run north-south and east-west. Roads which run off major routes can be very unpredictable, and are susceptible to poor weather conditions.</p>
<p>In Tobago, the roads, though narrow in parts, are improving dramatically and most of the island is easy to reach. There is a major highway (Claude Noel Highway) running west-east. Tourists should have no qualms about driving around Tobago at any time of the day or night, although caution should be exercised in more rural areas where chickens and sheep may wander across roads.  Hand signals, which may be unfamiliar, are often used.</p>l<p>The nation&rsquo;s bus connections have seen a boost in recent years, with many new vehicles introduced into a previously ailing fleet. The terminal in Port of Spain is at City Gate on South Quay, from where buses operate to San Fernando and other destinations in Trinidad. Some places in Tobago are served from the main bus station on Sangster&rsquo;s Hill in Scarborough.</p><p>All official taxis have registration 'H'. Hiring a private taxi (which must be done via telephone) is much more expensive but gives the freedom to go where you like. Though there are fixed rates for certain journeys (at official taxi stands such as Piarco International Airport, rates for main journeys are displayed on the taxi stands), it's best to establish this before you start your journey.</p>
<p>The quickest and most cost-effective way to get around is by Route taxis and Maxi taxis which serve standard routes within Trinidad, particularly around Port of Spain, starting their route from, in or near Independence Square. These have fixed rates. In Tobago, Route taxis (H registered and unregistered) are plentiful along most major routes during the day and can be stopped anywhere along them. Drivers will indicate they have room by sounding their horn.</p>
<p>The abundance of taxis and the dearth of bus routes in many parts of Trinidad and Tobago mean shared cabs are the accepted public transport option nationwide.</p><p>An International Driving Permit of a national licence from the Bahamas, Canada, France, Germany, the UK or the USA. These are valid for 90 days after arrival.</p><p>Trinidad's speed limit is 80kph (50mph) on highways and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas. While in Tobago, do not exceed 50kph (31mph). There is no left turn on a red light and u-turns are illegal. Drivers and front-seat passengers are legally required to wear a seat belt.</p><p>Cars and motorcycles are available in Port of Spain or Scarborough, and can be arranged via hotels and in Tobago at the airport as well. Consider jeep hire for exploring Trinidad&rsquo;s wild interior, much of which is accessible only by dirt tracks. You need to be at least 25 years of age and have held a licence for a minimum of two years to hire a vehicle. Mopeds and trailbikes (increasingly popular) can be hired too.</p><p>Cycling, particularly mountain biking, is taking off in Trinidad &amp; Tobago. Tobago leads the way here, with several places in the Lowlands west of Scarborough hiring out bicycles.</p><p>Trinidad's speed limit is 80kph (50mph) on highways and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas. While in Tobago, do not exceed 50kph (31mph). There is no left turn on a red light and u-turns are illegal. Drivers and front-seat passengers are legally required to wear a seat belt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Taxis noticeably outnumber buses even in Port of Spain and as such, most public transport journeys in the city are now made by shared taxis.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Caribbean Airlines (<a href="http://www.caribbean-airlines.com" target="_blank">www.caribbean-airlines.com</a>), whose routes include direct flights from New York to Port of Spain. British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) flies to Tobago from London, with a brief stop in Antigua. American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>) runs direct flights from Miami to Port of Spain.</p>
<p>Almost all international flights arrive at Piarco International Airport, 27km (17 miles) east of Port of Spain on Trinidad, as well as Tobago&rsquo;s Crown Point International Airport, 7km (4 miles) west of Scarborough.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/trinidad-and-tobago/crown-point-international-airport">A.N.R. Robinson International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 11 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 5 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>TT$100 or US$17. Children under five years of age are exempt. No tax is charged on flights between Trinidad and Tobago.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>A.N.R. Robinson International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.tntairports.com<p>A. N. R. Robinson International Airport is located on the southern tip of Tobago, around 11km (6.8 miles) from the Scarborough city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>868 639 8547</p>]]><b>Piarco International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.tntairports.com/piarco/index.html<p>The airport is 25km (16 miles) east of Port of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports</strong>: Port of Spain  and Scarborough.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The ferry to Venezuela is no longer in operation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>The international dialling code is +868. There are no area codes. In Tobago, international telephone calls can be made from the national communications provider, TSTT. Many public phone booths take phonecards which can be bought from local shops and TSTT.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is available in most of Trinidad and Tobago. Main networks are Telecommunications Services of Trinidad & Tobago (TSTT) AND Digicel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are numerous internet cafés on the islands. Piarco International Airport, as well as Rituals Coffee Shops across the country, have Wi-Fi access, as well as an increasing number of other locations. Rates in internet cafes start at around TT$6; access in libraries is free.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The government generally respects press freedom, which is enshrined in the constitution. There are five free-to-air TV channels (NCC, CCN TV6 (privately run and dominating the national ratings), Gayelle, CNC3 and C-TV. Another seven stations are available by cable. There are 39 radio stations (37 FM; 2 AM). Three leading daily newspapers are published: the Expres, the Guardian and Newsday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main post office is on Wrightson Road, Port of Spain. Airmail to Western Europe takes up to two weeks; incoming mail can take much longer. The main post office in Tobago is in Market Square, Scarborough.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1300-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bathe beside beautiful beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a dip at one of Tobago's fine beaches. Each has its own flavour, from the brown pelicans at Turtle Beach to fantastic snorkelling at Man O'War Bay. Store Bay, Mount Irvine, and Bacolet Bay are also well worth a visit, and Pigeon Point should not be missed.</p>]]><p><b>Be bowled over by the Cricket at Queen’s Park Oval</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Catch a cricket match at the Queen's Park Oval in Port of Spain, where the best national and international matches can be seen. Here, on the ground that launched cricket legend Brian Lara, is the only time you'll see football challenged as the national sport. The enthusiasm of the crowds is as entertaining as the games themselves.</p>]]><p><b>Call in at the Queen's Park Savannah</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Port of Spain's largest open space, Queen's Park Savannah, is a magnificent mixture of natural and manmade beauty with attractive trees, shrubs (including the African Tulip) and The Emperor Valley Zoo. The Royal Botanical Gardens boasts over 700 species of orchid, whilst its scattering of mansions include the historic President's House.</p>]]><p><b>Celebrate Carnival in Port of Spain</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Celebrate Carnival, Trinidad's wildest and most magical beano. The world-renowned festivities climax at the beginning of Lent, although the run-up to Carnival starts immediately after Christmas when the Calypso tents open and the Calypsonians perform their latest compositions. January through March are usually taken up with the preparations and festivities.</p>]]><p><b>Dance to Trinidad's greatest steel bands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Listen to the big steel bands bang their drums around Queen's Park Savannah, a large park in Port of Spain. Panorama, the Grand Steel Drum (pan) tournament is staged a week before Carnival. The preliminaries and local finals in Tobago are also well worth a visit.</p>]]><p><b>Find adventure in the water</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take advantage of the excellent watersports facilities at the beaches along the north and east coasts of Trinidad, and all around Tobago. Speyside and Buccoo Reef, just off the southwest coast of Tobago, have some of the Caribbean's finest reefs, offer exciting scuba-diving. Trips in glass-bottomed boats are very popular, as is both deep-sea and freshwater fishing.</p>]]><p><b>Find history and fine views at Fort George</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fort George, built in 1804, is, on the western side of Port of Spain, one of the nation's most important historical buildings. The most interesting feature is a signal box designed by an African prince. It yields superb vistas of the city and the mountains of northern Venezuela. High above the city, it's a good opportunity for birdwatching.</p>]]><p><b>Head underground in the Aripo Caves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Trinidad has several cave systems and the most extensive sits, appropriately perhaps, beneath its highest mountain, El Cerreo de Aripo. The stalactites and stalagmites here are sublime. Speleologists will also be intrigued by the Tamana Caves, which boasts 11 species of bat, and the subterranean treasure trove of Gasparee Caves, located on Gaspar Grande.</p>]]><p><b>Hike the Tobago Forest Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get active with a long hike along the excellent trails of  Tobago's Main Ridge Forest Reserve. Some of the country's best hiking can be had here. The Argyle Falls, a three-tiered cascade and one of the island's most iconic landmarks, is here, as is Flagstaff Hill, a dramatic viewpoint on the northern tip of the island.</p>]]><p><b>Kayak the calm waters of Chaguaramas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Comprising the entire peninsula which juts out to the west of Port of Spain, this is one of the best places in the country, especially Williams Bay, to try your hand at kayaking. You can book a tour of the isles peppered off the coast, where you can visit a lighthouse, cave systems and a (former) leper colony.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the vibrant Buccoo Reef</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Buccoo Reef is a jaw-droppingly beautiful coral reef that stretches around the coast from the island's highest point, Pigeon Point, to the arcing Buccoo Bay. A glass-bottomed boat tour will reveal some 40 types of coral, whilst Buccoo plays host to the best cultural events in the country, including the Sunday School Street Party and even a goat race. </p>]]><p><b>Pack your binoculars for Little Tobago</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to northeastern Tobago and the colourful beach settlement of Speyside. From here you can take a trip out to Little Tobago, also known as Bird of Paradise Island, a bird sanctuary and an essential stop-off for twitchers. Those wishing to spot the Scarlet Ibis, Trinidad and Tobago's national bird, should visit the Caroni Arena Reserve on Trinidad.</p>]]><p><b>Party and potter around Port of Spain</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A hefty dose of colourful, cosmopolitan life makes the Trinidadian capital a must-see. The city is far more diverse than you might expect: bazaars throng beneath modern skyscrapers and mosques rub shoulders with cathedrals. Whilst the architecture incorporates everything from Victorian houses to Stollmeyer's Castle, an imitation of a Bavarian Castle. Port of Spain is also home to the country's renowned carnival.</p>]]><p><b>Ride two wheels across rural Tobago</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tobago's lush, hilly interior has some fabulous biking trails, such as those in the Adventure Nature Reserve and around the Main Ridge Forest Reserve. For fans of all things two wheels, there are guided excursions to suit all ability levels with Mountain Biking Tobago.</p>]]><p><b>Spend away on Frederick Street</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With three malls, Port of Spain's shopping district is centred on Frederick Street. Nearby the Red House (a stately colonial building, now the seat of government), the National Museum and Art Gallery and the 19th-century Gothic Holy Trinity Cathedral offer plenty in terms of culture.</p>]]><p><b>Spend time in Tobago's tiny villages</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tobago is far more isolated than larger, more cosmopolitan Trinidad, and as such dropping in on some Tobago villages is a cultural eye-opener. On the Atlantic (windward) side of the island, there are many tiny villages including Mesopotamia and Goldsborough, the town of Roxborough and several beautiful bays. On the north coast, visit the picturesque villages of Castara and Parlatuvier.</p>]]><p><b>Swim in the sulphur pools of Pitch Lake</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to Trinidad's mellow southwest region to see Pitch Lake, one of the nation's weirdest phenomena. It is the largest natural deposit of asphalt anywhere in the world and is self-replenishing to boot. You can swim here in sulphur pools if accompanied by a guide.</p>]]><p><b>Try turtle-watching on Tobago</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For nature lovers, turtle-watching is magical. Three types – the giant leatherback, hawksbill and green – frequent the coast. The animals are legally protected, but you can take a guided tour to see the leatherbacks come ashore on Black Rock, or the hawksbills in the northeast of the island. March to August is when their infamous mating rituals take place.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Arnos Vale sugar plantation</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This former sugar plantation, the country's oldest, is now a hotel. However, the disused sugar mill, complete with formidable crushing wheels made in 1857, remains in the grounds. A well-presented museum rounds off what is all in all a fascinating testimony to a major chapter of Trinidad and Tobago's history.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$21.2 billion (2009).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum and petroleum products, natural gas, asphalt, manufactured goods, food and beverages.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, mineral fuels, manufactured goods, food and live animals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, Venezuela, Brazil, Jamaica, Spain, and Germany.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The oil and gas industry has been the most important in Trinidad and Tobago for some time. In the summer of 2003, Trinidad signed a landmark agreement with nearby Venezuela, one of the world's largest producers, to collaborate in all aspects of the oil and gas industries. Oil and gas stability, along with ties with Venezuela look to be lucrative for the country in the long-term future. Apart from oil and gas, Trinidad has the world's largest deposits of asphalt.  The non-oil industrial sector is concentrated in relatively new industries established with oil and gas revenues, such as plastics and electronics. The agricultural sector is small, with sugar cane, coffee, cocoa and citrus fruits as the main commodities.  The government has also sought to address historic under-investment in the tourism industry, a promising part of the economy which has undergone steady growth. The islands now cater to about 400,000 visitors annually; the industry is worth about US$275 million to the Trinidadian economy. Ecotourism is a sector which has seen a big lift, especially after Tobago was voted best ecotourism destination at the 2009 World Travel Awards. External debt has been substantially reduced. The economy grew by around 12% in 2006, while unemployment fell to a record low of 5.9%. Despite being hard-hit by the global financial crisis of 2009, the country had the diversity of economic resources in place to see it well on the road to recovery. A member of the  Caribbean trading bloc, CARICOM, Trinidad & Tobago is the most prosperous of the Caribbean nations and sees itself is a leading financial light in the region.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suits or 'shirt jacks' should be worn. It is normal to shake hands and exchange business cards. The country has some of the best and newest conference facilities in the Caribbean, and hosted both the 5th Summit of the Americas (SOTA) meeting and the Commonwealth Heads of Government Meeting (CHOGM) in 2009.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Trinidad and Tobago Chamber of Industry and Commerce (Inc)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 637 6966
					Website:http://www.chamber.org.tt
					Address: Westmoorings,Columbus Circle,Port of Spain,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Bars and restaurants open until late, with a very wide choice of local and Western food and drink. Chinese, Indian and West Indian cooking is available on both islands. Tobago also offers some notable seafood specialities and all types of fried fish. </p>
<p>Seafood is of course popular on the islands, with Trinidad&rsquo;s highlight being Buljol, a saltfish served with coconut bake and vegetables. On Tobago, trying the curried crab and dumplings is a must. The latter is great purchased from a roadside vendor: streetfood is a big thing across the country so do what the locals do and chow down on some.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Creole soups, the best being <em>sans coche</em>, <em>calaloo</em> and peppery pigeon pea soup.  <br />
&bull; Sorrel, a blood-red drink made from the sorrel fruit, or Angostura bitters (Trinidad &amp; Tobago is the proud home of the drink) <br />
&bull; <em>Tatoo</em> (armadillo) and<em> manicou</em> (opossum).<br />
&bull; Pork souse (pork boiled and served cold in a salty sauce with lime, cucumber, pepper, and onion slices). <br />
&bull; <em>Tum-tum</em> (mashed green plantains).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A 10 to 15% tip is usual in hotels and restaurants.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Trinidad has a wide and varied nightlife including hotel entertainment and nightclubs with calypso, limbo dancers and steel bands. Although it is dying out, you can still catch old-style calypso at Woodbrook in Port of Spain, whilst St James, on the western edge of the capital, is dubbed &ldquo;the city that never sleeps&rdquo; due to the pulsating bars and clubs.  During the carnival season (from New Year to Carnival, held two days before Ash Wednesday), both islands are alive with live music in the calypso tents and pan (steel band) yards. In Tobago, the main Calypsonians from Trinidad travel over to perform at Shaw Park, Scarborough and Roxborough. There is something happening most nights of the week at this time - details are available locally and from the <em>Tobago News</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can find goods from all over the world in Port of Spain, but characterful local purchases include calypso records, steel drums, leather bags and sandals, ceramics and woodcarvings. Gold and silver jewellery can be good value, as can Indian silks and fabrics. The country&rsquo;s cultural mix of African, Indian and Caribbean influences, in fact, means there are few better places on the planet to purchase bright clothes and materials. Rum should also be considered. Port of Spain&rsquo;s Frederick Street is the main shopping hub.</p><p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1600, Fri 0800-1800 and Sat 0800-1300. Some shops stay open later in Port of Spain, and malls are often open till 2100. Shops close on public holidays, especially during Carnival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major international chain hotels represented in Port of Spain include Crowne Plaza, Hilton, Hyatt and Marriott. There are  a number of smaller hotels in the surrounding areas. The capital is possibly the best place to stay for the business traveller in all the Caribbean islands. In Tobago, there is a growing number of international-standard resort hotels alongside the  many smaller private hotels and guest houses. A 10% government room tax and VAT are levied.  </p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> All types of accommodation must be booked months in advance for the Carnival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Tourism and Industrial Development Company Ltd publishes a list of guest houses found throughout Trinidad and Tobago. Great places to meet Trinidadians, guesthouses are ubiquitous, regularly inspected, and average (US$65) per night.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major international chain hotels represented in Port of Spain include Crowne Plaza, Hilton, Hyatt and Marriott. There are  a number of smaller hotels in the surrounding areas. The capital is possibly the best place to stay for the business traveller in all the Caribbean islands. In Tobago, there is a growing number of international-standard resort hotels alongside the  many smaller private hotels and guest houses. A 10% government room tax and VAT are levied.  </p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> All types of accommodation must be booked months in advance for the Carnival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major international chain hotels represented in Port of Spain include Crowne Plaza, Hilton, Hyatt and Marriott. There are  a number of smaller hotels in the surrounding areas. The capital is possibly the best place to stay for the business traveller in all the Caribbean islands. In Tobago, there is a growing number of international-standard resort hotels alongside the  many smaller private hotels and guest houses. A 10% government room tax and VAT are levied.  </p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> All types of accommodation must be booked months in advance for the Carnival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Public sector health care is free. However, health insurance is recommended as Tobago's health care provision is basic, with limited supplies and medication.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Drinking water outside main cities and towns may be contaminated and sterilisation is advisable. Bottled water is available. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables throughout both islands are generally safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are observed the following Monday. When two public holidays fall on the same date the following date is also given as a public holiday.<br /><br />(a) Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.<br /><br />(b) Hindu festivals are declared according to local astronomical observations and it is not possible to forecast the date of their occurrence exactly.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Spiritual/Shouter Baptist Liberation Day :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Indian Arrival Day :
							30 May </p><p>Corpus Christi :
							31 May </p><p>Sovereign's Birthday :
							09 June </p><p>Labour Day :
							19 June </p><p>Emancipation Day :
							01 August </p><p>Independence Day :
							31 August </p><p>Republic Day :
							24 September </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Trinidad and Tobago by persons over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1.5L of wine or spirits.<br />
&bull; Goods up to the value of TT$3,000 (you can only claim this limit once a year; if you make multiple trips, a record will be made of each claim until you meet the limit).&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted imports include firearms, honey, some toy guns and pornography.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Trinidad and Tobago Dollar (TTD; symbol TT$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of TT$100, 20, 10, 5 and 1. Coins are in denominations of 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents. The Trinidad & Tobago Dollar (TT$) is a relatively stable currency. Current rates: 1 TT$=US$0.15 or £0.10GBP. 1 US$ = 6.18 TT$. £1GBP = £9.93GBP.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currency can only be exchanged at authorised banks and some hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are accepted by most banks, shops and tourist facilities. A number of ATMs take debit and credit cards in both Trinidad and Tobago (Scarborough only).</p><p>A number of ATMs take debit and credit cards in both Trinidad and Tobago (Scarborough only).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are very widely accepted and will often prove the most convenient means of transaction. Banks charge a fee for exchanging traveller's cheques. Check for the best rates. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques, ideally in US Dollars or otherwise in Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1400, Fri 0900-1200 and 1500-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Trinidad and Tobago, a valid machine-readable passport is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: TT$200; multiple-entry visa: TT$400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Three months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy/high commission).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Depending on nationality, tourist visas will be issued in anything from a week to a month.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All visitors to Trinidad and Tobago must have proof of sufficient funds to cover their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To extend your stay, you need to apply to the Chief Immigration Officer. You can extend your stay to a maximum of six months from the date of entry into Trinidad and Tobago. See <a href="http://www.immigration.gov.tt" target="_blank">www.immigration.gov.tt</a> for details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[10.701007]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-61.152029]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>5,128 sq km (1,980 sq miles). Trinidad: 4,828 sq km (1,864 sq miles). Tobago: 300 sq km (116 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,364,973 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>238.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Port of Spain.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Trinidad and her tiny sister island of Tobago lie off the Venezuelan coast. Along the north of Trinidad runs the Northern Range of mountains, looming over the country's capital, Port of Spain. South of Port of Spain on the west coast the terrain is low, and the Caroni Swamps contain a magnificent bird sanctuary largely inhabited by the scarlet ibis. On the north and east coasts lie beautiful beaches. Central Trinidad is flat and largely given over to agriculture.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>26% Roman Catholic, 31.6% other Christian denominations, 22.5% Hindu,  6% Muslim and 16.1% other denominations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many local attitudes are often reflected in the lyrics of the calypso, the accepted medium for political and social satire since pre-emancipation days. Hospitality is important and entertaining is commonly done at home. Casual wear is usual, with shirt sleeves generally accepted for business and social gatherings, but beachwear is not worn in towns.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>115 volts AC, 60Hz. North American-style plugs with two flat pins (and sometimes a third grounding pin) are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Keith Rowley since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Paula Mae Weekes since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Arawak and Carib Indians, the original inhabitants of Trinidad and Tobago, led a relatively peaceful existence cultivating tobacco &ndash; from which the name Tobago derives &ndash; until the islands&rsquo; discovery by Christopher Columbus, who claimed them for Spain in 1498 with a Spanish colony being founded on Trinidad in 1532.</p>
<p>Over the ensuing centuries the islands became a battleground, fought over by the Spanish, Dutch, French and British, who left the fortifications to testify. Control switched hands some 30 times between the colonial powers as a lucrative sugar plantation industry run by slave labour developed. Abolition of slavery left a labour shortfall, which the British filled by encouraging Venezuelan farmers and forcing Indian labourers to settle.</p>
<p>Trinidad was formally ceded to the British Crown under the Treaty of Amiens in 1802; Tobago came under British control in 1814. In 1857 came the discovery that would shape the country thereafter: oil, which countered the near collapse of the sugar and cocoa industries. In 1888, Tobago was amalgamated with Trinidad and the islands have been administered as a single entity ever since.</p>
<p>By 1962, following various reforms, Trinidad and Tobago had achieved full independence. Eric Williams, for many still the father of the nation, took control of the country and served as prime minister from independence until his death in 1981. In 1976 the country became a republic within the Commonwealth and the economy boomed until a collapse in oil prices precipitated an attempt coup in 1990 when a 100-strong group of Islamic extremists occupied the Red House (the seat of Parliament) and the television station and held the country hostage for six days before surrendering.</p>
<p>The country remains a two-party system with a parliament based on the Westminster model and subject to elections every five years. Anthony Carmona, the fifth president, has been in office since 2013 and Prime Minister Keith Rowley took office in September 2015.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	The country can claim two Nobel Prize-winning authors in VS Naipaul and Derek Walcott, plus two Miss Universe titleholders with Janelle Commissiong in 1977 (the first black woman to take the title) and Wendy Fitzwilliam in 1998.<br />
&bull;	The two national birds on the Trinidad and Tobago coat of arms are the scarlet ibis and the cocrico.<br />
&bull;	The steelpan drum was first made in Trinidad and Tobago and is its national instrument.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[High Commission of the Republic of Trinidad and Tobago in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7245 9351.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.tthighcommission.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7245 9351.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700; Mon-Fri 1000-1400 (visa applications).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>42 Belgrave Square<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8NT<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Trinidad and Tobago in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 467 6490.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ttembassy.org/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 467 6490.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0900-1700, 1000-1430 (consular).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1708 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Trinidad and Tobago: two very different islands, one mighty inviting destination.  As the home of carnival, calypso and limbo dancing, not to mention Angostura Bitters, the country specialises in worldly contributions that have always been an assault on the senses. It&rsquo;s raw in places, cosmopolitan in others and has a wondrous line-up of festivals and celebrations. What&rsquo;s more, it punches way above its weight in the scenery stakes too. Diving? Hiking? Beaches? Waterfalls? Nightlife? Come on in.</p>
<p>To talk about it as one nation, however, is accurate but misleading. Oil-rich big brother Trinidad plays home to more than 95% of the country&rsquo;s population and has all the vigour this would suggest.  Port of Spain, surrounded by verdant hills, is the main city. Here, bazaars throng beneath modern skyscrapers and mosques share the skyline with cathedrals, while the whole place bounces to the beat of Carnival, one of the planet&rsquo;s great parties. It takes place annually on the Monday and Tuesday before Ash Wednesday &ndash; and more than meets the hype.</p>
<p>Beyond the capital beckon volcanoes, a self-replenishing asphalt lake and magnificent bird reserves, meaning the island is as famed among twitchers as it is among party animals.</p>
<p>Tiny Tobago, meanwhile, sitting 32km (20 miles) northeast of Trinidad, moves at an altogether gentler pace. No island was more fought over in the colonial era &ndash; it changed hands some 32 times, which says something about its appeal. It&rsquo;s fertile, located outside the hurricane belt and is even said to be the inspiration behind Daniel Defoe&rsquo;s Robinson Crusoe.&nbsp;Here, too, there are world-class attractions for nature lovers &ndash; it is home to the oldest protected rainforest in the Western Hemisphere &ndash; and you&rsquo;ll also find a spread of modern beach resorts. On both islands, meanwhile, the colourful jumble of different cultural influences has left T&amp;T with a delicious, spice-led cuisine.</p><p>Trinidad and Tobago: two very different islands, one mighty inviting destination.  As the home of carnival, calypso and limbo dancing, not to mention Angostura Bitters, the country specialises in worldly contributions that have always been an assault on the senses. It&rsquo;s raw in places, cosmopolitan in others and has a wondrous line-up of festivals and celebrations. What&rsquo;s more, it punches way above its weight in the scenery stakes too. Diving? Hiking? Beaches? Waterfalls? Nightlife? Come on in. To talk about it as one nation, however, is accurate but misleading. Oil-rich big brother Trinidad plays home to more than 95% of the country&rsquo;s population and has all the vigour this would suggest. Tiny Tobago, meanwhile, moves at an altogether gentler pace.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
