<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Tunisia" ColCode="tun" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="tn" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Tunisia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The areas of northern Tunisia that draw the most tourists have a typical Mediterranean climate, with hot, dry summers and mild, occasionally rainy winters. Along with destinations like <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/egypt">Egypt</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkey">Turkey</a>, Tunisia has claimed a good slice of the Mediterranean summer holiday market, making June to August a popular time for coastal resorts.</p>
<p>Spring and autumn both offer their own enticements though, both in terms of an appealing climate and a lessening of tourist traffic. This is the best time to visit the desert regions of the south and central Tunisia, as in summer the temperatures can climb to stifling heights, whilst in winter the Sahara can be bitterly cold at night.</p>
<p>Winter is low season in Tunisia and hotel prices often drop during the months of December to February. There are still plenty of sun-filled days but temperatures drop substantially once the sun has set and you need to come prepared for rain.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re visiting Tunis, December to March are the rainy season so pack an umbrella with you. May is a lovely time to visit as temperatures averaging 21C (70F). July and August are dry, but hot, averaging 28C (83F).</p>
<p>Sousse, located on the Gulf of Hammamet, has largely the same weather pattern as Tunis, though it is slightly cooler in comparison.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you are travelling in summer, lightweight clothing made from natural fibres such as cotton and linen are best to cope with the heat. Unless you will be exclusively staying on a resort, pack some longer sleeved tops, and long trousers or skirts for off-the-beach wear. In winter you'll need a rain jacket and a warm pullover to put on for the evenings. It's a good idea to bring these if you're travelling in spring and autumn as well.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline TunisAir (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.tunisair.com">www.tunisair.com</a>) and their subsidiary airline TunisAir Express (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.tunisairexpress.com.tn">www.tunisairexpress.com.tn</a>) are the only airlines operating domestic routes within Tunisia. From their hub at Tunis-Carthage Airport they have internal flights to Djerba, Monastir, Sfax, and Tozeur.</p>
<p>Prices are reasonable and services are normally heavily subscribed, so it is advisable to book ahead. However, the compact size of the country (Tunisia is the smallest in North Africa) means flying from A to B is rarely essential other than to save a few hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ferries operate between Sfax and the Kerkennah Islands, and between El Jorf and Djerba Island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Regular trains are run by SNCFT (tel: +216 71 345 511; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.sncft.com.tn">www.sncft.com.tn</a>) and connect Tunis with major towns. The main route is north-south between Tunis and Gab&egrave;s, via Sousse and Sfax, with a branch line to Monastir and Mahdia. Other lines out of Tunis link the capital with Bizerte and other northern spots.</p>
<p>There are three classes (classe confort, first class, and second class) all of which are air conditioned on most routes. Some 'Express' trains are one class only. It's a good idea to book in advance for popular routes, particularly over the summer months, though passengers can only book within 3 days of departure time and the best approach is to visit a train station and pay for the tickets in cash.</p>
<p>The historic Lezard Rouge (Red Lizard) train is a not-to-be-missed journey for train enthusiasts in Tunisia. The restored train carriages date from 1911 and the route, which runs three to five weekly from Metlaoui, offers passengers the spectacular views of Selja Gorge (tel: +216 76 241 469; www.lezard-rouge.com).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors who plan to make regular use of the rail network should buy a seven-, 15- or 21-day <em>carte bleue</em> (blue card), allowing unlimited travel on all routes. See SNCFT (<a href="http://www.sncft.com.tn" target="_blank">www.sncft.com.tn</a>) for details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tunisia has an extensive road network connecting all of the main towns and cities. Even smaller villages have some form of public transport which makes getting around the country using local transport reasonably easy.</p>r<p>All but the smallest roads are tar-sealed and the main motorways are generally in very good shape. Potholes can be a problem on minor roads.</p><p>The national bus company is SNTRI (tel: +216 71 905 433; <a href="http://www.sntri.com.tn" target="_blank">www.sntri.com.tn</a>) which runs a fleet of air-conditioned modern coaches between towns and cities across the country. Booking ahead is a good idea during the peak travel season of August and September.</p><p>There are two kinds of taxis in Tunisia. Private metered taxis are readily available within towns and cities and are reasonably priced. If you would like to hire the taxi for a half or full day it's usually cheaper to negotiate a price rather than work by the meter.</p>
<p>There are also long-distance shared taxis called <em>louages</em>. They leave their departure points when full and serve the whole of Tunisia. This is the quickest form of public road transport, although it can sometimes be a lengthy process waiting for the vehicle to fill. There are many louage stations and prices are similar to those of buses and trains.</p><p>Visitors must hold a full EU or international driving licence that has been valid for at least one year.</p><p>Speed limits are 50kph (30mph) in built-up areas, 90kpm (55mph) on the open road and 110kph (70mph) on freeways. Seatbelts are compulsory in the front seats.</p><p>Touring Club de Tunisie (tel: +216 71 323 114 or 182; <a href="http://www.touringclubtunisie.org" target="_blank">www.touringclubtunisie.org</a>), based in Tunis, can be of assistance in case of emergency breakdown.</p><p>You can find major international and local companies at all international airports and within bigger towns. Hire is relatively expensive; the charge usually includes insurance and breakdown cover. To hire a self-drive car, you must be over 21.</p><p>You can hire bikes from many hotels and guesthouses in resort areas such as Sousse and the island of Djerba, and in the town of Tozeur where they are a great form of sightseeing. Most local hired bikes are old and not in top-notch condition.</p>
<p>Anyone wanting to travel long distances by bike in Tunisia is better off bringing their bicycle from home. Cycling can be a pleasant way to see more of the countryside. Cyclists should be aware that rock-throwing can be an issue in remote areas, particularly in the south, and should always stay alert due to haphazard driving.</p><p>Speed limits are 50kph (30mph) in built-up areas, 90kpm (55mph) on the open road and 110kph (70mph) on freeways. Seatbelts are compulsory in the front seats.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tunisian cities and resorts are generally easy to get around by taxi, with the capital also offering local electric train services and a tram network. Care should be taken if driving, as pedestrians have a tendency to walk on the roads.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Tunisia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">tozeur</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Tunisia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">sfax</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Tunisia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">monastir</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Tunisia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">djerba</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flights to Tunisia are operated by the national airline, Tunis Air (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.tunisair.com">www.tunisair.com</a>) which has regular flights from many major European cities including <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/amsterdam">Amsterdam</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/berlin">Berlin</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/frankfurt">Frankfurt</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/madrid">Madrid</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/rome">Rome</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vienna">Vienna</a>, and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/z%C3%BCrich">Zurich</a>. Other airlines flying to Tunisia include Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>) from Paris and Eurowings (<a href="http://www.eurowings.com" target="_blank">www.eurowings.com</a>) from Cologne.</p>
<p>As Tunisia's main tourism focus is on summer beach breaks, the best flight prices are generally found in the low season, between the months of November to February, when the weather is distinctly cooler.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tunisia/tunis-carthage-international-airport">Tunis Carthage Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 3 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 11 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Tunis Carthage International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.tunis-airport.com<p>Tunis Carthage International Airport is located 7km (4 miles) northeast of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tunis">Tunis</a> city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+216 71 754 000</p>]]><b>Monastir Habib Bourguiba International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.habibbourguibaairport.com<p>The airport is 8km (5 miles) west of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Tozeur–Nefta International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 4km (2.5 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tunisia is very accessible by sea, with several regular ferry routes from European ports including <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/marseille">Marseille</a> (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a>), and&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/genoa">Genoa</a>, Civitavecchia, Salerno and&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/palermo">Palermo</a> (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy">Italy</a>). Tunisia has seven major ports at (from north to south) Bizerte, Tunis-La Goulette, Rad&egrave;s, Sousse, Sfax, Gab&egrave;s, and Zarzis. All are operated by Tunisia's Office de la Marine Marchande et des Ports (<a href="http://www.ommp.nat.tn" target="_blank">www.ommp.nat.tn</a>).</p><p>All public ferry routes to Tunisia run to/from Tunis-La Goulette Port except for one service from Trapani which uses Sousse Port.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From within Africa, a rail line exists from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/algeria">Algeria</a>, but no services currently operate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Due to ongoing security issues within <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/libya">Libya</a>, the situation at the Ras Ajdir border with Libya remains tense. Travellers are advised that the border may shut temporarily with little or no notice.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Public phones are found widely, with some shops also offering the service. Using Skype in an internet café though, is usually the more cost-effective option.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements with international mobile phone companies exist. You can buy a local SIM card at Tunisie Telecom offices if you provide appropriate identification.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tunisia has a high number of internet users, so email can be easily and cheaply accessed from Internet cafés in most towns and all resorts. Many hotels now also offer Wi-Fi for guest use. Connection is usually of a good standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The government has historically retained a tight hold on local broadcasting and the press, despite freedom of information being enshrined in the constitution. Although the ousting of the regime in early 2011 was hailed as a new beginning for press freedom in Tunisia, the national media is still very much controlled by the state. Journalists who challenge the government are discouraged through bureaucratic pressure and harassment and, at worst, imprisonment.</p>
<p>Daily newspapers are printed in Arabic or French, the most popular Arabic newspapers being <em>As-Sabah</em> and <em>Al-Horria</em>. French newspapers include <em>Le Quotidien</em>, <em>Nouvelles de Tunisie</em>, <em>La Presse de Tunisie</em> and <em>Le Temps</em>. Overseas newspapers are generally available in major centres two or three days after publication, and magazines like <em>Time</em> and <em>Newsweek</em> can also be found.</p>
<p>ERTT is the state-run broadcaster, owning the stations Tunisienne 1 and Tunisienne 2 (also known as Al Watanya 1 and Al Watanya 2). The country's privately-run commercial station is Hannibal TV and there are many foreign satellite channels (particularly from Egypt, Morocco, France and Italy). Tunisian Radio is state-run but there are now also several privately run stations including Radio Mosaique.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes three to five days; an express service guarantees delivery in four days or under.</p><p>Mon-Thu 0800-1200 and 1245-1645; Fri 0800-1200 and 1345-1645.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Matmata</p><![CDATA[<p>Due to a prominent role in the first Star Wars film, Matmata's subterranean dwellings, first dug out by the Berbers over 1000 years ago, attract hundreds of visitors each day. The main attraction here is Hotel Sidi Driss used as the cantina in <em>A New Hope</em>, and is still home to plenty of Star Wars paraphernalia. You can sleep here, troglodyte style, as well if you like.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bask in the glory of El-Jem</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For many visitors the UNESCO World Heritage-listed El-Jem Colosseum is Tunisia's historical highlight. Built in the 3rd century, this mammoth structure once held crowds of up to 35,000 and today towers over the modern surrounding town. The largest amphitheatre in North Africa and modelled on Rome's own Colosseum, it's an example of just how far the mighty long Roman arm reached – to the very centre of Tunisia.</p>]]><p><b>Cruise over sand dunes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The dramatic sand dunes of the Grand Erg Oriental ripple out in waves across the horizon. This hypnotic landscape was used in the movie <em>The English Patient </em>and has since become one of the most famous corners of the Sahara. From the dusty desert outpost of Douz you can organise camel treks or 4x4 trips to the dunes. Dune skiing and desert dune-buggy trips are also available.</p>]]><p><b>Delve into the ruins of Dougga</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This UNESCO World Heritage Site is one of North Africa's best-preserved ancient ruins. Although most of the surviving monuments here are from the Roman period, Dougga's history stretches right back to the 6th century. With its dramatic hilltop position and ample monumental buildings and temples, it is one of Tunisia's most impressive tourist attractions.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the town of Sidi Bou Saïd</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gorgeously quaint and stunningly picturesque, Sidi Bou Saïd is a vision of white-and-blue buildings perched above the Mediterranean. Wander the cobblestone alleyways through the village, stop for syrupy Arabic coffee at a cliff-side cafe, and then unwind on the charmingly old-fashioned beach. It's an easy day-trip from Tunis.</p>]]><p><b>Find the Force in Chott El Jerid</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Stretching for 5,000 sq m (53,819 sq ft) the salt pan of Chott El Jerid has a mesmerising otherworldliness which was used to great effect in the Star Wars films. In summer, the dry salt crust blisters and shimmers in the heat, while in winter sections of it flood and have to be traversed by boat. To visit the Chott El Jerid, most people stay in Tozeur.</p>]]><p><b>Get back to nature in Lake Ichkeul</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the far north of the country, World Heritage-listed Lake Ichkeul is a haven for birdwatchers and nature lovers. The best time to visit is between the months of December and March when thousands of migratory birds – including flamingos, egrets and storks – descend on the wetlands to pass the winter.</p>]]><p><b>Golf your way around Monastir</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Monastir is famed for its impressive seafront <em>rabat</em>, or fort, which was used in <em>Monty Python's Life of Brian</em>, as well as the sumptuous interior of Habib Bourguiba's mausoleum. But the seaside town now also attracts golf-tourism with championship courses Palm Links, El Kantaoui and the Flamingo Golf Course all in the vicinity.</p>]]><p><b>Have it all on Cap Bon Peninsula</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There's something for everyone on the Cap Bon Peninsula. Sun and sea-seekers will love the resort amenities at Nabuel, culture vultures can explore Kelibia's fort, the old Roman quarry at Ghar el-Khabir and the Punic ruins of Kerkouane, and everyone can enjoy El Haouaria's lovely strip of beach.</p>]]><p><b>Show solidarity at Bardo Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Tunisia's most important museums, Bardo was the target of a terrorist attack in March 2015. It held a reopening ceremony a week later (with beefed-up security) coinciding with a huge solidarity march through Tunis. The museum remains an essential guide to the country's multi-faceted history, with a superlative collection of mosaics and a comprehensive range of artefacts from countless ancient sites.</p>]]><p><b>Soak up cool vibes in the capital</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Shaped over the centuries by a mixture of Ottoman, Arabic and French-colonial influences, Tunisia's capital is a wonderful muddle of old and new. In the shady medina back alleys, old men puff on shisha and play backgammon, while along the broad French-style avenues of the modern town, the cafes brim with bright young things toting laptops and chattering on their mobiles.</p>]]><p><b>Steam with the locals in a hammam</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Tunisia's essential experiences is to visit a hammam, a traditional 'Turkish' bath that's a mix between a public bath and a sauna, typically in a lavish, old-tiled setting. The practice dates back to Roman and Punic times, when natural hot springs were much sought. Today there are five-star spa experiences, while traditional hammams such as El-Kachachine endure as dilapidated architectural gems.</p>]]><p><b>Step back in time at Bulla Regia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The semi-subterranean Roman ruin of Bulla Regia is one of Tunisia's most impressive archaeological sites. The Romans used underground architecture here to escape the brutal heat, but the unusual design also preserved the city from eroding over time, offering a rare chance to explore complete Roman villas.</p>]]><p><b>Support Sousse</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Like Bardo, Sousse was subject to a terrorist attack in the summer of 2015. Before then, it was a vibrant seaside town, especially Boujaffar Beach with its long stretch of white sand and lively nightlife strip, but tourism has naturally taken a hit. But Sousse has a long resilient history dating back to the Phoenicians, under whom it was an important coastal town. It will recover.</p>]]><p><b>Take it easy in Djerba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The chilled-out island of Djerba is a Mediterranean idyll with its whitewashed villages, craft markets, and postage-stamp sized beaches shaded by palm trees. It's a wonderful place to relax in, doing little more strenuous than browsing the shops, enjoying leisurely lunches of fresh seafood and lounging on the sands.</p>]]><p><b>Venture into the Sahara</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It seems a shame to come to Tunisia without getting a taste of the dramatic desolate horizons that make up the country's southern half. A number of companies organise Sahara trips, which range from a couple of hours on a camel to a full-on voyage into the sands.</p>]]><p><b>Venture under the sea around Tabarka</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tabarka is Tunisia's top spot for snorkelling and diving. The town itself is a gentle-paced seaside resort which oozes old fashioned style, and it's a lovely stop off if you want to recharge your travel batteries. Not far from shore is the magical underwater world of the Galite Islands, which are the main draw for scuba diving fans.</p>]]><p><b>Visit a galaxy far, far away in Matmata</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Due to a prominent role in the first Star Wars film, Matmata's subterranean dwellings, first dug out by the Berbers over 1,000 years ago, attract hundreds of visitors each day. The main attraction here is Hotel Sidi Driss, used as the cantina in <em>Episode IV:A New Hope</em>, and still home to plenty of Star Wars paraphernalia. You can even sleep here, troglodyte style, if the fancy takes you.</p>]]><p><b>Wonder at sacred Kairouan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Kairouan's skyline of minarets is packed to the brim with beautiful Islamic architecture, not least the breath-taking 9th-century Great Mosque. Founded in 670, the city dates back to the beginning of Islam in the Maghreb and is seen as the religion's fourth holiest site. Aside from sacred landmarks, you'll spend hours exploring the labyrinthine medina, full of spindling alleyways backed by crumbling pastel-hued houses.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$39.88 billion (2017).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Clothing, textiles, mechanical goods, chemicals, and agricultural products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Textiles, machinery, equipment, chemicals and food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, Germany, Italy, Spain and Libya.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tunisia's economy is based around agriculture (main products are wheat, barley, olive oil, wine and fruit), mining (phosphates, iron, lead, aluminium fluoride and zinc), tourism, and manufacturing (chemicals, textiles, machinery, paper and wood).<br />
The government is working to increase foreign investments and lower unemployment. Though budget deficit remains high and external debt has climbed, there are signs of economic recovery in pockets across the country.<br />
Tunisia's most important trade links are with the EU whose members (principally France, Germany and Italy) account for three-quarters of all the country's trade</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arabic and French are the most widely used languages in business circles and a knowledge of either is useful. Interpreter services are available. Appointments are required. General business is best conducted outside of the peak holiday periods, and visits can often be impractical during Ramadan.</p>
<p>Tunisians are relaxed about time-keeping, but it's wise to arrive on time for appointments even if the person you're meeting may well arrive late. Hospitality is both important and ritualised: an extended round of greetings welcomes any meeting.</p>
<p>After shaking hands it's customary to lightly press your right palm to your heart. Male acquaintances often kiss on the cheek on greeting. Coffee usually accompanies any meeting.</p>
<p>Suits are usually worn. Both sexes should avoid short sleeves and should keep their knees covered. Business relationships and negotiations tend to develop slowly and visitors should adopt the local pace. Conversations may be wide ranging, but politics should be avoided. If invited to a Tunisian's house, a small gift of sweets or flowers is appropriate.</p>
<p>Most large hotels in Tunisia have some conference facilities. Major conferences are usually held in Tunis or Hammamet.</p><p>Shops open from 0900-1300, though some may re-open in the evening, particular those selling souvenirs. Banks open from 0830-1100 in summers, and from 0830-1100 and 1400-1600 in winters. Museums and key attractions open until 1400 or 1500 hours.  Expect many businesses and offices to close on Friday lunchtime, and more closure during the month of Ramadan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre de Commerce et d'Industrie de Tunis</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (71) 350 300
					Website:http://www.ccitunis.org.tn/
					Address: 1000 Tunis,31 Avenue de Paris,,]]><b>Agence de Promotion de l'Industrie (API)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (71) 792 144
					Website:http://www.tunisieindustrie.nat.tn/
					Address: 1002 Tunis,63 rue de Syrie,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tunisian food combines Arabic, Berber, European and Middle Eastern elements. Dishes are cooked with olive oil, spiced with aniseed, coriander, cumin, caraway, cinnamon or saffron and flavoured with mint, orange blossom or rose water; many are accompanied by harissa, a spicy chilli and garlic condiment.</p>
<p>On the coast you'll find fresh seafood, while in the southern Sahara region menus often feature Berber specialties, most notably rustic, wholesome stews. Roast chicken and baked lamb dishes are popular throughout the country, as are dishes featuring couscous. Salads form an integral part of the diet all year-round, are simple and lightly dressed.</p>
<p>If you've a sweet tooth, you won't be disappointed in Tunisia. There is a dizzying array of Middle Eastern-style sweets and cakes to choose from, often containing plenty of nuts and drenched in honey or syrup. There are also delicious pastries left over from the years of French rule, so expect plenty of melt-in-the-mouth croissants and pains au chocolat.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Couscous</strong>: Ground semolina served with meat, fish or vegetable sauce.<br />
<strong>Harissa</strong>: A hot paste derived from chillies, tomatoes, spices and olive oil.<br />
<strong>Salade mechouia</strong>: Roasted vegetable salad, particularly peppers, sometimes topped with boiled eggs slices.<br />
<strong>Tajine</strong>: A kind of spiced quiche, served cold, not to be confused with the Moroccan dish of the same name.<br />
<strong>Brik</strong>: The Tunisian version of Turkish borek, a deep-fried filled pastry. Common ingredients include tuna, egg, onions, capers and parsley.<br />
<strong>Merguez</strong>: A heavily spiced beef sausage.<br />
<strong>Filfilmahshi</strong>: Peppers stuffed with beef and harissa.<br />
<strong>Lablabi</strong>: Chickpea soup with lashings of garlic and cumin.<br />
<strong>Marqa</strong>: A slow-cooked stew of meat and vegetables, particularly tomatoes and olives.<br />
<strong>Ojja</strong>: Tunisian scrambled eggs, usually spiced with harissa, as well as tomatoes, peppers and sometimes meat.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Not a requirement, but waiters and taxi drivers are usually tipped a few coins; waiters in tourist restaurants are accustomed to 10%.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18 years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local evening entertainment is dominated by cafe culture and even the smallest town will have one or two cafes where people congregate once the sun has set. The most atmospheric of these are the tiny places which spill out onto the pavement, with customers sucking on shisha pipes, playing backgammon, and drinking tea or coffee into the wee hours.&nbsp;</p>
<p>In bigger cities such as Tunis, Sfax and Sousse, these more traditional places are usually found in or around the medina. The new parts of town usually sport modern adaptations of the cafe which have a more European feel and sometimes serve alcohol. Spending an evening in a traditional cafe can be a great way of getting under the skin of local life.</p>
<p>Cinema is also extremely popular among Tunisians. Films are generally in Arabic or French, and the same is true of the plays at Tunis&rsquo;s several theatres. Tourist entertainment usually comes in the form of restaurants or hotel bars featuring live music and belly dancers in the evenings from May to September.</p>
<p>In areas that draw a lot of international visitors there are nightclubs, which tend to be either a magnet for wealthy young Tunisians or aimed solely at tourists. Summer is the season for arts festivals, when traditional and international artists arrive in Tabarka, Carthage, Hammamet and Nabeul. In late summer there are also several music festivals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The medinas of Tunisia's larger towns, such as Tunis, Kairouan, Sousse and Sfax are great places to buy Tunisian crafts, with an amazing range, but you will have to haggle. Souvenir shops in resort areas are plentiful, but you may have to look a bit harder to find high-quality goods.<br />
<br />
In terms of what to buy, special purchases include copper and brassware, olivewood sculptures, leather goods such as slippers and bags, clothing (kaftans, jelabas), perfume oils, pottery and ceramics, silver and enamelled jewellery and shishas (water pipes). Sidi Bou Said is famous for its decorative wooden bird cages. Nabeul is a pottery production centre with plenty of independent workshops selling tile work as well as other ceramic art. <br />
<br />
Rugs and carpets are a good buy. Kairouan is Tunisia's carpet capital and there are plenty of carpet dealers in town with sumptuous local carpets on display. Many carpet dealers are knowledgeable experts on the carpet craft and can be of excellent help when choosing a carpet. Unfortunately though, there are also a few willing to lie and cheat, so do be aware of this when shopping for a carpet. <br />
<br />
Tunisian carpets are, in general, boldly geometric in design and more muted in colour than their Central Asian counterparts. The two major types are woven (non-pile) and knotted (pile). Look out for traditional Berber pieces, called alloucha. The quality of all carpets is strictly controlled by the National Handicrafts Office, and a label attached to the carpet shows its quality seal and grading. The best advice is to only buy the carpet you love, and to never buy straight off the pile. If you spot a carpet you think you might like as it's thrown down, have the carpet dealer remove it from the pile so that you can look at it separately.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1300, though shops selling souvenirs are likely to open in the afternoon or evening. Hours are shorter during Ramadan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The appeal of Tunisia&rsquo;s Mediterranean beaches &ndash; and the sailing, sunbathing and golfing that go along with them &ndash; means the country&rsquo;s resort areas are now well stocked with high-standard international resorts. Many of the resorts in Tunisia are identical in terms of facilities and design to those found in the Spanish Costas.</p>
<p>Large resort-style hotels in Tunisia can usually be found in a 'Zone Touristique', which has all the major tourist hotels together in a specially constructed quarter. More characterful (but usually less luxurious) hotels in Tunisia&nbsp;are often to be found in the town centre. Most of the better tourist properties are located in the coastal resort areas, where several international chains have taken up presence in recent years.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotel accommodation in Tunisia is&nbsp;inspected by the government and&nbsp;is classified by a star system ranging from deluxe (5-star) to simple (1-star). Places that have not been inspected are designated <em>nonclassifi&eacute; </em>(NC; non-classified).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The appeal of Tunisia&rsquo;s Mediterranean beaches &ndash; and the sailing, sunbathing and golfing that go along with them &ndash; means the country&rsquo;s resort areas are now well stocked with high-standard international resorts. Many of the resorts in Tunisia are identical in terms of facilities and design to those found in the Spanish Costas.</p>
<p>Large resort-style hotels in Tunisia can usually be found in a 'Zone Touristique', which has all the major tourist hotels together in a specially constructed quarter. More characterful (but usually less luxurious) hotels in Tunisia&nbsp;are often to be found in the town centre. Most of the better tourist properties are located in the coastal resort areas, where several international chains have taken up presence in recent years.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotel accommodation in Tunisia is&nbsp;inspected by the government and&nbsp;is classified by a star system ranging from deluxe (5-star) to simple (1-star). Places that have not been inspected are designated <em>nonclassifi&eacute; </em>(NC; non-classified).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The appeal of Tunisia&rsquo;s Mediterranean beaches &ndash; and the sailing, sunbathing and golfing that go along with them &ndash; means the country&rsquo;s resort areas are now well stocked with high-standard international resorts. Many of the resorts in Tunisia are identical in terms of facilities and design to those found in the Spanish Costas.</p>
<p>Large resort-style hotels in Tunisia can usually be found in a 'Zone Touristique', which has all the major tourist hotels together in a specially constructed quarter. More characterful (but usually less luxurious) hotels in Tunisia&nbsp;are often to be found in the town centre. Most of the better tourist properties are located in the coastal resort areas, where several international chains have taken up presence in recent years.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotel accommodation in Tunisia is&nbsp;inspected by the government and&nbsp;is classified by a star system ranging from deluxe (5-star) to simple (1-star). Places that have not been inspected are designated <em>nonclassifi&eacute; </em>(NC; non-classified).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Taking out comprehensive travel insurance before travelling to Tunisia is essential.&amp;nbsp; If you are bringing medication into the country for a pre-existing medical condition, carry a letter from your doctor listing the names of the medications, and any syringes or needles, you are carrying with you. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tunisia's public healthcare system often provides excellent care in larger towns, but be aware that you have to pay for treatment, usually in cash, straight away whether you have travel insurance or not. Larger towns also have private hospitals called 'polyclinics' which provide a range of procedures. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The emergency/ambulance phone number in Tunisia is 190. Ambulance arrival times can be delayed and the service is not available in more rural areas.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water is normally chlorinated in urban areas; while it is safe to drink, it may cause mild abdominal upsets. It is advisable to only drink bottled water during your stay, which is widely available everywhere. It's worth also noting that ice is rarely made from bottled water (even in resort areas) so take precautions. Milk should be boiled when unpasteurised. UHT milk is available and is advised.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled before eating. When choosing where to eat, look for popular places which have a high turnover of food meaning food will be fresher and will not have been sitting around for a long time. Avoid ice cream being sold on the street, which might have melted and been refrozen.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against Hepatitis B are recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Independence Day :
							20 March </p><p>Youth Day :
							21 March </p><p>Martyrs' Day :
							09 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Republic Day :
							25 July </p><p>Women's Day :
							13 August </p><p>New Era Day :
							07 November </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Tunisia without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 500g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of alcoholic drinks over 25% volume or 2L of alcoholic drinks less than 25% volume.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited items include local currency, firearms (other than authorised hunting weapons), explosives, narcotics, counterfeit goods, used clothing (other than for personal use), palm trees and branches, henna, dangerous dogs, and anything considered harmful to good morals, health, public safety or state security.</p>
<p>Restricted items include professional audiovisual material, some telecommunications equipment, plants and animals, hunting rifles, and weighing and measuring instruments.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local currency, antiquities and artworks, firearms (other than authorised hunting rifles), explosives, narcotics, counterfeit goods, endangered species,&nbsp;and anything considered harmful to good morals, health, public safety or state security.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tunisian Dinar (TND; the symbol DT is also used commonly within Tunisia) = 1,000 millimes. Notes are in denominations of TND 50, 30, 20, 10 and 5 millimes. Coins are in denominations of TND 1, 5, 10 dinars, as well as 5, 10, 20, 50 and 500 millimes. The 10 and 5 millimes coins are not commonly used but are still legal tender. Please note that it is a criminal offence to import or export dinar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can exchange foreign currency at banks, bureau de exchanges, and at post offices. Exchange rates are fixed so there should not be any difference in the rate you are offered wherever you choose to exchange. Bring your passport along as it will usually be required if you want to change money. The easiest currencies to exchange are British Pounds, Euro and US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit and debit cards using the Visa network are accepted as payment in most larger tourist-orientated stores, and many midrange and luxury hotels, as well as at most car hire agencies and established travel agencies. Mastercard is also accepted but may sometimes have issues with authorization. American Express and Diners Club are only accepted in a few places in tourist areas and shouldn't be relied upon.</p><p>ATMs are widely available in tourist resorts and in most towns. Most ATMs are linked to the Visa network though a few, such as ATMs connected to the Bank of Tunisia, also accept Maestro. It is important to always have a small emergency cash fund at hand while travelling in Tunisia for the times when the ATM rejects your card, or simply doesn't work, which can be a quite frequent occurrence, especially once you're away from the coastal resort areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Officially travellers cheques should be able to be cashed at any bank or bureau de exchange. In reality, many banks (except larger branches in cities and tourist areas) will refuse to exchange them. You will be charged commission on every exchange. If you do want to take travellers cheques the most convenient currencies are Euros and US Dollars. Travellers cheques are only accepted in some hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Banks open from 0830-1100 in summers, and from 0830-1100 and 1400-1600 in winters. During Ramadan (the Islamic holy month of fasting), banks open for shorter hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Tunisia, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Children entering Tunisia are required to have their own passport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A seven-day transit visa is also available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Varies</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Entry visa: 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow two weeks for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dogs and cats must be vaccinated for rabies 30 days before travelling to Tunisia. A qualified veterinarian in your home country must complete the Tunisian Veterinary Certificate declaring that your animal is healthy and fit to travel. This then acts as a passport for your pet. Animals with the correct documentation are not required to be quarantined once they have arrived.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[34.356046]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[9.753961]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>163,610 sq km (63,170 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>11,375,220 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>67.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tunis.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Republic of Tunisia lies on the North African coast, 130km (80 miles) southwest of Sicily and 160km (100 miles) due south of Sardinia. Dwarfed by its neighbours, sandwiched between Algeria to the west and Libya to the east, Tunisia is just over 163,000 sq km in size. It may be small but Tunisia has a landscape which varies from the cliffs of the north coast, to the woodland of the interior, from desert to rich, arable land, and from mountains to salt pans below sea level.</p>
<p>The 1,148 km (713 miles) Mediterranean coastline is dotted with small islands, notably Djerba in the south and Kerkennah in the east. The coastline is backed by lush pasture, orchards, vineyards and olive groves and is the most populous area of the country.</p>
<p>The north of the country is increasingly mountainous with rolling pine-clad hills a large feature of the landscape. South of Gafsa and Gab&egrave;s the central region's countryside becomes starker with semi-arid plains as the Sahara begins to exert its influence.</p>
<p>The desert region of the Sahara is one of Tunisia's most famous features. Its diverse environment of mammoth salt pans, vast sand plains and towering dunes, interspersed with lush oases forms the landscape of the south.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The principal religion is Islam; there are small Roman Catholic, Protestant and Jewish minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arabic in culture and tradition, Tunisia is a liberal and tolerant Muslim society with many equality laws enshrined in the Tunisian Constitution brought in by the country's first president Habib Bourguiba. Polygamy is outlawed, women are free to choose whether to wear the headscarf, and have the right to ask for divorce, work, run their own businesses, and have access to abortion and birth control.</p>
<p>Although cities like <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/africa/tunisia/tunis">Tunis</a>, Sfax and Sousse can seem extremely liberal and modern, it is important to remember that in more rural areas local life is much more traditional. Outside of resort areas visitors should dress modestly out of respect for their culture. Most Tunisian men would not be caught dead wearing shorts once off the beach and in the countryside it is practically unheard of. Likewise, once away from touristy areas, women should avoid wearing skimpy, revealing clothing. When visiting mosques and other religious buildings, both sexes should make sure their clothing covers their upper arms and knees, and women should wear a headscarf.&nbsp;On a separate note, Tunisians take a lot of pride in their dress and although informal clothing is now very acceptable among younger Tunisians, visitors will garner more respect if they don&rsquo;t dress scruffily.</p>
<p>Shaking hands is the usual form of greeting. Women greeting other women and men greeting other men will often also kiss each other the cheek. It is common to place your right hand across your heart after shaking hands. This is also a polite way of showing your thanks. Occasionally, among more religious people greeting people of the opposite sex, this is used as a greeting instead of shaking hands.</p>
<p>Hospitality is important in Tunisia and a small gift in appreciation of hospitality or as a token of friendship is always well-received.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Youssef Chahed since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Beji Caid Essebsi since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Like much of North Africa, Tunisia's history is one littered with conquests that completely changed the country's path. The most famous people of the ancient world to mark the area of modern-day Tunisia were the Phoenicians, who settled here in the 1st millennium BCE and went on to found their legendary capital of Carthage.</p>
<p>The Phoenicians' expanding regional power brought them to the attention of the Ancient Greeks, and later Rome, leading to the Punic Wars. After three wars, Rome emerged victorious and it is largely their mighty monuments that have survived in Tunisia today.</p>
<p>As Rome waned, the region fell first into the hands of the Byzantine Empire, but it was the Arab Conquest of the 7th century CE that changed the land forever, introducing Islam and a sophisticated culture. Further invasions in the 11th to 13th centuries by Arab tribesman, then Almoravids and Almohads transformed the region even further, bringing near-total Arabisation, new cities and sparkling mosques.</p>
<p>By the 16th century, the Ottoman Turks had incorporated Tunisia into their vast empire, though left little mark on the masses. They held sway until the 19th century 'Scramble for Africa' by European empire builders. The Italians were initially most prominent, until French troops invaded from the neighbouring colony in Algeria, and made Tunisia a French protectorate in 1881.</p>
<p>Independence from France was achieved in 1956, and Habib Bourguiba became the country&rsquo;s first president. His government was responsible for many of the facets that still shape Tunisia today, from widespread public education to female emancipation.</p>
<p>Bourguiba was succeeded by President Zine El Abidine Ben Ali in 1987, who billed himself as a great moderniser, and announced major economic reforms. Despite this, his regime was guilty of numerous human rights offences and widening inequality, while cronyism and corruption became norms in the latter years of his dictatorship. At the same time, nearly all forms of opposition to Ben Ali's government were repressed through a powerful security apparatus.</p>
<p>In December 2010 rising disenchantment with the regime led to widespread public demonstrations over unemployment, poverty, and freedom of speech, which became known as the Jasmine Revolution and was the trigger for the Arab Spring that swept across the region. Ben Ali was forced to step down as president in January 2011, ushering in a new democratic era.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; The Berbers are believed to have arrived in modern-day Tunisia around 2000 BCE; there remains a small but significant Berber minority.<br />
&bull; During the French protectorate, Tunisians could become French citizens &ndash; only if they renounced their 'Muslim' status.<br />
&bull; Until independence, there were almost 100,000 Italians living in Tunisia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Tunisian Embassy in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(262) 862 1850</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.tunisianembassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(262) 862 1850</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1400 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1515 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20005<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Tunisian Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7584 8117</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.at-londres.diplomatie.gov.tn/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7584 8117</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1300 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>29 Princes Gate<br/>London<br/>SW7 1QG<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Tunisia ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(216) 71 108 700</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/world/tunisia</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(216) 71 108 700</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thu 0800-1630; Fri 0800-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Les Berges du Lac<br/>Rue du Lac Windermere<br/>Tunis<br/>1053<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From broad sweeps of beach overlooked by a tumble of sugar-cube houses, to grand ancient ruins and the vast, rolling dunes of the Sahara, Tunisia encapsulates everything that&rsquo;s enticing about North Africa.</p>
<p>Lose yourself in the maze of medina alleyways inTunis, explore the Maghreban mosques of Kairouan and stand on the shimmering salt flats of Chott El Jerid. Tuck into freshly baked <em>brik</em> at a bustling street market, pretend to be a Roman gladiator at El Jem&rsquo;s impressive amphitheatre and hoist yourself onto a camel for a trip into the desert.</p>
<p>Traditionally, sun-seeking tourists came to Tunisia for its beaches &ndash; lining the Mediterranean, the long, rambling coastline is impressive. There are also tiny coastal villages where fishermen haul in the day&rsquo;s catch on quiet beaches and cobblestone streets are lined with blooming bougainvillea.</p>
<p>But Tunisia is so much more than a seaside destination where visitors lounge on the sands all day long. Join the locals at a caf&eacute; after the last notes of the call to prayer have faded, or puff on apple-scented shisha as you watch old men play dominos. Alternatively, get scrubbed and steamed on a marble slab under the tiled domes of a hammam. Or haggle in the souks, sipping glasses of mint tea while you barter for the best price. Suffice to say the age-old traditions of Tunisian life are still alive and well.</p>
<p>Regarded as one of North Africa&rsquo;s most politically moderate countries, Tunisia balances traditional Islamic culture with modern influences. Beyond the ancient medina, the cities are full of restaurants, cafes and bars, many of which have a European air about them.</p>
<p>Though tourism took a hit in recent years after a number of suicide attacks on tourists and the authority. The Tunisian government is working to improve security in major cities and tourist resorts.</p><p>From broad sweeps of beach overlooked by sugar-cube houses, to grand ancient ruins and the vast, rolling dunes of the Sahara, Tunisia encapsulates everything that&rsquo;s enticing about North Africa.</p>
<p>Lose your way in the maze of medina alleyways in Tunis or explore the Maghreban mosques of Kairouan. Stand on the edge of the glittering Chott El Jerid salt flats to see the silver crust shimmer, mirror-like, for miles. Walk through the underground tunnel of El Jem and arrive in the middle of the amphitheatre as Roman gladiators once did. Or hoist yourself onto a camel and venture out into the desert dunes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
