<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Turkmenistan" ColCode="tkm" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="tm" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Turkmenistan]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Turkmenistan has an extreme continental climate: temperatures in Ashgabat vary between 46°C (114°F) in summer and -5°C (23°F) in winter, although it has been known to reach -22°C (-8°F) in extremity. Temperatures in the desert in summer can reach 50°C (122°F) during the day before falling rapidly at night. During the winter, it can reach -10° to -15°C (14° to 15°F).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For those intending to visit the desert in summer, lightweights are<br />vital for the day with warmer clothing for those intending to spend the<br />night in the open. Heavyweights should be taken for winter visits.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Turkmenistan Airlines&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.turkmenairlines.org" target="_blank">www.turkmenairlines.org</a>) runs regular flights between Ashgabat, Chardzhou, Dashoguz, Mary, Turkmenbashi and Turkmenabat, and to Kerki (far east) and Balkanabat. All flight tickets have to be paid for in local currency.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Trains are cheap, but slow and uncomfortable. There is a day-time and overnight train between Ashgabat and Turkmenbashi; overnight trains to Turkmenabat, one continuing to Dashgouz; and an overnight service between Ashgabat and Gushgi via Mary (although Gushgi is off limits due to its border with Afghanistan). The Trans-Caspian Railway runs from Turkmenbashi (formerly Krasnovodsk) in the west, through Ashgabat and Mary to Chardzhou in the east before continuing to Bukhara in Uzbekistan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main road in Turkmenistan runs along the route of the Trans-Caspian Railway.  There is also a road that runs north from Ashgabat to Tashauz and Kunya-Urgench before crossing into Uzbekistan.  This road crosses 500km (311 miles) of the Kara-Kum desert. Conditions can be dangerous.</p>r<p>You can find taxis and chauffeur-driven cars for hire in all major towns. Many are unlicensed and it's advisable to agree the fare in advance. As many of the street names have changed since independence, it's also worth knowing both the old and new street names when asking directions.</p><p>An International Driving Permit, or national licence with authorised translation, is required.</p><p>Self-drive hire is available from a few large hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Turkmenistan Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkmenairlines.org" target="_blank">www.turkmenairlines.org</a>). There are no direct flights to Turkmenistan from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>. Options include flights with Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>) via Istanbul, Lufthansa (<a href="http://www.lufthansa.com" target="_blank">www.lufthansa.com</a>) via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/frankfurt">Frankfurt</a>, or S7 Airlines (<a href="http://www.s7.ru" target="_blank">www.s7.ru</a>) via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a> (the first leg is operated by British Airways). From the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>, the quickest route is via Frankfurt with Lufthansa.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 9 hours (including stopover); from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 17 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare. However, you have to pay an arrival fee of US$12-14 depending on your nationality.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Ashgabat International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is approximately 13km (8 miles) northwest of the city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no international rail services into Turkmenistan. Only freight trains use the modern link from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iran">Iran</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Area code for Ashgabat: 12.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies. Coverage is limited to Ashgabat.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All Internet caf&eacute;s were closed by the government. The state strictly controls Internet access.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Turkmenistan has an incredibly poor record when it comes to press freedom. Reporters Without Frontiers has said the president uses the media solely to 'promote his own glory'. The Turkmen government controls all media, monitoring media outlets, operating printing presses and laying down editorial policies. Programmes from Russian TV stations are censored. The government controls Internet access, banning or censoring what it considers inappropriate sites and restricting use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Letters to Western Europe and the USA can take between two weeks and two months. Stamped envelopes can be bought from post offices. Mail addresses should be laid out in the following order: country, postcode, city, street, house number and lastly the person's name.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800. The main Post Office in Ashgabat is open until 1900.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bathe in an underground lake, Bakharden</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a day trip to Bakharden, 90km (56 miles) west of Ashgabat. The underground mineral lake (known in Turkmen as Kov Ata, which means "father of lakes") is fed by hot springs and has a constant temperature of 37°C (97°F). Bathing is permitted although there is an admission fee. Accommodation is not available.</p>]]><p><b>Climb the cooler climes of Chuli Valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy the natural splendour of the Chuli Valley, a popular mountain resort. Accessible by taxi or private car, the drive takes you through a picturesque gorge and up to the cooler air. Visitors hoping to hike and climb can do so by arrangement, and there is even the opportunity to stay here.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy a day at the races</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spend a day at the races: in spring and autumn, horse races are held at the Hippodrome in Ashgabat. A colourful spectacle of speed and agility, there is no public betting. For those wishing to get closer to the stallions, 10km (6 miles) south of Ashgabat is the national Turkmenbashi Stud Farm where the Akhal-Teke horses are bred.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the remains of Anau's famous mosque</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the ruins of the famous mosque, revered for its striking mosaic tiles and 8m-long (26ft) dragons, at the modern town of Anau. Once the site of the destroyed 15th-century city (whose fortress watchtowers can still be seen today), Anau is a short drive, 20km (12 miles) east of Ashgabat.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the Arch of Neutrality, Ashgabat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Turkmenistan capital stands on the southern rim of the Kara-Kum desert. Visit to see magnificent white marble Palace of Turkmenbashi, take in the museums, including the carpet museum and the National Museum of Turkmenistan, and hit the viewing platform of the Arch of Neutrality, a 75m- high (246ft) monument with a revolving golden statue of the late President Niyazov.</p>]]><p><b>Miss Mary and make to Merv</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mary is Turkmenistan's second city and other than its Regional Museum there is little to recommend here. However, it lies near the remains of the city of Merv, which was once the second city of Islam. Known as the "Queen of Cities", what survives are brick-built mausolea of rulers and holy men – including the impressive Mausoleum of Sultan Sanjar from 1140.</p>]]><p><b>Revel in the ruins outside Dashgouz</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dashgouz is the largest city in the northern region of Turkmenistan. The main sights are outside the city but include: the ruins of Konye-Urgench, an ancient fortress town with 14th-century relics; Kutlug Timur Minaret, one of the tallest minarets in Asia at 67m (220ft); and the mausoleums of Sultan Tekesh, Turabeg Khanym and Najm-ed-din Kubra.</p>]]><p><b>Swim in the Caspian Sea at Turkmenbashi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Situated on the shores of the Caspian Sea, Turkmenbashi (formerly Krasnovodsk) was a Russian creation. Built as a bridgehead for the campaign to subdue Central Asia, it later became the terminal for the Trans-Caspian Railway. Today visitors can enjoy panoramic mountainside views, good beaches and swimming, while the Museum of Regional History and Natural History makes an interesting stop.</p>]]><p><b>Take a tour of the Silk Road</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Uncover the delights of the Silk Road, the ancient trading route used by silk merchants from the 2nd century AD until its decline in the 14th century. The Tolkuchka Market in Ashgabat, the historical cities of Konye-Urgench and Merv (especially the windowless Kyz-Kala castle) and Kugitang Nature Reserve's dinosaur footprints are among the must-sees along the road. An organised tour is advised.</p>]]><p><b>Trail the countryside on horseback</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Turkmenistan is home to the Akhal-Teke horse, a special breed known for its speed and intelligence. They occupy a special place in Turkmen culture and are a source of great national pride. Saddle up just outside Ashgabat, to ride through the gorges of the Firuza River and to the local hot springs. Rides can be arranged through local tour operators.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the UNESCO-listed fortresses of Old Nisa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover the remains of Old Nisa, the capital of the Parthian kings who ruled from the 3rd century BC to the 3rd century AD. Overseeing an Empire that included Iraq and stretched as far as the Syrian Arab Republic, their might, which prevented the Roman Empire from progressing east, can be seen in the UNESCO-listed fortresses of Nisa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$17.1 billion (2005).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Gas, oil, petrochemicals and cotton.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, chemicals, food and live animals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, Ukraine, Italy, UK, France, Germany, Turkey, Iran and Russian Federation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although 90% of the land is occupied by the Kara-Kum desert, agriculture is important to the Turkmen economy. Substantial quantities of cotton (the country is the world's 10th-largest producer) are also produced under ecologically ruinous schemes established during the Soviet era. Grain, fruit and vegetables are widely grown and livestock breeding is an important source of employment.<br /><br />The other mainstay of the economy and its best prospect for the future is an abundance of oil and natural gas deposits, the scale of which rivals anything in the Persian and Mexican Gulfs. New pipelines are planned to supplement the sole existing one, which transports the products via Russia. Other commercially viable reserves include bromine, iodine salts and various other minerals.<br /><br />Most of Turkmenistan's industry is devoted to processing the country's principal raw materials: textiles are a key export industry and much of the extracted oil is refined within the country. Oil and gas account for 85% of Turkmenistan's export income (under long-term contracts, 80% of the gas goes to the Ukraine while 60% of the oil is bought by Italy). <br /><br />As one of the poorest republics of the former Soviet Union, Turkmenistan suffered considerable economic disruption and hardship after its demise in 1991 (GDP declined by 10% per year between 1993 and 1998); the increasing inability of many of its former trade partners to pay for its products has also caused serious difficulties. The government responded by seeking out new markets. <br /><br />In 1992, Turkmenistan joined the IMF and the World Bank, then the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (as a 'Country of Operation') and the Islamic Development Bank. The following year a new national currency, the Manat, was introduced.<br /><br />In 1996, the government introduced an economic reform programme aimed at controlling persistent inflation and promoting foreign investment, especially in the oil and gas sector. This has met with some success; inflation is now 10.7% (2005), while annual GDP growth is 9.6% (2005).<br /><br />The government has also concentrated resources in developing Turkmenistan's previously poor infrastructure, especially the road network. Some aspects of the reform programme have been delayed, including land reform in which the major role was to be assumed by the private sector.<br /><br />Turkmenistan is a member of the Economic Co-operation Organisation, which brings together the former republics of the southern Soviet Union with Romania, Bulgaria, Albania, Greece and Turkey.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The government is particularly interested in encouraging foreign investment in a number of areas, including oil and gas production and refining; agricultural production and processing (particularly in cotton); consumer goods; export-orientated products; research and development; environmental protection and infrastructure.<br /><br />The Turkmen government has put a number of measures in place to encourage foreign investment. Free Enterprise Economic Zones (one in each of the eight <em>velayat</em> (regions)) have been created with special incentives for companies that invest in them. These include: no import duties, a three-year tax holiday from the start of production, with a further 13 years of reduced taxes; full-profit repatriation and a swifter licensing procedure. Concerns which are 100% foreign owned must be sited in Free Enterprise Economic Zones, but joint ventures may be set up anywhere.<br /><br />All foreign investments are protected by government guarantee from expropriation. All foreign companies and individuals wishing to invest in Turkmenistan must go through the Commission for International Economic Affairs of the Office of the President of Turkmenistan.<br /><br />Business is conducted formally and smart dress is required.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (12) 354 717 ,355 594
					Website:
					Address: ,B Karryev Street 17,Ashgabat 744000,]]><b>US Department of Commerce Business Information Service for the Newly Independent States</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (202) 482 4655
					Website:http://www.bisnis.doc.gov
					Address: Stop R-Binis,USA Trade Center,Ronald Reagan Building,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Turkmen food is similar to that of the rest of Central Asia. There are a number of good Western-standard restaurants in Ashgabat, although they rarely have an extensive menu. In general, hotel food shows strong Russian influence: <em>borcht</em> is cabbage soup, <em>entrec&ocirc;te</em> is a well-done steak, <em>cutlet</em> are grilled meat balls, and <em>strogan</em> is the local equivalent of beef Stroganoff. <em>Pirmeni</em>, originating in Ukraine, are small boiled dumplings of meat and vegetables similar to ravioli, sometimes served in a vegetable soup.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; <em>Plov</em> (pronounced 'plof') is the staple food for everyday (but is also served at celebrations) and consists of chunks of mutton, shredded yellow turnip and rice fried in a large wok. <br />
&bull; <em>Shashlyk</em> (skewered chunks of mutton grilled over charcoal which come with raw sliced onions) and <em>lipioshka</em> (rounds of unleavened bread) are served in restaurants and are often sold in the street<br />
&bull; Manty are larger noodle dumplings filled with meat. <br />
&bull; <em>Shorpa</em> is a meat and vegetable soup. <br />
&bull; <em>Ka'urma</em> is mutton deep-fried in its own fat and <em>churban churpa</em> is mutton fat dissolved in green tea.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ashgabat has an opera and ballet theatre, which shows both Russian and European works and a drama theatre. There are also a few restaurants offering dancing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Sunday market is the best place in the world to buy the misleadingly-named Bukhara rugs, which are actually made in Turkmenistan. There is a shop in the <em>Art Gallery</em> which sells traditional Turkmen handicrafts, silver and costumes including the distinctive Turkmen sheepskin hats. The central bazaar in Ashgabat is a good place to buy food and curiosities.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800. Bazaars open at dawn.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no restrictions on where foreigners can stay in Turkmenistan. When Turkmenistan gained independence, there was an acute shortage of hotel accommodation, a situation which the Turkmen are working hard to rectify, with feverish hotel construction underway in Ashgabat. A row of luxury hotels has recently been built on the edge of town along a road known locally as the 'Miracle Mile'. These are small hotels with between 15 to 40 rooms that are owned and run by various ministries and governmental organisations. Architectural motifs are mosques, palaces and fortresses. Every provincial centre has at least one hotel, but visitors should not expect Western standards of comfort and amenities. The exception is a new hotel which recently opened in Turkmenbashi; however, as it only has 40 rooms, it is advisable to contact a recognised Turkmen tour company for a reservation. Accommodation and services in hotels are payable in local currency or US Dollars.</p>
<p>A tourist fee of 2 US$ is due for every foreign tourist or visitor per night. When staying at a hotel you can expect to pay additional special expenses.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><em>Dom Otdykha</em> (literally 'rest houses') were built on the shores of the Caspian Sea by co-operatives and other concerns for fatigued workers. It is sometimes possible for travellers to obtain accommodation in them.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no restrictions on where foreigners can stay in Turkmenistan. When Turkmenistan gained independence, there was an acute shortage of hotel accommodation, a situation which the Turkmen are working hard to rectify, with feverish hotel construction underway in Ashgabat. A row of luxury hotels has recently been built on the edge of town along a road known locally as the 'Miracle Mile'. These are small hotels with between 15 to 40 rooms that are owned and run by various ministries and governmental organisations. Architectural motifs are mosques, palaces and fortresses. Every provincial centre has at least one hotel, but visitors should not expect Western standards of comfort and amenities. The exception is a new hotel which recently opened in Turkmenbashi; however, as it only has 40 rooms, it is advisable to contact a recognised Turkmen tour company for a reservation. Accommodation and services in hotels are payable in local currency or US Dollars.</p>
<p>A tourist fee of 2 US$ is due for every foreign tourist or visitor per night. When staying at a hotel you can expect to pay additional special expenses.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no restrictions on where foreigners can stay in Turkmenistan. When Turkmenistan gained independence, there was an acute shortage of hotel accommodation, a situation which the Turkmen are working hard to rectify, with feverish hotel construction underway in Ashgabat. A row of luxury hotels has recently been built on the edge of town along a road known locally as the 'Miracle Mile'. These are small hotels with between 15 to 40 rooms that are owned and run by various ministries and governmental organisations. Architectural motifs are mosques, palaces and fortresses. Every provincial centre has at least one hotel, but visitors should not expect Western standards of comfort and amenities. The exception is a new hotel which recently opened in Turkmenbashi; however, as it only has 40 rooms, it is advisable to contact a recognised Turkmen tour company for a reservation. Accommodation and services in hotels are payable in local currency or US Dollars.</p>
<p>A tourist fee of 2 US$ is due for every foreign tourist or visitor per night. When staying at a hotel you can expect to pay additional special expenses.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical insurance, including cover for emergency repatriation, is highly recommended. Medical facilities are poor, high levels of disease have been reported. Travellers are advised to take a well-equipped first aid kit with them containing basic medicines and any prescriptions that they may need.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as a potential health risk. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tick-borne encephalitis, tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Oraza Bayram (End of Ramadan), Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Oraza Bayram itself. Oraza Bayram and Kurban Bayram (Feast of Sacrifice) may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Memorial Day :
							2018<br/>12 January </p><p>Flag Day :
							19 February </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Heroes' Day :
							08 May </p><p>Victory Day :
							09 May </p><p>Constitution Day :
							18 May </p><p>Remembrance Day (Anniversary of the 1948 Earthquake) :
							06 October </p><p>Independence Day :
							27 October </p><p>Neutrality Day :
							12 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Turkmenistan without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 200g of tobacco (passengers aged 16 and over).<br />
&bull; 2L of alcoholic drinks (passengers aged 21 and over).<br />
<br />
On entering the country, you must complete a customs declaration form which you must retain until departure. This allows the import of articles intended for personal use, including currency and valuables which you must register on the declaration form. Customs inspection can be long and detailed.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics, firearms and ammunition.</p>
<p>You must obtain a permit to import plants and certain medicines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics, firearms and ammunition.</p>
<p>You can only export works of art and antiques with permission from the Ministry of Culture.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Manat (TMT) = 100 tenge. Notes are in denominations of TMT1,000, 500, 100, 50, 10, 5 and 1. Coins are in denominations of 50, 20, 10, 5 and 1 tenge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The preferred hard currency is US Dollars and visitors carrying other currencies may find it hard to change them. It is advisable to take new, clean US Dollar notes in small denominations. Foreign currency can be changed at banks and major hotels. Foreigners are expected to pay all travel and hotel bills in hard currency, and prices bear little relation to what locals are expected to pay. Most packages are all-inclusive and extra payment for accommodation and meals is unnecessary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not generally accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Should be in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> currency, but generally not accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0930-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Turkmenistan, a passport valid for six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you are travelling through Turkmenistan by train, you must obtain a transit visa.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dependent upon nationality and duration of stay. Single- and multiple-entry visas can be granted for anything from 10 days to 12 months with costs varying from US$35 for a 10-day single-entry visa to US$515 for a 12-month multiple-entry visa. Fees are doubled for an express service.</p>
<p>You must also fill out an immigration card upon entry for which a US$14 charge applies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Subject to the nature of the visit and the discretion of the authorities in Turkmenistan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). Visas are issued at the airport in Ashgabat and the ferry port at Turkmenbashi, but prior approval from the Turkmenistan Migration Service is needed. It is, however, highly recommended that you obtain a visa before leaving for Turkmenistan; there have been cases of airline staff not allowing passengers to board flights without a visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow seven to 10 days for visa processing. An express service of two to three days is available for double the usual cost of the visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[39.201026]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[59.081988]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>488,100 sq km (188,456 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>5,438,670 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>10.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ashgabat.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Turkmenistan shares borders with Kazakhstan to the north, Uzbekistan to the east, Afghanistan to the southeast and Iran to the south. To the west is the Caspian Sea. Nearly 80% of the country is taken up by the Kara-Kum (Black Sand) Desert, the largest in the CIS. The longest irrigation canal in the world stretches 1,100km (687 miles), from the Amu-Darya River in the east, through Ashgabat, before being piped the rest of the way to the Caspian Sea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Predominantly Sunni Muslim with a small Russian Orthodox minority. Turkmenistan shares the Central Asian Sufi tradition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><em>Lipioshka</em> (bread) should never be laid upside down, and it is normal to remove shoes, but not socks, when entering someone's house. Shorts are rarely seen in Turkmenistan and, if worn by females, are likely to provoke unwelcome attention from the local male population.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Gurbanguly Berdymukhamedov since 2007.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Gurbanguly Berdymukhamedov since 2007.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The territory of what is now Turkmenistan provided the bedrock for many of the most powerful empires of their age. The Parthians, the Seljuks and the Khans of Khoresm all based their empires at various points on the edge of the Karakum Desert, while Alexander the Great conquered the region during his epic campaign of the 4th century BC. The influence of Islam dates from the 7th century AD, when the region was under Arab control.</p>
<p>Modern-day Turkmen are descended from tribes that migrated to the area from the northeast in the 10th century. Around 300 years later, Genghis Khan arrived from the same direction and incorporated Turkmenistan into his expanding empire. From the 15th century, the area was under Persian domination until the Russian move into Central Asia at the end of the 19th century.</p>
<p>Turkmenistan fell into the British sphere of influence until the Bolsheviks took control of the region in 1920 and incorporated Turkmenistan as a Soviet republic in 1925. Hampered by its backward economy, the country struggled to embrace the reforms made possible by Glasnost and, despite gaining independence in 1991, still retains many more of the trappings of the old system than other post-Soviet republics.</p>
<p>Elected as sole candidate, its first President, Saparmyrat Niyazov ruled until his death in 2006 having been declared president for life by a Mejlis (parliament) made up of elected representatives he had hand-picked. His successor Gurbanguly Berdimuhamedow repealed some of Niyazov&rsquo;s more eccentric laws, such as banning opera and circus, and established links with western powers hungry for Turkmenistan&rsquo;s vast reserves of natural gas.</p>
<p>A semblance of two-party politics has been introduced, but in practice the opposition Party of Industrialists and Entrepreneurs, established in 2012, operates only under the sanction of the dominant Democratic Party of Turkmenistan, the former Communist Party. Turkmenistan maintains a position of permanent neutrality in all international relations, a stance the United Nations has formally acknowledged since 1995.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	More than 80% of Turkmenistan is covered by the Karakum Desert.<br />
&bull;	The site of the ancient city of Merv, a major oasis-city on the Silk Road between West and East, has been listed as a UNESCO World Heritage Site.<br />
&bull;	In 1997, &lsquo;President-for-Life&rsquo; Saparmyrat Niyazov presented the country with a new national anthem he had composed and written the words for &ndash; it&rsquo;s called<em> &lsquo;Independent, Neutral, Turkmenistan State Anthem&rsquo;</em>. Catchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Turkmenistan in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2207 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Turkmenistan in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7255 1071.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7255 1071.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>14-17 Wells Street<br/>2nd Floor,St George's House<br/>London<br/>W1T 3PD<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s an accomplished geographer who can confidently point to Turkmenistan on a map. Despite being similar in size to Spain, this Central Asian nation remains well under most people&rsquo;s radar.</p>
<p>There are two reasons for this. One is that Turkmenistan is a country comprised largely of barren desert and untamed terrain &ndash; hardly a big draw for tourists. But the main reason for its obscurity can be traced to Turkmenistan&rsquo;s autocratic government, which has been compared to the regime of North Korea.</p>
<p>At the helm of this ex-Soviet state is President Berdymukhamedov, who promotes a Kim Jong-un style personality cult in which he and his inner circle enjoy absolute power over every aspect of life. Consequently, according to Human Rights Watch, Turkmenistan is one of the most repressed countries in the world, a place where &quot;human rights defenders and other activists face the constant threat of government reprisals.&rdquo;</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re not put off by repressive regimes, Turkmenistan is a destination that offers one thing most others don&rsquo;t: the chance to travel across the country without seeing other travellers. The isolation is palpable.</p>
<p>The brave few who do make it here usually arrive via the capital, Ashgabat. This modern city was built in 1948 after an earthquake destroyed the previous incarnation. Visitors can learn more about this devastating event at the touching Earthquake Museum, one of the city&rsquo;s finer attractions.</p>
<p>Many of Ashgabat&rsquo;s other landmarks take on a Soviet flavour &ndash; Independence Square, the Arch of Neutrality, numerous Lenin statues &ndash; but there are also mosques, galleries and gardens. The Altyn Asyr bazaar is worth a visit too, especially if you&rsquo;re in the market for a Turkmen carpet.</p>
<p>Outside the capital, almost all of the country&rsquo;s attractions lie around the fringes of the desert. Some of the world&rsquo;s most powerful empires settled here and their crumbling legacies can be seen at the Parthian Fortress of Nisa, Kunya-Urgench and Merv, which are all UNESCO-listed World Heritage Sites. And quiet ones at that.</p><p>It&rsquo;s an accomplished geographer who can confidently point to Turkmenistan on a map. Despite being similar in size to Spain, this Central Asian nation remains well under most people&rsquo;s radar.</p>
<p>There are two reasons for this. One is that Turkmenistan is a country comprised largely of barren desert and untamed terrain &ndash; hardly a big draw for tourists. But the main reason for its obscurity can be traced to Turkmenistan&rsquo;s autocratic government, which has been compared to the regime of North Korea. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
