<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Turkey" ColCode="tur" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="tr" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Turkey]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Turkey is a huge country, and its climate varies widely from region to region as well as seasonally. For sightseeing holidays to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/istanbul">Istanbul</a> and the most important ancient and medieval sights, and for active walking holidays, the best times to visit are spring (April-May) and autumn (October-early November) when days are generally warm and sunny but not uncomfortably hot. Rainy spells and cloudy days are possible, however, in spring and autumn, so the best months for a sun-and-sea holiday on the Aegean or Mediterranean coast are June to end September. Resort areas are most crowded from June until the end of August.</p>
<p>In developing ski areas such as Uludag near Bursa and Palandoken near Erzurum, the best time to visit is between December and April. Temperatures in and around Istanbul can vary from well below freezing in midwinter to above 40&deg;C (104&deg;F) in summer. The Aegean and Mediterranean coasts experience the hottest summers, with highs of 45&deg;C (113&deg;F), but midwinter temperatures can be as low as -5&deg;C (23&deg;F).</p>
<p>Mountainous Eastern Turkey has the most extreme climate of all, with winter temperatures as low as -43&deg;C (-45F) and highs up to 38C (100F). The climate of the central Anatolia is also extreme with summer highs of 40&deg;C (104&deg;F) and winter lows of -25&deg;C (-13&deg;F). The Turkish State Meteorological Office (<a href="http://www.mgm.gov.tr" target="_blank">www.mgm.gov.tr</a>) provides a day to day, region by region online weather forecast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Depending on where you are, appropriate clothing will vary widely.  If visiting during the summer take light cotton layers and a hat, as temperatures can reach scorching, particularly in the cities. During the winter months pack heavier layers and waterproofs. Sturdy shoes and equipment are advisable for anyone who will be trekking in the mountainous areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All of Turkey&rsquo;s major regional towns and cities are connected by air to Ankara, Istanbul and other major transport hubs including Izmir and Antalya. Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>) provides the largest internal flight network. Other airlines operating on key routes within Turkey and internationally include Atlasglobal (<a href="http://www.atlasglb.com" target="_blank">www.atlasglb.com</a>), Onur Air (<a href="http://www.onurair.com.tr" target="_blank">www.onurair.com.tr</a>), Pegasus Airlines (<a href="http://www.flypgs.com" target="_blank">www.flypgs.com</a>) and SunExpress (<a href="http://www.sunexpress.com.tr" target="_blank">www.sunexpress.com.tr</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A frequent car ferry crosses the Dardenelles at Gallipoli, from &Ccedil;anakkale to Eceabat and Gelibolu to Lapseki. Istanbul Fast Ferries (tel: +90 850 222 4436; <a href="http://www.ido.com.tr" target="_blank">www.ido.com.tr</a>) operates frequent seabus services from Bostanci, Kartal and Yalova to Yenikapi, Yalova and Bandirma.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many trains of the Turkish Railways (TCDD) (tel: 444 8233, in Turkey only; <a href="http://www.tcdd.gov.tr/" target="_blank">www.tcdd.gov.tr</a>) have sleeping cars, couchettes and restaurant cars. Some are air-conditioned. Fares are comparatively low, but are more expensive for express trains. Discounts are available for students (though a Turkish student card may be required), groups, round-trips and passengers over 60. Children aged seven and under travel free. You can buy tickets at TCDD offices at railway stations and TCDD-appointed agents. The journey from Istanbul to Ankara takes 4 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Train Tour Card:</strong>&nbsp;allows 30 days' unlimited travel on most of the Turkish train network. Tour cards are available for high-speed trains, express trains and sleeping car trains. Validity begins on the first day that the card is used.<br />
<br />
<strong>InterRail One-Country Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Turkey. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurail Turkey Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, five or eight days in one month within Turkey. Available to non-EU nationals from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Turkey&rsquo;s road network continues to improve, with four-lane motorways (<em>otoyol</em>) connecting major cities, and well-surfaced modern highways elsewhere. However, further east and in rural areas, roads may be less well surfaced.</p>
<p>Standards of driving can be poor, and serious accidents are common. Main highways are well policed, and radar cameras are in use. Fines are levied on the spot for speeding offences; drivers of rental cars must pay the penalty when returning the vehicle to the rental company, which may add an additional administration charge. In rural areas, and especially in southeast Turkey, drivers may encounter road blocks manned by armed<em> jandarma</em> (militia) officers.</p>r<p>Road conditions and standards of driving in Turkey can be poor. There is a road toll system in Turkey whith uses electronically-read HGS cards; hire cars should be fitted with these.</p><p>There is an extensive bus network around Turkey linking the larger urban centres to smaller villages, and if you're willing to put up with long-distance overland travel, these can be much cheaper than taking domestic flights.</p><p>There are many types of taxi, share-taxi and minibus in operation. Taxis are numerous in all Turkish cities and towns and are recognisable by their chequered black and yellow bands. All taxis have a meter which must be switched on at the start of the journey. For longer journeys, the fare should be agreed beforehand.</p>
<p>A <em>dolmuş</em> is a collective taxi or minibus which follows specific routes. Each passenger pays according to the distance travelled to specific stops. The fares are fixed by the municipality. The dolmuş provides services within large cities to suburbs, airports and often to neighbouring towns. This is a very practical means of transport and much cheaper than a taxi. Taxis may turn into a dolmuş and vice versa according to demand.</p><p>The Turkish Touring and Automobile Club (tel: +90 212 282 8140; <a href="http://www.turing.org.tr/" target="_blank">www.turing.org.tr</a>) provides insurance and advice for foreign drivers.</p>
<p>An International Driving Permit or photo-ID licence is necessary. Green Card international insurance, endorsed for all Turkish territory (or Turkish third-party insurance obtained at a frontier post) and car ownership documents are also required. A 'carnet de passage' is required for those continuing to the Middle East.</p>
<p>You can bring cars into Turkey for a maximum of six months in any year. For longer stays, it is necessary to apply to either the Ministry of Finance and Customs or the Turkish Touring and Automobile Club.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18 and front seat belts are compulsory. Children under 12 may not sit in the front. The speed limit is 120kph (75mph) on dual carriageways, 90kph (56mph) on highways and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas.</p><p>Both chauffeur-driven and self-drive cars are available in all large towns and resorts. All international companies are represented.</p><p>Cycling through Turkey is entirely possible but cyclists are advised to make sure they are prepared for the heat, and ensure bikes are in good condition as the rough roads are frequent, especially in the countryside. Cycling in the major cities is relatively uncommon and should only be attempted by the brave. Watch out for heavy traffic as drivers may not be used to bicycles sharing the road.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18 and front seat belts are compulsory. Children under 12 may not sit in the front. The speed limit is 120kph (75mph) on dual carriageways, 90kph (56mph) on highways and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Extensive conventional bus services operate in Istanbul, Ankara and Izmir. There are buses in all other large towns. These are generally reliable, modern and easy to use. Tickets are bought in advance from kiosks and validated on board. In Istanbul, you can pay as you go by buying <em>jetons</em> (tokens). Alternatively, an Istanbulkart&nbsp;smartcard&nbsp;can save money on bus, tram, ferry and metro journeys. These have replaced the old Akbil cards, and you can buy them at vending machines and booths near stops and stations.</p>
<p>Ankara has a four-line metro system; Istanbul's is more extensive but covers mainly the more central areas of the city. The Marmaray tunnel, an underground railway under the Bosphorus rive, connects the European side of Istanbul to the Asian side of the city in just eight minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Turkey</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">izmir</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">10.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Turkey</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">istanbul</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Turkey</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">erzurum</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">11.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">18.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Turkey</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">antalya</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">8.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Turkey's national airline is Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>), which flies to multiple destinations across the globe, including the UK and the USA. Other airlines offering direct flights to Turkey from the UK include Atlas Global (<a href="http://www.atlasglb.com" target="_blank">www.atlasglb.com</a>), British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) and Pegasus Airlines (<a href="http://www.flypgs.com" target="_blank">www.flypgs.com</a>).&nbsp;</p>
<p>Major airports are: Ankara Esanboga International Airport, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkey/istanbul-atatuerk-international-airport">Istanbul Ataturk International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkey/istanbul-sabiha-goekcen-international-airport">Istanbul Sabiha Gokcen International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkey/antalya-havalimani-airport">Antalya Havalimani Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkey/dalaman-airport">Dalaman Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkey/izmir-adnan-menderes-airport">Izmir Adnan Menderes Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To Istanbul: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 3 hours 40 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 9 hours 50 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Istanbul Atatürk International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.ataturkairport.com<p>Istanbul Atatürk International Airport is located 28km (17 miles) west of Istanbul.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+90 212 463 3000.</p>]]><b>Istanbul Sabiha Gökçen International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.sabihagokcen.aero<p>Istanbul Sabiha Gökçen International Airport is situated 12km (7 miles) north of Pendik and 45km (28 miles) east of Istanbul.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+90 216 588 8888.</p>]]><b>Antalya Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aytport.com<p>Antalya Airport is located 13km (8.1 miles) northeast of Antalya city centre, the main city on Turkey's Mediterranean coast.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+90 242 444 7423</p>]]><b>Izmir Adnan Menderes Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.adnanmenderesairport.com<p>Izmir Adnan Menderes Airport is located 18km (11 miles) south of Izmir.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+90 232 455 0000</p>]]><b>Dalaman Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.yda.aero<p>Dalaman Airport is located 6km (4 miles) south of Dalaman town centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+90 252 792 5555</p>]]><b>Ankara Esenboga International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.esenbogaairport.com<p>The airport is located 28km (17 miles) northeast of Ankara</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+90 312 590 4000</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s possible to travel to Turkey by water, depending where you are coming from. Hopping from the Greek islands over to Istanbul is a popular route. All ships, including private yachts, arriving in Turkish waters must go to one of the following ports of entry: Ak&ccedil;ay, Alanya, Anamur, Antalya, Ayvalik, Bandirma, Bodrum, Botas (Adana), &Ccedil;anakkale, &Ccedil;esme, Dat&ccedil;a, Derince, Didim, Dikili, Fethiye, Finike, Giresun, G&uuml;ll&uuml;k, Hopa (Artvin), Iskenderun, Istanbul, Izmir, Kas, Kemer, Kusadasi, Marmaris, Mersin, Ordu, Rize, Samsun, Sinop, S&ouml;ke, Tasucu (Silifke), Tekirdas, Trabzon and Zonguldak.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can travel by train to Istanbul via some of the major European cities. The journey from London takes three nights via Belgrade and Sofia or four nights via Budapest. Turkish Railways (TCDD) in Istanbul (tel: 444 8823, in Turkey only; <a href="http://www.tcdd.gov.tr" target="_blank">www.tcdd.gov.tr</a>) runs the rail network within Turkey. As of 2015, the Trans-Asia Express service between Ankara and Tehran has been suspended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving overland to Turkey from the UK takes around three days straight driving, travelling through Germany, Austria, down through the Balkan countries of Croatia and Serbia and finally over the Greek or Bulgarian border.</p><p>The Eurasia tunnel for car travel between the Kazlicesme and Goztepe areas of Istanbul will be ready in late 2016, cutting journey times from 100 minutes to 15 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>The cheapest way to make calls is from PTT telephone booths, which are found in all areas. These operate using phone cards, which can be bought from kiosks, or by using major credit cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mobile phone coverage is generally good, but can be patchy in some rural areas in eastern Turkey. As Turkey is outside the EU, roaming charges are very much more expensive than for mobile phone use in the UK and the rest of the EU.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafés throughout Turkey, even in small towns and rural villages. Almost all hotels (including even small guesthouses and budget hostels) offer free Wi-Fi internet access, as do many restaurants, bars and cafés.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Turkish media tends to be self-censoring on controversial religious, cultural and political issues. Journalists, novelists, film-makers and broadcasters have been prosecuted under laws against &lsquo;insulting' the country, the armed forces, and &lsquo;Turkishness'.</p>
<p>English-language newspapers include <em>The Turkish Daily News</em>, whilst the main Turkish-language papers are <em>H&uuml;rriyet, Milliyet, Sabah, Zamam Cumhuriyet</em> and <em>Yeni Asir</em>. An edition of the British <em>Sunday Times</em> is printed in Istanbul. The state broadcaster TRT operates several TV and radio channels. Private channels include ATV, Kanal D, Show TV and Star TV. CNN T&uuml;rk is the Turkish channel of news network CNN. TRT radio stations include TRT 1 (cultural and educational), TRT 3 (classical, jazz and popular music) and TRT 4 (Turkish folk and classical music). Best FM, Show Radyo and Capital Radio are commercial stations whilst Radyo Foreks broadcasts news.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Turkish post offices are recognisable by their yellow PTT signs. It takes around 4-5 working days for mail from Turkey to reach Europe.</p><p>Major post offices are open Mon-Sat 0800-2400, Sun 0900-1900; smaller post offices have the same opening hours as government offices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be dazzled by the Whirling Dervishes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The renowned Whirling Dervishes are one of Turkey's most iconic tourist attractions. Members of the Mevlevi Order perform the famous whirling dance known as Sema as part of an aged ceremony. It's best seen in Konya where the Order originated, though many shows catering to visitors are put on in Istanbul, too.</p>]]><p><b>Cruise down the Black Sea</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the northern suburbs of Istanbul by ferry-boat, criss-crossing the Bosphorus to visit villages that stretch up to the mouth of the Black Sea. You can escape the tourists further and join holidaying Turks at one of the small Black Sea coast towns like Ünye or Giresun – less crowded, cooler and greener than the Mediterranean coast.</p>]]><p><b>Detour to the capital, Ankara</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Turkish capital is overlooked by many visitors but has some excellent museums. The superb Museum of Anatolian Civilisations provides a rich chronicle on the dynamic history of the region, while the Ethnographic Museum in Ankara provides a great insight into Turkish culture.</p>]]><p><b>Discover caves and bazaars in Sanliurfa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wander through a traditional bazaar at Sanliurfa in the southeast, close to the Syrian border, and pay a visit to the cave where Abraham is said to have been born. Since the conflict in Syria, the border has become less secure, and caution is advised.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the Kaçkar mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go trekking in the wild Kaçkar mountain range of Turkey's northeast, close to the Georgian frontier. Take a trail through dense pine forests and scenic pastures, before hitting heights of almost 4,000m (13,123 ft). Routes across higher altitudes are only open during the summer months unless trekkers are equipped for snowy weather.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the beaches of Bodrum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Although home to one of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World – the Mausoleum of Mausolus – Bodrum in Turkey's southwest is perhaps better known today as the country's finest Aegean resort. Dominated by the Castle of St John, the town is renowned for its shopping, dining and nightlife, not to mention its sweeping sandy beaches.</p>]]><p><b>Get some water therapy</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The incredible pools at Pamukkale near Denizli attract tourists and locals alike who come to bathe in the warm therapeutic waters that fill the natural travertine terraces. The pools, together with the ancient ruins of the city of Hierapolis nearby have been declared a World Heritage Site.</p>]]><p><b>Glide over the dreamland of Cappadocia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Formed after the eruption of Mount Erciyes and fashioned by nature over the ages, Cappadocia offers an unrivalled landscape of rock cones, sprawling pinnacles and gaping ravines. Only many years later did the human touch arrive, providing tourists with cave houses and underground tunnels to explore. Hot-air balloon rides over the area are very popular.</p>]]><p><b>Go white-water rafting</b></p><![CDATA[<p>White-water rafting is becoming increasingly popular with tourists in Turkey. There are trips going down the Dalaman River, the Köprülü River, the Zamanti River or the Coruh River, which is rated by professionals as one of the top rafting descents in the world. Hold on tight!</p>]]><p><b>Hit the southern coastal town of Antalya</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Not much known in the West, Antalya is nevertheless one of the most-visited cities in the world. Sitting on the Mediterranean and Turkey's southern coast, it's not hard to see why with its vast beaches, lively nightlife and atmospheric old town. Then there's the harbour, Kaleiçi, and the superb Archaeological Museum, as well as many historic sights throughout the city, not least Hadrian's Gate.</p>]]><p><b>Hop on a boat through Lake Van</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Use the eastern city of Van as a base to travel along the beautiful south shore of Lake Van. From there you can catch a boat out to the 10th-century Armenian church on Akdamar island, famous for its intricate stone reliefs depicting biblical scenes.</p>]]><p><b>Search for Noah on Mount Ararat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Look for fragments of Noah's Ark, reputed to have washed up on the slopes of 5,165m (16,945ft) Mount Ararat in Turkey's eastern region. Apart from the biblical appeal, the snow-capped mountain is an incredible sight, visible from many kilometres away. Only authorised trekking companies are recommended for scaling mighty Ararat.</p>]]><p><b>Sumela Monastery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Before Ottoman rule, much of Anatolia was home to Greek settlements. One spectacular example is the 14th-century Greek Orthodox Sumela Monastery, 54km (34 miles) from Trabzon. Set into a sheer cliff, 300m (1,000ft) above the valley floor, it's a jaw-dropping sight. The inside is filled with magnificent frescoes.</p>]]><p><b>Take a ferry to Prince's Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sip tea or smoke shisha as you watch the sunset at one of the traditional cafés beneath Istanbul's Galata Bridge. Then take a ferry from the Eminönü dock to the Princes' Islands, a tranquil summer getaway popular with Istanbulites where cars are banned and horse-drawn carriages and bicycles are the transport of choice.</p>]]><p><b>Trek the Lycian Way</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Turkey isn't touted much for its hiking, but it has some great, uncrowded routes. One of the most beautiful is the Lycian Way, which stretches for 500km (311 miles) between Fethiye and Antalya, providing a month's walking through some of Turkey's most spectacular scenery.</p>]]><p><b>Walk with historical giants in Istanbul's Old City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once the capital of Byzantium – the greatest empire in Christendom during the Middle Ages – Constantinople became Istanbul after the Ottoman conquest of the 15th century, and has been an Islamic metropolis ever since. Its architectural treasures include the Blue Mosque, the Topkapi Palace and Hagia Sophie.</p>]]><p><b>Wind down in a Turkish bath</b></p><![CDATA[<p>You can't visit Turkey without experiencing a traditional Turkish bath. Known as a hammam, locals go for a scrub and massage, as well as a good steam. The most popular historic baths in Istanbul are the Galatasaray Hammam in Beyoğlu and Cağaloğlu Hammam in Sultanahmet, though less-known local baths are often just as good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$794.5 billion (2012).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Clothing and textiles, food, manufactured goods, transport equipment.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, chemicals, appliances and parts, mineral fuels and oil, road vehicles.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Germany, Iraq, Iran, Russia and China.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The agricultural sector, previously of great economic importance, now accounts for only 9.1% of the GDP, although it a quarter of the labour force are still . It remains a major employer however, and Turkey is self-sufficient in basic foodstuffs like maize, sugar, wheat and barley.<br />
<br />
Manufacturing and services are the most important and fastest growing sectors, with banking and the construction industry enjoying major growth in recent years. The services sector makes the greatest overall contribution to the country's economy, accounting for around 60% of Turkey's GDP. The country's tourist industry is also of primary importance, with the number of tourists increasing year on year, going from around 27 million tourists in 2007 to over 31 million in 2012. The tourism industry brought in over US$$20 billion in revenue in 2012.<br />
<br />
Underlying structural problems coupled with years of mismanagement and world events brought the Turkish economy to its knees in 2001. In the face of this crisis, the government introduced an International Monetary Fund-backed austerity program that succeeded in cutting inflation from 70% to 6%. Unemployment in 2012 stood at 9.2%. Up until the financial crisis in 2008, Turkey&rsquo;s GDP experienced strong growth and although impacted by the subsequent instability of Europe&rsquo;s financial market, this has now stabilised at around 2-3%.</p>
<p>Istanbul and Antalya are the most popular venues, followed by Ankara, Marmaris and Bodrum. There are many 4- and 5-star hotels, which provide facilities and can host conferences and meetings to international standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As Turkey's capital, Ankara is an administrative hub where formal conventions prevail. For business meetings, a dark suit (with tie) is the norm for men. Women are advised to wear business suits with trousers or skirts below the knee. Visiting businesswomen will usually be treated with the same respect as male colleagues. However, women should be aware that after-dinner invitations to accompany the men to a revue bar or belly-dancing club might imply going to an upmarket brothel, and a woman's company will be resented. Women are advised to clarify the nature of the establishment before going.</p>
<p>English is widely spoken in business circles though to have even the most basic knowledge of Turkish wins considerable respect. Punctuality is expected, with lunch meetings commonplace. Business cards and formal greetings are widely used.</p>
<p>Most Turks prefer to do business with someone they know, trust and respect so establishing a personal relationship is an important part of deal-making. Once a relationship has been established, communication is direct. It is customary for business visitors to address new acquaintances by their first names followed using 'Bey' (sir) or 'Hanim' (lady).</p>
<p>Secretaries are rarely empowered to take important messages or even know the boss's schedule, so when phoning, it is usual for callers to be told to ring back 'one hour later' or fax your queries. Once the appropriate contacts have been made, however, business visitors are usually treated with personal warmth and courtesy.</p>
<p>As a Muslim nation, Turkey observes the festivals of the Islamic calendar so avoid scheduling meetings during Ramadan. Alcohol consumption is socially acceptable across most of Turkey, however many choose abstinence so it is important to check to be sure.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1200 and 1330-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Istanbul Convention and Exhibition Centre</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (212) 373 1100
					Website:http://www.icec.org/
					Address: ,Harbiye 34267,Istanbul,]]><b>Union of Chambers and Commodity Exchanges of Turkey</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (312) 413 8000
					Website:http://www.tobb.org.tr/
					Address: 149 Bakanliklar,TOBB Atatürk Bulvari,Ankara,6640]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Turkish food combines culinary traditions from the people's nomadic past in Central Asia with influences of the Middle Eastern and Mediterranean cuisine. Such mixed heritage when it comes to food can be the cause of fierce debate when brought up, in particular when it comes to discussing whether dishes are Greek or Turkish in origin. Debate aside, Turkish food is excellent, with wide variation, going far beyond the familiar kebab.</p>
<p>Meat is a large component of the Turkish diet, with lamb featuring heavily and dishes tend to be fragrantly spiced, although they are not as hot as those found in Indian cuisine. Vegetarians will find they are easily catered for, as meze &ndash; a selection of sauces, dips and vegetables &ndash; can be found on almost every menu and it&rsquo;s not unusual to them as a main meal. Dolma (stuffed vegetables) are also veggie-friendly dishes.</p>
<p>Guests are usually able to go into a kitchen and choose from the pots if they cannot understand the names of the dishes. A wide range of international cuisine is also available in the major cities, and standard German and British dishes along the coasts.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; K&ouml;fte (spicy sausage-shaped meatballs made of minced lamb).<br />
<em>&bull; </em><em>Shish kebab</em> (pieces of meat threaded on a skewer and grilled).<br />
<em>&bull; Pide</em> (the Turkish equivalent of pizza topped with cheese and eggs).<br />
<em>&bull; </em><em>Dolma</em> (vine leaves or vegetables stuffed with pine nuts and currants). <br />
<em>&bull; Lokum</em> (Turkish Delight - originally made from dates, honey, roses and jasmine bound by Arabic gum and designed to sweeten the breath after coffee).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Turkey is a secular state and alcohol is widely enjoyed, although during Ramadan it is considered polite for visitors to avoid drinking alcohol in public. Some local restaurants do not serve alcohol. Wine and spirits are heavily taxed and therefore expensive compared with local beers, which are less heavily taxed.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A service charge is included in hotel and restaurant bills. It is customary to leave a small tip (10 to 15%) for barbers, hairdressers, Turkish Bath attendants and waiters in smarter establishments.  In inexpensive cafes and restaurants a small gratuity is appreciated. When using taxis, passengers should just round up the fare.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In a country where half the population is under 30, it&rsquo;s no surprise that the nightlife scene is one of the best in Europe. It ranges from sophisticated to brash depending on where you are but the sheer variety of taverns, bars and clubs keeps things interesting.</p>
<p>In big cities such as Istanbul, Antalya, Izmir and Ankara, Turkey&rsquo;s newly prosperous younger generation patronise stylish jazz bars and huge, gleaming dance clubs that rival similar venues in European cities. In Istanbul, enjoy a sunset along one of the many bars lining the banks of the Bosphorus, before heading out to trendy Beyoglu where you can grab great views across the city.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, in resorts such as Marmaris, Olu Deniz, Kusadasi and Bodrum, streets lined with happy-hour cocktail bars and sports TV pubs cater to British and other European holidaymakers. Bodrum&rsquo;s huge Halicarnassus open-air dance club, with room for up to 5000, is a legend in its own right. Belly-dancing is a Turkish tradition, but in the 21st century attracts more tourists than locals, with &lsquo;traditional&rsquo; belly dancing shows performed at most larger hotels or in venues that are purpose-built for tourist nightlife tours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s more to shopping in Turkey than just colourful carpets. Traditionally a place of trade and commerce, shopping and haggling are part of the fabric of life here, and whether your preference is busy bazaars or more modern malls, rare is the visitor who doesn&rsquo;t come away with some token of their time here.</p>
<p>Souvenir shoppers will find all sorts of items here. Locally made Turkish handicrafts include textiles, embroideries, copperwork, ceramics, and pottery, onyx, mother-of-pearl, inlaid woodwork, leather and suede products, jewellery, rugs and kilims. <em>Nargiles</em> (water pipes) and musical instruments make good, reasonably priced souvenirs.</p>
<p>Those who enjoy shopping will find Istanbul a delight, as the city is rammed with with plenty of cosmopolitan boutique stores and big label brands which will keep the most prolific shopper occupied (although you may have to do some digging to sniff out the gems).</p>
<p>Resorts such as Bodrum, Marmaris and Kusadasi have market areas peddling generally low quality souvenirs and handicrafts and copies of designer-brand shoes, footwear handbags, wristwatches and sunglasses. Bargaining is less essential than in the past, and many traders refuse to offer big discounts. When buying carpets and kilims, the seller must issue an invoice (<em>fatura</em>) stating the item's estimated age and purchase price in order to satisfy customs that it is not a restricted antiquity.</p>
<p>When buying big ticket items, get a receipt of the transaction. This can then be shown to customs agents at the airport to verify the purchase is above board and within allowances.</p><p>Daily 0930-1900 in tourist areas. Closing hours vary, with some shops staying open until midnight. Outside tourist areas shops may close at lunchtime and on Sundays. Istanbul covered market: Mon-Sat 0800-1900 (closed Sunday).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Places to stay in Turkey range from purpose-built villa and apartment complexes and mid-range hotels in seaside resorts to luxury city hotels aimed at business travellers, budget hostels, simple <em>pansiyons</em> (guesthouses) and an ever-increasing number of stylish small boutique hotels in coastal and rural villages.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels registered with the Ministry of Tourism are graded from 1 star (1<em> yildizli</em>) to 5 stars (5 <em>yildizli</em>). There are also unclassified hotels that have no stars, which can range from poor to acceptable. Classification is based on the standard of service and facilities. Motels and holiday villas are first class (1 <em>sinif</em>) or second class (2 <em>sinif</em>). There are other establishments registered with local authorities, and these too correspond to a certain standard in regard to facilities and services. There is also a national hotel association, TUROB (<a href="http://english.turob.com/" target="_blank">http://english.turob.com</a>) which has comprehensive listings of accredited hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guest houses (<em>pansiyons</em>) can be found in some resorts and in most towns and villages. These usually offer clean but basic accommodation (not all have en-suite WC and shower or air conditioning). Most do not have a bar or restaurant, but some offer a simple breakfast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Places to stay in Turkey range from purpose-built villa and apartment complexes and mid-range hotels in seaside resorts to luxury city hotels aimed at business travellers, budget hostels, simple <em>pansiyons</em> (guesthouses) and an ever-increasing number of stylish small boutique hotels in coastal and rural villages.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels registered with the Ministry of Tourism are graded from 1 star (1<em> yildizli</em>) to 5 stars (5 <em>yildizli</em>). There are also unclassified hotels that have no stars, which can range from poor to acceptable. Classification is based on the standard of service and facilities. Motels and holiday villas are first class (1 <em>sinif</em>) or second class (2 <em>sinif</em>). There are other establishments registered with local authorities, and these too correspond to a certain standard in regard to facilities and services. There is also a national hotel association, TUROB (<a href="http://english.turob.com/" target="_blank">http://english.turob.com</a>) which has comprehensive listings of accredited hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Places to stay in Turkey range from purpose-built villa and apartment complexes and mid-range hotels in seaside resorts to luxury city hotels aimed at business travellers, budget hostels, simple <em>pansiyons</em> (guesthouses) and an ever-increasing number of stylish small boutique hotels in coastal and rural villages.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels registered with the Ministry of Tourism are graded from 1 star (1<em> yildizli</em>) to 5 stars (5 <em>yildizli</em>). There are also unclassified hotels that have no stars, which can range from poor to acceptable. Classification is based on the standard of service and facilities. Motels and holiday villas are first class (1 <em>sinif</em>) or second class (2 <em>sinif</em>). There are other establishments registered with local authorities, and these too correspond to a certain standard in regard to facilities and services. There is also a national hotel association, TUROB (<a href="http://english.turob.com/" target="_blank">http://english.turob.com</a>) which has comprehensive listings of accredited hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Turkey's healthcare system is in the midst of reform and has greatly improved over past decades, but the country has only basic public hospital medical facilities and has no state-funded general practitioner system. There is however an extensive private health care sector, including private emergency care hospitals, surgeons, dentists and other specialists. Inside the major urban centres such as Istanbul and Ankara, the quality of care in these clinics will match standards in Western Europe, but without private health insurance, getting treated in this environment can result in a hefty bill. Travel insurance which covers medical aid is essential. In the case of a medical emergency call 112.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is chlorinated in towns and cities, but it is advisable to drink the widely available bottled mineral water. If a water source bears the words &lt;em&gt;i&amp;ccedil;ilmez&lt;/em&gt;, it is not potable; sources labelled &lt;em&gt;i&amp;ccedil;ilir&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;i&amp;ccedil;me suyu &lt;/em&gt;are safe to drink. Milk is pasteurised. Eat only well-cooked meat and fish. When it comes to street food, common sense is advised; eat food that is freshly cooked and ideally, has been prepared in front of you. During the summer Turkey can experience temperatures up to 40&amp;deg;C (104&amp;deg;F)&amp;nbsp;so carry a bottle of water to avoid dehydration.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. It is recommended that travellers visiting rural areas, get a rabies vaccination as this may be found in dogs, cats and other animals throughout the countryside. Turkey has very low risk of malaria, with the risk increasing towards the Syrian border in the south east of the country, but keen trekkers may want to stock up on supplies of insect-repellent.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Ramazan Bayrami (End of Ramadan), Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Ramazan Bayrami itself. Ramazan Bayrami and Kurban Bayrami (Feast of Sacrifice) may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>National Sovereignty and Children's Day :
							23 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Commemoration of Atat :
							19 May </p><p>Victory Day :
							30 August </p><p>Republic Day :
							28 October </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Turkey by travellers aged 18 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 600 cigarettes, 100 cigarillos, 50 cigars and 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L  of alcohol over 22% volume or 2L of alcohol under 22% volume. <br />
&bull; 5 bottles (maximum 120ml each) of perfume and eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; 1kg each of tea, coffee, chocolate or confectionery.<br />
&bull; Gifts to the value of &euro;430 (reduced to &euro;150 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics. Sharp implements (including camping knives) and weapons require a special permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The export of souvenirs such as carpets is subject to customs regulations regarding age and value. The export of antiques is strictly forbidden, with harsh penalties for those caught doing so. Minerals may only be exported under licence from the General Directorate of Mining Exploration &amp; Research. You can't export tea, coffee, grain products or spices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Turkish Lira (TRY; symbol YTL) = 100 New Kurus (Ykr). Notes are in denominations of YTL200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of YTL1 and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 New Kurus.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cash can usually be exchanged commission free in currency exchange offices (<em>döviz bürosu</em>). Banks usually charge commission. Traveller's cheques can only be exchanged in banks with a passport. Travellers planning to exchange currency back from Turkish Lira to their own country before leaving Turkey, or those making a major purchase which may need to be declared to customs, must retain transaction receipts to prove that the currency was legally exchanged.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa is the most popular, closely followed by MasterCard. American Express is accepted in top-flight hotels, restaurants and some gift shops. ATMs are widely found in most areas. In all smaller restaurants, bars, guesthouses and shops cash is preferred. Many establishments in resort areas will accept Euros.</p><p>ATMs are easily found in most urban areas. As with all transactions be careful with your card, taking care to keep it in sight, and  be discreet with cash.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques can only be exchanged in banks. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Pounds Sterling, Euros or US Dollars. Credit cards are far more convenient.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0830-1200 and 1330-1700. Some banks in tourist areas and large cities are open daily. Cash can be exchanged in currency exchange offices (döviz bürosu) in all major cities and towns. Banks charge commission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>unavailable</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes/1/2</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Passports must be valid for at least 60 days beyond the expiry date of the traveller's visa or the end of the traveller's visa exemption period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>e-Visa in advance: free (Maltese nationals); US$20 (other EU and US nationals); US$60 (Australian and Canadian nationals).</p>
<p>e-Visa on arrival at Turkish airports: free (Maltese nationals); US$30 (other EU and US nationals); US$70 (Australian and Canadian nationals).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>e-Visa: 90 days within a 180-day period.</p>
<p>For longer stays or frequent visits, you can obtain single- or multiple-entry visas valid for six months, one year or five years from your nearest Turkish embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Apply online at <a href="http://www.evisa.gov.tr">www.evisa.gov.tr</a>, at least 48 hours before departure. For long-term visas, apply to the nearest consulate/embassy. For all visas issued by the Turkish Consulate in the UK, you need to apply online at <a href="http://www.visa.gov.tr" target="_blank">www.visa.gov.tr</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>At the final stage of the application, you are given a link to the e-Visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[39.051018]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[34.930036]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>783,562 sq km (302,535 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>79,622,062 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>101.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ankara.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Presidential system.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Turkey borders the Black Sea,&nbsp;Georgia and Armenia to the northeast, Iran to the east, Iraq to the southeast, Syria and the Mediterranean to the south, the Aegean Sea to the west and Greece and Bulgaria to the northwest. Asia Minor (or Anatolia) is the name given to the peninsula that forms a bridge between Europe and Asia. It accounts for 97% of the country's area and forms a long, wide peninsula 1,650km (1,025 miles) from east to west and 650km (400 miles) from north to south. The biggest city is Ankara, which is situated in the central plains of Anatolia.</p>
<p>The other 3% of the country is Thrace, the tiny land mass which is the European portion of Turkey bordering Bulgaria and Greece and separated from Anatolia by the Bosphorus, a strait linking the Black Sea and Aegean Sea. Despite its small size 10% of the population lives here, with most of these in Istanbul.</p>
<p>Two east-west mountain ranges, the Black Sea Mountains in the north and the Taurus in the south, enclose the central Anatolian plateau, but converge in a vast mountainous region in the far east of the country. It is here that the ancient Tigris and Euphrates rivers rise.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Muslim, with around 70% Sunni, 25% Alevis and a very small Christian minority. Turkey is a secular state which in theory guarantees complete freedom of worship to non-Muslims.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shaking hands is the normal form of greeting a stranger; &nbsp;kissing on the cheek is reserved for meeting friends and family. Hospitality is very important and visitors should respect Islamic customs. Informal wear is acceptable, but beachwear should be confined to the beach or poolside. Smoking is widely acceptable but prohibited in cinemas, theatres, buses, coaches and <em>dolmuş</em> (collective taxis).</p>
<p>Until recently women working in civil service or government roles, or studying in university, were banned from wearing headscarves. This ban was lifted in 2013, but the subject remains a contentious issue. However, if visiting a mosque, women are advised to take scarves to cover their hair and to wear long-sleeved tops. Both men and women should have legs covered from the knees upwards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Recep Tayyip Erdoğan since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Turkey is a relatively stable, secular democracy that remains broadly pro-Western, seeking to eventually become part of European Union. However, its recent past is more turbulent. Defeat in the Balkan Wars of 1912-13 and World War 1 led to the collapse of the Ottoman Empire, the subsequent declaration by President Kemal Ataturk, of a secular Turkish Republic, and the &lsquo;exchange of populations&rsquo;, when more than a million ethnic Greeks left Turkey for Greece, while around half a million Turkish Muslims returned to Turkey.</p>
<p>Turkey remained neutral during World War 2, but in the post-war years the army intervened several times to overthrow governments of which it disapproved. In 1974, Turkey and Greece came close to war over Cyprus, and the issue remains the biggest obstacle to Turkey joining the EU, with the country divided along the Green Line &ndash; the north is Turk-Cypriot, whilst the south is Greek-Cypriot. Since the 1960s, Kurdish separatists seeking an independent state in southeast Turkey have clashed with security forces.</p>
<p>Turkey&rsquo;s history stretches back more than 5000 years. Asia Minor cradled the Hittite kingdom, from around 2200 BC, ancient Troy and the Greek city-states, which rose along the coasts during the first millennium BC. Their struggle with the Persian Empire ended with its conquest by Alexander the Great whose own empire broke up after his death and by 2BC the region had been conquered by Rome.</p>
<p>Relics such as the Temple of Diana at Ephesus and the Roman theatres at Aspendos and Side are among the great sights of present-day Turkey. In AD330, Emperor Constantine I moved the Roman capital to Byzantium, strategically located on the Bosphorus, renamed it Constantinople and imposed Christianity on the Empire. The Seljuk Turks trickled into Anatolia (eastern Turkey) and were followed by the Ottoman Turks. In 1453 Constantinople fell to Sultan Mehmet II. His successors expanded the Ottoman Empire further, and at its apogee, they held sway over a territory that stretched from the Balkans to the Red Sea and the Nile.</p>
<p>With recent uprisings in the Middle East, including the 2011 Arab Spring and Syria&rsquo;s civil war, Turkey&rsquo;s stability now finds itself under threat. Most recently, the heavy-handed quashing of demonstrations in Istanbul and Ankara against the authoritarian style of the police under Prime Minister Erdoğan&rsquo;s government has brought international condemnation.</p>
<p>An attempted coup in July 2016 failed to gain public support and was followed by a decisive crackdown on the civil service and Erdoğan&rsquo;s opponents.</p>
<p>In 2017, a referendum was narrowly passed in favour of the winner of the 2019 election assuming full control of government, thus ending the country's parliamentary political system and strengthening Erdoğan&rsquo;s grip on power. The three largest cities, Istanbul, Ankara and Izmir voted against these measures, and the opposition party intends to challenge the results.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; Turkish coffee is on the UNESCO Intangible Cultural Heritage list for Turkey.</p>
<p>&bull; Since Ottoman times Turkey&rsquo;s national sport has been Yağlı g&uuml;reş, oiled wrestling.</p>
<p>&bull; As many as 99.8 per cent of Turks are Muslim.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Turkey in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 612 6700 or 6740 (consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.washington.emb.mfa.gov.tr</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 612 6700 or 6740 (consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1800.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2525 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Turkish Consulate General in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7591 6900 or 09068 347 348 (recorded visa information; calls cost 60p per minute). </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.turkishconsulate.org.uk/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7591 6900 or 09068 347 348 (recorded visa information; calls cost 60p per minute). </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1230 (visas).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Rutland Lodge<br/>Rutland Gardens<br/>SW7 1BW<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Turkey in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7393 0202</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://london.emb.mfa.gov.tr</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7393 0202</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1730 (appointment only).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>43 Belgrave Square<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8PA<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For sheer diversity, Turkey is hard to beat. The country is best measured in multitudes &ndash; of people, natural landscapes and cultures. It is a land of vast open spaces and massive mountain ranges, fertile valleys and rugged coastline, fast-growing cities and sleepy villages, seaside resorts and remote beaches.</p>
<p>Countless waves of invasion, rebellion and immigration have forged a country whose cultural depth and breadth may surprise visitors as they venture not just through major cities, but across the country.</p>
<p>Turkey overflows with historic sites and archaeological wonders, all set in a varied and beautiful landscape. The Mediterranean coastline is punctuated with well-preserved Greco-Roman cities like Pergamom and Ephesus, while the otherworldly landscapes of the Cappadocia region harbour cave churches and underground cities.</p>
<p>Though capital status eludes it, Istanbul is very much the beating heart of the nation. The city is an archive of cultural influences throughout the centuries, playing host to Roman aqueducts, Byzantine churches and Ottoman mosques and palaces. Yet it&rsquo;s no relic. Cafes, bustling bazaars, hammams (public baths), and nightclubs all buzz with activity.</p>
<p>Still, Istanbul is just one piece of the vast Turkish puzzle. Beach-lovers can while away lazy sunny days at the ever-popular Bodrum, Marmaris and Izmir resorts along Turkey&rsquo;s Aegean and Mediterranean coasts.</p>
<p>The unlikely capital city, Ankara, may be less frequented, but its location in central Anatolia makes it worthy of a few days&rsquo; visit, if only to witness the contrast between the city&rsquo;s modernity and the surviving citadel. Away from the more European sensibilities of Istanbul, Ankara also presents an opportunity to gain insight into other facets of Turkish culture.</p>
<p>However deep its roots are, Turkey is today a thrusting and dynamic society, navigating cultural, economic and political change while seeking to retain the best of its multicultural heritage and time-honoured traditions. And that's arguably what makes it so rewarding.&nbsp;</p><p>For sheer diversity, Turkey is hard to beat. The country is best measured in multitudes &ndash; of people, natural landscapes and cultures. It is a land of vast open spaces and massive mountain ranges, fertile valleys and rugged coastline, fast-growing cities and sleepy villages, seaside resorts and remote beaches.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Turkey overflows with historic sites and archaeological wonders, all set in a varied and beautiful landscape. The Mediterranean coastline is punctuated with well-preserved Greco-Roman cities like Pergamom and Ephesus, while the otherworldly landscapes of the Cappadocia region harbour cave churches and underground cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
