<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Turks and Caicos Islands" ColCode="tca" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="tc" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Turks and Caicos Islands]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Turks and Caicos benefit from a tropical climate; tempered by trade winds, and generally pleasant, nights can be cool, with rain in winter. Hurricanes and tropical storms (with flooding) can strike between July and November.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical lightweights. Light sweaters are advised for evenings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In addition to the international airports on Grand Turk and Providenciales, there are landing strips on Middle Caicos, North Caicos, South Caicos, Parrot Cay, Pine Cay and Salt Cay.</p>
<p>interCaribbean (<a href="http://intercaribbean.com" target="_blank">intercaribbean.com</a>)&nbsp;and Caicos Express Airways (<a href="http://caicosexpress.com" target="_blank">caicosexpress.com</a>) cover domestic destinations.</p><p>There are currently no airports on East and West Caicos. However, an airport at West Caicos is under construction as part of a long-delayed development project to bring a luxury resort to the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The TCI Ferry operated by Caribbean Cruisin (<a href="http://www.caribbean-cruisin.com" target="_blank">www.caribbean-cruisin.com</a>) is a daily ferry service between Providenciales and North Caicos, and twice-weekly to South Caicos. A commuter ferry runs on Tuesdays, Wednesdays and Fridays between Grand Turk and Salt Cay. You can charter boats at most of the inhabited islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Grand Turk and Providenciales have the most developed road systems and can be easily covered by car. Roads in rural areas can be poor.</p>l<p>There are over 120km (75 miles) of roads on the islands, of which an increasing number are sealed. Road signage, which generally follows UK protocols, has been improved in recent years. Traffic at major junctions is controlled by roundabouts, not traffic lights.</p>
<p>Use caution while driving; traffic laws are only loosely enforced and some drivers can be aggressive or reckless.</p><p>There are no public buses on Turks &amp; Caicos, and you should avoid using the illegal jitneys that are common on the island that at best, overcharge tourists and at worst may be unsafe.</p><p>Available at most airports, but the supply may be limited and you often need to share. Negotiate the fare beforehand.</p><p>A national driving licence, plus an International Driving Permit if your licence isn't in English.</p><p>Seat belts must be worn at all times. Speed limits are 32kph (20mph) in town and 64kph (40mph) elsewhere.</p><p>Available from some local firms on Providenciales, Grand Turk, and North, Middle and South Caicos. In addition to cars, agencies may rent scooters, dune buggies and three-wheeled roadsters. On Salt Cay, the main form of motorised transport is electric golf carts.</p><p>Bike hire is available on Grand Turk, Providenciales, North Caicos and Salt Cay. There are no designated bike routes or bike lanes in Turks &amp; Caicos, so use extreme caution when biking on main roads outside resort areas.</p><p>Seat belts must be worn at all times. Speed limits are 32kph (20mph) in town and 64kph (40mph) elsewhere.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Taxis and hire cars are the main form of transportation in Turks &amp; Caicos. Hiring a car is recommended if you're planning to do any substantial independent sightseeing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Turks and Caicos Islands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">south_caicos</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Turks and Caicos Islands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">salt_cay</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.05</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Turks and Caicos Islands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">providenciales</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Turks and Caicos Islands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">north_caicos</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.25</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Turks and Caicos Islands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">middle_caicos</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Multiple international airlines serve Providenciales International Airport (PLS), with onward connections available to Grand Turk and other islands. The main carrier is interCaribbean (<a href="http://intercaribbean.com" target="_blank">intercaribbean.com</a>).</p>
<p>British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) flies from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>&nbsp;(with a brief stop in Antigua). From the USA, there are direct flights with&nbsp;American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>), Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>), and JetBlue (<a href="http://www.jetblue.com" target="_blank">www.jetblue.com</a>) on a seasonal basis. Travellers are more likely to get discounted airfares during the Caribbean low season, mid-December to mid-April.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 11 hours 30 minutes (including a short stop in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/antigua-and-barbuda">Antigua</a>); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 3 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Despite its name, JAGS McCarthy International Airport (GDT) on Grand Turk does not currently have any scheduled international service; Providenciales is the sole international gateway to Turks &amp; Caicos.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Despite its name, JAGS McCarthy International Airport (GDT) on Grand Turk does not currently have any scheduled international service; Providenciales is the sole international gateway to Turks &amp; Caicos.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Grand Turk JAGS McCartney International Airport </b><![CDATA[http://www.visittci.com/grand-turk-jags-mccartney-international-airport-gdt]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Providenciales International Airport </b><![CDATA[http://provoairport.com/<p>The airport is around 10km (6 miles) west of the main tourist centre of Grace Bay.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main ports are Grand Turk, Cockburn Harbour (South Caicos), Providenciales and Salt Cay.</p><p>You can charter boats to sail between islands as well as to the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bahamas">Bahamas</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/haiti">Haiti</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There is a good communications network run by <em>Cable & Wireless</em>, with automatic exchange on all the islands. The local telephone directory lists charges for international calls. There is a 10% tax on all calls. Public card-phones are in operation on all the islands; phonecards are available from <em>Cable & Wireless</em> and outlets near phone booths. Cheap rates are in operation Mon-Fri 1900-0600 and Sat-Sun all day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone companies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public access is available in Internet kiosks located at the airport and in Internet caf&eacute;s around the islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Newspapers <em>Turks &amp; Caicos Free Press</em>, <em>Turks &amp; Caicos Sun</em> and <em>The Turks &amp; Caicos Weekly News</em> are published weekly. <em>The Times of the Islands</em>, a showcase for the islands' culture and environment, is published quarterly. <em>Where, When, How </em>is a travel magazine which appears regularly. Turks and Caicos Television is the islands' only TV station; broader-based cable and satellite TV are available, and stations from the Bahamas can be picked up. In addition to the government-run Radio Turks and Caicos, there are a few local music radio stations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The General Post Office is on Grand Turk, with sub-offices on North Caicos, South Caicos and Providenciales. Airmail to Western Europe takes five days.</p><p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1600, Fri 0800-1530.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bask on the beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Powder-fine, soft and white, the sands of the Turks and Caicos Islands are the stuff of romance. Chill out on the beaches that line Providenciales' renowned Grace Bay, or seek out your own private spot; there's plenty of choice, with some of the best on North and Middle Caicos.</p>]]><p><b>Dive on pristine coral reefs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Exquisite coral reef formations and excellent underwater visibility have brought diving fame to the islands, especially Providenciales, West and South Caicos, and the Turks Islands. Marine species that can be observed include turtles, spotted eagle rays and manta rays, as well as numerous colourful reef fish.</p>]]><p><b>Escape it all on North Caicos</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Known as the "Emerald Isle," North Caicos has miles of deserted white sandy beaches with gentle surf and excellent snorkelling, along which hotels providing luxurious accommodation… and all just a short ferry ride from Providenciales. Flamingos, ospreys, iguanas and various other wildlife can be seen at the island's nature reserve. The ruins of the Wade's Green Plantation, built in 1789 to raise cotton and sisal, are also a popular destination for visitors.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Cockburn Harbour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The town of Cockburn Harbour on South Caicos is situated on a small ridge at the extreme southwest of the island of South Caicos. It was once the chief port for the shipment of salt from the islands. The town is a quiet and pleasant place to potter around in the evening, with some interesting remnants of the salt industry and a few local restaurants serving fresh fish. It's also a jumping off point to discover the island's excellent beaches and reefs.</p>]]><p><b>Go birdwatching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rare birds and butterflies are bountiful on the archipelago… and so are the twitchers who come to seek them. Visitors can see wild flamingos in Grand Turk, North Caicos and Provo, where there are designated birding trails. On Provo, Northwest Point National Park offers some of the best birdwatching opportunities and you may see ospreys, pelicans, egrets, herons, and more.</p>]]><p><b>Grand Turk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A few minutes from South Caicos by air, with the small metropolis of Cockburn Town, Grand Turk is the islands' seat of government and commerce, as well as their historic and cultural centre. Front Street has a number of colonial buildings, dating from the early 19th century. Visit the lighthouse overlooking North Creek on the north coast - it was shipped to Grand Turk from the UK in pieces in the 19th century and reassembled. Heritage walks and guided tours are available.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in Providenciales</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Boasting luxury resorts, fine dining restaurants, coral reefs and beaches as pure as the driven snow, the island of Providenciales is the epicentre of the country's tourism industry. Most of the action takes place around Turtle Cove, with its peaceful yacht basin, and Grace Bay, which has a 19km (12-mile) beach. The island is also home to Princess Alexandra National Park, the Caicos Conch Farm (the only one of its type in the world) and the Bamboo Gallery (an arts centre).</p>]]><p><b>Make friends with migrating whales</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Between February and April, whale watching enthusiasts are able to observe large numbers of the North Atlantic humpback whale population passing very close to the western shores of Grand Turk and Salt Cay en route to their breeding grounds at Mouchoir Bank nearby. During this period, divers can listen to an underwater concert of whale songs; charter boats equipped with hydrophones also allow visitors to see and hear whales.</p>]]><p><b>Pedal your way around the islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A network of field-roads across North, Middle and East Caicos makes for great walking and cycling across these unspoiled islands, sometimes joining up the dots between plantations, beaches and other attractions. On Provo, the Grace Bay and Turtle Cove areas are the safest for on-road cycling, and Grace Bay has pavements for safe strolling. Of course, walking beautiful Grace Bay Beach is also very popular.</p>]]><p><b>Relax on Middle Caicos</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Also known as Grand Caicos, Middle Caicos is sparsely developed. The three main settlements on the island are Conch Bar, Banbarra and Lorimers. The island is blessed with a spectacular coastline, which is blessed with bluffs, small coves, limestone cliffs, sandy beaches, swampland and caves. There is a causeway linking Middle Caicos and North Caicos, so it's easily accessible for visitors.</p>]]><p><b>Set sail to West Caicos</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The westernmost island has an abrupt coastline leading to deep water that is ideal for fishing and scuba diving. Uninhabited, it is currently only visited by sailors, fishermen and thousands of seabirds. An ideal place to see a variety of birdlife is Lake Catherine. Ruins of Yankee Town, a railroad and a steam engine are remnants of the time when the island was habited; a more modern 'ruin' is that of the unfinished Ritz-Carlton Molasses Reef resort on the island's north end.</p>]]><p><b>Step back in time on Salt Cay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The tiny Salt Cay is home to just 70 people, and a handful of self-catering villas for visitors. Uncluttered and unspoilt, its timelessness is accentuated by disused salt ponds and an almost total lack of motorised transport. Island Thyme makes a great venue for lunch or dinner.</p>]]><p><b>Take a glow-worm cruise</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once a month following the full moon, the waters around the islands light up with glow worms as part of an elaborate mating ritual, and evening cruises are laid on to see this magical display.</p>]]><p><b>Wander the ruins of cotton plantations</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For a short time at the end of the 18th century, the cotton plantations of Cheshire Hall on Providenciales and Wade's Green on North Caicos were worked by numerous slaves owned by Loyalist refugees from the former American colonies. Now in ruins, the plantations remain evocative places to visit, and through a degree of restoration, their story lives on.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$559 million (2011).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Lobster, dried and fresh conch, and conch shells.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Foods and beverages, tobacco, clothing, manufactured goods and construction materials.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>UK and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Since salt mining went into decline in the mid-1960s, and finally ceased during the 1990s, the Turks and Caicos Islands have relied on tourism, fishing and offshore financial services for most of their income. <br />
<br />
There is little agriculture, but the sizeable fishing industry is both a major contributor to the islands' food requirements, and a valuable export earner - particularly from the USA, which buys much of the catch. The only other notable industry is construction, which is largely geared towards improving tourism infrastructure.<br />
<br />
In the mid-1980s, measures were introduced by the government to attract an offshore financial services industry, and these have met with reasonable success. Unfortunately, it brought laundered money and illicit capital fleeing from elsewhere. Under pressure from London and, more publicly, the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD), the government introduced a tighter regulatory structure in an attempt to prevent fraud and money laundering.<br />
<br />
Meanwhile, the government has refocused on tourism as the key to the islands' future economic well-being. The sector is now the main source of revenue, worth in excess of US$500 million to the islands' economy, contributing around 47% of the total GDP in 2011. Tourism is dominated by visitors from the USA who make up around two thirds of the total. Despite receipts from tourism and the financial service, some aid from the >UK is provided to assist in various areas, such as government administration, environmental protection, and to fund capital projects.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The informal, relaxed atmosphere of the island prevails even in business circles. That said, a formal style of address rather than first names may be preferable on first acquaintance. A lightweight suit is advised.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Providenciales Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (649) 242 6418
					Website:http://www.provochamber.com
					Address: Providenciales,PO Box 361,Turks & Caicos Islands,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Local food in Turks & Caicos is mostly Creole style and can be found at inexpensive eateries such as the Middle Caicos Cafe and Sailing Paradise on Providenciales. Nor do you have to dig deep in your pockets to get a meal at a more polished restaurant: the popular chicken and ribs dinner on Wednesday nights at the Tiki Hut in Turtle Cove Marina is just over $10, and the most famous eatery in Turks & Caicos, Da Conch Shack, offers reasonably priced conch and seafood dishes.</p><p>As well as traditional foods, continental dishes are also available. Many visitors dine in their hotels, but there are plenty of alternatives. Although some establishments have buffet-style dining, table service is common. Alcohol is freely available and a wide selection of imported beer, wines and spirits can be found in most bars.</p><p>More upscale dining is available at resorts and stand-alone restaurants, especially in Providenciales. Parallel 23 at the Regent Palms and O'Soleil at the Somerset at Grace Bay are examples of fine-dining restaurants serving international cuisine.</p><p>Grand Turk has the familiar Margaritaville but also authentic local eateries and the gourmet Guanahani restaurant at the Bohio Resort. Options on the smaller islands are generally informal cafes and beach bars.</p><p>Bambarra Rum, named in honor of a Middle Caicos colony founded by survivors of a slave ship wreck in 1841, is a relatively new addition to the Turks & Caicos culinary scene. Silver, gold, and aged Bambarra rums are blended and bottled in Providenciales, although the sugar cane for rum-making comes from elsewhere in the Caribbean.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>• Hominy (pigeon peas and grits served with fish, conch, or pig's tail).<br/>• Conch salad.<br/>• Fresh lobster and fish.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>In restaurants, tip 15%.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are bars and casinos on Providenciales, and hotels arrange beach parties and other entertainments. Events are broadcast in advance on local radio.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The islands' small shops sell locally-made baskets, jewellery, wooden model boats, ceramics, shells, sponges, hand-screened cloth and souvenir T-shirts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is accommodation on Grand Turk, North, Middle and South Caicos, Salt Cay, and Providenciales, as well as the highly exclusive Parrot Cay and Pine Cay, with more planned on West Caicos and Dellis Cay. Options range from hotels, inns and all-inclusive resorts to self-catering apartments and villas. The standard is generally high, and many places have beach frontage, private gardens, swimming pool and extensive watersports facilities. On Providenciales, there is a Club Med Turkoise. <br /><br /><strong>Note:</strong> All rooms are subject to 10% government tax and most establishments levy a further 10% service charge. Advance reservation is necessary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is accommodation on Grand Turk, North, Middle and South Caicos, Salt Cay, and Providenciales, as well as the highly exclusive Parrot Cay and Pine Cay, with more planned on West Caicos and Dellis Cay. Options range from hotels, inns and all-inclusive resorts to self-catering apartments and villas. The standard is generally high, and many places have beach frontage, private gardens, swimming pool and extensive watersports facilities. On Providenciales, there is a Club Med Turkoise. <br /><br /><strong>Note:</strong> All rooms are subject to 10% government tax and most establishments levy a further 10% service charge. Advance reservation is necessary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is accommodation on Grand Turk, North, Middle and South Caicos, Salt Cay, and Providenciales, as well as the highly exclusive Parrot Cay and Pine Cay, with more planned on West Caicos and Dellis Cay. Options range from hotels, inns and all-inclusive resorts to self-catering apartments and villas. The standard is generally high, and many places have beach frontage, private gardens, swimming pool and extensive watersports facilities. On Providenciales, there is a Club Med Turkoise. <br /><br /><strong>Note:</strong> All rooms are subject to 10% government tax and most establishments levy a further 10% service charge. Advance reservation is necessary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There is a limited reciprocal health agreement with the UK. On presentation of proof of residence in the UK (NHS card, driving licence, etc), those under 16 or over 65 receive all medical and dental treatment free of charge. Other UK residents are entitled to free treatment as follows: on Grand Turk, dental treatment, prescribed medicines and ambulance travel; on the outer islands, medical treatment at government clinics and prescribed medicines. There are community clinics on all islands, and a small hospital on Grand Turk, as well as a number of private practitioners, and also an emergency care facility, but for serious emergencies patients are taken to the USA. Comprehensive insurance is strongly advised for all nationals.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccination against hepatitis B is sometimes advised. Occasional cases of dengue fever have been reported.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Commonwealth Day :
							12 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>National Heroes Day :
							28 May </p><p>Her Majesty The Queen's Birthday :
							18 June </p><p>Emancipation Day :
							06 August </p><p>National Youth Day :
							28 September </p><p>International Human Rights Day :
							24 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into the Turks and Caicos Islands without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 220g tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1.136L of alcohol.<br />
&bull; Gifts to the value of US$200 (US$400 for residents).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics, weapons and pornography.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is a criminal offence to take shells or coral from any national park, which includes much of the coastline. It is illegal to take any coral out of the country.</p>
<p>Until 2013, visitors had to obtain a permit from the Department of Environmental and Maritime Affairs to export conch shells. However, in conch season (mid-October to mid-July), tourists can now export up to three queen conch shells without a permit. If you wish to export more than three shells, you need to obtain a CITES permit. During closed season (mid-July to mid-October), exporting conch shells is prohibited, but the legislation is currently being revised meaning visitors will soon be able to export conch shells year-round.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar (USD; symbol US$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of US$100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of $1 and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted by most hotels, shops, restaurants, banks and taxi services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0830-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter the Turks and Caicos, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single visitor's visa: US$150.</p>
<p>British embassies charge &pound;115 for receiving, handling and forwarding visa applications for British Overseas Territories.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British Consulate (or consular section at embassy) or High Commission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow three weeks to a month if applying for a visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing a pet to the Turks and Caicos, you animal must have a health certificate issued by the veterinary authority of the country of origin stating the animal has been identified with a microchip or tattoo, shows no signs of disease, and has up-to-date vaccinations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[21.505028]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-71.753972]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>948 sq km (366 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>34,904 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>53 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cockburn Town, Grand Turk.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British Overseas Territory.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Turks and Caicos Islands are an archipelago of 40 islands (eight of which are inhabited) forming the southeastern end of the Bahamas chain. There are two principal groups, each surrounded by a continuous coral reef. Caicos is the larger group, comprising Providenciales, and North, Middle, East, West and South Caicos, plus numerous small cays, some of which are inhabited. The Turks group, separated by a 35km-wide (22 miles) channel of water, consists of Grand Turk, Salt Cay and a number of smaller uninhabited cays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Christian, represented by several denominations, including Roman Catholic, Anglican, Methodist, Baptist, Seventh-Day Adventist and Pentecostal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shaking hands is the normal form of greeting. Hospitality is important and, when visiting someone's home, normal social courtesies should be observed - if possible, a return invitation should be made. A souvenir from home is well received. Informal dress is accepted for most events, but beachwear should be confined to the beach.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110-120 volts AC, 60 Hz. North American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without third grounding pin) are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Premier Rufus Ewing since 2012.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 2015, represented locally by Governor Peter Beckingham since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None of the Lucayan Indians, who occupied the islands when Columbus first discovered them in 1492, survived the 16th century, with most taken as slaves by the Spaniards. Legend has it that the islands were named after the indigenous, red-topped Turk&rsquo;s-cap cactus, shaped like a Turkish fez, and the Lucayan phrase &lsquo;<em>caya hico</em>&rsquo;, meaning &lsquo;string of islands&rsquo;.</p>
<p>During the mid-17th century, the Turks and Caicos Islands became a major centre for the salt industry. In fact the archipelago provided the American mainland with salt well into the 19th century, with African slaves &ndash; many brought to the islands by Loyalists fleeing the War for Independence in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">United States</a> &ndash; being used as labour. During the 18th century, control of the islands changed hands several times among the French, Spanish and British, who eventually asserted dominance. Emancipation came in 1834 after a series of slave escapes to nearby <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/haiti">Haiti</a>.</p>
<p>Following a period of near warfare between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bermuda">Bermuda</a> and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bahamas">Bahamas</a> over control of the islands, the British Crown decisively shifted control to its <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jamaica">Jamaica</a> colony, which had aided the islands after the great hurricane of 1874. In 1962, having been a Jamaican dependency for some 75 years, the Turks &amp; Caicos Islands became a separate British colony.</p>
<p>That same year, the splashdown of US astronaut John Glenn off the coast of Grand Turk following his successful Earth orbit helped raise the global profile of the country.</p>
<p>The islands held their first general election in 1976, and the decline in the salt industry following the devastation of Hurricane Donna in 1959 coincided with the first large-scale tourism development in the country, notably the opening of the Club Med resort in the early 1980s on Providenciales, which at the time had a population of less than 100 people.</p>
<p>Political instability, including the conviction of a former chief minister on drug charges in the US, the adoption (and later, rewrite) of a new constitution, and corruption charges into the 2000s have not slowed the rapid expansion of tourism infrastructure (particularly in Providenciales) or the emergence of Turks &amp; Caicos as a centre of offshore banking. The nation remains a British Overseas Territory.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	A great number of Canadian tourists visit the Turks and Caicos Islands and periodically the question of a union between Canada and the islands is raised by politicians.<br />
&bull;	Hollywood stars Ben Affleck and Jennifer Garner married on Parrot Cay in 2005.<br />
&bull;	Club Med has a risqu&eacute; adults-only resort on the Caicos island of Providenciales.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Diplomatic Representation]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Governor's Office]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(649) 946 2308/2909.</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/the-governors-office-turk-and-caicos-islands</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(649) 946 2308/2909.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0800-1630&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Waterloo<br/>Governor's House<br/>Grand Turk<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Blessed with an abundance of natural riches &ndash; white powdery beaches, pellucid waters and some of the best reefs in the Caribbean &ndash; the Turks and Caicos Islands have a reputation for exclusivity. That may not be entirely fair, but this 40-island archipelago is certainly skewered towards the well heeled, with its credit card-melting hotels and private island resorts, where the rich and famous go to escape the hoi polloi.</p>
<p>If your bank balance can&rsquo;t stand the heat, there are affordable options to be found on the likes of Grand Turk, the largest island, where visitors can take in the delights of Governor&rsquo;s Beach or head offshore to bathe on Little Sand Cay, a tiny island comprised of white sand and a handful of swaying palms.</p>
<p>A visit to Salt Cay off Grand Turk offers a rare opportunity to view migrating humpback whales. Come on a full moon and you could also be treated to a natural light show courtesy of the bioluminescent glowworms, which inhabit the local waters. Swimming with stingrays off Gibbs Cay and kayaking through nearby salt marshes are just some of the other diversions.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s not all about the coast, though. There are numerous parks, reserves and historic attractions inland, such as Cheshire Hall, a crumbling colonial plantation where guides regale visitors with historical anecdotes about the islands.</p>
<p>Those seeking culture should head to Grand Turk, where you will find the archipelago&rsquo;s capital, Cockburn Town, which is home to exquisite colonial era buildings, a smattering of museums and a handful of restaurants.&nbsp;A sophisticated, more upbeat vibe prevails on the island of Providenciales, which boasts lively beach bars, some excellent restaurants and the venerable Provo Golf &amp; Country Club, one of the Caribbean&rsquo;s finest. Those who fancy escaping the crowds can hop on a ferry to nearby North Caicos, an island of few people and many flamingoes.</p><p>Blessed with an abundance of natural riches &ndash; white powdery beaches, pellucid waters and some of the best reefs in the Caribbean &ndash; the Turks and Caicos Islands have a reputation for exclusivity. That may not be entirely fair, but this 40-island archipelago is certainly skewered towards the well heeled, with its credit card-melting hotels and private island resorts, where the rich and famous go to escape the hoi polloi.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
