<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Uganda" ColCode="uga" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ug" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Uganda]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Uganda has a warm tropical climate, with temperatures ranging from 25-29&deg;C (77- 84&deg;F), apart from in the mountainous areas, which are much cooler; the top of Mount Elgon is often covered with snow. The hottest months are December to February. Evenings can feel chilly after the heat of the day with temperatures around 17- 18&ordm;C (63-64&deg;F).</p>
<p>Most regions of Uganda, apart from the dry area in the north, have an annual rainfall of between 1,000mm and 1,500mm. There is heavy rain between March and May and between September and November, making road travel difficult in parts of the country. The best time for trekking is during the dry seasons, between January and February and June to August. Wildlife viewing is best at the end of the dry seasons, when game is more concentrated around water sources.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight clothes with a warm cover-up for the evenings are advised. Short or revealing clothes should be avoided - women should avoid shorts in particular. Knee-length skirts or dresses are more acceptable. Take a pair of good walking shoes or boots for forest trekking, and long-sleeved tops to protect against mosquitoes. If you&rsquo;re planning to go to mountainous areas, be sure to take warm clothing, as temperatures drop substantially. White clothes won&rsquo;t stay white for long with Uganda&rsquo;s red dust roads, so go for darker colours. Travellers can also pick up bargains at second-hand clothes markets in Kampala, Jinja and Fort Portal, which sell trousers, boots and fleeces.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fly Uganda (<a href="http://www.flyuganda.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.flyuganda.com</a>), Eagle Air (<a href="http://www.eagleair-ug.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.eagleair-ug.com</a>) and Aerolink (<a href="http://www.aerolinkuganda.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.aerolinkuganda.com</a>) offer scheduled and charter internal flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passenger ferry links Nakiwogo Dock in Entebbe to Lutoboka on Buggala in the Ssese Islands on Lake Victoria. There is also a free vehicle ferry which runs from Bukakata, 40km (25 miles) east of Masaka, to Buggala. Lake taxis also link some of the other islands. Popular with travellers, the Sseses offer plenty of opportunities for walking, birdwatching and beach activities.</p>
<p>You can take a variety of boat trips from Paraa to the base of Murchison Falls, and kayak and raft at Bujagali Falls near Jinja.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no passenger services, other than a Kampala-Namanve commuter service, which launched at the end of 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Domestic bus travel is cheap, but departures aren&rsquo;t always on schedule. There are two classes of bus travel &ndash; <em>matatu</em> (minibus) or <em>kigati</em> (van) which travel fixed routes, and larger coaches or buses. Self-drive and hiring a private car with a driver are other options.</p>l<p>The roads are of variable quality and radiate from Kampala, although the network is sparse in the north. While some major roads are paved, the majority of minor and side roads are unpaved and can be bumpy and pot-holed, so drive with caution, especially in the rainy season.  Note that there are still some army and police checkpoints on roads. Always keep vehicle doors locked and valuables out of sight.</p><p>Uganda&rsquo;s coach and bus services connect all major towns. The Post Office&rsquo;s Post Bus Service (<a href="http://www.traveluganda.co.ug/businfo.php" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.traveluganda.co.ug</a>) offers relatively comfortable buses and is more safety-aware than some other bus companies.</p>
<p>Most major routes are also covered by smaller white minibuses. These are faster than coaches, but drivers wait until they are full before leaving and departure times are not fixed.</p><p>Private taxis are identifiable by their black and white stripes. Boda-bodas (motorbike taxis) are often a cheaper option and, while fun, are not for the faint-hearted. Don&rsquo;t be afraid to ask your driver to slow down if necessary, as accidents are common. Like Uber, you can hail a boda-boda using the app SafeBoda.</p><p>An International Driving Permit and adequate third-party insurance is required. UK driving licences are accepted. Drivers must carry their vehicle log books and must pay for a temporary road licence.</p><p>The speed limit is 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 80kph (50mph) outside built-up areas and 100kph (62mph) on highways. Also, drivers must give way to traffic on their right when at intersections.</p><p>Most car hire companies include breakdown cover. The Automobile Association of Uganda (+256 41 4255917; <a href="http://aau.co.ug/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">aau.co.ug</a>)&nbsp;can provide information and assistance.</p><p>International hire companies are based near Entebbe International Airport and in the centre of Kampala. A 4-wheel drive is recommended for rural areas.</p><p>Cycling in Uganda requires nerves of steel; many roads are dusty or under construction and motor vehicles rarely allow cyclists room. Always wear a helmet and use rear-view mirrors. Avoid cycling at night.</p><p>The speed limit is 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 80kph (50mph) outside built-up areas and 100kph (62mph) on highways. Also, drivers must give way to traffic on their right when at intersections.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines serving Uganda include Egyptair (<a href="http://www.egyptair.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.egyptair.com</a>),&nbsp;Emirates (<a href="http://www.emirates.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.emirates.com</a>), Ethiopian Airlines (<a href="http://www.ethiopianairlines.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.ethiopianairlines.com</a>), Kenya Airways (<a href="http://www.kenya-airways.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.kenya-airways.com</a>) and Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>). There are no direct flights from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> or the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>.</p>
<p>Flights to Uganda are cheapest during the rainy seasons from March to May and October to November. The best wildlife viewing months are June to September and December to February, when flights are likely to be more expensive.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 11 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 19 hours 30 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$40, usually included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Entebbe International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 40km (22 miles) southwest of Kampala (journey time - 30 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Following suspension of the ferry service due to a series of accidents, passenger boats no longer run between Uganda&rsquo;s main ferry port on Lake Victoria, Port Bell, and Mwanza in Tanzania. However, cargo boats sometimes take passengers, so it may pay to ask around.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are currently no international passenger train services running in or out of Uganda, although the railway is still used in places for carrying freight.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Uganda shares land borders with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tanzania">Tanzania</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kenya">Kenya</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/congo">Democratic Republic of Congo</a> (DRC), <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/rwanda">Rwanda</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-sudan">South Sudan</a>. Several international reputable bus companies link Kampala to other major cities in the region.</p>
<p>If driving from Europe, drivers should check <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/foreign-commonwealth-office" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Foreign and Commonwealth Office</a> (FCO) updates regarding travelling through countries in the region. Yellow fever certificates are required at the border if entering Uganda from a country where yellow fever is present.</p>
<p>Driving in Uganda is challenging due to the poor condition of the roads in places (especially in the rainy season), the somewhat erratic driving of others on the road, and potential collisions with livestock. Before setting off, ensure your vehicle is in good working order and has a sound spare wheel (preferably two), as the country's corrugated and dirt roads are sure to take their toll. A 4-wheel drive is advisable if you intend to go off the beaten track, along with a jerry can with spare petrol, oil, water, a fire extinguisher, a wheel spanner, jack and a first-aid kit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Service for local calls is unreliable. Phone shops are available in towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Coverage extends to all major towns and international roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone companies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet caf&eacute;s in most large towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Uganda has been a pioneer of liberalisation in the African media. Private radio and television stations have thrived since the government loosened its control of the media in 1993, with over two dozen daily and weekly newspapers and many radio stations. Ugandans have unrestricted access to international media and around 15% of the population accessed the internet in 2012.</p>
<p>While the country&rsquo;s laws allow for freedom of expression in the press, there have been clashes between media outlets that have been critical of policies and the government.</p>
<p>English-language papers include private daily <em>The Monitor</em> (<a href="http://www.monitor.co.ug" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.monitor.co.ug</a>) and state-owned daily <em>New Vision</em> (<a href="http://www.newvision.co.ug/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.newvision.co.ug</a>). Vernacular papers include state-owned <em>Bukedde </em>(<a href="http://www.bukedde.co.ug" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.bukedde.co.ug</a>), <em>Etop</em> (<a href="https://www.facebook.com/etop.newspaper/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.facebook.com/etop.newspaper/</a>) and <em>Rupiny </em>(<a href="https://www.facebook.com/rupiny.newspaper.7/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.facebook.com/rupiny.newspaper.7/</a>).&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe can take from three days to several weeks.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1230 and 1400-1800. Some post offices are open Sat 0900-1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Enjoy the charming town of Jinja</b></p><![CDATA[<p>No visit to Uganda is complete without a trip to Jinja, the country&rsquo;s second-largest town and the supposed location of the Source of the Nile. Jinja is also the departure point for a host of adventure activities on and around the river, and a very pretty place in its own right.</p>]]><p><b>Experience Bwindi Impenetrable National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This special forest, which was designated a UNESCO World Heritage Site in 1994, is a sanctuary for around half the world's remaining mountain gorillas. The park is also home to colobus monkeys, various species of chimpanzee, hundreds of species of birds and many other animals, including snakes, lizards, chameleons and butterflies.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the Budongo Forest Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Situated near Masindi on the road to Lake Albert, the Budongo Forest Reserve is the largest mahogany forest in East Africa and one of the most diverse, with around 465 plant species. The forest is home to Uganda&rsquo;s largest chimpanzee population, along with approximately 366 bird species and blue monkeys, black-and-white colobus monkeys and the implausibly cute potto (another primate).</p>]]><p><b>Get out and about in Kisoro</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With breath-taking views of the volcanic peaks of the Virungas, Kisoro is a popular stop for travellers visiting Mgahinga Gorilla National Park and going gorilla trekking in Rwanda&rsquo;s Volcanoes National Park. There are many walks outside of the town with lakes, craters and caves to explore and bustling markets every Monday and Thursday.</p>]]><p><b>Get your adrenaline fix at Bujagali Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The adventure capital of Uganda, the stretch of the White Nile between Jinja and Bujagali is a playground for rafters and kayakers. Adrenalin-junkies can ride the rapids – where the volume of water is equivalent to ten times that of the Zambezi – while looking out for hippos, crocodiles and monkeys along the way.</p>]]><p><b>Hike through Rwenzori Mountains National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Uganda&rsquo;s ten national parks, Rwenzori is regarded as one of the continent's most spectacular. This mountain range in Africa runs almost 120km (75 miles) along the Congolese border and is known for its incredible hiking and climbing opportunities. It&rsquo;s also a hotspot for wildlife including the endemic Angola colobus monkey.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back on the Ssese Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This archipelago of 84 islands scattered along Lake Victoria's northwest shore boasts some beautiful white sandy beaches and famous sunsets. Buggala is the most accessible island, while Banda is more of an old fashioned backpackers retreat. A great place for relaxing with a good book and then sipping a few drinks around the bonfire at night.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the wildlife in Murchison Falls National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The largest protected area in Uganda, this national park is named after the stunning and dramatic waterfall which cascades 43m (141ft) over the rift valley wall, after travelling an 80km (50 miles) stretch of rapids. Keep your eyes peeled for lions, Nile crocodiles and elephants in the park, or visit rhinos at the Ziwa Rhino Sanctuary.</p>]]><p><b>Safari in Queen Elizabeth National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to this popular and picturesque park&rsquo;s remote Ishasha Plains for a rare opportunity to see the feted tree-climbing lions. The park boasts over 90 mammal species in total, and more than 500 bird species. Comprising a wide array of landscapes and ecosystems, it has an almost unparalleled biodiversity rating.</p>]]><p><b>Take time out in Fort Portal</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the country's most attractive towns, Fort Portal is a hub for travellers wanting to explore some of Uganda's best wildlife destinations, including Kibale, Semliki, Bigodi, Rwenzori and Lake Nkuruba. Try and find time to check out the nearby crater lakes, Karambi Tombs and the recently restored Toro Palace.</p>]]><p><b>Track chimpanzees in Kibale National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are around 325 bird species and at least 60 species of mammals in this impressive park, including 13 primate species. The flora of Kibale National Park is just as impressive with approximately 229 species of trees. Kibale&rsquo;s most famous inhabitants are its chimps, which you&rsquo;ll have a high chance of spotting on a guided tracking tour, whilst night treks reveal some amazing animals of the nocturnal kind.</p>]]><p><b>Trek to the summit of Mount Elgon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to Mount Elgon to explore sky-soaring mountains, lush forest-clad hills and vast wetlands. Straddling the Kenyan border, this extinct volcano is a must for trekkers, with excellent walks including the Karamoja, the Central Circuit trail and the Sasa River Trail, as well as the Sipi and Sisyi waterfalls.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the lovely Lake Bunyonyi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Almost certainly the prettiest lake in the country, Bunyonyi is surrounded by steeply terraced green hills and scattered with fascinating islands. Like Ssese, it&rsquo;s a perfect spot for some beach relaxation, but there are also a number of interesting historical sites and activities to experience. During your Lake Bunyonyi trip, take time out to visit the Batwa pygmies to learn about their culture and history.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$25.53 billion (2017).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Coffee, fish and fish products, tea, tobacco and cotton, horticultural products and gold.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Capital equipment, vehicles, petroleum, medical supplies and cereals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC), Kenya, Belgium, UAE, China and the Netherlands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Agriculture dominates the Ugandan economy, accounting for half of total output and employing around 69% of the workforce in 2017. The industrial sector produces textiles, cement, fertilisers and metal goods. There are deposits of copper and cobalt. In addition, there are known deposits of tin, tungsten, beryllium and tantalum ores.</p>
<p>The economy recorded fairly steady economic growth throughout most of the last decade (4.4% annual growth as of 2017) but growth of 2.3% in 2012 is one of the lowest recorded for more than 10 years. Inflation stood at 6.8% in November 2013, as the country recovered from droughts earlier in the year. Increased periods of drought, high energy costs, poor transportation infrastructure and instability in the surrounding regions inhibit Uganda&rsquo;s economic development, but there is optimism that the discovery of oil and gas will lead to a boost in the country&rsquo;s economy.<br />
<br />
The most pressing problem has been the country's debt burden. Its total external debt now stands at just under US$5.8 billion. In exchange for debt cancellation programmes, the government has been obliged to introduce a series of economic reforms, principally the removal of price controls and trade restrictions and a reduction in government spending.&nbsp;Uganda is a member of the African Development Bank and of the Common Market for Eastern and Southern Africa (COMESA). In 2003, Uganda joined with neighbouring Kenya and Tanzania in a plan to revive the East African Customs Union (a previous attempt folded in 1977).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Formal greetings are important to Ugandans, so always be polite, shake hands and enquire how they are when meeting someone. To make a good impression at business meetings, men should wear a smart suit and tie, while women should dress professionally. English is generally used for all business discussions and as a rule, all appointments should be made in advance. Be prepared for meetings to start and finish later than originally planned as punctuality isn&rsquo;t enforced.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1300 and 1400-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Uganda Investment Authority</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (41) 301 000
					Website:http://www.ugandainvest.com
					Address: Lumumba Avenue,PO Box 7418,Investment Centre,Plot 22B,Kampala,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Ugandan cuisine draws on English, Arab and Asian &ndash;&nbsp;especially Indian &ndash; influences and uses local produce including plantains, sweet potatoes, corn, beans and cassava.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s easy to eat cheaply almost anywhere in the country. International restaurants can be found in larger towns, with Indian, Chinese and Italian being the most popular.</p>
<p>Traditional foods include <em>ugali</em> (solidified maize meal porridge) served with a stew of groundnuts (peanuts), beans, chicken or meat such as beef, goat or mutton. Game can be found on menus in some restaurants and at safari lodges. Fish including the tiger fish, mukini, mputa and tilapia are popular.</p>
<p>Vegetarians may struggle outside of major towns, but Uganda&rsquo;s Indian and Chinese restaurants generally offer a selection of vegetarian dishes.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Chapati:</strong> Indian-style flat bread fried in oil.<br />
<strong>Grasshoppers:</strong> The crunchy, deep-fried insects are a popular street food.<br />
<strong>Luwombo:</strong> Stew made from meat, vegetables or fish steamed in banana leaves.<br />
<strong>Matoke:</strong> A green banana, often steamed in its own leaves and mashed.<br />
<strong>Millet bread:</strong> A mixture of millet and cassava flour, eaten with peanut or meat sauce.<br />
<strong>Posho:</strong> Made from white cornflour, this starchy staple is similar to polenta.<br />
<strong>Rolex:</strong> An omelette with onion and veg rolled up in a chapatti.<br />
<strong>SimSim:</strong> Roasted sesame paste mixed into a dish of beans or greens and served as a side.<br />
<strong>Kikomando:</strong> A chapati cut into pieces and served with fried beans.<br />
<strong>Mandazi:</strong> A doughnut often served with cinnamon or sugar.<br />
<strong>Pombe:</strong> Fermented beer made from millet or banana.<br />
<strong>Waragi:</strong> A potent local gin.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Although always appreciated, it is not standard practice. Aim to tip 10% at tourist-orientated restaurants.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main towns of Kampala, Entebbe and Jinja all have a relatively lively nightlife scene, with bars and clubs opening until late.</p>
<p>Kabalagala or &lsquo;Kabs&rsquo; is the place to head to party late in Kampala, with many places opening 24 hours, seven days a week. There are also pubs, bars and clubs along the Ggaba Road close to Kampala International University and on the Muyenga Road.</p>
<p>Kampala&rsquo;s industrial area off Jinja Road also has three big clubs, with good DJs. Wednesday is &lsquo;Ladies&rsquo; Night&rsquo; in some clubs, where entry is free to women.</p>
<p>Visitors can see traditional music and dance at Kampala&rsquo;s National Theatre, which also has a musician&rsquo;s jam session on Monday nights, while La Bonita theatre on Colville Street also has live dance performances. The Ndere Centre at Ntinda has cultural shows by the internationally acclaimed Ndere Troupe and an Afro-Jazz night every Thursday.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Karaoke is also popular, especially in Kampala, home of Uganda&rsquo;s first ever karaoke palace, Sabrina&rsquo;s, and there are also bars to belt out a tune in Entebbe and Jinja.</p>
<p>Entebbe has two main nightclubs, Club XS and Nightriders, while Jinja has the Viewers Nightclub and also a casino, the Nile View.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Practical goods such as toothpaste, soap and batteries should be easy to find across Uganda, with supermarkets in many towns, although travellers are advised to bring goods which they may need, such as medication, from home.</p>
<p>Souvenirs from the country include interesting local musical instruments, woven goods such as baskets, wooden carvings, batiks and ceramics. The best places to buy are in one of the country&rsquo;s many markets, and there are also opportunities to purchase crafts along the side of the road from stalls or established outlets in well-travelled areas. Locally-produced jewellery, including bangles and necklaces, and packets of local tea and coffee are also popular gifts.</p>
<p>The craft market next to Daisy&rsquo;s Arcade in Kampala is one of the city&rsquo;s biggest, with over 30 stalls and there&rsquo;s also a night market every Friday in Nsambiya on Ggaba Road where you can practice your bargaining skills.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Nommo Gallery in Uganda&rsquo;s National Art Gallery, in Kampala&rsquo;s Nakasero, has a shop selling African arts and crafts. Banana Boat shops sell African crafts and tribal arts, including work from Ugandan women&rsquo;s groups, from their three shops in Kampala at Garden City Shopping Centre,&nbsp;Plot 23 Cooper Road in Kisementi and the Lugogo Mall.</p>
<p>Try to find time to pay a visit to Uganda Crafts 2000 in Kampala, a non-profit fair-trade shop which sells some unusual, well-made craft items, the proceeds of which go towards helping the country&rsquo;s disabled and disadvantaged people.</p>
<p>Whilst it&rsquo;s always fun to barter, remember that many of Uganda&rsquo;s residents live below the poverty line, so paying an extra dollar or two for goods may make a huge difference to the seller. Be generous wherever you're able.</p><p>Mon-Sat 1000-1800, some shops may close earlier on Saturdays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a broad range of hotels from budget to high-end in Uganda. More expensive, international-standard hotels and resorts can be found in Entebbe, Kampala and Jinja, and there are also some upmarket lodges in some of the country&rsquo;s national parks. Some hotels also offer <em>bandas</em>, which are separate rooms or cottages, within the hotel complex. Cheaper hotels are found in main centres, as well as smaller towns and even villages. Since June 2013, hotels in Uganda are required to charge VAT, which meant increases of up to 18% on hotel bills throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are several good bed and breakfast options in Kampala, Entebbe, Jinja and other larger towns. These are usually friendly, clean and comfortable, with en-suite bathrooms. Many also offer laundry facilities and internet.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a broad range of hotels from budget to high-end in Uganda. More expensive, international-standard hotels and resorts can be found in Entebbe, Kampala and Jinja, and there are also some upmarket lodges in some of the country&rsquo;s national parks. Some hotels also offer <em>bandas</em>, which are separate rooms or cottages, within the hotel complex. Cheaper hotels are found in main centres, as well as smaller towns and even villages. Since June 2013, hotels in Uganda are required to charge VAT, which meant increases of up to 18% on hotel bills throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a broad range of hotels from budget to high-end in Uganda. More expensive, international-standard hotels and resorts can be found in Entebbe, Kampala and Jinja, and there are also some upmarket lodges in some of the country&rsquo;s national parks. Some hotels also offer <em>bandas</em>, which are separate rooms or cottages, within the hotel complex. Cheaper hotels are found in main centres, as well as smaller towns and even villages. Since June 2013, hotels in Uganda are required to charge VAT, which meant increases of up to 18% on hotel bills throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Visitors should bring personal supplies of medicines that are likely to be needed, but enquire first at the embassy or high commission whether such supplies may be freely imported. Comprehensive health insurance is essential and should include cover for emergency air repatriation in case of serious accident or illness. The Ugandan health service has still not recovered from the mass departure of foreign personnel in 1972 and there are medical facilities of a reasonable standard only in large towns and cities.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being a potential health risk. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;HIV/AIDS is widespread. Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes advised. After road accidents, malaria is the most serious health concern for travellers visiting Uganda. Seek up-to-date advice regarding malarial areas and the appropriate antimalarial medication prior to your trip, usually doxycycline, Malarone or mefloquine. Pregnant women are more vulnerable to malaria and are advised against travel to regions where malaria is present. Take a good insect repellant and try to avoid bites between dusk and dawn by always covering up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Foreign and Commonwealth Office in the UK also reports regular outbreaks of a wide range of serious diseases in Uganda, including cholera, Ebola haemorrhagic fever (EHF), Marburg haemorrhagic fever (MHF) meningococcal disease (meningitis A and W) and hepatitis E.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Liberation Day :
							2018<br/>26 January </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Martyrs' Day :
							03 June </p><p>Heroes' Day :
							09 June </p><p>Independence Day :
							09 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Uganda by visitors over 18 years without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 250g of tobacco products.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits (including liquors) or 2L of wine.<br />
&bull; 500ml of perfume and eau de toilette, of which up to 250ml may be perfume.<br />
&bull; Goods up to the value of US$500 (returning residents).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics, pornography, used underwear, used computers and appliances, counterfeit items, cultural artefacts and explosives are not permitted. Some medication may also be restricted; check before you travel.</p>
<p>You must obtain a permit to import hunting weapons, live animals, fruit, flowers, cuttings or seeds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A special permit is required to export game trophies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The local currency is the Uganda Shilling (UGX). Notes are in denominations of UGX50,000, 20,000, 10,000, 5,000, 2,000 and 1,000. Coins are in denominations of UGX500, 200, 100, 50 and 10 (rarely used). However, UGX1,000 notes are soon to be replaced by coins. Try not to accept very old or damaged notes where possible and any series of UGX from 1987, as most places will refuse to take them.</p>
<p>The US dollar, euro and pound sterling are all recognised currencies in Uganda, and both euros and dollars are now widely accepted for cash payments. Other international currencies may also be accepted in some places in the major cities, although visitors may struggle with other currencies in smaller towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currency may be exchanged at the Central Bank, commercial banks and foreign exchange bureaux. Be aware that US dollar notes from before 2006 will not be accepted for exchange.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Discover Cards and MasterCard are rarely accepted, except in a few spots. Visa cards are readily accepted. Some large hotels, restaurants, travel agencies and shops in urban areas accept credit cards.</p><p>ATMs are available in the larger cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are not widely accepted outside Kampala. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars or Pounds Sterling. It is advised that travellers bring sufficient US dollars in cash in case of emergencies. Higher denomination bills usually give a better exchange rate than smaller notes.&nbsp;If you have to use a traveller&rsquo;s cheque it is best to use American Express ones only.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally Mon-Fri 0830-1400, Sat 0900-1200. Forex bureaux are open until 1700 and able to do electronic transfers to and from overseas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Uganda, a passport valid for at least six months from the date of entry is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visas are also available through the e-Visa scheme and cost US$100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry e-Visa: US$50; East African tourist e-Visa: US$100.</p>
<p>Multiple-entry e-Visa: US$100 (six to 12 months), US$150 (12 to 24 months), US$200 (24 to 36 months).</p>
<p>Single-entry visa in advance: &pound;40;&nbsp;East African tourist visa in advance: &pound;70.&nbsp;<a id="fck_paste_padding">﻿</a></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>e-Visa/single-entry visa: three months from the date of issue.</p>
<p>Multiple-entry visa: up to 36 months.</p>
<p>East African tourist visa: three months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can either apply through the e-Visa system (<a href="http://www.visas.immigration.go.ug" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.visas.immigration.go.ug</a>) or via the nearest Ugandan embassy or high commission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow five working days for visa processing at the consulate/high commission and for e-Visas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers should have sufficient funds to cover their stay in Uganda, but proving this should only be necessary if you arrive with a one-way ticket, as officials may need reassurance that you can afford to leave the country when it&rsquo;s time to go home.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to extend your stay, you must contact the Immigration Headquarters in Kampala before your current visa expires. If you overstay your visa, you will be charged US$100 per day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cats and dogs must have a certificate of good health from a registered veterinarian in the area of origin, which must be issued, signed and stamped no earlier than 10 days before arrival in Uganda. You will also need a certificate confirming the animal is free of rabies and has been inoculated as necessary.</p>
<p>Dogs require vaccinations against distemper, parvo-virus, rabies, hepatitis and leptospirosos, not less than 30 days prior to arrival.</p>
<p>Cats should be vaccinated against rabies and feline entritis, not less than 30 days prior to arrival.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[1.282022]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[32.387990]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>241,038 sq km (93,072 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>41,487,965 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>157.1 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kampala.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Landlocked, Uganda lies between the eastern and western sections of Africa&rsquo;s Great Rift Valley. The country shares borders with South Sudan to the north, Kenya to the east, Lake Victoria to the southeast, Tanzania and Rwanda to the south and the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC) to the west. Whilst the landscape is generally quite flat, most of the country is over 1,000m (3,280ft) in altitude.</p>
<p>Mountainous regions include the Rwenzori Mountains that run along the border with the DRC, the Virunga Mountains on the border with Rwanda and the DRC, and Kigezi in the southwest of the country. An extinct volcano, Mount Elgon, straddles the border with Kenya.</p>
<p>The capital city, Kampala, lies on the shores of Lake Victoria, the largest lake in Africa and second-largest freshwater inland body of water in the world. Jinja, located on the lake, is considered to be the start point of the River Nile, which traverses much of the country.</p>
<p>The varied scenery includes tropical forest, a semi-desert area in the northeast, the arid plains of the Karamoja, the lush, heavily populated Buganda, the rolling savannah of Acholi, Bunyoro, Tororo and Ankole, tea plantations and the fertile cotton area of Teso.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>84.5% Christian and 13.7% Muslim with the remaining being atheist, or belonging to traditional religions. There are tiny minorities that practice Hinduism and Judaism.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors to the country will generally find Ugandans to be warm, friendly and relaxed.Shaking hands is the normal form of greeting and it&rsquo;s considered rude not to greet a person properly before rushing into asking them a question. Most people will know &lsquo;Hello&rsquo;, but the Swahili &lsquo;Jambo&rsquo; is also used. Casual dress is usual for most occasions in the daytime or evening.</p>
<p>Ugandans have adopted a socially conservative culture and expressing emotions or affection in public is best avoided. Expressing anger is also frowned on and generally counter-productive, so try and keep calm in frustrating situations.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Drug abuse is illegal and widely condemned, as is homosexuality. There has been much publicity in recent years regarding Uganda&rsquo;s hardline approach to homosexuality, with the government proposing in 2009 &ndash;&nbsp;it was later overturned in 2014 &ndash;&nbsp;an Anti-Homosexuality Bill which would have included death penalties for anyone proved to be indulging in same-sex activities. While the bill provoked strong international condemnation, homosexuals in Uganda still regularly face persecution, outings in the media or through the church, eviction, arrests and violence. As such, any LGBTQ+ travellers to the country are advised to be extremely cautious.</p>
<p>Photography: Since 1992, photography has been allowed in all areas with the exception of airports or military installations. However, some areas are still sensitive and it is advisable to take local advice. Commercial photographers should consult the Ministry of Information for a permit. If taking a photograph of people, ask their permission first.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>240 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Ruhakana Rugunda since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Yoweri Kaguta Museveni since 1986.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Before the arrival of Europeans in the 19th century, the Buganda Kingdom had become the ascendant dynasty in the region, having edged out other contenders with well-developed armed forces and agriculture.</p>
<p>From the 1840s, Muslim traders entered the region from the Indian Ocean coast. In 1862, British explorer John Hanning Speke became the first European to visit the kingdom, soon followed by a number of Christian missionaries, who were welcomed by the Bugandan king, Mutesa. The territory, renamed Uganda, officially became a British protectorate in 1894.</p>
<p>The country officially gained its independence from Britain in 1962, and most of its post-independence history has been characterised by politically inspired violence. President Obote, who banned opposition parties in 1969, was overthrown by the notorious and murderous Idi Amin, who remained in power until he was deposed by a joint force of Tanzanian forces and Ugandan exiles in 1979.</p>
<p>Obote subsequently returned to office but he too found himself fighting guerrilla groups &ndash; the remnants of Amin's army and Yoweri Museveni's National Resistance Army (NRA). The third major military force in the country was the Uganda National Liberation Army (UNLA), led by Tito Okello.</p>
<p>In July 1985, Obote was overthrown once again, this time by a military council with Okello at its head. The Okello government lasted just six months, and the NRA took control of the capital in 1986, establishing the National Resistance Council to govern the country.</p>
<p>By the early 1990s, Museveni had succeeded in restoring order and a measure of prosperity to most of the country. Presidential elections, comfortably won by Museveni, were held in 1989. Museveni continues to hold the presidency today, having won subsequent elections in 1996, 2001, 2006 and 2011.</p>
<p>For decades after Museveni came to power in 1986, two regions of northern Uganda, Gulu and Kitgum, continued to be embroiled in a civil war. This resulted in a civilian death toll of 10,000 people, most at the hands of the extremely violent Lord's Resistance Army (LRA), a quasi-religious anti-government outfit that terrorised the border regions of northern Uganda by deliberately targeting civilians.</p>
<p>While the Ugandan army failed to formally end the war, the LRA hasn't been active in northern Uganda since 2005 and the region and its people have finally been able to join the rest of the country in a prolonged period of relative peace and stability.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Winston Churchill dubbed Uganda the &ldquo;Pearl of Africa&rdquo; when he visited in 1907.<br />
&bull; Uganda has repeatedly been ranked in the top 25% in alcohol consumption.<br />
&bull; In 2016 nearly half of Uganda&rsquo;s population were under the age of 14, making it the youngest country in the world after Niger.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Uganda in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 726 7100.</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://washington.mofa.go.ug/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 726 7100.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1600; 0930-1500 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>5911 16th Street<br/>Washington<br/>20011<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[High Commission for the Republic of Uganda in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 207 839 5783</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://london.mofa.go.ug/data/smenu/13/Visa-Information.html?option=smenu&amp;id=13</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 207 839 5783</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1600, 0930-1300 (visa section).&amp;nbsp;Closed between 1300 and 1400 for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Trafalgar Square<br/>Uganda House, 58-59 Spring Gardens<br/>London<br/>WC2N 5DX<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Uganda]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+256 312 312000</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-high-commission-kampala</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+256 312 312000</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thu 0830-1300 and 1400-1700, Fri 0830-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>4, Windsor Loop, P.O. Box 7070<br/>Kampala<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A reputation for political instability and the looming shadow of Idi Amin have long &ndash; and unfairly &ndash; blighted Uganda&rsquo;s fledgling tourism sector. Now, though, things are looking up for the East African nation once described as &ldquo;the pearl of Africa&rdquo; by Winston Churchill.</p>
<p>And a brief look around is enough to show you why. From the second you step off the plane, the overwhelming impression of Uganda is one of rich natural diversity, friendly locals and a burgeoning cultural scene that is currently producing some of the most exciting artists in Africa.</p>
<p>Culturally, much of the action happens in the capital, Kampala, a hilly urban sprawl ringed by farmland and perched on the muddy banks of Lake Victoria. While most foreign travellers confine themselves to the city centre or the diplomatic quarter, Kololo, its worth venturing into the bustling bars and clubs of Kabalagala, where expats and locals meet for a slug of the local Nile beer and a friendly game of pool.</p>
<p>Away from the capital, Uganda&rsquo;s towns and cities have little in the way of diversions (although Jinja&rsquo;s location on the banks of the River Nile has made it a favourite with thrill-seeking rafters). Instead, head west towards the Congo border where, along with the fascinating pygmy people of Fort Portal, Uganda&rsquo;s natural wonders reveal themselves.</p>
<p>A popular spot for wildlife watching is Queen Elizabeth National Park, which is home to four of the Big Five, a flock of flamboyant flamingos and the rare tree-climbing lions of Ishasha.</p>
<p>The star attraction, though, is the iconic mountain gorilla, which can be found further south in Bwindi Impenetrable Forest. While you&rsquo;re down there it&rsquo;s also worth taking a detour to Lake Bunyonyi, a mountain retreat famed for its stunning vistas and freshwater crayfish.</p>
<p>More natural wonders await in northern Uganda, home to the magnificent Murchison Falls, and in the east, where visitors will find the outstanding desert crags and ossified anthills of Kidepo.</p>
<p>Regardless of where you go in Uganda, when it comes to leaving, it will be with a reluctant heavy heart.</p><p>A reputation for political instability and the looming shadow of Idi Amin have long &ndash; and unfairly &ndash; blighted Uganda&rsquo;s fledgling tourism sector. Now, though, things are looking up for the East African nation once described as &ldquo;the pearl of Africa&rdquo; by Winston Churchill.</p>
<p>And a brief look around is enough to show you why. From the second you step off the plane, the overwhelming impression of Uganda is one of rich natural diversity, friendly locals and a burgeoning cultural scene that is currently producing some of the most exciting artists in Africa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
