<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Ukraine" ColCode="ukr" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ua" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine has a temperate continental climate with cold, snowy winters and warm summers. Summer is generally the best time to visit (between June and September), although it can occasionally be uncomfortably hot and many hotels do not have air conditioning. July and August are peak holiday months in Crimea and its resorts can become crowded with domestic and Russian tourists. Spring and autumn are both fairly short and both tend to be reasonably mild. The best season for trekking in the Carpathian Mountains is May and October when it is driest.<br />
<br />
The northeast of Ukraine has the coldest winters and the Crimean peninsula has the warmest temperatures. The wettest part of Ukraine is the Carpathian Mountains region of the far west.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight clothes needed in summer, light- to mediumweight in the spring and autumn and heavyweight in the winter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Domestic flights in Kiev depart from both Borispol Airport (KBP) and from Zhulany Airport (IEV). Ukraine International Airlines (<a href="http://www.flyuia.com" target="_blank">www.flyuia.com</a>) is the main carrier.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Ukraine is a large country, so flying between major cities such as Kiev, Lviv and Odessa (which require lengthy overnight train journeys) can save valuable travelling time. Advance booking is advisable in summer and during holiday periods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cruises between Kiev and Odessa are very popular and can be booked through various tour operators.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Trains are more reliable than air travel in winter, when aircraft are sometimes grounded. Timetables for trains in CIS states, including trains within Ukraine, are available in English online (<a href="http://www.poezda.net" target="_blank">www.poezda.net</a>). Or you can check times through Ukrainian Railways (tel: +380 44 309 7005; <a href="http://www.uz.gov.ua" target="_blank">www.uz.gov.ua</a>). There are no domestic rail passes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Getting around by road can be difficult outside the main cities. Roads are often potholed and driving standards can be poor.&nbsp;Outside urban areas, Ukrainian roads can be badly lit and in poor condition.  Border points are at Chop, Mostiska and Uzhgorod.  A road tax is payable at the border.  Petrol stations and repair garages are becoming more common, but it is recommended to carry spare parts.</p>r<p>The main coach companies in Ukraine are Avtolux (tel: +380 44 594 9500; <a href="http://autolux.ua" target="_blank">autolux.ua</a>) and Gunsel (tel: 0800 303 010, in Ukraine only; <a href="http://www.gunsel.com.ua" target="_blank">www.gunsel.com.ua</a>), both of which have services throughout the country.</p><p>Hiring a driver for a long-distance journey is a realistic and affordable option.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required. Third-party insurance is compulsory.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Seatbelts must be worn. Children under 12 cannot travel in the front seat. There is a zero tolerance policy on drink driving. Speed limits are 60kph (37mph) in built-up areas, 90kph (55mph) in outside areas and 130kph (80mph) on the motorways. Police may stop foreign cars and issue on-the-spot fines for minor infringements. Right-hand drive cars are prohibited.</p><p>European breakdown cover valid for Ukraine should be arranged at home in advance for drivers with their own cars. Car hire companies should have their own breakdown assistance but it is important to check.</p><p>Self-drive hire cars are available from both local and international car hire operators in major towns, especially Kiev. The minimum age for hiring a car is 21 years.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Seatbelts must be worn. Children under 12 cannot travel in the front seat. There is a zero tolerance policy on drink driving. Speed limits are 60kph (37mph) in built-up areas, 90kph (55mph) in outside areas and 130kph (80mph) on the motorways. Police may stop foreign cars and issue on-the-spot fines for minor infringements. Right-hand drive cars are prohibited.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All towns and cities have a comprehensive network of buses and trolleybuses that tend to be slow, crowded but very cheap. These are supplemented by fleets of battered minibuses (<em>marshrutky</em>) that will stop or put down anywhere along fixed routes. Official taxis, found in cities and larger towns, are metered and can be identified by a yellow and black sign on the roof. Fares should be negotiated in advance for private taxis.</p>
<p>Kharkiv, Kiev and Dnipropetrovsk have clean, efficient and cheap metro systems. You can buy tickets at vending machines inside the stations or use reloadable smartcards. Hitchhiking is very common, although not recommended. Passengers are expected to pay for the ride and the price, usually about the same as the bus fare, should be agreed upon before boarding.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national carrier is Ukraine International Airlines (<a href="http://www.flyuia.com" target="_blank">www.flyuia.com</a>), whose routes include direct flights from the UK and the USA. British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) also operates direct flights from the UK to Ukraine.&nbsp;Prices tend to be higher in July and August.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kiev-boryspil-international-airport">Kiev Boryspil International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ukraine/lviv-danylo-halitskyi-international-airport">Lviv Danylo Halitskyi International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kiev">Kiev</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 3 hours 15 minutes: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 9 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Boryspil International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.kbp.aero/en/<p>Most international flights arrive and depart through terminal B, 40km (25 miles) east of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kiev">Kiev</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(044) 490 4777</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong> Ilyichevsk, Izmail and Odessa.</p>
<p>Ukrferry (tel: +380 482 344 059; <a href="http://www.ukrferry.com" target="_blank">www.ukrferry.com</a>) operates ferries from Ilyichevsk to Poti and Batumi, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/georgia">Georgia</a>; from Ilyichevsk to Varna, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bulgaria">Bulgaria</a>; from Ilyichevsk to Haydarpasa, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkey">Turkey</a>; and from Ilyichevsk to Constantza, Romania.</p>
<p>Ferries run by Gess Tur between Sevastopol and Istanbul, Turkey are currently suspended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine's railways link most towns and cities within the republic and further links extend from Kiev to all other CIS member states. The main stations are Kiev and Lviv, with regular daily services connecting these stations with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a>. There are international trains to many other major European cities although trains north to the Baltic countries pass through <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belarus">Belarus</a> and require a transit visa.</p>
<p>If travelling from the UK, the easiest route is via Eurostar to Brussels, ICE train to Cologne, overnight sleeper from Cologne to Warsaw, and overnight sleeper from Warsaw to Kiev. Fast 'firmeny' trains are the most rapid, modern and comfortable trains. Tickets are cheap by UK standards. If travelling by overnight train, do not leave the compartment unattended.</p>
<p>Timetables for trains to Ukraine, as well as approximate fares, are available in English at <a target="_blank" href="http://www.poezda.net">www.poezda.net</a>. InterRail or Eurail passes are not valid in Ukraine.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>You can buy telephone cards of UAH20, 50 or 100 for public payphones in post offices and at kiosks. Many post offices have international phone booths where calls can be made after paying a deposit. International phone cards are also available in the larger cities, but by far the cheapest connections are those found at internet cafés.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Ukraine's mobile phone coverage is good and local SIM cards (Kyivstar or UMC) are available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafés are available in all cities and towns. Connections are usually reasonable. Some hotels offer Wi-Fi connectivity.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A free media is one of the very tangible benefits of the Orange Revolution. Until 2004 there was very limited press freedom, with independent journalists being intimidated, and, in one famous case, murdered, when not toeing the government line. Following the election of Viktor Yushchenko as president in 2005, a free press has flourished, although media watchdogs claim that attacks on journalists have increased since the 2010 election of Viktor Yanukovych.<br />
<br />
The most widely read newspapers include the daily <em>Fakty i Kommentarii</em><em>, Segodnya</em>, <em>Ukryina Moloda</em> and <em>Den</em>.English-language newspapers include the daily <em>Kyiv Post</em> and the weekly <em>Zerkalo Nedeli</em>. The state-run <em>National TV Company of Ukraine</em> operates <em>UT1</em>, <em>UT2</em> and <em>UT3</em> channels, and the state-run radio  broadcaster <em>National Radio Company of Ukraine</em> operates three networks. A number of commercial television and radio stations are also available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Services are erratic. Letters to Western Europe can take two weeks or more. The main post office in Kiev is located at Khreshchatik 22 and is open 24 hours. You can make telephone calls and send faxes here.</p><p>Generally 0800-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Carpathian Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ski or snowboard in the Carpathian Mountains in the west. The leading resorts are Bukovel, Slavsko, Drahobrat and Tysovets. Bukovel is the only resort of international standard, although Drahobrat has the most reliable snow.</p>]]><p><b>Caves Monastery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Kiev's religious heritage at the Caves Monastery. This ancient institution is the focal point of the early Orthodox Church. You'll need to carry candles to see the church relics, which are set in a maze of spooky catacombs.</p>]]><p><b>Chernobyl</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a macabre guided tour to Chernobyl, scene of the world's worst ever nuclear disaster, just a day trip from Kiev. It's safe to visit for short periods and doubtless one of the more unique Ukrainian experiences.</p>]]><p><b>Kamyanets-Podilsky</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Marvel at the stunning Western Ukrainian town of Kamyanets-Podilsky, a medieval stunner set on a tall rock outcrop that has beguiled travellers for centuries and was famously described as 'a stone flower on the rock' by poet Lesya Ukrayinka.</p>]]><p><b>Kiev</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover Kiev, both the ancient cradle of Russian civilisation and the city from which the Orthodox faith spread throughout Eastern Europe. The extraordinary Golden Gate of Kiev is the last remnant of the 10th-century walls built to defend the city. Take part in the Kiev Days celebrations, held annually during the last weekend of May. Events include performances by actors and musicians, as well as fireworks displays.]]><p><b>Lviv</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover gorgeous Lviv, an open-air museum of extraordinary architectural wealth. The Old Town, a UNESCO World Heritage site, is centered on the glorious Market Square, stuffed full of dazzling gothic, baroque, Renaissance and rococo buildings. For a dazzing evening, see a theatre or operatic performance at The Ivan Franko Opera House: an extravagantly built, richly decorated structure, classed among the best theatres in Europe.</p>]]><p><b>Mystetskyi Arsenal</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once an abandoned military arsenal building in the middle of the city, Mystetskyi Arsenal has been transformed into Kiev's premier arts and cultural space. At over 53,000 sq m, it is one of the largest museums in Europe, housing art laboratories, libraries and classrooms as well as exhibition space.</p>]]><p><b>Odessa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relive the world's most famous cinema scene in Odessa, the site of the famous Potemkin Stairway from Sergei Eisenstein's film, <em>Battleship Potemkin</em>. Odessa is the country's most cosmopolitan city, with a thriving Jewish population and boundless confidence.</p>]]><p><b>River swimming</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Join the locals who swim in summer in the Dnieper River in Kiev and climb onto its ice in winter to fish. Even better, come here for Orthodox Epiphany and be splashed with icy water during the celebrations.</p>]]><p><b>Sevastopol</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the fascinating catacombs of Sevastopol (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.sevdig.sevastopol.ws/">www.sevdig.sevastopol.ws</a>), for over two centuries the secret naval headquarters on the Black Sea. Discover the extraordinary underground submarine base and be James Bond for the day.</p>]]><p><b>St Sofia Cathedral</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the 11th-century St Sofia Cathedral, which contains splendid icons and frescoes and is situated in beautiful grounds. The Cathedral of St Vladimir is the headquarters of the rival pro-Ukrainian church.</p>]]><p><b>Wine tasting</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The region's vineyards produce good-quality wine which can be tasted locally quite cheaply. The Wine Tasting Hall in Yalta is as good a place as any.</p>]]><p><b>Yalta</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Make a trip south to Yalta, the 'Pearl of the Crimea'. Nearby is the Livadia Palace, where Roosevelt, Churchill and Stalin met in 1945 to reshape the map of Europe, and where the tsars spent their summer holidays before the Bolshevik Revolution.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$218.6 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Ferrous and nonferrous metals, fuel and petroleum products, chemicals, machinery and transport equipment, and food products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Energy, agricultural machinery and equipment, cars, chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Russian Federation, Germany, Turkey, Turkmenistan, Italy and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine has large areas of very fertile land, which give it the reputation as the 'bread basket' of the former Soviet Union. Grain, sugar beet and vegetables are the main crops and there is extensive livestock farming. The country also boasts large mineral resources, particularly coal in the huge Donbass fields, as well as iron ore, manganese and titanium.<br />
<br />
There are a few reserves of gas and oil, but Ukraine has to import more than three-quarters of its requirements of these products from elsewhere, mainly from the Russian Federation. In recent years Ukraine has seen its gas and oil supply temporarily cut off by Russian energy giant Gazprom in protest at non-payment of bills. <br />
<br />
Ukraine gained membership of the World Trade Organization in 2008. Several of Ukraine's neighbours are now EU members. Ukraine itself is far from a condition in which it might be accepted for EU membership, but this is bound to have a major impact on the country's economic policy-making.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kiev is the business hub of Ukraine, though it&rsquo;s not a particularly formal place to do business. Suits and ties are usually worn by men for business meetings. The exchange of business cards is extremely common and visitors are advised to bring company cards. Russian and English are the two main business languages here.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700/1800. Lunch tends to be at least one and a half hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Ministry of Economy</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (44) 253 9394
					Website:http://www.me.gov.ua/
					Address: ,12/2 vulitsa Grushevskogo,Kyiv,1008]]><b>Economic and Commercial Section/Trade and Economic MissionEmbassy of Ukraine in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 7221 0589
					Website:http://www.mfa.gov.ua/uk
					Address: London W11 3SJ,60 Holland Park,UK,]]><b>Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (44) 272 2911
					Website:http://www.ucci.org.ua/
					Address: ,33 vulitsa Velyka Zhytomyrska,Kyiv,1601]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Traditional Ukrainian food, such as that in Russia, is mostly of the 'filling and hearty' variety, with a heavy emphasis on dumplings, potatoes and sour cream. Vegetables tend to be seasonal: excellent fresh fruit and vegetables including peppers, cucumbers and tomatoes are available at markets in summer, while the winter months are dominated by bottled fruit and preserved cabbage.<br />
<br />
Pizza places are ubiquitous and in the larger towns (especially Kiev) visitors have a wide choice of cuisines that includes French, Indian, Italian and Turkish. Asian restaurants can also be found in the larger urban centres.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; <em>Borshch</em> (beetroot soup made with meat broth).<br />&bull; <em>Varenniki</em> (dumplings containing potatoes, cheese, meat or fruit).<br />&bull; <em>Deruny</em> (potato pancakes). <br />&bull; <em>Pelmeny</em> (meat-filled ravioli originally from Siberia).<br />&bull; Chicken Kiev exists but is better known in the West.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tips are appreciated. A service charge of 10-15% is sometimes included in smarter restaurant and on hotel bills.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>The minimum legal drinking age is 18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Opera is performed in the ornate theatres of Kiev, Lviv and Odessa. Ukrainians have a deep-rooted musical tradition and singing is very popular. Most cities offer opportunities to experience live music performances (rock, folk and jazz) and some of the more upmarket restaurants, in Kiev and Odessa especially, stage live music at weekends. Most cities also have good musical comedy, puppet-theatre and troupes performing theatrical works in Ukrainian and Russian. Tickets are cheap by Western standards and readily available on the day of performance at the box offices. Prominent visiting artists most often perform in Kiev's vast Ukraine Theatre, where prices are higher. For party animals, Kiev has an animated nightclub and disco scene, some of which operates from barges on the Dnieper River.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Popular souvenirs include paintings, ceramics and jewellery, all of which can be purchased at galleries or direct from artists on the street. Other good and authentically Ukrainian souvenirs include hand painted eggs <em>(pyansky)</em>, carved wooden items and <em>matryoshka</em> dolls, which are actually Russian in origin. Hand-embroidered clothes are another good bet, although the quality can be variable.<br />
<br /> 
Religious artefacts can make a good purchase, but it should be remembered that it is illegal to take antique objects out of the country. Soviet-era souvenirs are another popular buy although many of these have actually been manufactured recently abroad in countries like China. The buying of fur products is not to be encouraged as these may come from endangered species.</p><p>Large state or department stores tend to open Monday to Friday 0800-1900, whereas small boutiques are generally open 0900-1800.Some shops stay open as late as 2000. Smaller shops may close for an hour at lunch, usually from 1300-1400 or 1400-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not long ago, most hotels in Ukraine were former Soviet institutions where little had changed for decades. These days, many of the older establishments have been either closed or refurbished to a decent standard offering a range of rooms of varying quality and price. In larger towns and cities, especially in Kiev, Odessa, Lviv and Yalta, there is also a new generation of hotels offering the same high standards found elsewhere in Europe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not long ago, most hotels in Ukraine were former Soviet institutions where little had changed for decades. These days, many of the older establishments have been either closed or refurbished to a decent standard offering a range of rooms of varying quality and price. In larger towns and cities, especially in Kiev, Odessa, Lviv and Yalta, there is also a new generation of hotels offering the same high standards found elsewhere in Europe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not long ago, most hotels in Ukraine were former Soviet institutions where little had changed for decades. These days, many of the older establishments have been either closed or refurbished to a decent standard offering a range of rooms of varying quality and price. In larger towns and cities, especially in Kiev, Odessa, Lviv and Yalta, there is also a new generation of hotels offering the same high standards found elsewhere in Europe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;The health service does, in theory, provide free medical treatment for all citizens and travellers who become ill. However, as in most parts of the former Soviet Union, health care is a serious problem. For minor difficulties, visitors are advised to ask the management at their hotels for help. For major problems, visitors are well advised to seek help outside the country. Travel insurance is strongly recommended. It is advisable to take a supply of those medicines that are likely to be required (but check first that they may be legally imported) as medicines can prove difficult to obtain. Travellers are advised to contact their embassy, in the first instance, for advice on where to get medical help.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled. Street food is generally safe if it is fresh and hot. Freshwater fish and mushrooms or berries gathered in the area around Chernobyl north of Kiev are best avoided.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes advised. Tick-borne encephalitis is quite common in the Ukrainian countryside between April and August. Visitors should take precautions against ticks in forested areas by wearing long sleeves and trousers and a hat.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are observed the following Monday. Holidays falling on Tuesday or Thursday may be observed the preceding Monday or following Friday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Orthodox Christmas Day :
							2018<br/>07 January </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Orthodox Easter Sunday :
							08 April </p><p>Labour Days :
							01 May </p><p>Victory Day :
							09 May </p><p>Orthodox Pentecost :
							27 May </p><p>Constitution Day :
							28 June </p><p>Independence Day :
							24 August </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Ukraine by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits and 2L of wine and 5L of beer.<br />
&bull; Food products to the value of &euro;200, weighing no more than 2kg.<br />
&bull; Other goods to the value of &euro;1,000 if arriving by air or &euro;500 if arriving by land or sea, weighing no more than 50kg.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Illegal drugs and unlicensed firearms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Illegal drugs and unlicensed firearms.</p>
<p>You must obtain authorisation to export cultural goods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hryvnya (UAH) = 100 kopiyok (singular: kopiyka). Notes are in denominations of UAH500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of UAH1 and 50, 25, 10, 5, 2 and 1 kopiyok.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Money should only be changed at currency booths on the street or in banks. It is advisable to keep receipts showing money changed. Changing money with black-market traders is not recommended and can be dangerous. If you wish to exchange currency of 150,000 UAH or over you will need to present your passport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although still largely a cash economy, credit cards are becoming increasingly more accepted for the payment of goods and services, however, cheaper restaurants and hotels will not usually accept them. Travellers should be aware there is a high level of credit card fraud.</p><p>ATMs are increasingly common throughout Ukraine, in towns as well as cities, and are generally reliable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not generally advised as they can be difficult to exchange. If taken, they should be made out in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0930-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Ukraine, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors requiring a visa who are merely passing through Ukraine can apply for a transit visa that allows a five-day stay in the country. Documentary proof, such as a visa for another country or an onward ticket, is required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Varies depending on your nationality.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas are usually valid for stays of up to 90 days within a six-month period, although the six months can be extended up to as much as five years according to individual circumstances.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). You need to make your initial application online (<a href="http://visa.mfa.gov.ua" target="_blank">visa.mfa.gov.ua</a>).&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow up to 15 days for visa processing. Some cases may take as long as 30 days. Consulates may consider granting visas in less than 15 days for double the normal fee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign visitors to Ukraine must be able to show proof of sufficient funds to cover their stay. You must have at least US$100 per day plus a five-day reserve of US$500. Your proof can be in the form of cash, bank or credit card statements showing the appropriate balance, a confirmed accommodation booking, a tourist voucher, a letter of invitation from a sponsor stating he/she will cover your costs while in Ukraine, or a return/onward ticket.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[48.926989]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[31.477987]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>603,700 sq km (233,090 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>42,418,235 (2017).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>73.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kiev.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine is bordered by the Russian Federation to the north and east; Belarus to the north; Poland, the Slovak Republic and Hungary to the west; and Romania and Moldova to the southwest. It is a varied country with mountains in the west, plains in the centre and the Black Sea views to the south. The north of the state is dominated by forests. Its other two main features are wooded steppe with beech and oak forests and the treeless steppe. The River Dnieper divides Ukraine roughly in half, and flows into the Black Sea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>About 16% of Ukraine&rsquo;s population claim to be either not religious or do not identify with a particular church. Around 55% are members of the Eastern Orthodox Church while 6.5%, mostly in western Ukraine, adhere to the Uniate (Eastern-rite) or Ukrainian Greek Catholic tradition. Other minorities include the Ukrainian Autocephalous Orthodox Church, the Roman Catholic Church and various Protestant groups. There is also a Muslim minority (mainly consisting of Tatars in Crimea), which makes up 1.1% of the population.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian people are generally warm and friendly to visitors. It is not at all uncommon for Ukrainians to invite strangers into their own homes. Shoes should be removed on entering a home. Formal attire is rarely required, though people dress smartly for the theatre. Visitors should avoid ostentatious displays of wealth in public places. Men should not shake a woman&rsquo;s hand unless it is offered to them. Women should cover their heads when entering a church or mosque.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Volodymyr Groysman since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Petro Poroshenko since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine has long been associated with its much larger and more powerful neighbour Russia and first came under Russian control in the 1650s when the only real alternative was invasion by the Poles.<br />
<br />
By the 19th century, although the western part of Ukraine was under Austro-Hungarian control, most of the country became part of the Russian Empire. After various attempts at independence around the period of the 1917 Russian Revolution, Ukraine became a republic within the USSR and its territory enlarged slightly around the time of World War II. Crimea became part of Ukraine in 1954 and, due to its predominantly Russian population and strategic position on the Black Sea, is still the subject of on-going dispute between Ukraine and Russia especially since the 2014 annexation of Crimea by Russia.<br />
<br />
In 1986, in the final years of the Soviet era and during the Perestroika period of President Gorbachev, the accident at the Chernobyl nuclear plant in northern Ukraine brought worldwide attention and was arguably a significant factor in accelerating the collapse of the Soviet Union.<br />
<br />
Full independence came with the breakup of the Soviet Union in 1991, but Ukraine&rsquo;s foreign relations are still dominated by the Russian Federation, a fact which displeases many of the country&rsquo;s ethnic Ukrainian population, particularly those in the west of the country.<br />
<br />
Rigged presidential elections in 2004 that declared Prime Minister Viktor Yanukovych the victor sparked bitter public outcry and resulted in the so-called Orange Revolution and the subsequent 2005 election of pro-Western Viktor Yushchenko as President, with Yulia Tymoshenko as his Prime Minister. However, Yanukovych soon returned to power as Prime Minister in 2006 and in 2010 was elected President once more. Ousted by Parliament in 2014, he fled the country and according to some reports was granted Russian citizenship in a &lsquo;secret decree&rsquo; by Vladimir Putin. In January 2015 he was placed on Interpol&rsquo;s wanted list.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
&nbsp;</p>
<p>The current President Petro Poroshenki was elected by an outright majority in 2014 and in 2016 took Ukraine into the Deep and Comprehensive Free Trade Area with the EU in an attempt to modernise and develop its economy, political structure and rule of law by gradually increasing its connection to the EU&rsquo;s internal market.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; The National Police Force of Ukraine was formed on 3 July 2015 to replace the discredited and unpopular Militsiya.</p>
<p>&bull; The University of Lviv, founded in 1661, is the oldest in Ukraine.</p>
<p>&bull; Traditional Ukrainian Easter eggs, known as pysanky, are thought to at least 1000 years old and pre-date the Christian era.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Ukraine in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 349 2963 </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.mfa.gov.ua/usa</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 349 2963 </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1800.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3350 M Street<br/>Washington<br/>20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Ukraine in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 (0)20 7727 6312.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://uk.mfa.gov.ua/ua</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 (0)20 7727 6312.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1300 and 1400-1800. Not open to personal callers.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Kensington<br/>60 Holland Park<br/>London<br/>W11 3SJ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vast and mysterious to many, Ukraine is barely known to outsiders despite being one of the largest countries in Europe. Long-associated with its colossal neighbour Russia, it's a country that stands out in its own right for its varied landscapes and surprising cultural diversity.</p><p>To the majority of those visiting for the first time, the reputation of Ukraine's hardy inhabitants can seem formidable. But while, much like in neighbouring Russia, cracking a smile at a stranger in the street is deemed a sure sign of madness, locals tend to be a thoroughly welcoming lot once you've broken the ice. Before long they'll be showing you round the sights and inviting you to their home for a steaming <em>borscht </em>– the country's iconic beetroot soup<em>. </em></p><p>Ukraine's natural side is also seen as tough – and it's true that in winter snow covers most of the land as temperatures plummet. During the rest of the year, though, it's surprisingly clement. What's more, with its largely unspoilt, verdant interior, Ukraine is ideal for hikers and cyclists.</p><p>The Carpathian Mountains that spill over the border with Poland, Hungary and Romania dominate the west of the country while flat plains carpeted with sunflowers and cereals make up much of the central and eastern region. To the south are the almost Mediterranean-like Black Sea coast and the Crimean Peninsula, which remains a huge draw for holidaymakers every summer. And even when snow falls through the winter, the landscape is beautiful, while there are many old churches and Soviet-era buildings to dive into for shelter.<br/><br/>Ukraine's capital, Kiev, founded in the eighth century, displays a heady mix of architecture befitting of a city that was once capital of Kievan Rus, the precursor of the modern Russian state. A wealth of baroque and Renaissance architecture can also be found in Lviv, one of Europe's oldest cities, while Odessa is probably best known for the Potemkin Stairway that featured in Sergei Eisenstein's epic film <em>The Battleship Potemkin</em>.</p><p>Recently, Ukraine has been in the news for the wrong reasons due to Russian separatism on the border. Despite this, most of the country is completely safe for visitors.</p><p>Vast and vaguely mysterious, Ukraine is barely known to outsiders despite being one of the largest countries in Europe. Long associated with its colossal neighbour Russia, it's a country of varied landscapes and surprising cultural diversity.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
