<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="New York State" ColCode="nwy" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ny" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[New York State]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> is warm and sunny from May to October, followed by cold winters. Snow is common in the mountains and interior part of the state. Buffalo gets more snow than Anchorage, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/alaska">Alaska</a> due to the lake effect from Lake Erie. Summer in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York City</a> can be hot and humid, with occasional tropical storms. Due to vehicular emissions, the city often issues ozone alert days during summer months. Fall is a popular time to visit New York, as the leaves on trees turn brilliant shades of red, yellow and orange, and temperatures tend to be very comfortable. "Leaf peeping" is a popular autumn activity among locals and visitors alike. Winters are usually cold, with occasional snowstorms, freezing rain and bitter cold winds, which blow off both the Hudson and the East Rivers. The winter conditions outside the city often mean liberal snow for skiers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Due to variable weather conditions, visitors should pack clothing that allows for layering. Lightweight cottons and linens are advised for summer months, while heavyweight clothing with extra bundling are advised for the winter. Visitors planning on engaging in outdoor activities, regardless of the time of year, should be sure to pack relevant specialty clothing. Keep in mind that the water in the Atlantic Ocean never gets particularly warm, so those planning on surfing at popular points such as Montauk should plan on wearing a full wet suit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>JetBlue (<a href="http://www.jetblue.com" target="_blank">www.jetblue.com</a>) is the primary domestic carrier offering affordable air travel within the state of New York. The airline offers flights between JFK and Buffalo (BUF), Rochester (ROC), Saranac Lake (SLK), and Syracuse (SYR).</p><p>JetBlue regularly adds new destination cities; check its website for new service.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Water-based transport is an increasingly popular way to get around New York. In New York City, the Water Taxi (<a href="http://www.nywatertaxi.com" target="_blank">www.nywatertaxi.com</a>) has been expanding routes and frequency of service.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Trains are an excellent way to travel around New York State. MetroNorth, Long Island Rail Road, and Amtrak originate and terminate in New York City. Service extends across the state.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Amtrak offers rail passes in 15-, 30- and 45 day increments; prices vary. Check the website for current information.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most interstates have toll roads and all bridge and tunnel approaches into New York City have tolls. If your car does not have an EZ-Pass unit, you will need to make sure you are in the lane accepting cash payments. Note that most rental car agencies provide EZ-Pass units inside their vehicles, but levy a surcharge for their use. You can opt to keep the unit closed and pay cash.</p>r<p>Roads throughout New York State are typically safe and well-maintained.</p><p>Greyhound (<a href="http://www.greyhound.com" target="_blank">www.greyhound.com</a>), Peter Pan (<a href="http://www.peterpanbus.com" target="_top">www.peterpanbus.com</a>), and Trailways (<a href="http://www.trailways.com" target="_blank">www.trailways.com</a>) are the three major companies operating between cities within New York State. Budget buses such as Fung Wah, Vamoose, BoltBus, and megabus offer affordable service between major cities in the northeastern US.</p><p>Yellow taxis are ubiquitous in New York City and may be hailed on the street. All taxis must use a meter. All taxis are now equipped with machines allowing passengers to pay with a credit or debit card. <br />
<br />
Outside of New York City, taxis are not as ubiquitous, nor as easily identifiable. In many towns, you will need to call a local taxi company to request service. Your hotel concierge or front desk can provide contact information for local companies.</p><p>You will need to present a valid driver's license to rent and/or drive a car in the state of New York.</p><p>Seat belt use is required throughout the state of New York. Mobile phones may not be used while driving. Speed limits, designated in miles per hour, vary by road type and area; look for posted signs for prevailing limit.</p><p>Your rental car agency should provide you with instructions for requesting breakdown service. Ask about this at the time of rental.</p><p>All major US rental car agencies have branches at New York City's airports. Most regional airports also have car rental services. State law requires that renters hold a valid driver's license. They must be at least 18 years of age; however, renters under the age of 25 may be charged an additional fee, which is not standard or set by the state. Additional drivers are allowed if they meet the license and age requirements, and they may be charged up to US$3 per day.</p><p>New York is increasingly bike-friendly, especially in New York City, which has a growing number of bike lanes. By law, riders must move with the flow of vehicular traffic and use bike lanes if they are available. Riding on the sidewalk is not permitted, nor is cycling on the Interstate.</p><p>Seat belt use is required throughout the state of New York. Mobile phones may not be used while driving. Speed limits, designated in miles per hour, vary by road type and area; look for posted signs for prevailing limit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New York City has one of the world's oldest, busiest, and most renowned public transportation systems, and while busy, it is easily navigable with a map and unlimited Metrocard. The city's public transportation system consists of an extensive network of buses and subway trains. Free maps are available in stations and online at www.mta.info.<br/><br/>
Outside New York City, public transportation is limited and towns and cities tend to have car-centred cultures, much like most other cities and towns in the US.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International flights to New York land at John F. Kennedy International Airport (JFK) or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-jersey">New Jersey</a>'s Liberty International Airport (EWR). Domestic flights land at JFK, LaGuardia (LGA), or EWR.</p>
<p>New York is a popular year-round destination. Flights tend to be highest for winter holidays and around New Year's, and lower in the height of summer. But most major airlines do hold regular fare sales.</p>
<p>International carriers offer regular, if not daily, flights to and from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York City</a>. British Airways (<a target="_top" href="http://www.britishairways.com">www.britishairways.com</a>) and Virgin Atlantic (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.virgin-atlantic.com">www.virgin-atlantic.com</a>) are the two UK-based airlines with most frequent service to New York.</p>
<p>For air travel within the state, low-cost carriers like JetBlue (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.jetblue.com">www.jetblue.com</a>) provide affordable, regular service, often with multiple flights per day, between the state's major cities.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york/new-york-la-guardia-airport">New York LaGuardi Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york/long-island-macarthur-airport">Long Island Macarthur Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york/new-york-john-f-kennedy-international-airport">New York John F Kennedy International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york/westchester-county-airport">Westchester County Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york/buffalo-niagara-international-airport">Buffalo Niagara International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York City</a> is approximately 7 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Though all three of the area's airports are among the nation's busiest, there are no current plans to add any new airports in the New York City area. There are capital development projects, however, to improve upon and expand existing infrastructure at all three airports. All three airports are easily accessible by public transportation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Though all three of the area's airports are among the nation's busiest, there are no current plans to add any new airports in the New York City area. There are capital development projects, however, to improve upon and expand existing infrastructure at all three airports. All three airports are easily accessible by public transportation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>New York John F. Kennedy International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.panynj.gov<p>New York John F. Kennedy International Airport is located 25km (15.5 miles) southeast of Manhattan.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 718 244 4444</p>]]><b>New York LaGuardia Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.laguardiaairport.com<p>New York LaGuardia Airport is located 13km (8 miles) east of Manhattan, in the Flushing neighbourhood in the borough of Queens.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 718 533 3400</p>]]><b>Buffalo Niagara International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.buffaloairport.com<p>Buffalo Niagara International Airport is situated 14km (9 miles) east of Buffalo.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 716 630 6000</p>]]><b>Newark Liberty International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.panynj.gov<p>Newark Liberty International Airport is located 3km (2 miles) south of Newark and 26km (16 miles) southwest of New York City.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 973 961 6000</p>]]><b>Long Island MacArthur Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.flylima.com<p>Long Island MacArthur Airport is located in Ronkonkoma on Long Island, some 80km (50 miles) northeast of Manhattan.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(631) 467 3300.</p>]]><b>Westchester County Airport</b><![CDATA[http://airport.westchestergov.com<p>Westchester County Airport is situated 56km (35 miles) northeast of New York City, and 9km (6 miles) northeast of White Plains.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 914 995 4860</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New York is located on the northeastern coast of the United States and so is easily accessible by water. New York City is a port city, as is Buffalo in the upstate; however, Buffalo is solely a cargo port.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New York City's Pennsylvania Station (&ldquo;Penn Station&rdquo;) serves the Long Island Railroad, with routes to Long Island; NJ Transit, with routes to New Jersey; and Amtrak, with service to other stations in New York state and nationwide (tel: 1 800 872 7245, in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> only; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.amtrak.com">www.amtrak.com</a>).</p>
<p>New York City's Grand Central Station is the terminus for services to upstate New York (via Metro North rail services) and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/connecticut">Connecticut</a>. There are daily trains to Montr&eacute;al and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/toronto">Toronto</a> in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada">Canada</a> as well.</p>
<p>From New York on the 'Maple Leaf' to Niagara Falls is 9 hours; on the 'Silver Meteor' to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/orlando">Orlando</a> (Disney World) is 21 hours; and on the 'Crescent' to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/atlanta">Atlanta</a> is 16 hours. There are frequent shuttles to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/washington-state">Washington</a> D.C. and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/boston">Boston</a>, taking 3 hours 15 minutes and 4 hours 30 minutes respectively.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Amtrak (<a href="http://www.amtrak.com" target="_blank">www.amtrak.com</a>) offers USA rail passes in 15-, 30-, and 45 day increments. Prices vary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The major interstates within New York State are I-78, I-84, I-87, I-90, and I-95. Parts of these interstates may have tolls.</p><p>In general, roads in New York State are safe, well-maintained and efficient.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Adirondack Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Experience America's largest wilderness reserve outside Alaska: the Adirondack Park (<a href="http://www.visitadirondacks.com" target="_blank">www.visitadirondacks.com</a>). Explore miles of sandy beaches and secluded swimming holes, and take to the lakes with a spot of windsurfing, boating and fishing. There are also nine ski areas and hundreds of trails for cross-country skiing and snowshoeing.</p>]]><p><b>Bethel Woodstock Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relive the days of the 1969 Woodstock Music and Arts Festival, the most famous rock concert in history, at the Bethel Woodstock Museum (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.bethelwoodscenter.org/Museum">www.bethelwoodscenter.org/Museum</a>) at Kauneonga Lake. Woodstock today is a haven of art and craft galleries and shops.</p>]]><p><b>Bronx Zoo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Learn about the world of nature at world-famous Bronx Zoo (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.bronxzoo.com/">www.bronxzoo.com</a>). Go for a stroll in the New York Botanical Garden (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nybg.org/">www.nybg.org</a>), which encompasses over 101 hectares (250 acres), 50 gardens and a landmark conservatory.</p>]]><p><b>Brooklyn Bridge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Walk across the Brooklyn Bridge, beautiful by night and bustling with people by day. Across the river, explore Brooklyn Heights by foot.</p>]]><p><b>Catskill Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover the beautiful Catskill Mountains (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.visitthecatskills.com/">www.visitthecatskills.com</a>). From the lush greenery of the southern Catskills to the dramatic, unspoiled peaks of the north, there is plenty to enjoy, whether seeking excitement or the perfect spot for a tranquil stay.</p>]]><p><b>Central Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rollerblade or jog through <strong>Central Park</strong> (website: <a target="_blank" href="http://www.centralparknyc.org/">www.centralparknyc.org</a>), New York's most famous park, created in 1856. John Lennon fans may pay their respects at <strong>Strawberry Fields</strong>. During summer, the park hosts afternoon and evening concerts.  &bull;&nbsp;</p>]]><p><b>Chinatown</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Manhattan's thriving Chinatown (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.explorechinatown.com/">www.explorechinatown.com</a>), which extends from Canal Street into Little Italy (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.littleitalynyc.com/">www.littleitalynyc.com</a>) and the Lower East Side. This labyrinth of narrow streets is crammed with Chinese stores and restaurants and home to over 100,000 residents.</p>]]><p><b>Coney Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Eat candyfloss at Coney Island (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.coneyisland.com/">www.coneyisland.com</a>), see freaks and wonders at the circus sideshow or walk along Brighton Beach (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.brightonbeach.com/">www.brightonbeach.com</a>), full of Russian shops and restaurants.</p>]]><p><b>Culinary Institute of America</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Have lunch at the Culinary Institute of America (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.ciachef.edu/">www.ciachef.edu</a>), one of the world's great cookery schools. Visitors can sample the cuisine at one of the restaurants on its campus, the American Bounty Restaurant, Ristorante Caterina de Medici or Escoffier Restaurant, as well as two cafes.</p>]]><p><b>Empire State Building</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ride a lift up to the observatory on the 86th floor of the Empire State Building (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.esbnyc.com/">www.esbnyc.com</a>), where you can see for approximately 80km (50 miles). When the 102-storey New York landmark was completed in 1931, it was the tallest building in the world.</p>]]><p><b>Erie Canal</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the five enormous locks of the Erie Canal on the Lockport Cave Tour (<a href="http://www.elockport.com" target="_blank">www.elockport.com</a>), which travels through a tunnel blasted out of rock in the 19th century, and ends in an underground boat ride.</p>]]><p><b>Financial District</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Walk through the Financial District, past Wall Street and the New York Stock Exchange.</p>]]><p><b>George Eastman</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Roll back the clock from the world of satellite images and digital photography to the day when George Eastman invented the Kodak camera and roll film in 1892. Visit his house in Rochester, and tour the International Museum of Photography (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.eastmanhouse.org/">www.eastmanhouse.org</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Greenwich Village</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the artsy and upmarket <strong>Greenwich Village</strong> (website: <a href="http://www.nycgv.com/" target="_blank">www.nycgv.com</a>) and SoHo (website: <a href="http://www.sohonyc.com/" target="_blank">www.sohonyc.com</a>), a melting pot for art, literature and music for decades, with plenty of galleries, cafes, boutiques and loft spaces.</p>]]><p><b>Hudson River Valley </b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the national heritage area of the Hudson River Valley (<a href="http://www.hudsonrivervalley.com" target="_blank">www.hudsonrivervalley.com</a>), originally inhabited by Native Americans, then settled by the Dutch. A retreat for the wealthy in the mid- to late-19th century, it is now popular year-round for outdoor activities.</p>]]><p><b>Hunter Mountain</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy the snow at Hunter Mountain (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.huntermtn.com/">www.huntermtn.com</a>) ski resort in the Catskills, known as 'the snowmaking capital of the world'. Over 50 trails on three mountains cater for everyone from beginners to experienced skiers.</p>]]><p><b>Lake Placid</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ski Lake Placid (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.lakeplacid.com/">www.lakeplacid.com</a>). Explore the winter playground by ski, snowmobile, snowshoe, dogsled or horse-drawn sleigh.</p>]]><p><b>Metropolitan Museum of Art</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the Metropolitan Museum of Art (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.metmuseum.org/">www.metmuseum.org</a>), one of the greatest museums in the world. Egyptian, Roman and Greek Art, along with Oriental paintings, modern art and ancient glass, feature in some of the museum's many collections.</p>]]><p><b>National Baseball Hall of Fame and Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the National Baseball Hall of Fame and Museum in Cooperstown (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.baseballhall.org/">www.baseballhall.org</a>). Also home of the Doubleday Field and numerous trading card and memorabilia shops, this vibrant village is situated on the shore of Otesgo Lake.</p>]]><p><b>New York City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Most visitors to the state will be heading here, to New York City. The fast-paced pulse of the city and its ever-changing landscape mean you'll need a lifetime to explore it all, but that's part of its beauty. Major tourist attractions are mainly located in Manhattan - the Empire State building, Central Park and Times Square are must-sees. Other essential visits include the Staten Island Ferry and the Statue of Liberty (the interior is closed for renovations until Dec 2012 but Ellis Island remains open). There are also plenty of quirky gems to be found in the artsy quarters of Greenwich Village, Chinatown on the Lower East side, and hipster hangout Brooklyn.</p>]]><p><b>New York State Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour Albany's New York State Museum (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nysm.nysed.gov/">www.nysm.nysed.gov</a>), the country's oldest and largest state museum, which portrays the urbanisation of New York City and has lifelike dioramas on Native Americans, gems and birds.</p>]]><p><b>Niagara Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sail into the spray of the mighty Niagara Falls (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.niagara-usa.com/">www.niagara-usa.com</a>) on the Maid of the Mist Boat Tour (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.maidofthemist.com/">www.maidofthemist.com</a>), and gaze in awe at one of the most outstanding spectacles on the North American continent.</p>]]><p><b>Rockefeller Center</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the Rockefeller Center (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.rockefellercenter.com/">www.rockefellercenter.com</a>), famous for its wintertime ice skating rink. Tour NBC Studios, or ride to the Top of the Rock observation deck for unobstructed views of the Brooklyn Bridge, the Chrysler Building and Central Park.</p>]]><p><b>Saratoga Spa State Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relax in style at Saratoga Spa State Park (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.saratogaspastatepark.org/">www.saratogaspastatepark.org</a>), with its 890 hectares (2,200 acres) of woodland, manicured lawns, Georgian architecture and mineral bathhouses. Float above the countryside on a sunrise or sunset hot-air balloon flight.</p>]]><p><b>Saratoga Springs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bet on the horses at Saratoga Springs (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.saratoga.com/">www.saratoga.com</a>), a leading spa and horseracing centre since the late 19th century. Take a walking tour down streets lined with regal Victorian mansions. See harness racing, summer polo matches or the country's most prestigious thoroughbred racing in late July and August.</p>]]><p><b>Staten Island Ferry</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take the Staten Island Ferry from Battery Park for a view of the classic New York skyline, and cruise past the Statue of Liberty and Ellis Island (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.statenislandusa.com/">www.statenislandusa.com</a>). The Verrazano-Narrows Bridge connects Staten Island with Brooklyn.</p>]]><p><b>Statue of Liberty</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ride to the observation platform atop the 46.5m- (151ft-) high Statue of Liberty (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/stli">www.nps.gov/stli</a>), in the middle of New York Harbour. See the Wall of Honor (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.wallofhonor.com/">www.wallofhonor.com</a>) on Ellis Island, commemorating over 600,000 immigrants to the United States.</p>]]><p><b>The Hamptons</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to the<strong> </strong>Hamptons (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.hamptons.com/">www.hamptons.com</a>) for a mix of culture, restaurants, historic sites, nightlife, shops and recreational activities. Visit the seaside resort of Montauk, with its lighthouse, wildlife and ocean beaches.</p>]]><p><b>Times Square</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy the now 'family-friendly' Times Square (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.timessquarenyc.org/">www.timessquarenyc.org</a>), with the renovated Biltmore Theater, and the world's largest toy store, with a 18m (60ft) Ferris wheel and life-size <em>Barbie</em> house.</p>]]><p><b>Westchester County</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy boating, sailing and watersports in Westchester County (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.thewestchesterway.com/">www.thewestchesterway.com</a>), bordered by the Hudson River and Long Island Sound. Play golf on any of the 40 private and public golf courses, and shop in exclusive boutiques or discount malls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>New York is packed with thousands of restaurants serving food from around the world. The cultural mix has brought every kind of ethnic food to New York City and the surrounding region. Also, the state is increasingly acknowledging its agricultural roots, and farms around New York supply residents with fresh, local food, often sold at community-based farmers' markets. Reservations are highly recommended at most restaurants and reservations should even be made for lunch when planning to dine at an upscale restaurant or popular establishment. Restaurants without the expensive and difficult-to-acquire beer, wine, or liquor license granted by the state may allow customers to bring their own bottle; in such cases, a corkage fee may be imposed.</p>
<p>New York delis and diners are known the world over, and remain popular lunch spots for New Yorkers on the go as well as visitors to the city. Delis offering massive sandwiches and seemingly endless hot and cold bars are prevalent throughout the city.</p>
<p>New York City street vendors have long been popular among food lovers who seek more casual fare, but such vendors are seeing increasing competition from food trucks, which have become a visible phenomenon in the city. Selling everything from Chinese-style dumplings and Mexican tacos to Dutch waffles and American cupcakes and coffee, these trucks are wildly popular among locals and visitors alike.</p>
<p>The city's desserts and pastries are also world-famous, and there is no shortage of bakeries. Traditional favourites are rugelach and black-and-white cookies, as well as New York cheesecake &ndash; and a certain popular romantic comedy featuring Sarah Jessica Parker has made a particular Greenwich Village bakery's cupcakes so famous that a line forms outside its doors nearly every day.</p>
<p>More and more visitors are venturing beyond the borough of Manhattan to try the cuisine of New York City&rsquo;s ethnic neighbourhoods, such as Flushing, Queens' Chinatown. <br />
<br />
Outside the city, the food scene is no less exciting. Farm-to-table fare is typical, and is exemplified at popular places such as Blue Hill at Stone Barns, a restaurant on a working farm in the Hudson Valley. It's &ldquo;Farmer's Feast&rdquo; tasting menus are created anew each day based on the current harvest. Blue Hill at Stone Barns is a newer iteration of the kind of place New Yorkers have loved for decades. The much-beloved, much older restaurant Moosewood in Ithaca, also famous for its series of cookbooks, is known for its natural foods menu and its co-op oriented business model.</p>
<p>Another New York State food institution is Buffalo wings, which originated in Buffalo, New York. The classic wings now appear on menus across the USA and beyond, and are reported to have been dreamed up by the owner of the Anchor Bar (<a href="http://www.anchorbar.com" target="_blank">www.anchorbar.com</a>), who needed a quick snack to feed her college-aged son and his friends.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Wine. <br />
&bull; Steaks. <br />
&bull; Seafood. <br />
&bull; Waldorf salad.<br />
&bull; Bagels.<br />
&bull; Deli-style sandwiches.<br />
&bull; New York cheesecake.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Restaurant hours tend not to be as late outside of the city. </p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A 15-20% tip is customary for good service in restaurants around the state. In many restaurants, particularly in New York City, a gratuity will automatically be added to bills for parties of 4-6 or more. Be sure to check with your server about the policies of the restaurant where you are dining before leaving an additional tip.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>21.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nightlife in New York State isn't solely limited to New York City, however this pulsating city certainly lives up to its international reputation as the city that never sleeps. From theatre and film, to comedy and dance clubs, to jazz, blues and rock, there are nocturnal activities to suit all tastes and budgets. Some of the world's most respected and iconic performance venues are here, among them Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts and Carnegie Hall.  </p>
<p>If you're on a budget, don't worry; there are plenty of things for you to do. Half-price tickets for Broadway and off-Broadway performances are available on the day of the show from the TKTS booths in Times Square, South Street Seaport and downtown Brooklyn. During the summer, most of New York City parks put on free outdoor movies and concerts, and many cultural institutions have free or low-cost outdoor fairs and performances bringing some of the world's best talent to the city's stages.  </p>
<p>Outside of New York City, nightlife may seem a bit tamer... unless you're in Buffalo, where last call is at 0400. The Chippewa Entertainment District, known locally as &ldquo;The Chip Strip,&rdquo; is lined with bars, dance clubs and live music venues, and restaurants, and home to the only mechanical buffalo &ndash;which you can ride, of course &ndash; in the US.  College towns and resort areas also tend to be nightlife hubs, though their offerings can vary considerably depending on the time of year. In The Hamptons, find nightlife options abound, from clubs like the Pink Elephant and the White House to the bars of trendy boutique hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fifth Avenue, New York City's most glamorous thoroughfare, is filled with luxury shops and department stores. No trip to New York is complete without stopping by Bloomingdale's (1000 Third Avenue at 59th Street), Lord and Taylor (Fifth Avenue at 38th Street) and Saks Fifth Avenue (611 Fifth Avenue at 50th Street). Don't forget Macy's, known as the world's largest store, 131 West 34th Street at Herald Square, or the chance to buy a special piece of jewellery at Tiffany's (727 Fifth Avenue at 57th Street).</p>
<p>For shopping that&rsquo;s more affordable and just as fun, head to Chinatown. Canal Street, which runs through parts of Chinatown, is known for its imitation goods such as luxury perfumes and purses. Touts whispering &ldquo;Prada, Prada, Gucci, Gucci, Coach?&rdquo; as you walk down the pavement are eager to show - and sell - their wares. Street fairs are great places to buy creative and fun gifts; in the city, these are held most weekends during summer months. SoHo, Greenwich Village, and Tribeca - all Manhattan neighbourhoods - are known for their funky boutiques.</p>
<p>Woodbury Common, located in Long Island, just one hour's drive from Manhattan, is the largest discount designer outlet in the world. Long Island offers a variety of ever-increasing shopping opportunities - from indoor shopping malls such as Roosevelt Field in Garden City, the East Coast's largest shopping centre, to quaint visitor-oriented shopping villages on historic main streets in places like Huntington, Sea Cliff, Stony Brook and Syosset. Manhattan Mall in Midtown Manhattan has an eight-floor mall with 60 shops.</p>
<p>Many of New York State's smaller towns have independently owned shops and galleries selling locally made goods. The Gaffer District, a neighbourhood in the city of Corning, located in the Finger Lakes Region, is known for its glasswork, which you can buy directly from artists at work in their hot glass studios. These make lovely gifts and souvenirs. Locally made wine and honey are also popular purchases. New York is also known for handcrafts harking back to the Arts &amp; Crafts Movement of the early 1800s, and its Adirondack chairs, a staple on the porch of resorts in the state.</p><p>Shopping hours vary according to the type of shop and town or city. In some of the resort towns, shopping hours also vary by season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a vast range of accommodation in New York running across the spectrum, from luxurious five-star hotels to youth hostels and camping sites. New York City has thousands of hotels and apartments to choose from, whilst out of the city there are plenty of lodges, chain hotels, motels and bed and breakfasts to choose from. Be sure to book far in advance if you plan to visit during the busy seasons, which is summer for Long Island and most of the state beyond New York City, and holidays for New York City. Prices for hotel and motel rooms tend to be higher during busy season and rooms book up quickly.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Though there are a few bed and breakfast accommodations in New York City, this is a particularly popular form of lodging in the other regions of the state, especially in the Hudson Valley.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a vast range of accommodation in New York running across the spectrum, from luxurious five-star hotels to youth hostels and camping sites. New York City has thousands of hotels and apartments to choose from, whilst out of the city there are plenty of lodges, chain hotels, motels and bed and breakfasts to choose from. Be sure to book far in advance if you plan to visit during the busy seasons, which is summer for Long Island and most of the state beyond New York City, and holidays for New York City. Prices for hotel and motel rooms tend to be higher during busy season and rooms book up quickly.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a vast range of accommodation in New York running across the spectrum, from luxurious five-star hotels to youth hostels and camping sites. New York City has thousands of hotels and apartments to choose from, whilst out of the city there are plenty of lodges, chain hotels, motels and bed and breakfasts to choose from. Be sure to book far in advance if you plan to visit during the busy seasons, which is summer for Long Island and most of the state beyond New York City, and holidays for New York City. Prices for hotel and motel rooms tend to be higher during busy season and rooms book up quickly.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[40.714353]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-74.005973]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>140,059 sq km (54,077 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>19.8 million (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>141.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Albany.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New York State may not be among the largest states in the US, but it is geographically diverse, with mountains, forests, valleys, lakes, and oceans creating diverse landscapes and microclimates. Though many visitors' perceptions of New York may be of a bustling, vibrant hyper-urban tableau, the majority of the state is actually quite pastoral, and both residents and politicians tend to support land preservation initiatives.</p>
<p>New York State borders six other states, one country (Canada), and two of the nation's Great Lakes, as well as the Atlantic Ocean. Recently, concerns have arisen about modern geological activity, especially seismic activity. A 2011 earthquake felt in New York caused residents to become more interested in learning about the state's fault lines, and concerns about climate change have precipitated conversations about flood zones and long-term infrastructure planning, especially in New York City.</p>
<p>The state features several mountain ranges, including the Catskills and the Adirondacks, whose geographical attributes are largely responsible for attracting so many visitors who love the outdoors.</p>
<p>Though rivers are an important feature of the state's geography, particularly in New York, which is hemmed in by the Hudson River on its west side and the East River on its east side, the state is perhaps even better known for its lakes, the number of which have given rise to the name of an entire region: the Thousand Lakes. Of course, there is also the Atlantic Ocean, which is certainly one of the main attractions for visitors to Long Island.</p>
<p>The area now known as New York state was once glacial, which is why modern visitors can enjoy Niagara Falls, the result of glacial melt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Catholics represent 40% of New York's population, while 30% of New Yorkers identify as Protestant. Smaller Jewish and Muslim minorities comprise 8.5 and 3.5% of the population, respectively. Approximately 13% of New Yorkers say they have no religious affiliation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While visitors' perceptions of New York State may be that of a liberal state, keep in mind that that perception is shaped primarily by and about <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York City</a>. It is often forgotten that there is more to New York State than the New York metropolitan area, where because of their heavy accents and fast-paced lifestyle downstate New Yorkers are prone to being stereotyped as abrasive, loud and snobbish. </p>
<p>Though they are not an insignificant part of the state's population (indeed, they number more than 8 million of the state's 19.5 million residents), they are also not representative of the larger norm. Practices, behaviours, and forms of dress and speech that are perfectly acceptable in New York City may be considered inappropriate in other parts of the state. </p>
<p>Outside of New York City, it is generally considered impolite to discuss  religious or political beliefs among acquaintances. People meeting for  the first time typically shake hands rather than kiss or embrace. Outside of the city New Yorkers are known for their friendliness. </p>
<p>From downstate to upstate, New   <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/york">York</a> has a very diverse population. Because of the myriad cultures and religions New   York possesses an eclectic mix of social conventions, but while cultural diversity <em>is</em> visible in other parts of the state, it is not as evident as in New York City. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New York has a fascinating history, not least because it was once the capital of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>. Before that, however, Native American tribes called the region home. The area was colonised early on, when Henry Hudson claimed New York for the Dutch in 1609. In 1624 the Dutch established lower New York State as New Netherlands. They traded actively with the Native Americans throughout the 17th  century and ruled the colony, then called &ldquo;New Netherland&rdquo; until 1664,  when it was conquered by the British who then took over the area and named it New York after the Duke of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/york">York</a>.&nbsp; Just over a century later, in 1776, New York declared its independence, making it one of the original 13 states of the union.&nbsp;</p>
<p>New York has played a central role in much of the nation's history. It was the site of the first major battle of the Revolutionary War and at least one-third of that war's battles were fought here. It was the birthplace or home of many of the fathers of the new nation; it was a centre for debate and activism related to the abolition and suffrage movements; and it was the primary port of call for immigrants arriving to the US in the 19th century and beyond.</p>
<p>New York is often associated with the Statue of Liberty, which was gifted from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> to the USA and erected in the New York Harbour in 1886. During this time millions of European immigrants entered New   York&rsquo;s waters and the statue became an American symbol of freedom. In this age of immigration, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York City</a> in particular became a multicultural hub and the standout example of the US's &ldquo;melting pot&rdquo; demographics.</p>
<p>New York City has also been significant in global history. Many trends &ndash;political, financial, and cultural &ndash; are born in New York, and its position as a world centre of commerce remains unshaken by the horrific 2001 terrorist attacks on the World Trade Center which killed nearly 3,000. Today, construction of the Freedom Tower, a memorial to victims of the attack, is underway.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Buzzing NYC is one of the highlights of New York State, but beyond this mega city lie fine beaches, forested mountains, pretty towns and bountiful historical attractions.</p>
<p>A short hop east from Manhattan, Long Island is a popular weekend escape for sweltering New York City dwellers. You can join the likes of J-Lo and Steven Spielberg by snagging yourself a posh summer home in the Hamptons or, more realistically, pitch a tent amongst windswept ocean dunes.</p>
<p>Flowing through the Hudson Valley north of NYC is the scenic Hudson River, which inspired a mid-19th century art movement. Today many artistic communities remain, perched atop dramatic cliffs overlooking the river.</p>
<p>Further north are the Catskill and Adirondack mountain ranges, a magnet for adrenaline junkies, who come to hike, bike, camp, fish and ski. Nearby Adirondack Park is the largest publicly protected area in the USA, and teems with boreal forests, rocky peaks and pristine waterways. It's absolutely stunning, particularly in autumn.</p>
<p>To the west, the Finger Lakes region boasts lakes, woodlands and campsites aplenty. Not to mention the historic Erie Canal, Lake Ontario and more than 1,000 waterfalls. This is the state&rsquo;s prime wine-producing region, with ample opportunities to imbibe at local vineyards. Nearby Chautauqua-Allegheny offer more outdoor activities, plus the opportunity to visit Amish communities, Native American reservations and wineries.</p>
<p>Albany, the state capital, lies in the picturesque Capital-Saratoga region, famous for Saratoga Springs, a historic spa town. Thousand Islands lives up to its name with some 2,000 islets scattered across Lake Erie, Lake Ontario and other iconic waterways. But the jewel in New York State&rsquo;s crown is the thundering Niagara Falls, a 12,000-year-old natural wonder that is awesome in every sense of the word.</p><p>Buzzing NYC is one of the highlights of New York State, but beyond this mega city lie fine beaches, forested mountains, pretty towns and bountiful historical attractions.&nbsp;But the jewel in New York State&rsquo;s crown is the thundering Niagara Falls, a 12,000-year-old natural wonder that is awesome in every sense of the word.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
