<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Guernsey" ColCode="gue" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="cg" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Guernsey]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guernsey enjoys a temperate oceanic climate categorised by long, dry summers and mild winters.</p>
<p>Spring (March to May) starts off cool but by May, temperatures reach an average of high of 14&deg;C (57&deg;F) and an average low of 9&deg;C (48&deg;F), a good time for hikers to savour the uncrowded landscapes.</p>
<p>Summer (June to August) is peak season and rainfall at its lowest. 19&deg;C (66&deg;F) is the average high in July and August, and with the sea temperatures ranging from 16&deg;C (61&deg;F) to 19&deg;C (66&deg;F) in August, this is the perfect time to go for a swim in the ocean.</p>
<p>Autumn (September to November) is the best time to visit for budget-conscious travellers as prices are lower and the weather is still warm. Every October, the island hosts the Tennerfest where foodies feast on a three-course meal for &pound;10 to &pound;20 per person.</p>
<p>Winter (December to February) is never that cold but can be grey and rainy. February is considered the coldest month with an average high of 7&deg;C (45&deg;F) and an average low of 4&deg;C (39&deg;F), still relatively warm considered by many.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normal beach and holiday wear for summer, with a jacket or a sweater for the evenings. Rainwear are advised from November to March.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no internal flights in Guernsey.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is possible to charter a yacht or motor boat to sail around the island.  There are also numerous sailing clubs. Ferries zip from Guernsey to other nearby islands, including Sark, Herm and Alderney.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving in Guernsey is practical and easy. The island is 19km (12 miles) long with an area of 62 sq km (38 sq miles), making it easily covered by car.</p>l<p>Roads are of high quality, well tarmacked and signposted throughout the island.</p><p>A full national driving licence is required.</p><p>As in the rest of the British Isles, driving is on the left on Guernsey's quiet roads, which meander around the island. Most roads impose a 40kph (25mph) limit, though the maximum speed is 56kpg (35mpg). You must be 20 years of age or older to hire a car.</p>

<p>Parking is free, although you must pay attention to Disc Parking Zones which indicate the length of time you can park in that zone. Once you exceed the allocated hours, fines are levied. You're required to purchase a parking disc (£2.75) that allows you to set the time when you park. You can purchase the parking disc from Driver & Vehicle Licensing Bulwer Avenue Office, the Information Centre, the Police Station, and a number of retail outlets and petrol stations.</p>

<p>At certain intersections, you will see 'filter-in-turn' which means you can proceed with caution if there is no traffic, but when other cars are present, you will need to stop and the first car arrives will go first.</p><p>There are a number of car hire companies available in Guernsey offering good rates which are around £20 to £25 per day for a small sedan. Some companies offer unlimited mileage allowance while some operate on a full-to-full basis.</p><p>Bicycle hire is available from various companies for daily or weekly hire.</p><p>As in the rest of the British Isles, driving is on the left on Guernsey's quiet roads, which meander around the island. Most roads impose a 40kph (25mph) limit, though the maximum speed is 56kpg (35mpg). You must be 20 years of age or older to hire a car.</p>

<p>Parking is free, although you must pay attention to Disc Parking Zones which indicate the length of time you can park in that zone. Once you exceed the allocated hours, fines are levied. You're required to purchase a parking disc (£2.75) that allows you to set the time when you park. You can purchase the parking disc from Driver & Vehicle Licensing Bulwer Avenue Office, the Information Centre, the Police Station, and a number of retail outlets and petrol stations.</p>

<p>At certain intersections, you will see 'filter-in-turn' which means you can proceed with caution if there is no traffic, but when other cars are present, you will need to stop and the first car arrives will go first.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Buses travel all over the island, check <a href="http://www.buses.gg" target="_blank">www.buses.gg</a> for routes and information. Taxis are available from all the towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Guernsey</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">sark_island</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Guernsey</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">jersey</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Guernsey</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">herm_island</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Guernsey</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">alderney</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main airline serving Guernsey is Aurigny  (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.aurigny.com">www.aurigny.com</a>) which flies direct from a number of UK destinations including Birmingham, Bristol, Exeter, East Midlands, Leeds-Bradford, Manchester, Norwich, London City, London Gatwick and London Stansted. Aurigny also serves the route between Guernsey and Dinard and Grenoble in France.</p>
<p>Flybe (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.flybe.com/">www.flybe.com</a>) also flies to Guernsey from the UK (Cardiff, Exeter and Southampton) and from Düsseldorf in Germany.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London to Guernsey is 1 hour.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Guernsey Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.guernsey-airport.gov.gg<p>The airport  is 6km (4 miles) from St Peter Port.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guernsey is accessible via ferry from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england">England</a> and France and the other <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/channel-islands">Channel Islands</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Landline phones are commonplace and most hotels will have phone facilities for guest use. Public telephone boxes can be found on Guernsey although their number is dwindling. They are painted blue, rather than the red found on the UK mainland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone companies and phone coverage is good overall. Those visiting from the UK should be aware that data roaming charges may apply in Guernsey, depending on what tariff you are on.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public access is available at internet cafés and in libraries. Most hotels offer Wi-Fi in rooms and public areas, although some may charge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British media are free and able to report on all subjects. The variety of publications reflects the full spectrum of political opinion. The local newspapers is&nbsp;<i>The Guernsey Press and Star.</i>&nbsp;All the main British newspapers are available in Guernsey on the day of publication.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guernsey Post is the postal service for the island. Only Guernsey stamps will be accepted on outgoing mail. Post is delivered during the week but not on weekends. In St Peter Port the main post office is situated on Smith Street. Post boxes are painted blue.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1700; Sat 0830-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Castle Cornet</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Overlooking the harbour in St Peter Port stands Castle Cornet. Built between 1206 and 1256 following the division of the Duchy of Normandy, it bears influences from many eras, through to the German occupation of WWII. It houses five museums – The Story of Castle Cornet Museum, 201 Squadron (RAF) Museum, Maritime Museum, Royal Guernsey Light Infantry Museum and Royal Guernsey Militia Museum. From March to November, there is a daily cannon fire at noon and from April to September, the castle also hosts outdoor theatre performances.</p>]]><p><b>Castle spotting</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fortifications are scattered all around the coast - among them Ivy Castle near Le Bouet, a Norman stronghold, and Vale Castle at St Sampson. On the West Coast lies Fortress Rousse, an 18th-century tower open to the public.</p>]]><p><b>Cliff-top walks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Out of the 42 miles of cliff and coastal paths on the island, many hikers prefer the south coast cliff walks starting from La Vallette and finishing at Pleinmont. The 270 descending steps leading to the secluded Petit Port, and the 300 ascending steps to the Saints Bay headland are definite highlights. Every May and September, the island also hosts walking festivals with accredited guides leading many walks.</p>]]><p><b>Diving</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Diving and snorkelling excursions and courses are popular with families and professional divers alike. Divers can enjoy a variety of marine life on the reefs, while seasoned divers can explore one of the many wrecks littered around Guernsey's coast.</p>]]><p><b>Experience German occupation</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are four museums on the island covering the dark history during Germany's WWII occupation of the Channel Islands – the German Underground Hospital at La Vassalerie, the German Occupation Museum at Forest (with a reconstruction of an occupied street), the La Vallette Underground Military Museum at La Vallette, and the German Naval Signal Museum at St Jacques.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are 27 beaches on the island to suit everyone. Vazon Bay on the north is the largest and an excellent surfing beach. L'Eree Bay on the west boasts a wide crescent beach of glorious soft white sand. The east-facing Fermain Bay is another beautiful spot for swimmers and sunbathers.</p>]]><p><b>Lithou Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Accessible to walkers only for a couple of hours at low tide, this island is home to flocks of seabirds. Clamber down rocks to Venus Pool, a deep and sheltered rock pool that is sensational and great for a swim.</p>]]><p><b>Little Chapel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Little Chapel at Les Vauxbelets is thought to be the smallest church in the world, with space for a priest and a congregation of five. The exterior and interior walls are entirely bedecked in colourful fragments of crockery, making this a charmingly quirky spot in Guernsey.</p>]]><p><b>Prehistoric Guernsey</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dolmens (Neolithic tombs) are common on the island. Déhus Dolmen in Vale is the best-kept Dolmen in Guernsey with a bearded figure carrying a bow and arrow. Le Trépied, on a mound overlooking Perelle Bay, was reputedly once a witches' meeting place.</p>]]><p><b>Roquaine Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A shingle beach, Rocquaine Bay has a small harbour and is the venue of Rocquaine Regatta, a popular summer event featuring a day of activities including raft races. At one end of the bay stands Fort Grey, a tower built in 1804 to defend the west coast. Affectionately nicknamed 'Cup and Saucer', Fort Grey now houses the Shipwreck Museum.</p>]]><p><b>Sausmarez Manor</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a peek into this historic Sausmarez Manor in St Martin. From May to October, there is a ghost tour on some Thursday evenings plus a farmer's market on every Saturday morning with a few stands selling fresh and local produce. Within the compound, there is also a sub-tropical garden displaying beautiful sculptures.</p>]]><p><b>St Peter Port</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The island's charming capital St Peter Port has cobbled streets spreading out from its picturesque marina leading visitors to a plethora of attractions including the Guernsey Tapestry at the Gallery in St James Concert Hall and Hauteville House, former home of French writer Victor Hugo. On the south side stands Castle Cornet, an 800-year old castle which now houses five museums. A little further south from there you will find three Victorian bathing pools, the La Vallette Underground Military Museum and the Guernsey Aquarium.</p>]]><p><b>Surfing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Catch the breaks off the coast of Guernsey, with many locals agree that Vazon Bay, with six surfing spots depending on the swell and wind conditions, is the best area for beginners and seasoned surfers.</p>]]><p><b>Victor Hugo's House (Closed in 2018)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pay your respects to Victor Hugo at Hauteville House, above the south side of St Peter Port, where he once lived. It was here that he wrote <i>The Toilers of the Sea</i> (which is set in St Sampson). In 1914, the French government gifted Guernsey a statue of Victor Hugo which now stands in Candie Gardens.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>£2.8 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Cut flowers, ferns, tomatoes, sweet peppers and other vegetables.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Coal, petrol, oil, machinery and equipment.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>UK, France.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Finance, tourism and light industry are the main components of Guernsey's economy. With laws favouring light tax and low death duties, the island is a well-developed offshore financial centre with about two dozen banks operating on the island, providing services such as fiduciary, insurance, fund and trust management.<br />
<br />
Flowers and tomatoes, once the main horticultural exports, are in decline. Tourism is still important and providing stable employment for the people of Guernsey.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businesspeople are generally expected to dress smartly, with a suit and tie for men. Appointments should be made and business cards are customary. Business is conducted primarily in English although French can also be spoken if all parties are fluent.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Guernsey Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (01481) 727 483
					Website:http://www.guernseychamber.com
					Address: 16 Glategny Esplanade,Suite 3,St Peter Port,GY1 1WN]]><b>Meet Guernsey</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (01481) 726 270
					Website:http://www.conferenceguernsey.com/
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Guernsey is famous for its food and the island has a wide variety of restaurants ranging from traditional French and English cuisine to Italian, Indian and Chinese. St Peter Port is the major culinary hub, with clusters of restaurants on the seafront and high street.</p>
<p>Every October, the Channel Islands (including Guernsey) host the Tennerfest. In Guernsey, about 80% of its restaurants participate in this island-wide event, offering a three-course meal for £10 to £20 per person. Diners can feast on fresh seafood to local delights such as Bean Jar and artisan cheeses.</p>
<p>Local breweries include Randalls and White Rock. Established in 1868, Randalls is behind the award-winning Breda pale lager, while White Rock, believing in classic styles and modern variations, produces great quality brew from hoppy IPA to smooth and aromatic stout. If you like cider, make a beeline for the Rocquette Cider Company.</p>

Ormers, a type of shellfish also known as abalones, were once in plentiful supply but nowadays during the ormering season between January and April, those who brave the cold waters may only gather a dozen or so. The traditional way is to make ormer casserole.]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull;	Rose veal<br />
&bull;	Spider crab (traditionally sold with bread and butter)<br />
&bull;	Ormer casserole (a fruit cake)<br />
&bull;	Bean jar (pork and bean stew)<br />
&bull;	Guernsey ice cream<br />
&bull;    Guernsey Gâche (a fruit bread)</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Table service is normal in restaurants, with counter service in bars. Eating out is also excellent value for money as there is no VAT. Pubs in Guernsey are now able to stay open until 0045 six nights a week.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10 to 12% is normal, except where a service charge is included.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guernsey after dark is a low-key affair. Several swanky cocktail bars can be found around St Peter Port and within luxury hotels scattered around the island. There are also local pubs serving Guernsey beer (Randalls and White Rock Brewery) and Rocquette cider. For clubbing fans, Fusion Nightclub and Barbados Beach Club, both are located at The Pollet, are popular spots.</p>
<p>Outside St Peter Port, evening entertainment is provided by some hotels during the summer season, while other options include local pubs where you could try a pint of local Randalls beer or Guernsey cider. Another option is picking up some tasty fish and chips at Cobo Bay and taking a walk along the beach at sunset, a favourite with the locals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As the capital of the island, St Peter's Port is the place to head for those wanting to hit the shops. The high street has the usual chain stores, but there are plenty of charming independents selling products and goods unique to the island. Foodies might like to stock up on award-winning cheeses such as smoked cheddar from Meadow Court Farm, or the unique Fort Grey made by an islander. Creamy Guernsey fudge made from the milk of the local cows is sticky and sweet, and found in many shops. Guernsey cream is another favourite  gift. Another favourite is g&acirc;che, a type of bread made with raisins and mixed peel. </p>
<p>There is no VAT (Value Added Tax) on the island and prices of luxury goods tend to be cheaper than in the UK. Favourite gifts include local pottery, knitted sweaters (particularly the famous Guernsey jumper), crafts, gold and silver jewellery and candles.</p>
<p>Outside of St Peters Port, "hedge veg" refers to the unique local practice of buying fresh produce and daily catch from unmanned roadside stands and leaving payment in a box.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1730. <br />Only a small number of shops open on Sundays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guernsey has a great selection of hotels available with a large number congregates around St Peter Port. The classically decorated Old Government House Hotel and Spa (<a href="http://www.theoghhotel.com/" target="_blank">www.theoghhotel.com</a>) is the only five star on the island, while the Fermain Valley Hotel (<a href="http://www.fermainvalley.com/" target="_blank">www.fermainvalley.com</a>) is another favourite in the higher-end hotel category.</p>
<p>Hikers tend to prefer hotels that are next to the coastal paths, such hotels include the Peninsula Hotel (<a href="http://www.peninsulahotelguernsey.com/" target="_blank">www.peninsulahotelguernsey.com</a>) which is near to the Rousse Tower, Cobo Bay Hotel (<a href="http://www.cobobayhotel.com/" target="_blank">www.cobobayhotel.com</a>) in between Saline and Cobo, and Hotel Jerbourg (<a href="http://hoteljerbourg.com/" target="_blank">hoteljerbourg.com</a>) on the south. Advance booking is advisable during the summer period when demand is at a peak.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong>The Guernsey government has a scheme for the compulsory inspection and grading of hotels to ensure standards of accommodation are maintained and improved. All hotels are graded from 1 to 5 stars according to the facilities offered.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are normally family-run establishments, providing a good standard of accommodation in a homely atmosphere. This can be based on full-board, half-board or bed &amp; breakfast, according to the visitor's requirements. A number of these have residential liquor licences. All are graded from 1 to 5 diamonds according to services and comfort.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guernsey has a great selection of hotels available with a large number congregates around St Peter Port. The classically decorated Old Government House Hotel and Spa (<a href="http://www.theoghhotel.com/" target="_blank">www.theoghhotel.com</a>) is the only five star on the island, while the Fermain Valley Hotel (<a href="http://www.fermainvalley.com/" target="_blank">www.fermainvalley.com</a>) is another favourite in the higher-end hotel category.</p>
<p>Hikers tend to prefer hotels that are next to the coastal paths, such hotels include the Peninsula Hotel (<a href="http://www.peninsulahotelguernsey.com/" target="_blank">www.peninsulahotelguernsey.com</a>) which is near to the Rousse Tower, Cobo Bay Hotel (<a href="http://www.cobobayhotel.com/" target="_blank">www.cobobayhotel.com</a>) in between Saline and Cobo, and Hotel Jerbourg (<a href="http://hoteljerbourg.com/" target="_blank">hoteljerbourg.com</a>) on the south. Advance booking is advisable during the summer period when demand is at a peak.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong>The Guernsey government has a scheme for the compulsory inspection and grading of hotels to ensure standards of accommodation are maintained and improved. All hotels are graded from 1 to 5 stars according to the facilities offered.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guernsey has a great selection of hotels available with a large number congregates around St Peter Port. The classically decorated Old Government House Hotel and Spa (<a href="http://www.theoghhotel.com/" target="_blank">www.theoghhotel.com</a>) is the only five star on the island, while the Fermain Valley Hotel (<a href="http://www.fermainvalley.com/" target="_blank">www.fermainvalley.com</a>) is another favourite in the higher-end hotel category.</p>
<p>Hikers tend to prefer hotels that are next to the coastal paths, such hotels include the Peninsula Hotel (<a href="http://www.peninsulahotelguernsey.com/" target="_blank">www.peninsulahotelguernsey.com</a>) which is near to the Rousse Tower, Cobo Bay Hotel (<a href="http://www.cobobayhotel.com/" target="_blank">www.cobobayhotel.com</a>) in between Saline and Cobo, and Hotel Jerbourg (<a href="http://hoteljerbourg.com/" target="_blank">hoteljerbourg.com</a>) on the south. Advance booking is advisable during the summer period when demand is at a peak.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong>The Guernsey government has a scheme for the compulsory inspection and grading of hotels to ensure standards of accommodation are maintained and improved. All hotels are graded from 1 to 5 stars according to the facilities offered.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are generally observed the next working day.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Early May Bank Holiday :
							07 May </p><p>Liberation Day :
							09 May </p><p>Spring Bank Holiday :
							28 May </p><p>Summer Bank Holiday :
							27 August </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Channel Islands are not part of the UK or the EU and are subject to different allowances. To complicate matters further there are duty free differences between the Bailiwick of Jersey and the Bailiwick of Guernsey (which includes the islands of Alderney, Sark, Herm, Jethou and Lihou).</p><p>The following goods may be imported into the Bailiwick of Jersey by travellers over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p><p>• 200 cigarettes or 250g of other tobacco products.<br/>• 1L of spirits.<br/>• 4L of wine.<br/>• 16L of beer or cider.<br/>• Other goods to a value of £390 (reduced to £270 if arriving by private plane or boat).</p><p>Alternatively, you may import more wine or beer if you don't bring in any spirits or tobacco. In this case, you may import:</p><p>• 36L of table wine or 48 x 750ml bottles of wine or 110L of beer.</p><p>The following goods may be imported into Bailiwick of Guernsey by travellers over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p><p>• 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br/>• 4L of still table wine.<br/>• 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of fortified wine/sparkling wine/liqueurs or an additional 4L of still table wine if no spirits, liqueurs, fortified and sparkling wines.<br/>• 50L of beer of cider.<br/>• An unlimited value of other goods (if coming from within the EU) or goods to the value of £390 (if coming from a non-EU country; reduced to  £270 if arriving by private plane or boat).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted goods include unlicensed drugs, offensive weapons, obscene or pornographic material, and counterfeit goods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Channel Islands have their own notes – the Guernsey pound and the Jersey pound, both of which are at par with the UK pound. Pound Sterling (JEP; symbol £) = 100 pence. Notes are in denominations of £50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of £2, £1, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 pence.<br/><br/>Channel Islands notes and coins are not accepted in the UK, although they can be reconverted at parity in UK banks. Sark, Herm and Alderney use the Guernsey pound.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies can be exchanged at bureaux de change, in banks and at many hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are all widely accepted.</p><p>On the main islands of Jersey and Guernsey ATMs are widespread and accessible, while on Alderney there are two ATMs. There are no cash machines on Sark or Herm.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers cheques are not commonly used nowadays, although larger establishments may still accept them. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0930-1530. Some banks are open later on weekdays and Saturday mornings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[49.528046]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-2.406037]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>62 sq km (38 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>66,500 (2017).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>965 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>St Peter Port.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Self-governing dependency of the British Crown.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guernsey is situated in the Gulf of St Malo, 50km (30 miles) from the coast of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> and 130km (80 miles) from the south coast of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england">England</a>. The cliffs on the south coast rise to 80m (270ft), from which the land slopes away gradually to the north. Guernsey is an ideal centre for excursions to the other <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/channel-islands">Channel Islands</a> and France. The islands of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/channel-islands/alderney">Alderney</a>, Brecqhou, Herm, Jethou, Lihou and Sark are dependencies of Guernsey.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Church of England, Presbyterian, Baptist, Congregational and Methodist.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is the customary form of greeting and normal social courtesies should be observed when visiting someone's home. It is not usual to start eating until everyone is served. If invited to someone's home, a small present such as flowers or chocolates is appreciated. Casual wear is acceptable in most places. Smoking is banned in enclosed public places.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with three square pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gavin St Pier is the President of Guernsey states.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Lieutenant Governor Ian Corder since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guernsey has some 1500 years of recorded history having been settled by Britons migrating to Brittany in the 5th century. Part of the medieval Duchy of Normandy, it became inextricably linked to Britain when William the Conqueror gained the crown in 1066. Later in 1204, when King John lost Normandy to France, Guernsey, along with other Channel Islands, remained loyal to the English monarchy.</p> 
<p>Although occupied by Capetian French and by Aragonese mercenaries during the Hundred Years War, it remained in British hands until the German invasion during WWII. Many of the island's children were evacuated to mainland England, thus avoiding the harsh conditions under which those that remained had to live. The best-selling novel, The Guernsey Literary and Potato Peel Pie Society, which peels back the curtain on life in Nazi-occupied Guernsey, remains in print. A film adaptation is now a blockbuster.</p>
<p>Liberated in 1945, the Bailiwick of Guernsey, which includes the islands of Alderney and Sark, both of which have their own parliament, and the smaller islands of Herm, Jethou and Lihou, enjoys a large degree of self-government, with its own legal and political institutions.</p>
<p>Guernsey is a British Crown dependency but it is not part of the United Kingdom. It is also not part of the European Union.</p> 
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	French author Victor Hugo lived on Guernsey for 15 years and the French Consulate is based at his former home, Hauteville House.<br />
&bull;	Guernsey&rsquo;s post boxes (since 1969) and telephone kiosks (since 2002) are painted blue, but are otherwise identical to their red counterparts in the UK.<br />
&bull;	Many houses in the west of Guernsey have a piece of granite protruding from their walls. Known as "witches' seats", they are meant for witches to have a rest while flying around on broomsticks. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lush botanical gardens, alluring hidden coves, and glorious sunsets over the Atlantic Ocean give the Channel Island of Guernsey an unlikely subtropical feel. Sitting just 50km (30 miles) from the shore of Normandy in France, this little isle also has a Gallic air with its French street names and culinary flair. Listen carefully and you may even hear the ancient local dialect of Dg&egrave;rn&eacute;siais (Norman patois) being spoken.</p>
<p>Although small, only 62 sq km (38 sq miles) in size, Guernsey harbours a strong local identity. It's a self-governing British Crown dependency, and the locals are quick to point out that it is not part of the United Kingdom and European Union. Keen-eyed observers will spot a few differences, like blue post boxes and the use of numerical car plates. On May 9 Liberation Day, the islanders celebrate the end of the German occupation during World War II with the towns and houses across the island decked out in flags and bunting.</p>
<p>British families have been drawn to Guernsey for generations &ndash; it certainly is the quintessential holiday destination, where kids can roam free while parents relax with a book on the beach. The pace of life is certainly more relaxed than Britain, so visitors can take their time, wander the coastline, enjoy a round of golf and stroll the streets of the island's pretty capital, St Peter Port.</p>
<p>Vazon Bay on the north western coast of Guernsey is the largest beach among the island's 27 beaches. Meanwhile, the southern coast's rocky coastline is perfect for nature-loving kayakers who can gaze back at the towering cliffs, or even get up onto the rocks for coasteering and abseiling. Alternatively, head to Cobo Bay and Vazon Bay to join scores of kitesurfers and windsurfers testing their mettle out to sea.</p>
<p>Landmarks to look out for on Guernsey include the Little Chapel and Castle Cornet, while a little patch of France comes in the form of Victor Hugo&rsquo;s house. With daily ferries to the nearby islands of Herm, Sark and Jersey are popular, Guernsey also makes a great base from which to explore the other Channel Islands.</p><p>Lush botanical gardens, alluring hidden coves, and glorious sunsets over the Atlantic Ocean give the Channel Island of Guernsey a distinctly subtropical feel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
