<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Wales" ColCode="wal" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="wl" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Wales]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wales tends to be wetter than <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/i/united-kingdom/england"><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england">England</a></a>, with slightly less sunshine. Temperatures in the coastal areas, however, can be very warm in summer ranging from 15&deg;C (59&deg;F) to rare highs of around 25&deg;C (77&deg;F).&nbsp;Conditions in upland areas such as the peaks of Snowdonia or the Brecon Beacons can be changeable at all times of the year. Be prepared for sudden downpours in summer as well as winter.</p>
<p>The summer months of June to August are the hottest, though they are also the busiest as they coincide with the school holidays. Beaches are heaving with families, hotels are rammed and attractions are a frenzy of queues. For those able to travel outside of the holidays, May and September will offer lovely warm days without the hectic crowds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Similar to the rest of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, dress according to season. Waterproofs are advised for both the winter and summer; take a look at the weather forecast before embarking on outdoorsy activities. Take strong hiking boots if doing any trekking through mountainous areas, and warm clothes such as fleeces and thermals are likely to be required for upland areas. During summer if the weather is good, lightweight fabrics are fine, although it is always sensible to take some heavier layers, just in case the weather turns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no domestic flights within Wales.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a large number of local steam railways, rescued by railway enthusiasts during the Beeching era, known collectively as The Great Little Trains of Wales (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.greatlittletrainsofwales.co.uk/">www.greatlittletrainsofwales.co.uk</a>). The most famous of these is the one at Ffestiniog, Porthmadog in Snowdonia, which has lovingly restored locomotives and carriages from the last century. <br />
<br />
Others include the Welshpool and Llanfair Railway (in north Powys), the Talyllyn Railway (near Barmouth in Cardigan Bay) and the Bala Lake Railway. Passport tickets are available, giving access to all the railways for the whole season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving around Wales is fine, with nearly all roads of a decent standard, subject  to the odd pothole and roadworks. Many of the smaller roads are slow, and in upland areas may become impassable during bad weather. The latest traffic information is available from Traffic Wales (<a href="http://www.traffic-wales.com" target="_blank">www.traffic-wales.com</a>).</p>l<p>Roads are generally of excellent quality, tarmacked and well signposted. Gravel paths are more common in more rural areas.</p><p>Both Megabus (<a href="http://www.megabus.com" target="_blank">www.megabus.com</a>) and National Express (<a href="http://www.nationalexpress.com" target="_blank">www.nationalexpress.com</a>) serve many towns in Wales.</p><p>Taxis are usually available from ranks in city railway stations. Stick to reputable licenced minicabs. Outside cities, taxi journeys may be expensive if you are going long distances, and you usually need to pre-book. Youth hostels or hotels can usually supply you with the number for a reliable local taxi company.</p><p>Drivers must have third party insurance and vehicle registration documents.</p><p>Speed limits are 48kph (30mph) in urban areas, 113kph (70mph) on motorways and dual carriageways, elsewhere 80kph (50mph) or 97kph (60mph) as marked. Seat belts must be worn by the driver and front seat passenger. Where rear seat belts have been fitted, they must also be worn. It is illegal to use a hand-held mobile phone while driving. The minimum driving age is 17.</p><p>The AA (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.theaa.com">www.theaa.com</a>) and RAC (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.rac.co.uk">www.rac.co.uk</a>) are able to provide a full range of services to UK members touring the UK. These organisations can also assist people who are travelling from abroad with maps, tourist information and specially marked routes to major events or places of interest.</p><p>Car hire can be arranged in most major towns and cities. Prices are usually cheaper when booked further in advance.</p><p>Wales is excellent cycling country and whilst commuter cycling is not common, leisure cycling is a popular pursuit along the lanes and trails of the beautiful Welsh countryside. Bikes can be hired in most major towns and cities.</p><p>Speed limits are 48kph (30mph) in urban areas, 113kph (70mph) on motorways and dual carriageways, elsewhere 80kph (50mph) or 97kph (60mph) as marked. Seat belts must be worn by the driver and front seat passenger. Where rear seat belts have been fitted, they must also be worn. It is illegal to use a hand-held mobile phone while driving. The minimum driving age is 17.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All the main centres have local bus services. There is a good network of local train services radiating from Cardiff.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flights to Wales are served by Flybe (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><a href="http://www.flybe.com" target="_blank">www.flybe.com</a>) flies to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/wales/cardiff-international-airport">Cardiff</a> from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/channel-islands/jersey">Jersey</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/edinburgh-airport">Edinburgh</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a>, whilst Lufthansa (<a href="http://www.lufthansa.com" target="_blank">www.lufthansa.com</a>) fly to Cardiff from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/duesseldorf">Dusseldorf</a>. Aer Lingus (<a href="http://www.aerlingus.com" target="_blank">www.aerlingus.com</a>) connects Cardiff with the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/chicago">Chicago</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/boston">Boston</a>) via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ireland/dublin-airport">Dublin</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> flights take around 4 hours, with most indirect via Jersey. Flights to Cardiff from Dublin take 1 hour and 10 minutes, and from Paris 1 hour 30 minutes. Indirect flights from New York, via Dublin with Aer Lingus, take from around 9 hours 40 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cardiff Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.cardiff-airport.com<p>Cardiff Airport is situated in Rhoose, 20km (12 miles) west of Cardiff city centre and 16km (10 miles) from junction 33 on the M4.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+44 1446 711 111</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main ports are at Fishguard, Holyhead (Anglesey) (<a href="http://www.holyheadport.com" target="_blank">www.holyheadport.com</a>), Pembroke (<a href="http://www.mhpa.co.uk" target="_blank">www.mhpa.co.uk</a>) and Swansea (<a href="http://www.abports.co.uk" target="_blank">www.abports.co.uk</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are two mainline routes into Wales. One runs from London Paddington to Fishguard along the south Wales coast (branching at Whitland to serve Haverford West and Milford Haven), while the other links Holyhead with Chester and northwest <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/i/united-kingdom/england">England</a> before connecting with London Euston. In addition, the line from Cardiff to Chester (via Newport, Hereford and Shrewsbury) links the south Wales cities with Abergavenny in Gwent and Wrexham in Clwyd. <br />
<br />
There are also two smaller cross-country lines. These run from Shrewsbury to Welshpool, Barmouth, Harlech, Porthmadog and Pwllheli; from Shrewsbury via Welshpool to Aberystwyth; and from Craven Arms (on the Shrewsbury-Ludlow line) through Llandrindod Wells and Llandovery down to Swansea. For details, contact National Rail Enquiries (tel: 0845 748 4950; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.nationalrail.co.uk/">www.nationalrail.co.uk</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A BritRail pass (www.britrail.com/uk)allows unlimited rail travel around the UK for a set number of days and within a set time period. Various options are available. These passes are not available to UK residents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Once in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, driving to Wales is one of the easiest and most accessible ways to get to the country.. If driving from mainland <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/europe">Europe</a>, the Channel Tunnel is the best way to get to the UK. From here on the south coast, the most direct route passes via London and then westwards onto the M4 motorway which crosses into South Wales. The A470 is one of the main roads leading north from Cardiff towards Snowdonia and Llandudno.</p><p>National Express (tel: 0871 781 8178; www.nationalexpress.com) and Megabus (tel: 0871 266 3333; www.megabus.com) operate coach services between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england">England</a> and Wales and within Wales itslf.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Cardiff Castle  (Castell Caerdydd)</p><![CDATA[<p>Originally home to a Roman garrison, the site of Cardiff Castle was later developed as a stronghold by the Normans. The ruins of the Norman keep can still be visited, but the present castle owes its appeal to the Victorian eccentricities of the third Marquis of Bute. Under his direction, architect William Burges created a gothic fantasy of towers, swirls and ornate interiors with murals, stained glass windows and decorative carving. The apartments can only be visited as part of a tour but the knowledgeable guides bring the history of the castle to life.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Conquer Snowdon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Drink in some spectacular views and hike up Mount Snowdon, Wales' highest mountain, situated in Snowdonia National Park. At 1,085m (3,560ft) Snowdon is the UK's highest peak outside the Scottish Highlands. There are various routes to reach the summit, ranging from the straightforward to the nerve-jangling.</p>]]><p><b>Cross over to Anglesey</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cross the Menai Strait to the island of Anglesey, notable for its long stretches of wild coastline (most of which is officially designated an Area of Outstanding Natural Beauty) and being home to the UK's longest place name: Llanfairpwllgwyngyllgogerychwyrndrobwllllantysiliogogogoch. For reasons of practicality, the village is commonly called Llanfair PG.</p>]]><p><b>Get active</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wales' rocky landscapes and tumbling waters provide ideal settings for high-octane outdoor activities such as white-water rafting, abseiling and caving. A relatively recent attraction is Zip World, in Penrhyn quarry near Bangor – the zipline reaches speeds of up to 75mph (120kph), making it one for the thrill-seekers. And something a lot muddier? Try bog snorkelling.</p>]]><p><b>Go for a paddle in Llandudno</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy this popular seaside resort's 19th century charms, where a huge sweeping bay looks out over the Irish Sea while the limestone headlands of Great Orme and Little Orme rise in the background. There's still plenty in the way of traditional British seaside charm, as well as some stately Victorian architecture along the seafront.</p>]]><p><b>Go green at CAT</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located close to the market town of Machynlleth is the Centre for Alternative Technology, an educational attraction dedicated to environmental issues and sustainable energy use. Expect interactive displays and kid-friendly activities alongside a full programme of events and tours. The site actually generates renewable energy of its own.</p>]]><p><b>Go to a rugby match</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wales remains a rugby nation at heart, so a visit to Cardiff's Millennium Stadium on an international match day is generally a feisty occasion. The ground has the advantage of being right in the heart of the city, meaning a colourful pre-match atmosphere in the surrounding pubs.</p>]]><p><b>Hike in the Brecon Beacons</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Breathe in the fresh air of south Wales' biggest inland draw: the green upland scenery of Brecon Beacons National Park. Hikers and mountain-bikers will be in their element, and it's a great spot for star-gazing too, being officially recognised as a Dark Sky Reserve</p>]]><p><b>Learn about mining</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Experience Wales' days as an industrial powerhouse by visiting the former coal-producing valleys located inland from Cardiff. Blaenafon, a UNESCO World Heritage Site, offers a superb heritage attraction in the form of the Big Pit National Coal Museum. It includes the possibility of taking an underground tour.</p>]]><p><b>Relax on the Gower Peninsula</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This breathtaking stretch of land is one of Wales' most prominent natural treasures. Stretching out next to less-than-pretty Swansea, the Gower Peninsula is a bevy of pretty coves, crashing waves and jagged cliffs. Head to the enormous Rhossili beach – often voted one of the UK's best – for vast stretches of sand, glistening waters and surfing lessons.</p>]]><p><b>Retrace the steps of Dylan Thomas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the greatest writers and poets ever to come out of Wales, Dylan Thomas still occupies a special place in national culture. Learn more about his life and legacy by visiting his Swansea birthplace and other significant locations such as Newquay and Laugharne.</p>]]><p><b>See Wales by train</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Ffestiniog Railway passes through glorious scenery in the Snowdonia National Park, while the Welshpool and Llanfair Railway passes through gentler countryside close to the English border. Another scenic option, the Snowdon Mountain Railway, climbs to the summit of Wales' highest peak.</p>]]><p><b>Spend time at the National History Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get to grips with the roots of Welsh culture at St Fagans' popular open-air National History Museum. Set in the grounds of a huge 16th-century manor house, the 'living museum' includes more than 40 original buildings, including a farm, a school and houses. Craftsmen still showcase traditional skills.</p>]]><p><b>Spend time in Cardiff</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Welsh capital is a lively place to spend time, with busy pubs, quality restaurants and first-rate cultural attractions (including the Doctor Who Experience, Time Lord fans). Be sure to take in Cardiff Castle and the revamped Cardiff Bay area.</p>]]><p><b>Step back in time at Conwy Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Constructed between 1283 and 1289, the strikingly handsome Conwy Castle was one of a number of fortresses built in North Wales to subdue the Welsh Princes. Dominating the town of Conwy itself, it sits high on a rocky plateau above an estuary, backdropped by the dramatic scenery of Snowdonia.</p>]]><p><b>Visit history at Chepstow Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The construction of Chepstow Castle began in 1066 just after the Battle of Hastings, and was the first castle in Britain to be built entirely of stone. It opened its doors to tourists for the first time in 1953 and today features life-size models of its former inhabitants and rulers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Wales' gastronomic stock is rising, as more and more visitors discover that it's laced with pleasures for foodies. The old adage runs that Wales has more sheep than people – and it's true that lamb is never off the menu for long – but there's more to Wales than this.</p><p>The coastline provides a great variety of fresh fish and shellfish: mullet and brown shrimps are common on the Gower peninsula, as well as cockles, whilst several producers have awards for their crab and smoked fish. These producers have attracted a legion of new fans that care about provenance. Farmers' markets and food festivals have gained popularity.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Cockles:</strong> Usually served steamed.<br />
<strong>Cheese:</strong> Look out for Caerphilly and local goats&rsquo; cheeses.<br />
<strong>Salt-marsh lamb:</strong> Lamb raised on salt marshes to graze samphire and sorrel, usually served with rosemary.<br />
<strong>Bara brith:</strong> Fruit loaf made with tea-soaked raisins and currants.<br />
<strong>Laverbread:</strong> Bread made with seaweed and oatmeal.<br />
<strong>Welsh cakes:</strong> Scone-like small flat sweet pancakes made with sultanas or currants.<br />
<strong>Welsh oggie:</strong> A large pastie stuffed with meat and vegetables.<br />
<strong>Welsh cawl:</strong> A meat and vegetable broth, usually with lamb and leeks.<br />
<strong>Monkfish:</strong> Often served with laverbread.<br />
<strong>Welsh rarebit:</strong> Cheese on toast.<br />
<strong>Cider:</strong> Try Orchard Gold or the pear-based Perry Vale.<br />
<strong>Brains:</strong> No, not actual brains, but a dark ale.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A service charge (usually 10-12.5%) might be included in the prices stated on the menu but it is more likely to be added to the bill at the end. This is technically an optional charge. Where 'service is not included', a tip of at least 10% is expected.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Welsh culture is steeped in music, and the inhabitants famously know how to party. The major cities of Swansea and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/wales/cardiff-international-airport">Cardiff</a> are at the centre of Welsh nightlife, offering clubs and pubs for late nighters. </p>
<p>For something distinctive to this land, listen to a Welsh choir. These vary from small church choirs to massive male voice choirs on tour at the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>'s biggest music venues. You might also find some ad hoc singing at one of Wales' legendary rugby matches. </p>
<p>For opera buffs, the Wales Millennium Centre in Cardiff is the place to go, but music isn't confined to the cities; the biggest music event of the year is the Eisteddfod, a celebration of Welsh music, which moves to a different destination every year. Folk music fans should head to the Green Man Festival in Hay-on-Wye, while the Brecon annual festival promotes jazz. </p>
<p>Rural nightlife traditionally focuses around the old-fashioned village pub, with local beer and good hearty food.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wales has not escaped the infiltration of high street chains, but independent shops certainly hold their ground more here than in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/i/united-kingdom/england"><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england">England</a></a>. Local artists and craftsmen sell handmade gifts such as jewellery and pottery. The town centre of Chepstow has some lovely independent shops, including regular craft and food markets; while Monmouth, Cardigan and Abergavenny also have pleasant high streets.</p>
<p>Up in Snowdonia, the idyllic towns of here are a picture of rural charm. Betws-y-coed is home to the Trefriw Woollen Mills which produces the famous Welsh tapestry textiles. Buy waistcoasts, bedspreads and throws here, for distinctive souvenirs. In the larger town of Llandudno you&rsquo;ll find cute boutiques selling handmade items &ndash; try the Craft Cymru shop which stocks authentic Welsh produce and crafts. Back towards the southwest, the lush beaches of the Gower peninsula may be a surfer&rsquo;s paradise, but it&rsquo;s the brownies from Gower Cottage (<a href="http://www.gowercottagebrownies.co.uk/" target="_blank">www.gowercottagebrownies.co.uk</a>) that you won&rsquo;t forget in a hurry. Book lovers should head to Hay on Wye near the Welsh border. Known as the home of the UK&rsquo;s largest literary festival, it is home to around 40 second hand bookshops, earning it the nickname &lsquo;town of books&rsquo;.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/i/cardiff"><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/wales/cardiff-international-airport">Cardiff</a></a> is the city with the biggest choice and the big names. If you like big-name brands or late night opening, then the city centre is the place to visit. Here you&rsquo;ll find the majority of the shops highly concentrated within arcades rather than the high streets. Market lovers mustn&rsquo;t miss the St Mary street market for its mixture of vintage clothing and antique furniture, whilst the recently created Cardiff Fashion Quarter, houses a treasure trove of independent stalls. &nbsp;For surprising shopping experiences, meander through the byways and highways of the Welsh hills and valleys and veer off the trodden path to explore small villages and craft centres.</p><p>Mon-Fri 1000-1700, Sat 1000-1700, Sun (some shops) 1100-1700. In cities some shops open later on Thursday nights, and are more likely to open on Sundays. In remote areas few shops open on Sundays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation in Wales ranges from shiny chain hotels in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/wales/cardiff-international-airport">Cardiff</a> to boutique boltholes in the countryside. Five star hotels in Cardiff are thin on the ground but there are plenty of moderate properties worthy of a stay in the city; the same is true of Swansea. For those looking for something a little different, a selection of Wales' finest hotels can be found at Welsh Rarebits (<a target="_blank" href="http://rarebits.co.uk">rarebits.co.uk</a>). Standards vary, with price not always an indicator of quality but star gradings can give some idea of the level of facilities. In the most rural outposts, it's not always possible to find a hotel,&nbsp; but alternatives such as B&amp;Bs or guesthouses are usually available.<br />
<strong><br />
Grading:</strong> VisitWales, VisitScotland, VisitBritain, the AA and RAC have now agreed common standards for quality assessment. Hotels and guest houses are classified by from 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bed and breakfasts and guesthouses are available throughout Wales. Usually a cheaper option than a staying in a hotel, B&amp;Bs may be the more appropriate option for those visiting rural areas, or on a budget. Properties can range from not much more than a few rooms in a private house or rustic farmhouses, to a grand townhouse on a par with the best hotels. A list of B&amp;Bs can be found at Visit Wales (<a href="http://www.visitwales.com" target="_blank">www.visitwales.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation in Wales ranges from shiny chain hotels in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/wales/cardiff-international-airport">Cardiff</a> to boutique boltholes in the countryside. Five star hotels in Cardiff are thin on the ground but there are plenty of moderate properties worthy of a stay in the city; the same is true of Swansea. For those looking for something a little different, a selection of Wales' finest hotels can be found at Welsh Rarebits (<a target="_blank" href="http://rarebits.co.uk">rarebits.co.uk</a>). Standards vary, with price not always an indicator of quality but star gradings can give some idea of the level of facilities. In the most rural outposts, it's not always possible to find a hotel,&nbsp; but alternatives such as B&amp;Bs or guesthouses are usually available.<br />
<strong><br />
Grading:</strong> VisitWales, VisitScotland, VisitBritain, the AA and RAC have now agreed common standards for quality assessment. Hotels and guest houses are classified by from 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation in Wales ranges from shiny chain hotels in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/wales/cardiff-international-airport">Cardiff</a> to boutique boltholes in the countryside. Five star hotels in Cardiff are thin on the ground but there are plenty of moderate properties worthy of a stay in the city; the same is true of Swansea. For those looking for something a little different, a selection of Wales' finest hotels can be found at Welsh Rarebits (<a target="_blank" href="http://rarebits.co.uk">rarebits.co.uk</a>). Standards vary, with price not always an indicator of quality but star gradings can give some idea of the level of facilities. In the most rural outposts, it's not always possible to find a hotel,&nbsp; but alternatives such as B&amp;Bs or guesthouses are usually available.<br />
<strong><br />
Grading:</strong> VisitWales, VisitScotland, VisitBritain, the AA and RAC have now agreed common standards for quality assessment. Hotels and guest houses are classified by from 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Early May Bank Holiday :
							07 May </p><p>Spring Bank Holiday :
							28 May </p><p>Summer Bank Holiday :
							27 August </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[51.481383]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-3.186035]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>20,732 sq km (8,004 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>3.1 million (2014).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>148.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cardiff.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy, with some powers devolved to the National Assembly for Wales.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wales is a country of great geographical variation with many long stretches of attractive and often rugged coastline. South Wales is mainly known for its industrial heritage but the western part of the coast between Carmarthen Bay and St David's is similar to that of the more pastoral west country of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england">England</a>, and backed by some equally beautiful countryside.</p>
<p>The scenery of Mid-Wales includes rich farming valleys, the broad sandy sweep of Cardigan Bay and rolling hill country. North Wales is one of the most popular tourist areas in the British Isles, with many lively coastal resorts. Inland, the mountainous region of Snowdonia has long been popular with walkers and climbers. Much of the central inland area of the country is mountainous, with some breathtaking scenery; many striking lakes can be found inland. The region of Snowdonia in the north covers an area of 2,130 sq km (822 sq miles), extending from the north and western coasts of Wales, inland towards Bala and Llandrillo. Snowdon is the second highest peak in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">Britain</a>, after Scotland&rsquo;s Ben Nevis, standing at 1,085m (3,560ft) above sea level.</p>
<p>Further south, the Brecon Beacons is another mountain range running from Hay on Wye in the east to Llandeilo in the west, covering 1,344 sq km (519 sq miles). The highest peak in the range is Peny Y Fan 886m (2907ft).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Predominantly Christian (Church of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england">England</a>, Roman Catholic, Presbyterian, Methodist), sizeable Muslim, Sikh, Jewish and Hindu minorities. Around 15% of the population have no religion.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The monarchy, though now only symbolic politically, is a powerful and often subconscious unifying force. Members of the Royal Family are the subject of unceasing fascination, with their every move avidly followed and reported by the popular press, both in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> and abroad.<br /><br />Handshaking is customary when introduced to someone for the first time. Normal social courtesies should be observed when visiting someone's home and a small present such as flowers or chocolates is appreciated. It is polite to wait until everyone has been served before eating.<br /><br /><strong>Clothing:</strong> Some nightclubs and restaurants do not allow jeans and trainers, otherwise casual wear is widely acceptable.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with three square pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Theresa May since July 2016. (UK&nbsp;government). First Minister Carwyn Jones since 2009 (National Assembly for Wales).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Invasions and battles pockmark the history of Wales. The Romans, the Saxons and the Normans all eyed up the Welsh countryside and set off across the River Severn to see what they could claim &ndash; with mixed results. Today, the rugged castles still dotted around the country stand as testament to attempts by these invaders to keep the locals in check.</p>
<p>Welsh historical heroes range from the semi-mythical King Arthur &ndash; who is also claimed by the Cornish and who features in ancient Welsh documents as an emperor and war hero &ndash; to bona fide legends such as Owain Glyndwr. Also known as Owen Glendower, he featured in Shakespeare's Henry IV and waged violent battles against the English, claiming right to the title Prince of Wales.</p>
<p>After winning a series of conflicts and signing an allegiance with France, Glyndwr drew the wrath of the English king, who clamped down on the Welsh, banning substantial gatherings of people and preventing Welshmen from holding office. Glyndwr's period of glory eventually came to an end when the forces of Henry V took back the castles and strongholds the Prince of Wales had gained.</p>
<p>Non-conformist religion, particularly in the form of the Baptist and Methodist Churches, marked the rise of Welsh nationalism in the 19th century. The non-conformists broke off from the official state religion (Anglican) and taught the Welsh language at Sunday schools. Even today, the country still has a strong sense of identity and national pride.</p>
<p>The industrial revolution in the late 18th and early 19th centuries left a heavy mark on Welsh history, altering the focus of the countryside and its workforce from agriculture onto coalmining and ironwork. The period was also marked by increased immigration into Wales, boosting the population.</p>
<p>The University of Wales was established in 1893, and the national library and museum both received their royal charters in 1907. From 1999, an elected Welsh assembly was established in Cardiff, with powers devolved from Westminster. Less positive was the decline of the coalmining industry, which some communities are still reeling from today.</p>
<p>The Welsh assembly quickly established an independent frame of mind and has taken a different route from English policies on some issues, most famously free prescriptions and university tuition fees.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	It&rsquo;s claimed that lawn tennis was invented in the 1870s at Nantclwyd Hall, a stately home in Denbighshire.  <br />
&bull;	Mount Everest is named after a Welshman, the 19th-century surveyor Colonel Sir George Everest.<br />
&bull;	When the Menai Bridge across to Anglesey was opened in 1826, it was the longest bridge in the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Though Wales forms an integral part of the United Kingdom, it often sits in the shadows of its high-achieving neighbours. But treat Wales as an after thought and you&rsquo;ll be missing a trick.</p>
<p>It may be small, but Wales is resourceful, squeezing in green hills, bustling cities and colourful seaside villages, fronted by UNESCO-listed beaches. Its people are welcoming but passionate, harbouring the spirit of the iconic red dragon that adorns its national flag.<br />
<br />
Starting at the top, the beautiful island of Anglesey (Wales&rsquo;s largest island) has shot into the limelight recently thanks to the residency of the Duke and Duchess of Cambridge. But ask any local and they&rsquo;ll tell you the island has long been revered &ndash; some North Walians still consider it to be the true heartland of Wales. Tread carefully.<br />
<br />
Further down the mainland lies the awe-inspiring Snowdonia National Park, home to Snowdon, Wales&rsquo;s highest peak, not to mention some of the best hiking trails in the British Isles. The restaurant at the summit offers album-worthy panoramas and is arguably the best spot in the country to sample Welsh oggie (a lamb and leek pasty).<br />
<br />
To claim that the journey to the south of the country transcends time from traditional to modern Wales is overly dramatic, but there is a wisp of truth in this remark. Sleepy villages give way to modern cities and the national tongue, for the most part, slips from Welsh into English.<br />
<br />
Here, the cities of Swansea, a stone&rsquo;s throw from the surfer-strewn sands of the Gower peninsular; Newport, a modern port city emerging from its industrial roots; and Cardiff, the cosmopolitan capital, dominate the landscape and provide ample opportunities for urban adventure.<br />
<br />
These modern cities have not abandoned their heritage, though; scattered amongst them are museums, medieval castles (Cardiff, Coch and Caerphilly to name a few) and historic sites chronicling the redundant coal mining industry, a big part of the nation&rsquo;s identity.<br />
<br />
Granted, it may lack the pulling power of its heavyweight neighbours, but Wales is a country that rewards the adventurous.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p><p>Though Wales forms an integral part of the United Kingdom, it often sits in the shadows of its high-achieving neighbours. But treat Wales as an after thought and you&rsquo;ll be missing a trick.</p>
<p>Rather than small, Wales is resourceful, squeezing in green hills, bustling cities and colourful seaside villages, fronted by UNESCO-listed beaches. Its people are welcoming but passionate, harbouring the spirit of the iconic red dragon that adorns its national flag.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
