<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Scotland" ColCode="sco" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="sc" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Scotland]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Scotland is generally colder than the rest of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, especially in the more northerly regions. The west tends to be wetter and warmer than the cool, dry east. In upland areas, snow is common in winter, and fog and mist may occur at any time of year. The five Scottish ski areas are usually open from December/January to April, but as snow accumulations come and go with the varying temperatures, check ahead to make sure the lifts are running. If there&rsquo;s been late-season snow, skiing sometimes continues into May.<br />
<br />
Springtime sees the Highlands wake from their barren winter slumber, and come alive with wild flowers and fresh green shoots; August sees a striking landscape dripping in purple Scottish heather; autumn brings a rush of gold and crimson leaves.</p>
<p>The busiest tourist season is July and August, when schools are on holiday and when many summer festivals occur (including the Edinburgh Festival in August).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Similar to the rest of the UK, according to season. In autumn, winter and often well into spring you&rsquo;ll need a warm jacket. Although temperatures rarely dip below freezing during the day in winter thanks to the warming Gulf Stream, overnight frost is common. (You should expect daytime freezing temperatures at altitude however.) Summer can see temperatures hit the mid-20s &deg;C (mid-70s &deg;F) on occasion, but this is the exception rather than the rule, so you&rsquo;ll generally need at least a light sweater and probably a light jacket too.</p>
<p>The Scottish weather is unpredictable and changeable though, so you could easily find yourself needing an umbrella and warm coat one day and a T-shirt and sunhat the next. Wherever you&rsquo;re travelling, you should definitely take a waterproof jacket (and trousers too if you&rsquo;re hiking in the hills). You might be lucky and hit a heatwave, but chances are you&rsquo;ll need warm clothing in the Highlands, even in summer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are several small airports in the north of Scotland that are served by flights from Glasgow and, in some cases, from Aberdeen, Inverness and Edinburgh as well. These include Barra, Benbecula, Kirkwall (Orkney), Sumburgh (Shetland), Stornoway and Tiree. The islands are accessible by ferry too, but if your time is limited, it may be worth taking a flight. The landing strip at Barra is especially spectacular &ndash; planes land on the beach! Flybe (<a href="http://www.flybe.com" target="_blank">www.flybe.com</a>) operates most routes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ferry services operate between the mainland and all the Scottish islands. Caledonian MacBrayne (tel: 0800 066 5000; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.calmac.co.uk">www.calmac.co.uk</a>) operates the largest network of ferries on the River Clyde and west coast, serving many islands, including the Inner and Outer Hebrides. Northlink Ferries (tel: 0845 600 0449; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.northlinkferries.co.uk">www.northlinkferries.co.uk</a>) operates services to Orkney and Shetland; from Aberdeen to Lerwick (some via Kirkwall, Orkney); and from Scrabster to Stromness (journey time - 1 hour 30 minutes).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>ScotRail (tel: 0845 755 0033; <a href="http://www.scotrail.co.uk" target="_blank">www.scotrail.co.uk</a>) operates train services across Scotland. There are good services connecting all the main towns, particularly in the Edinburgh-Glasgow area. Many of the routes that pass through the Highlands (such as Perth-Inverness, Inverness-Kyle of Lochalsh and Glasgow-Fort William-Mallaig) are spectacular. The network extends right up to Thurso and Wick in the extreme north of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Freedom of Scotland pass:</strong> allows four days&rsquo; travel within eight days or eight days&rsquo; travel within 15 days. The pass covers journeys on all trains within Scotland, ferry travel on Caledonian MacBrayne and Argyll Ferries (20% discount available on Northlink Ferries), and numerous coach routes. Available to UK residents from ScotRail (<a href="http://www.scotrail.co.uk" target="_blank">www.scotrail.co.uk</a>) or to overseas residents from BritRail (<a href="http://www.britrail.com" target="_blank">www.britrail.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Highland Rover:</strong> allows four days&rsquo; travel within eight days on trains, ferries and coaches in the Highlands. Available from ScotRail or BritRail.</p>
<p><strong>Central Scotland Rover:</strong> allows three days&rsquo; travel within seven days on trains between Glasgow and Edinburgh along with unlimited travel on the Glasgow Underground. Available from ScotRail or BritRail.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main motorways within Scotland connect Edinburgh with Glasgow (M8); Edinburgh with Stirling (M9); and the Forth Bridge, near Edinburgh, with Perth (M90). The main cross-country road, the A9, connects Perth with Inverness and Thurso. National Tourist Routes are brown-signposted scenic roads.</p>l<p>In general, the internal trunk road network is better and more direct on the east coast, and roads north of Inverness tend to be slower and often single track. Snow is common in winter, especially in the Highlands, and motorists are advised to follow local advice concerning weather conditions. The main cross-country road, the A9, connects Perth with Inverness and Thurso.</p><p>Scottish Citylink (tel: 0871 266 3333; www.citylink.co.uk) is Scotland's main coach operator, connecting over 200 towns and cities across the country. The Explorer Pass offers savings if you're planning on making a few journeys.</p><p>It's easy to hail a taxi on the street or pick one up at a taxi rank in the larger cities. Taxis in Edinburgh and Glasgow are metered black hackney cabs, so are highly visible. In smaller towns, you may need to call up a taxi in advance; hotels and tourist information centres will be able to provide numbers.</p><p>National driving licences are valid for one year. Drivers must have third party insurance and vehicle registration documents.</p><p>Speed limits are 48kph (30mph) in urban areas, 113kph (70mph) on motorways and dual carriageways, elsewhere 80kph (50mph) or 97kph (60mph) as marked. Seat belts must be worn by the driver and front seat passenger. Where rear seat belts have been fitted, they must also be worn. It is illegal to use a hand-held mobile phone while driving. The minimum driving age is 17.</p><p>The AA (<a href="http://www.theaa.com/" target="_blank">www.theaa.com</a>) and RAC (<a href="http://www.rac.co.uk/" target="_blank">www.rac.co.uk</a>) are able to provide a full range of services to UK members touring the UK. These organisations can also assist people who are travelling from abroad with maps, tourist information and specially marked routes to major events or places of interest. In the event of a breakdown, call the AA on 0800 887 766 or RAC on 0844 273 7172.</p><p>All the major international car hire companies are represented in Scotland's cities and larger towns.</p><p>Scotland has a wealth of quiet roads suited to cycling. Highlights include the Border Loop in the south, the northwest Highlands, the route from Barra to Lewis (with ferry crossings) and the Glasgow-Inverness stretch of Sustrans Route 7. Most cities and larger tourist towns offer bike hire. Scotland's mountain biking is world class too. Downhill junkies can test their mettle on the UK's world cup course at the Nevis Range ski area. The 7stanes, meanwhile, are seven superb courses in the south of Scotland.</p><p>Speed limits are 48kph (30mph) in urban areas, 113kph (70mph) on motorways and dual carriageways, elsewhere 80kph (50mph) or 97kph (60mph) as marked. Seat belts must be worn by the driver and front seat passenger. Where rear seat belts have been fitted, they must also be worn. It is illegal to use a hand-held mobile phone while driving. The minimum driving age is 17.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All the major towns and cities have bus services. Glasgow also has an underground and a suburban train network. Edinburgh is building a controversial and much delayed tram line, which is due for completion in 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>United Airlines (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>) flies to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/edinburgh-airport">Edinburgh</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/glasgow-airport">Glasgow</a> from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>. US Airways (<a href="http://www.usairways.com" target="_blank">www.usairways.com</a>) also connects the USA with Glasgow. British Airways (<a href="http://www.britishairways.com/" target="_blank">www.britishairways.com</a>) and Flybe (<a href="http://www.flybe.com" target="_blank">www.flybe.com</a>) fly from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england">England</a> to Edinburgh and Glasgow; other airlines operating flights to Scotland from European cities include easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>) and Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flights from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to Edinburgh take 1 hour 20 minutes; from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a> takes 6 hours 50 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Edinburgh Airport was sold by BAA to Global Infrastructure Partners in spring 2012, which is likely to result in airport improvements and new routes from the capital within the next few years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Edinburgh Airport was sold by BAA to Global Infrastructure Partners in spring 2012, which is likely to result in airport improvements and new routes from the capital within the next few years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Aberdeen International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aberdeenairport.com<p>Aberdeen International Airport is situated 11km (7 miles) northwest of Aberdeen.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+44 (0)844 481 6666</p>]]><b>Edinburgh Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.edinburghairport.com<p>Edinburgh Airport is situated 12km (8 miles) west of Edinburgh.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+44 844 448 8833</p>]]><b>Glasgow Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.glasgowairport.com<p>Glasgow Airport is located 13.8km (8.6 miles) west of Glasgow city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+44 844 481 5555</p>]]><b>Inverness Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.hial.co.uk/inverness-airport<p>Inverness Airport is situated 13km (8 miles) northeast of Inverness city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+44 1667 464 000</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Main ports are situated at Aberdeen, Cairnryan, Leith, Lerwick, Oban, Rosyth and Stranraer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are two mainline routes into Scotland from England: Virgin Trains (tel: 0871 977 4222; <a href="http://www.virgintrains.co.uk" target="_blank">www.virgintrains.co.uk</a>) runs the service from London Euston up the west coast to Glasgow Central; and East Coast (tel: 0845 722 5225; <a href="http://www.eastcoast.co.uk" target="_blank">www.eastcoast.co.uk</a>) operates from London Kings Cross up the east coast to Edinburgh and beyond to Dundee and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/aberdeen-airport">Aberdeen</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/western-australia/perth-airport">Perth</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/inverness-airport">Inverness</a>. ScotRail (tel: 0845 755 0033; <a href="http://www.scotrail.co.uk" target="_blank">www.scotrail.co.uk</a>) runs sleeper services from London Euston to Glasgow, Fort William, Edinburgh, Aberdeen and Inverness. For timetables, contact National Rail Enquiries (tel: 0845 748 4859; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.nationalrail.co.uk">www.nationalrail.co.uk</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>InterRail offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 30 European countries for European residents with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five in 10 days or 10 in 22 days across all countries. <br />
<br />
The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month. Travel is not allowed in your country of residence. There are reductions for children and travellers under 26 years. Available from InterRail (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.interrailnet.com">www.interrailnet.com</a>).</p>
<p>The Eurail pass (available to non-European residents) does not cover the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> (including Scotland).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving from England into Scotland is straightforward, with several options available. The main driving routes are: via the M6 from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england/birmingham-airport">Birmingham</a> followed by the M74 from Carlisle to Glasgow; via the A1/A1(M) from London to Edinburgh; and via the A68 from the northeast of England through the Scottish Borders to Edinburgh.</p>
<p>National Express (tel: 0871 781 8178; <a href="http://www.nationalexpress.com">www.nationalexpress.com</a>) and Megabus (tel: 0871 266 3333; <a href="http://www.megabus.com">www.megabus.com</a>) both operate coach services between England and Scotland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Celtic Park</p><![CDATA[<p>Celtic Football Club is one of Glasgow's two top teams, the other being Glasgow Rangers. Celtic moved to its present ground at Celtic Park in 1892. The all-seater ground, also known as Parkhead and Paradise to its fans, has a capacity of 60,500. A double tier rings most of the ground with the single tiered section housing the Club Museum. Celtic and Rangers have dominated Scottish football for years and the atmosphere on derby days is passionate and can be quite firey. The ground has good conference and hospitality facilities and is available for private hire.<br /><br /><br /><br />Address: Celtic Football Club, Celtic Park, Glasgow G40 3RE, Scotland</p>]]><br/><p>Celtic Park</p><![CDATA[<p>Celtic Football Club is one of Glasgow's two top teams, the other being Glasgow Rangers. Celtic moved to its present ground at Celtic Park in 1892. The all-seater ground, also known as Parkhead and Paradise to its fans, has a capacity of 60,500. A double tier rings most of the ground with the single tiered section housing the Club Museum. Celtic and Rangers have dominated Scottish football for years and the atmosphere on derby days is passionate and can be quite firey. The ground has good conference and hospitality facilities and is available for private hire.<br /><br />Address: Celtic Football Club, Celtic Park, Glasgow G40 3RE, Scotland</p>]]><br/><p>Ibrox Football Stadium</p><![CDATA[<p>Inaugurated in 1899, Ibrox Stadium is the home of Glasgow Rangers football club, one of the city's two top teams, the other being Celtic. The magnificent all-seater stadium has a capacity of 50,400 and is one of only 12 football grounds in Europe to have been awarded the highest 5-star rating by UEFA, footballs' governing body. Visitors can take a tour of the ground as well as viewing the museum and the coveted Trophy Room that opened to the public in 1959. The ground itself is a great mix of old and new with visitors being greeted by the famous original red-brick entrance to Ibrox. Inside, the ground boasts executive boxes, conference rooms and hospitality suites and can be hired for corporate functions and wedding ceremonies.</p>]]><br/><p>Speyside Whisky Trails</p><![CDATA[<p>Originally celebrated for its apparent medicinal qualities, whisky grew to become an integral part of daily Scottish life, drank for its reviving properties and to warm the body during the long, cold Scottish winters. As its popularity grew, extortionate taxes were imposed on whisky production in the latter stages of the 16th century which drove many distilleries underground, with several establishing themselves in the hills of the <em>Grampian Highlands</em> away from the eyes of the excise men. Smuggling became common practice and distilleries would signal from one hilltop to the next when excise men entered the area. In 1823, a new tax system was introduced that made it possible for distilleries to make a profit and pay taxes, and the illegal production of whisky gradually phased out. But many of the old distilleries remain in their dramatic locations in the hills and today form a popular whisky trail where visitors can tour distilleries and sample a wee dram or two of their favourite malt or scotch whisky. The distilleries on the <em>Speyside Trail</em> include <em>Benromach</em>, <em>Cardhu</em>, <em>Dallas Dhu</em>, <em>Glenfiddich</em>, <em>Glen Grant</em>, <em>Glenlivet</em>, <em>Glen Moray</em> and <em>Strathisla</em>. The award-winning <em>Speyside Cooperage</em> and visitor centre is also on the trail where visitors can see how the traditional oak casks used for maturing the whiskies are made. Other popular trails in the Grampian Highlands include the <em>Castle Trail</em>, the <em>Coastal Trail</em> and the <em>Victorian Heritage Trail</em> and the whole area is renowned for its stunning scenery.</p>]]><br/><p>Waverley Historic Paddle Steamer</p><![CDATA[<p>The <em>Waverley</em> is the last sea-going paddle steamer in the world and provides visitors with the opportunity to sail on scenic cruise journeys throughout the UK. Built on the <em>Clyde</em> in 1945, the Waverley originally sailed the waters between <em>Craigendorran</em> and <em>Arrochar</em> in <em>West Scotland</em> before falling into disrepair. After a lengthy repair project, the Waverley was fully restored in 2003 and is now docked in <em>Glasgow</em> from where it offers passengers the opportunity to sail on the Clyde as well as on longer voyages throughout the UK. The Waverley is also available for private hire.</p>
<p>Address:&nbsp;Waverley Terminal, Anderston Quay, Glasgow G3 8HA, Scotland</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be Entertained at the Edinburgh Festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>While the Edinburgh International Festival is the biggest arts festival in the world, drawing the best classical, theatrical and comedy players, it is the Fringe Festival that grabs the headlines. Drama, comedy, improvisation, music, dance, art installations – you name it, it's here. The choice among one of Britain's most beautiful cities is truly dazzling.</p>]]><p><b>Be at one with nature in Cairngorms National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This mass of rugged countryside features the UK's highest mountain range, rivers, lochs, forest and oodles of wildlife, including pine martens, red squirrels, badgers and wildcats. As well as hiking and mountain climbing, you can enjoy birdwatching, beautiful camping grounds, and great skiing in the winter.</p>]]><p><b>Be culturally captivated in Scotland’s largest city</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Stylish and continually reinventing itself, culturally rich Glasgow is Scotland's largest city. It's a hotbed of innovative art, design, music and film, with first-rate museums to boot. Discover architectural delights on the Rennie Mackintosh Trail, gaze at boats, bikes and buses in the Zaha Hadid-designed Riverside Museum, or check out a band beneath the bright lights of the Barrowland Ballroom.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy a dram – or more – on the malt whisky trail</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sample some Scotland's favourite export, whisky. Between Inverness and Aberdeen thirsty tourists can follow the malt whisky trail, visiting distilleries to learn about this national icon. You'll fine the UK's only working cooperage in Dufftown, where you can still see whisky barrels being crafted – though you may need to draw straws to decide who's driving.</p>]]><p><b>Escape to quiet of Outer Hebrides</b></p><![CDATA[<p>On the fringes of Scotland lies a magical necklace of unspoiled islands comprising powder-sand beaches, ancient Neolithic sites and incredible wildlife. Paddle by kayak to secluded coves, gaze in wonder at the Calanais standing stones, rummage for Celtic jewellery in the numerous galleries and studios, and keep your eyes peeled for orcas, dolphins and golden eagles.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Scotland’s exceptional capital, Edinburgh</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A vast swathe of striking UNESCO-listed architecture, the Queen's former yacht and one heck of a castle make Scotland's elegant capital city unmissable. Explore the Old Town's Royal Mile and hidden closes, amble among graceful Georgian townhouses, inhale the scent of conifers in the Royal Botanic Garden, and pop in on Edinburgh Zoo's pandas, Tian Tian and Yang Guang.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the poetically picturesque Burns country</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Southwest Scotland was home to the nation's bard, Robert Burns. Explore his thatched birthplace cottage and adjacent state-of-the-art museum in Alloway, Ayrshire. Also open to visitors are Ellisland Farm and the Robert Burns House, his former homes in Dumfries and Galloway. In Dumfries itself, you can sit fireside in his old chair at The Globe Inn.</p>]]><p><b>Fall under the spell of the Shetland Isles</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This geologically diverse group of over 100 islands are closer to Norway than Edinburgh. Cast a line for sea trout, halibut or mackerel, meet the residents of an iron-age village, shop for unique knitwear on the Shetland Craft Trail, or play a round of late-night golf in the almost perpetual daylight of midsummer.</p>]]><p><b>Find adventure at Loch Lomond and The Trossachs National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Around 1,865 sq km (720 sq miles) of startling beautiful lowlands, mountains, lochs, rivers and forests make up this cracking national park. Tackle one (or more) of 21 Munros, take to two wheels on the West Lomond Cycle Path, kayak in the Queen Elizabeth Forest Park, or camp wild on the shores of Loch Lomond itself.</p>]]><p><b>Find folk stories and fantastic views in The Highlands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Walk and wonder at the scenery of the Highlands – perhaps the most famous region in Scotland. On their southern fringes at Callander, pilgrims can visit the gravestone of Scottish folk hero, Rob Roy, while views from the road heading north are among the finest in the country.</p>]]><p><b>Find your swing at the home of golf</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Old Course at St Andrews attracts (and truly tests) golfers from around the world. The prestigious university town is also home to the British Golf Museum, containing over 16,000 artefacts. Scotland has over 550 courses nationwide, including top championship courses at Carnoustie, Turnberry, Royal Troon and Muirfield.</p>]]><p><b>Roam the grounds of Glamis Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Set in the heart of the Angus Glens, Glamis Castle has been a royal residence since 1372. Grand and impressively imposing, the majestic building brims with history and lays claim (loosely) to being the setting for Shakespeare's Macbeth. Outside, its vast, well-manicured grounds include an Italian Garden, Pinetum and Nature Trail, and prove particularly popular with visitors.</p>]]><p><b>Run away to Gretna Green</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Situated on the old coach route that linked London and Edinburgh, Gretna Green is the first village across the border from England. Here, young English couples would flee and marry under Scotland's relaxed marriage laws. The Old Blacksmith's Shop is Gretna's most famous venue and still hand fasts couples today. It's also a quaint museum, restaurant and heritage shop.</p>]]><p><b>See the sights of Scotland by bike</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Scotland has an extensive 3,379km (2,100 miles) of sign-posted cycling routes to explore, including on-road, traffic-free and mountain bike trails. The fittest of two-wheelers should tackle the Glasgow to Edinburgh classic, while historic sites and canal routes are ideal for families. Bicycle hire and cycling tours are available throughout the country.</p>]]><p><b>Seek out Loch Ness’s most famous resident</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Whether 'Nessie' exists or not doesn't seem to deter the thousands of visitors from trying to catch a glimpse of the fabled lake monster at Loch Ness. The Loch Ness Exhibition Centre in Drumnadrochit is an amusing port of call for believers and sceptics alike, while the walking trails around the lake offer a pleasing alternative to mythical monster hunting.</p>]]><p><b>Seek out the breath-taking vistas at Stirling</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Historic Stirling has its fair share of turbulent tales to tell. Unlock centuries of history at magnificent Stirling Castle, before climbing the eye-catching National Wallace Monument, commemorating the Battle of Stirling Bridge. Finally, step onto the fields at Bannockburn, site of the eponymous battle of 1314, where King Robert the Bruce defeated the English.</p>]]><p><b>Seek out the scenic Scottish Borders</b></p><![CDATA[<p>South of Edinburgh, the Borders is a lovely landscape of gently rolling hills peppered with pretty towns and villages. Discover four ruined abbeys on the 104km (65-mile) Borders Abbeys Way walking trail, cheer on local and international rugby teams at the Melrose Sevens, hook a salmon on the River Tweed, or splash out on cashmere in Hawick.</p>]]><p><b>Walk Britain’s biggest peak, Ben Nevis</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Scotland's northwest is a dramatic region of glacially hewn glens and splendid mountains. At 1,344m (4,409ft), if you're daunted by Britain's highest peak, Ben Nevis, look up from Fort William where the spectacular Great Glen stretches from Neptune's Staircase (a series of canal locks) via Loch Ness to Inverness. To the north, remote Torridon is a walker's utopia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Scottish cuisine has a reputation for strong flavours and interesting ingredients. Inspiration often comes from traditional Scots products – oats, whisky, salmon, Aberdeen Angus beef and game. In season, pheasant, grouse and partridges often feature. Scottish smoked salmon has long been celebrated, and the langoustine, mackerel or haddock can be similarly good. Fish and chip shops are widespread.</p><p>When it comes to eating out, visitors have a multitude of options these days, from high-end Michelin-starred dining and gourmet rural restaurants to stylish vegetarian cafés, farm shops and traditional pub lunches.</p><p>In Scotland's cities, you'll come across a huge assortment of international cuisine; Glasgow in particular is famed for its Italian restaurants and first-rate curry houses. Scots won't deny that they're prone to the odd sugary or deep-fried temptation, but new ranks of celebrity chefs have helped change outside perception.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Porridge:</strong> A traditional Scottish breakfast made from locally grown oats and either milk or water.<br />
<strong>Haggis:</strong> Chopped oatmeal and offal, traditionally cooked in the stomach of a sheep and served with neeps (turnips) and tatties (potatoes).<br />
<strong>Cullen skink:</strong> A thick soup of smoked haddock.<br />
<strong>Smoked salmon:</strong> Usually served in slices.<br />
<strong>Partan bree:</strong> Crab broth with rice and cream.<br />
<strong>Arbroath smokies:</strong> Smoked haddock.<br />
<strong>Stornoway black pudding:</strong> A savoury pudding made from pig&rsquo;s blood.<br />
<strong>Cranachan:</strong> Whipped cream, whisky, honey, raspberries and oatmeal.<br />
<strong>Clootie dumpling:</strong> Traditional steamed pudding cooked in a cloth.<br />
<strong>Tunnock&rsquo;s teacakes:</strong> Soft marshmallow on a biscuit base coated in milk chocolate.<br />
<strong>Whisky:</strong> Scotland&rsquo;s most famous export; you really shouldn&rsquo;t leave without sampling a few drams.<br />
<strong>Irn-Bru:</strong> A sweet fizzy drink that&rsquo;s bright orange in colour.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10-15% is typical</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18. If you appear to be under the age of 25 and are buying alcohol, you could be asked for ID.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/edinburgh-airport">Edinburgh</a> has a vibrant nightlife, with many bars, restaurants, and entertainment venues to discover. See new theatre at the Traverse Theatre and classical shows at the Festival and Playhouse Theatres, while classical music fans should head for the Usher Hall. During August, the city is a magnet for worldwide talent as the annual Edinburgh Festival attracts global audiences.</p>
<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/glasgow-airport">Glasgow</a> claims to have 700 pubs and clubs, ranging from the original to the bizarre, with much focused around the West End. The Citizens Theatre is famous for its cutting-edge productions, while the SECC (Scottish Exhibition and Conference Centre) is a popular concert arena for live bands.</p>
<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/aberdeen-airport">Aberdeen</a> has some cosy pubs, ideal for a pint, or a <em>wee dram</em> (small whisky) on a cold winter's evening. A night out in the compact riverside city of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/inverness-airport">Inverness</a> is also likely to focus on pubs, where you might find some Gaelic music being played. Try the local Black Isle beers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/edinburgh-airport">Edinburgh</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/glasgow-airport">Glasgow</a> vie for the title of Scotland&rsquo;s best shopping destination, but Glasgow probably has the edge over its easterly rival. Glaswegians are stylish and love to look good, and there&rsquo;s a first-rate assortment of both well-known names and independent boutiques to sate their retail requirements. It has been known to rain in Glasgow, so thankfully there are plenty of indoor shopping opportunities: among these, Buchanan Galleries houses top high-street names, Princes Square is an upmarket alternative and the Argyll Arcade is the place to hunt for some bling. Back outside, Ingram Street is the place to head for designer labels. For something different and quirky, try Byres Road in the West End.</p>
<p>That said, Edinburgh is fast catching up with Glasgow in terms of shopping status. George Street is home to a whole host of classy and trendy brands, from Hobbs and Jaeger to Hollister and Jack Wills. Though no longer independent, Edinburgh&rsquo;s oldest department store Jenners is worth a browse &ndash; the food hall stocks some scrumptious Scottish specialities. Harvey Nichols and adjacent Multrees Walk keep high-end shoppers kitted out in Armani, Louis Vuitton and other designer brands. Fill your bags with delectable fresh local produce at the Edinburgh Farmers&rsquo; Market.</p>
<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/aberdeen-airport">Aberdeen</a> is giving its southern cousins a run for their money with the flashy Union Square shopping centre, which contains 60 shops, restaurants, a cinema and a hotel.</p>
<p>The less trodden high streets of country villages have handmade items for sale in small shops. Examples of traditional Scottish crafts are everywhere, including woven tartans, tweed, wool sweaters, jewellery and paintings. Jams, meat pies and whiskies are also local specialities.</p><p>Shops are generally open from 0900-1730. Unlike in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england">England</a>, larger stores can stay open all day on Sundays. Edinburgh, Glasgow and Aberdeen all have late-night shopping on Thursdays until 2000. Some small towns have a half-day when shops close at lunchtime, often on Wednesday. Shops may be closed on Sundays in smaller places and will almost certainly be closed in the Western Isles.</p><p>Visitors from outside the EU can claim back VAT on purchases from stores participating in the VAT Retail Export Scheme. See <a href="http://www.global-blue.com" target="_blank">www.global-blue.com</a> for further information.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Scotland range from five-star luxury, mostly in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/edinburgh-airport">Edinburgh</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/glasgow-airport">Glasgow</a>, to quirky, individual, small hotels in the Highlands. Outside the cities, many hotels make a special effort to cater for walkers and cyclists with facilities such as drying rooms and bike sheds.</p>
<p>VisitScotland runs a Green Tourism Business Scheme, which encourages all types of accommodation to improve their environmental credentials, for example by using low-energy lightbulbs, featuring local produce on the menu or promoting wildlife walks in the area. You can search for GTBS-accredited properties on VisitScotland&rsquo;s website (<a href="http://www.visitscotland.com" target="_blank">www.visitscotland.com</a>). There are over 700 members, each given a Bronze, Silver or Gold award.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Accommodation in Scotland is classified using a star rating system of 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Family-run bed &amp; breakfasts can be a good way to see the country (particularly in remote parts of the Highlands), with the chance to chat to locals thrown in. Hosts usually offer a classic Scottish breakfast with eggs, bacon, toast and often haggis. Accommodation can range from the flowery and fussy to the über-modern.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Scotland range from five-star luxury, mostly in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/edinburgh-airport">Edinburgh</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/glasgow-airport">Glasgow</a>, to quirky, individual, small hotels in the Highlands. Outside the cities, many hotels make a special effort to cater for walkers and cyclists with facilities such as drying rooms and bike sheds.</p>
<p>VisitScotland runs a Green Tourism Business Scheme, which encourages all types of accommodation to improve their environmental credentials, for example by using low-energy lightbulbs, featuring local produce on the menu or promoting wildlife walks in the area. You can search for GTBS-accredited properties on VisitScotland&rsquo;s website (<a href="http://www.visitscotland.com" target="_blank">www.visitscotland.com</a>). There are over 700 members, each given a Bronze, Silver or Gold award.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Accommodation in Scotland is classified using a star rating system of 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Scotland range from five-star luxury, mostly in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/edinburgh-airport">Edinburgh</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/glasgow-airport">Glasgow</a>, to quirky, individual, small hotels in the Highlands. Outside the cities, many hotels make a special effort to cater for walkers and cyclists with facilities such as drying rooms and bike sheds.</p>
<p>VisitScotland runs a Green Tourism Business Scheme, which encourages all types of accommodation to improve their environmental credentials, for example by using low-energy lightbulbs, featuring local produce on the menu or promoting wildlife walks in the area. You can search for GTBS-accredited properties on VisitScotland&rsquo;s website (<a href="http://www.visitscotland.com" target="_blank">www.visitscotland.com</a>). There are over 700 members, each given a Bronze, Silver or Gold award.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Accommodation in Scotland is classified using a star rating system of 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>2nd January :
							2018<br/>02 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Early May Bank Holiday :
							07 May </p><p>Spring Bank Holiday :
							28 May </p><p>Summer Bank Holiday :
							06 August </p><p>St Andrew's Day :
							30 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pound (GBP; symbol £) = 100 pence. Notes are in denominations of £50, 20, 10, 5 and 1. Coins are in denominations of £2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 pence. Scotland has its own bank notes (produced by three different banks – The Royal Bank of Scotland, the Bank of Scotland and Clydesdale Bank), but English notes have exactly the same value and are accepted as well. You'll receive Scottish notes from ATMs and usually as change too. Coins are identical.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can exchange foreign currency in banks, bureaux de change, post offices and some hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, MasterCard and Visa are all widely accepted. Cash can be obtained from a multitude of ATMs available across the country.</p><p>You can withdraw cash from a multitude of ATMs available across the country. Stock up on cash if you're visiting any rural areas however, as remote villages won't necessarily have an ATM. If you're travelling from overseas, it's worth letting your bank know that you're planning on using your debit card abroad so the bank doesn't think the card is being used fraudulently.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Widely accepted in banks and bureaux de change. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Pounds Sterling. Many travellers now find it easier to purchase a prepaid currency card which can then be used in the same way as a debit card, either to withdraw money or to pay for goods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700 (there may be some variations in closing times). Some banks are open Saturday morning; some all day Saturday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[56.490671]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-4.202646]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>78,772 sq km (30,414 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>5.3 million (2014).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>67.9 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Edinburgh.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy, with some powers devolved from the UK government to the Scottish government.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Scotland consists of the southern Lowland area, a region of moorland and pastoral scenery (where most of the population is concentrated) and the northern Highlands, dominated by the Grampian Mountains and the Northwest Highlands. Ben Nevis, at 1,344m (4,409ft) is the highest peak in the British Isles. Scotland&rsquo;s capital city, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/edinburgh-airport">Edinburgh</a>, lies in the southeast of the country on the Firth of Forth, while <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/glasgow-airport">Glasgow</a>, its largest metropolis, is situated on the River Clyde around 72km (45 miles) to the west. Dundee and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/aberdeen-airport">Aberdeen</a> are both located on the east coast. Scotland&rsquo;s longest river is the Tay, which courses a route of 193km (120 miles) from the western Highlands through <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/western-australia/perth-airport">Perth</a> and into the North Sea at the Firth of Tay, immediately south of Dundee.</p>
<p>Scotland&rsquo;s coastline is exceptionally beautiful, particularly the west coast, which is indented with lochs. Off the west coast there are many islands, the largest of which are Skye and Lewis, the latter being part of the Outer Hebrides. The archipelagos of Orkney and Shetland lie to the northeast of the Scottish mainland; Orkney is directly across the Pentland Firth from John O'Groats, while Shetland lies 80km (50 miles) further northeast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Predominantly Christian (around 40% Church of Scotland, 15% Roman Catholic and 6% other Christian denominations) with small Buddhist, Muslim, Hindu and Sikh minorities. Around a quarter of the population have no religion.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is customary when introduced to someone for the first time. Normal social courtesies should be observed when visiting someone's home and a small present such as flowers or chocolates is appreciated. It is polite to wait until everyone has been served before eating.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with three square pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Theresa May since July 2016 (UK Government). First Minister Nicola Sturgeon since 2014 (Scottish government).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Scottish history is dotted with stirring, colourful figures, from Robert the Bruce and Bonnie Prince Charlie to William Wallace and Mary Queen of Scots, although its written history begins with the arrival of the Romans in the 1st century AD. The invaders found strong resistance from the land&rsquo;s current occupants, the Picts, which eventually led to Roman construction of Hadrian&rsquo;s Wall.</p>
<p>Scotland was then subjected to Viking attacks and Norman influence. There was an infamous power-grab from the English in 1296, when Edward I deposed Scotland&rsquo;s King John. William &lsquo;Braveheart&rsquo; Wallace briefly ruled until being captured and executed.</p>
<p>Key events over the following centuries include the Battle of Bannockburn in 1314, where Edward II was defeated by Robert the Bruce, and the 16th-century renewal of the &lsquo;Auld Alliance&rsquo; between Scotland and France, which saw the Scots invade England. In the tense decades that followed, Mary Queen of Scots was sentenced to death by Elizabeth I.</p>
<p>Despite the 1707 Treaty of Union between Scotland and England, there has always been a strong independent spirit in the nation. It still retains its own banknotes, legal and education systems, and from 1999 Scotland regained its own parliament as part of the devolution process. The Scottish parliament has powers over a number of domestic policies.</p>
<p>Scottish National Party (SNP) leader Alex Salmond made political history in 2007 after becoming the first nationalist to be elected First Minister of Scotland, heading the first minority administration since devolution. The banking crisis hit Scotland&rsquo;s confidence, however, battering its image as a strong financial centre, with The Royal Bank of Scotland at the centre of a media storm.</p>
<p>In 2011, the SNP won an outright majority in the Scottish parliamentary elections and held a referendum on independence in 2014. A hard-fought campaign on both sides resulted in the &lsquo;No&rsquo; side winning, having accrued some 55% of the public vote. However, the SNP made history again at the UK general election in 2015, taking 56 of 59 seats in the country and becoming the third largest party in the Commons, under the leadership of First Minister Nicola Sturgeon. An appetite for independence lingers.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; 'Ivanhoe by Sir Walter Scott' is a perfect anagram of 'novel by a Scottish writer'. <br />
&bull;	With something of a lack of foresight, King James II once ordered that &ldquo;futeball and the golfe be utterly cryit down&rdquo; &ndash; he was concerned the sports were stopping his yeomen practice their archery. <br />
&bull;	When Queen Victoria visited the Highlands, it&rsquo;s said she smoked cigarettes to keep away midges. <br />
&bull;	Edinburgh was the first city on the planet to have its own fire brigade.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Crammed with sky-high mountains, rugged coastlines, romantic lochs, cultured cities and a fiercely proud people, bonnie Scotland is an incredible destination.</p>
<p>One day you could be quaffing smoked salmon and single malt in the glens and the next you could be tracking the Jacobite forces at Culloden Battlefield or following in the footsteps of royalty at Stirling Castle.</p>
<p>That's assuming you aren't busy swigging local craft ales at music festivals, trailing Harry Potter on the real Hogwarts Express or guffawing along to stand-up comedy at the famous Edinburgh Festival Fringe.</p>
<p>Although compact, Scotland is studded with an astonishing number of ancient monuments and buildings, which span many millennia.</p>
<p>Travel back in time 5,000 years at the UNESCO-listed Heart of Neolithic Orkney and wonder at its prehistoric settlements and burial tombs; delve into Scotland&rsquo;s turbulent past at citadels and forts like Eilean Donan Castle and Finlarig; or just gaze in awe at the Calanais Stones in Lewis.</p>
<p>Scotland&rsquo;s largest cities, Edinburgh and Glasgow, provide exceptional galleries and museums, stylish boutiques, innovative restaurants, traditional pubs, chic cocktail bars and hip hotels.</p>
<p>Beyond the cities, Scotland's charming abbey towns, coastal villages and remote, Gaelic-speaking Highland communities entice visitors with their picturesque buildings, scenic walks and warm welcomes.</p>
<p>Many also host eccentric festivals; from porridge-making championships to the traditional Highland Games (complete with caber tossing and hammer throwing).</p>
<p>Scotland is also a Mecca for outdoor enthusiasts. Adrenaline-junkies can hurtle down the rapids in Perthshire, test their nerves climbing ice falls in Glencoe and trek through dramatic glens along the spectacular West Highland Way.</p>
<p>Those seeking more genteel diversions can track the elusive wildcat in Cairngorms National Park, go whale watching in the Orkneys, salmon fishing on the River Tweed and, of course, tee off at St. Andrews.</p>
<p>A land of mountains and music, glaciers and golf, castles and cabers, wildcats and whales &ndash; Scotland has it all, bar the weather.</p>Crammed with sky-high mountains, rugged coastlines, romantic lochs, cultured cities and a fiercely proud people, bonnie Scotland is an incredible destination. A land of mountains and music, glaciers and golf, castles and cabers, wildcats and whales – this wee nation has it all, bar the weather.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
