<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="England" ColCode="eng" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="en" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[England]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The weather in England is temperate, with warm wet summers and cool wet winters. Weather varies from day to day and throughout the country as a whole. In general, the west coast and mountainous areas receive the most rain.</p>
<p>Winters range from late October to early March.<strong> </strong>The east coast, particularly in the north, is colder and windier with winds blowing in from Siberia; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cambridge">Cambridge</a>, Yorkshire and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england/newcastle-international-airport">Newcastle</a> suffer the brunt of this. Cold snaps with heavy snow can cause problems with transport and infrastructure; those from cooler climates may marvel at how a relatively innocuous snow storm can bring transport to a standstill but severe storms are still quite uncommon. Temperatures have been known to hit -5&deg;C (23&deg;F) during winter but in England temperatures below this are rare.<br />
<br />
Summers range from May to early September. The southeast is the sunnier than the north of the country, with less rain and a climate approaching the continental. During summer, temperatures can reach as high as 30&deg;C (86&deg;F); the southwest has the mildest climate overall. <br />
<br />
England has much to occupy whatever the season, but the best chance of catching sunny days is between May and September. Popular summer holidaying spots such as <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brighton">Brighton</a>, Devon and Cornwall become particularly crowded during the end of July and throughout August when schools are closed.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>England's reputation for rain is deserved, so pack some rainwear in the form of coats, umbrellas and appropriate footwear. During summer, shorts, sandals and t-shirts are fine, but bring extra layers as weather can be changeable, and temperatures cool down considerably in the evenings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Despite the its small size, there are domestic flights available from London to most if not all of the major regional cities around England. Manchester and Birmingham International Airport are two of the biggest regional airports outside London.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>England has a large network of rivers and canals but these are used for leisure travel rather than a purposeful means of getting around. The Environment Agency (<a href="http://www.environment-agency.gov.uk" target="_blank">www.environment-agency.gov.uk</a>) gives comprehensive advice to those wishing to sail the UK&rsquo;s waterways.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travelling by train in the UK is a popular way to see the country but the system can be confusing and it's expensive. Different private operators are responsible for different routes (usually categorised by region), making negotiating smooth passage throughout the country tricky for nationals and travellers alike. The official information source for UK rail journeys is National Rail (tel: +44 207 278 5240; <a href="http://www.nationalrail.co.uk" target="_blank">www.nationalrail.co.uk</a>) where fare information and timetables are easy to find. Tickets can be purchased here, directly at the train operator&rsquo;s website or at the station but buying fares on the same day of travel almost always works out more expensive. In general, the further in advance you buy tickets, the cheaper the fare, but look out for concessionary fares for under-25s, seniors and on group travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>BritRail (<a href="http://www.britrail.com" target="_blank">www.britrail.com</a>) offers a variety of rail passes which allow travel around various regions of the UK. It is only available to non-UK residents for purchase. Tickets can be purchased up to six months in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving around England by car is one of the best ways to get around and see the country if you are travelling outside the major cities. The road network is extensive, and even the smallest of villages is accessible via lanes and small highways whilst motorways and trunk roads connect larger towns and cities. The M1 and M6 motorways connect London to the north, whilst the M4 motorway connects London to the East, into Wales. The M25 is an orbital ring road around the outskirts of London.</p>l<p>Road quality is good, with towns and cities clearly signposted and street lamps and cat's eyes lit up at night. Major cities may experience congestion at peak commuter times or because of road works.</p><p>There is a good coach network linking the major towns and cities across England. National Express (tel: 0871 781 8181; <a href="http://www.nationalexpress.com" target="_blank">www.nationalexpress.com</a>) and Megabus (tel: +44 141 352 4444; <a href="http://uk.megabus.com" target="_blank">http://uk.megabus.com</a>) are two popular services.</p><p>Taxis in England come in two forms - private hire vehicles known as minicabs, or Hackney carriages (also called black cabs). Minicabs differ in shapes and sizes but must be ordered beforehand and cannot be flagged down in the street. Fares are at the discretion of the taxi firm but a price is usually negotiated beforehand. Black cabs are the only taxis allowed to pick up fares on the street or from designated ranks. Journeys are metered, with fares set by the local authority. If the taxi light is on, this means the taxi is available and can be flagged down. Uber operates in most major cities.</p><p>Drivers over 17 years, with a full and valid licence are free to drive in the UK for 12 months from the time of last entry into the UK.</p><p>The speed limit for cars is 112kph (70mph) for motorways and dual carriageways, 96kph (60mph) for single carriageways, and 48 kph (30mph) in built up areas. Seatbelts are compulsory, and it is illegal to use a mobile phone or similar device when driving. The blood alcohol limit for drivers is 0.08%.</p><p>If you break down, pull over to side of the road (or the hard shoulder if on the motorway) and put on hazard warning lights. If on the motorway you can call the Highways Agency from the emergency roadside phones that are spaced at intervals of 1.6km (1 mile). Alternatively, do call your car hire provider; many will have 24 hour breakdown cover. The AA (tel: 08457 887 766; <a href="http://www.theaa.com" target="_blank">www.theaa.com</a>) and RAC (tel: 0800 828 282; <a href="http://www.rac.co.uk" target="_blank">www.rac.co.uk</a>) are two well known providers of breakdown cover.</p><p>Cars are available for hire in most major towns and cities from the major providers.</p><p>Cycling has always been popular as a pasttime in England but more and more people are using bikes as a method of transport, with London in particular seeing an increase in urban cyclists. As a method of getting around cities, cycling can often be a quicker option than taking a car or public transport. It is possible to travel long distance by bike but cyclists must stick to local routes and paths rather than major arterial roads.</p><p>The speed limit for cars is 112kph (70mph) for motorways and dual carriageways, 96kph (60mph) for single carriageways, and 48 kph (30mph) in built up areas. Seatbelts are compulsory, and it is illegal to use a mobile phone or similar device when driving. The blood alcohol limit for drivers is 0.08%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All towns and cities have bus and taxi services. In addition, a few cities have trams, whilst Birmingham, Liverpool, Sheffield, Manchester and the cities in South Yorkshire and Newcastle have suburban rail services. Newcastle also has an underground metro. <br />
<br />
London has a comprehensive public transport system, which is run by Transport for London (Tfl) (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.tfl.gov.uk/">www.tfl.gov.uk</a>). The London Underground (colloquially, &lsquo;the tube') is the world&rsquo;s oldest subway system, and in conjunction with the Docklands Light Railway (DLR) covers most of central London. Information on timetables and help with planning journeys around in London can be found on the Transport for London website and mobile app.</p>
<p>There is also an extensive network of buses, as well as overground rail services branching out to the suburbs. Leisure and commuter boat services on the River Thames are run by a variety of private companies whilst taxis can be hailed in the street or ordered by phone.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flights to England are well served by the major global airline carriers and the country is extremely accessible by air. National carrier British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com">www.ba.com</a>) flies long haul routes from many of the world&rsquo;s destinations including <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tokyo">Tokyo</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/shanghai">Shanghai</a> and Sydney. Other airlines, including Virgin (<a href="http://www.virginatlantic.com" target="_blank">www.virginatlantic.com</a>) and Lufthansa (<a href="http://www.lufthansa.com" target="_blank">www.lufthansa.com</a>) also run regular transatlantic flights. Short haul flights from mainland Europe are served by a plethora of low cost airlines including Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>) and easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>) who as well as flying to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>, also fly to regional bases <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/manchester/manchester-airport">Manchester</a> and Birmingham International.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From New York: 7 hours 10 minutes</p>
<p>From Sydney: 23 hours (including stopover)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Leeds Bradford International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.leedsbradfordairport.co.uk<p>Leeds Bradford International Airport is situated 18km (11 miles) northwest of Leeds and 11km (7 miles) north of Bradford in West Yorkshire.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+44 871 288 2288</p>]]><b>London Gatwick Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.gatwickairport.com<p>London Gatwick Airport is located 45km (28 miles) south of London.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+44 844 892 0322</p>]]><b>London Heathrow Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.heathrow.com<p>London Heathrow Airport is located 24km (15 miles) west of central London.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+44 844 335 1801</p>]]><b>London Luton Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.london-luton.co.uk<p>London Luton Airport is located 51km (32 miles) north of central London.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+44 1582 405 100.</p>]]><b>London Stansted Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.stanstedairport.com<p>London Stansted Airport is located 48km (30 miles) northeast of central London, in Essex.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+44 844 335 1803.</p>]]><b>Manchester Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.manchesterairport.co.uk<p>Manchester Airport is located 17km (10 miles) southwest of central Manchester.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+44 871 271 0711.</p>]]><b>London Southend Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.southendairport.com]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(01702) 538 500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>England is accessible via ferry across the Channel or the North Sea, from several countries on the coast of mainland Europe. Most common departures are from France, Spain and the Netherlands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are connections to London and Ashford (Kent) from major cities all over Europe through the Channel Tunnel with Eurostar (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.eurostar.com">www.eurostar.com</a>).<br />
<br />
England's rail network (tel: +44 207 278 5240; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.nationalrail.co.uk">www.nationalrail.co.uk</a>) serves all main cities in the UK mainland. Rail services are operated by numerous private companies. Routes tend to radiate from London.<br />
<br />
There are rail services to Fishguard, Holyhead and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/liverpool">Liverpool</a>, from where travellers can catch ferries departing for the Republic of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ireland">Ireland</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/northern-ireland">Northern Ireland</a>.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Walk-up railway fares can be  expensive, especially if travel is at peak times, so travellers may find better value in buying a rail pass. The InterRail Global pass (<a href="http://www.interrail.eu" target="_blank">www.interrail.eu</a>) allows travel to 30 countries including the UK. Travellers may choose between travelling over a consecutive period of time, or on a set number of days within a given time period.  Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>) offers a variety of passes for train travel around Europe but please note that these do not cover travel to or around the UK.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>England is accessible from mainland Europe by road via the Eurotunnel (<a href="http://www.eurotunnel.com" target="_blank">www.eurotunnel.com</a>) which connects Calais in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a>, to Folkestone on the south coast. Coach services from all over Europe connect to the UK this way, with many offering express and stopping services throughout England and the rest of the UK. The main operator, National Express (tel: 0871 781 8181; <a href="http://www.nationalexpress.com" target="_blank">www.nationalexpress.com</a>), provides nationwide coach information. It is also easy to drive across in your own car for a fee &ndash; note that passage through the Eurotunnel does not entail driving through the actual tunnel. Instead the car is transported on a train which then makes the crossing. Travel time is approximately half an hour.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Alton Towers</p><![CDATA[<p>Alton Towers is the UK's most popular theme park, attracting the young and old alike with its vast selection of whizzing rides and flashing attractions. The park, which opened in 1980, also includes 200 acres (81 hectares) of landscaped gardens, live entertainment and the historic towers building which was the residence of the Talbot family (the Earls of Shrewsbury) until 1923.</p>]]><br/><p>Cheddar Gorge and Caves </p><![CDATA[<p>The spectacular Cheddar Caves and Gorge complex has been attracting visitors for over 200 years with caverns that were carved out by Ice Age melt waters over a million years ago. Archaeological finds include the discovery of the Cheddar Man - at 9,000 years old, Britain's oldest complete skeleton. Human habitation in and around the site dates back over 40,000 years. The most famous cave, Gough's cave stretches 0.4km (0.25 miles) underground whilst above, 274 steps known as Jacob's Ladder take visitors from the foot of Britain's biggest gorge to the very top. Caving, climbing and abseiling courses can also be arranged at the site.</p>]]><br/><p>Chessington World of Adventures</p><![CDATA[<p>Chessington World of Adventures is the biggest theme park and zoo in the South of England. The park began life as a zoo, but was transformed into a theme park during the late 1980s, with the first rollercoaster ride opening in 1991. The park attracts thousands of visitors each day who come to enjoy the rides and zoo. The latter, which has been combined with the park, is home to one of the biggest families of gorillas in Europe and some of the world's rarest large cats.<br />Highlights of the park include the Trail of the Kings animal enclosure, which allows visitors to see animals safely from behind viewing screens, while the SEA LIFE Centre houses sharks and sting rays. In March 2010, the new Wild Asia land opens featuring a spinning disc ride called KOBRA, a jungle bus tour, a walk-through aviary in which visitors can hand feed nectar to birds plus a colourful Maharaja's Market.<br /><br /><br /><br /><br />Address: Chessington World of Adventures, Chessington, Surrey KT9 2NE, UK</p>]]><br/><p>Great Yarmouth</p><![CDATA[<p>Great Yarmouth's Pleasure Beach is set along a nine-acre seafront site on the picturesque East Anglian coastline. The Pleasure Beach is a traditional seaside resort built around a lively promenade and is a popular attraction for families. The Pleasure Beach's attractions include traditional fairground rides, arcades, flower gardens, mini golf and candy floss and ice cream stalls. It may have lost some of its grandeur but it nevertheless remains one of the most popular attractions in East Anglia and attracts close to 1.5 million visitors each year.</p>]]><br/><p>Harrods</p><![CDATA[<p>Harrods, perhaps London's most famous department store, is named after Charles Henry Harrod, who opened a family grocers shop on the site in 1849. The shop has grown to become a byword for expensive and glamourous shopping, priding itself on its motto Omnia Omnibus Ubique, meaning 'All things, for all people, everywhere'. Bought by Egyptian businessman Mohamed Al Fayed in 1985, the eye-catching seven-storey building, which is illuminated by 11,500 lightbulbs each night, contains over 300 departments selling luxury items, from furniture and ladies fashion to polo mallets and wax coats for dogs. For those on a tighter budget, there is a Harrods gift shop, selling assorted souvenirs such as pencils and teddybears. One department not to be missed is the world-famous Food Halls. Harrods also provides banking and real estate services, currency exchange facilities and, for those who want to see the British capital in style, a luxury coach tour of London complete with tea and biscuits.<br /><br /><br />Address: 87-135 Brompton Road, Knightbridge, London SW1X 7XL, UK</p>]]><br/><p>Harrods</p><![CDATA[<p>Harrods, perhaps London's most famous department store, is named after Charles Henry Harrod, who opened a family grocers shop on the site in 1849. The shop has grown to become a byword for expensive and glamourous shopping, priding itself on its motto Omnia Omnibus Ubique, meaning 'All things, for all people, everywhere'. Bought by Egyptian businessman Mohamed Al Fayed in 1985, the eye-catching seven-storey building, which is illuminated by 11,500 lightbulbs each night, contains over 300 departments selling luxury items, from furniture and ladies fashion to polo mallets and wax coats for dogs. For those on a tighter budget, there is a Harrods gift shop, selling assorted souvenirs such as pencils and teddybears. One department not to be missed is the world-famous Food Halls. Harrods also provides banking and real estate services, currency exchange facilities and, for those who want to see the British capital in style, a luxury coach tour of London complete with tea and biscuits.</p>]]><br/><p>Lake Windermere</p><![CDATA[<p>At 17kms (10.5 miles) long and plunging to 61m (200ft) deep in places, <i>Lake Windermere</i> is the largest lake in England. It forms part of the <i>Lake District National Park</i> and is in an area of outstanding natural beauty with numerous stunning walking trails. Many visitors prefer to explore the lake from the water itself and <i>Windermere Lake Cruises</i> (<a href="http://www.windermere-lakecruises.co.uk/">www.windermere-lakecruises.co.uk</a>) operate an extensive network of steamers and launches; a popular trip is the Islands Cruise from Bowness, which passes wooded islands and secluded bays. Other attractions in the area include the <i>Aquarium of the Lakes</i>, the <i>Beatrix Potter Attraction</i>, the <i>Lakeside and Haverthwaite Railway</i>, <i>Fell Foot Park</i> and the <i>South Lakes Wild Animal Park</i>.</p>]]><br/><p>London Zoo</p><![CDATA[<p><em>London Zoo</em>, which opened in 1828, is situated on the north side of Regent&rsquo;s Park. The zoo was the site of the world&rsquo;s first children&rsquo;s zoo, which opened in 1938, followed by the first reptile house in 1849, the first public aquarium in 1853 and the first insect house in 1881. Today, the Zoo is home to around 12,000 animals, including Asian lions, Sumatran tigers, Sloth bears, Leadbeater&rsquo;s possums and Death adders. The famous spiral-shaped <em>Penguin Pool</em>, which is Grade I listed,<em> </em>is the home of Black-footed penguins, whilst the<em> Aquarium </em>houses sharks, piranhas and other sea creatures.<em> </em>The zoo also has beautiful gardens, as well as innovative zoo buildings, designed by architects such as Decimus Burton who designed the <em>Giraffe House</em>, Berthold Lubetkin who was responsible for the Penguin Pool and Sir Hugh Casson, responsible for the <em>Elephant and Rhino Pavilion</em>.</p>
<p>Address:&nbsp;Outer Circle, Regent&rsquo;s Park, London NW1 4RY, UK</p>]]><br/><p>Neasden Temple</p><![CDATA[<p>The exotic sight of the Neasden <em>Shri Swaminarayan Temple</em> sits alongside suburban houses in Neasden in northwest London. The limestone Hindu temple was inspired by Lord Swaminarayan, an 18th century Indian guru who walked barefoot across the length of India raising awareness about the plight of the country&rsquo;s poor and downtrodden people. It was built using an estimated 2,000 tons of Italian marble and 3,000 tonnes of Bulgarian limestone which had first been shipped to India where 1,000 local craftsmen volunteered their skills to sculpt the elaborate structure that now stands in West London.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Address:&nbsp;105/115 Brentfield Road, Neasden, London NW10 8JP</p>]]><br/><p>Poole Harbour</p><![CDATA[<p>Poole Harbour is a vibrant quay on England's southern coast that bustles with an array of bars, cafes and restaurants. Visitors wanting to learn more about the history of the region can follow the newly developed Cockle Trail discovering myths and legends about Poole's smugglers and ghosts of yesteryear. A series of brass plaques mark the way charting 750 years of Poole's history culminating at the Waterfront Museum. Popular sports in and around the harbour include windsurfing, kitesurfing, water-skiing, wakeboarding, surfing, snorkelling and kayaking. Of course, boat trips are popular and visitors can sail out to the National Trust's Brownsea Island, protected for its wildlife and peaceful woodland walks.</p>]]><br/><p>Royal Academy of Arts</p><![CDATA[<p>Located in London's Piccadilly, the Royal Academy of Arts is an independent fine arts institution which supports contemporary artists and promotes interest in the arts through a comprehensive exhibition programme. It was founded in 1768 with Sir Joshua Reynolds as its first President; today it is governed by Royal Academicians - eminent practising painters, printmakers, sculptors and architects. The RA attracts well over one million visitors each year, making it one of London's top ten attractions.</p>]]><br/><p>St Michael's Mount</p><![CDATA[<p>Perched proudly on a rocky island, St Michael's Mount rises 70m (230 ft) from sea level and is one of Cornwall's best-known attractions. According to legend, it was built by a giant called Cormoran who terrorised local farmers, but history tells us that the Abbot of Mont St Michel in Normandy built it in 1135. Over the years it has been a priory, a fort, a pilgrimage site and a private residence for the St Aubyn family. In 1954, the family partnered with the National Trust opening up the castle and grounds to the public. At low tide it's possible to walk out across the causeway to St Michael's Mount; remember to check local tide times first.</p>]]><br/><p>Stonehenge</p><![CDATA[<p>Erected between 3000 and 1600 BC, Stonehenge is a giant stone circle that stands on Salisbury Plain and is considered today to be one of the most famous surviving sites from the ancient world. The stones, which stand at 6.7m (22ft) high, attract hundreds of visitors every day, who come to marvel at the ingenuity of those who engineered the construction of the site and the techniques used to move and position the stones. There are also many burial mounds nearby, as well as long barrows from the Neolithic Age, the most famous of which is West Kennet Long Barrow. Visitors can also look forward to seeing the new Visitor's Centre where guests will be able to virtually 'stand in the stones', see 300 other prehistoric objects on display, and check out the museum detailing the various theories about how Stonehenge came to be.</p>]]><br/><p>Swaffham I Ecotech Centre</p><![CDATA[<p>Owned and operated by Ecotricity, <em>Swaffham I</em> is the first multi-megawatt wind turbine in the UK and is one of a new generation of direct drive, variable speed wind turbines. Located in Swaffham in rural Norfolk, the turbine was installed at the <em>Ecotech Centre</em> in 1999 and represents what the future could be like for power generation. A second turbine was built in 2003 and together the two turbines produce enough electricity for approximately 7,000 people &ndash; about 75 per cent of the town. The Ecotech Centre is an environmental education centre and Swaffham I includes a viewing platform which is accessed via a 300-step spiral staircase. Since opening, over 50,000 people have visited the site.</p>]]><br/><p>Tamworth (Drayton Manor Family Theme Park)</p><![CDATA[<p><i>Drayton Manor Theme Park</i> is set in 280 acres of lakes and parkland and offers a fun day out for young and old alike. Thrill seekers will enjoy rides such as the <i>Cyclone</i>, <i>Shockwave</i>, <i>Pandemonium</i>, <i>G-Force</i> and <i>Apocalypse</i> &ndash; the world's first stand-up drop tower. There's also the <i>Drayton Manor Zoo</i> that's home to over 100 species from all over the world including big cats, monkeys, reptiles and an exotic creature reserve. In addition to the theme park and zoo, Drayton Manor also hosts wedding receptions and corporate events at its function rooms.</p>]]><br/><p>Wookey Hole Caves</p><![CDATA[<p>Situated in the heart of Somerset, the Wookey Hole caves are a spectacular sight. Evidence of early man around Wookey Hole can be traced back over 50,000 years and as well as human artefacts, other finds include the bones of tropical and Ice Age animals such as rhinoceros, bear, mammoth and lion. Visitors can tour the caves, meet the Wookey Hole witch and enjoy other attractions including the Dinosaur Valley with life-size models of dinosaurs.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire architecture and art in York</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its medieval architecture, magnificent minster (northern Europe's largest church) and ancient city walls, York demands a stop on any English itinerary. York Museum will reveal the city's Viking past, whilst the surrounding countryside and smaller towns are showing a burgeoning cultural revolution, spurred by the new Hepworth Wakefield gallery in Wakefield and Yorkshire Sculpture Park nearby.</p>]]><p><b>Delight in delicious Devon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Clear the cobwebs on a blustery walk along the spectacularly rugged North Devon Coast, exploring its castles and coves. If you are feeling brave enough, try a spot of surfing, before sating your appetite with a delicious Devonshire cream tea – a pot of tea drunk with a combination of scones, clotted cream and jam.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the illustrious past of Leeds Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located in Kent (rather than the northern city it shares a name with), Leeds Castle is built on two islands in a lake. Over the centuries, six medieval queens and Henry VIII have called the castle home. Famed for its aviary, which includes black swans, the castle features fine art and tapestries as well as a maze, vineyard and Culpeper Garden outside.</p>]]><p><b>Experience the high life at Chatsworth House</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the opulent Chatsworth House, perhaps the country's finest country home. Set in the Peak District, among sculptures, parks and woodland full of deer, this stately home was once used as a prison by Elizabeth I. The seat of the Duke of Devonshire, the house is an insight into the British aristocracy through the ages.</p>]]><p><b>Find the Fab Four and much more in Liverpool</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Liverpool is a city transformed. Once the butt of Scouser jokes and stereotypes, it's now a flourishing, cultured city. The arrival of the Tate art gallery, the waterfront and Albert Dock regeneration and the Museum of Liverpool have reshaped the city into a dynamic hub. Thankfully, its musical heritage still remains – see where the Beatles first performed at the Cavern Club.</p>]]><p><b>Head for the bright lights of Blackpool</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Blackpool has been attracting holiday visitors since 1735 when the city's first guesthouse opened. Today, the Blackpool Pleasure Beach amusement park draws in tourists of all tastes and ages with rides and rollercoasters. The 156m-tall (518ft) Blackpool Tower houses a ballroom, an aquarium and viewing deck and dominates the skyline along Blackpool's lively promenade. </p>]]><p><b>Learn about Poole Harbour's pirate past</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Poole Harbour is a vibrant quay on England's southern coast that bustles with an array of bars, cafes and restaurants. Follow the Cockle Trail to discover myths and legends about Poole's smugglers and ghosts of yesteryear, culminating at the Waterfront Museum. Adventure-seekers can try watersports in and around the harbour or take a ferry to the National Trust's Brownsea Island.</p>]]><p><b>Play on the pleasure pier in Brighton</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Shop around the bustling Laines in the bohemian seaside town of Brighton, before picking up some fish and chips and taking a long shore-side stoll. Set in lavish gardens is the ornate former seaside home of George IV, Brighton's Royal Pavilion. On the beach Brighton Pier brims with life, whilst the burnt-out bones of the West Pier cut a forlorn figure.</p>]]><p><b>Re-live history at Warwick Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Imagine life in the imposing Warwick Castle, first built by William the Conqueror in 1068. Along with Leeds in Kent, it is one of the best-preserved castles in England. See the castle come to life with mediaeval re-enactments, tours of the Dungeons, and interactive experiences such as Merlin: The Dragon Tower.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the roller coasters at Alton Towers</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Alton Towers is the UK's most popular theme park, attracting young and old alike with its vast selection of whizzing rides and flashing attractions. The park, which opened in 1980, also includes 200 acres (81 hectares) of landscaped gardens, live entertainment and the historic towers building which was the residence of the Talbot family (the Earls of Shrewsbury) until 1923.</p>]]><p><b>Rove London, England's greatest city</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Britain's capital is one of the world's greatest. Visit a huge range of museums and galleries; melt the credit card in its shops and markets, and (over)indulge in its restaurants, bars, pubs and nightclubs. Look out over the city from the gigantic Shard building or spend an afternoon ogling the crown jewels in the Tower of London.</p>]]><p><b>See a traditional British seaside in Southwold</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Situated on the north Suffolk coastline, Southwold is a traditional seaside town that forms part of the Suffolk Heritage Coast. With its brightly painted beach huts, working lighthouse, harbour and bustling fish markets, Southwold is a quintessential English resort town of yesteryear without the brashness of a pleasure beach.</p>]]><p><b>See some Shakespeare at Stratford-upon-Avon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Catch a performance by the Royal Shakespeare Company at the Royal Shakespeare Theatre in Stratford-upon-Avon, the birthplace of William Shakespeare. Set on the banks of the River Avon, Stratford makes a delightfully picturesque setting for numerous festivals and events over the year, including a literary festival in April and a river festival in July.</p>]]><p><b>Speculate at Stonehenge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Erected between 3000 and 1600 BC, Stonehenge is a giant stone circle that stands on Salisbury Plain and is one of the most famous surviving sites from the ancient world. Marvel at the stones and the ingenuity of the construction; the interactive visitor centre has various theories about how the structure came to be and houses over 250 prehistoric treasures.</p>]]><p><b>Stroll the beautiful city of Bath</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit limestone-clad Bath and enjoy high-end boutiques and lovely restaurants before submerging yourself in the city's famous Roman baths. Perfectly preserved Georgian terraces embody a genteel reputation, with the Royal Crescent a must-see, whilst literature fans will want to visit the Jane Austen Centre, a museum dedicated to Bath's most famous resident.</p>]]><p><b>Stroll, swim and sail at the scenic Lake Windermere</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At 17km (10.5 miles) long and plunging to 61m (200ft) deep, Lake Windermere is the largest lake in England. It forms part of the Lake District National Park and is in a designated Area of Outstanding Natural Beauty with numerous stunning walking trails, although many visitors prefer to explore the lake from the water itself.</p>]]><p><b>Study the sights at Oxford and Cambridge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the two most important seats of learning in the country: Oxford and Cambridge. Oxford University is the oldest university in the English-speaking world, having existed since the 11th century. Cambridge University was founded in 1209. Both are beautiful cities full of centuries-old colleges, cosy ancient pubs and architectural gems with the larger, Oxford, full of cosmopolitan zeal.</p>]]><p><b>Visit royalty at Windsor Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Windsor Castle is one of the homes of Queen Elizabeth II and is the largest and oldest occupied castle in the world. Painstakingly restored after severe fire damage, the castle has been continuously inhabited by Britain's monarchs since its construction by William I. The remains of numerous British sovereigns lie here too including Henry VIII, Charles I and George V.</p>]]><p><b>Walk the causeway to St Michael's Mount</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Perched proudly on a rocky island, St Michael's Mount is one of Cornwall's best-known attractions. Built in 1135 by the Abbot of Mont St Michel, legend claims it was constructed by a giant called Cormoran. The castle is open to the public and at low tide it's possible to walk the causeway to reach it. Check local tide times first.</p>]]><p><b>Wonder at the majesty of Canterbury Cathedral</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Canterbury Cathedral is a masterpiece of Romanesque and gothic architecture. Inside, visitors can see stained glass windows dating from the 12th century and the medieval tombs of King Henry IV and Edward the Black Prince, as well as those of numerous archbishops including Thomas Becket, who was murdered in the northwest transept in 1170.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>England has shed its reputation as a culinary no man's land. Cooking has become cool, and the flurry of excellent restaurants up in the capital and beyond is the proof in the pudding. The use of local, seasonal ingredients has spread throughout the country from gastropubs in Yorkshire to fish restaurants in Cornwall.</p><p>Of course, for every locally sourced partridge dish there is a plate of over-boiled vegetables and bland meat, but the range of acceptable options outside of formal fine-dining has widened considerably. With a little research, you can eat very well indeed. London and the larger cities offer every type of ethnic food imaginable, with Asian food such as Indian, Chinese and Thai being particularly popular and value for money.</p><p>Where drink is concerned, both craft beer and gin have enjoyed remarkable renaissance in recent years, and English wine is growing in stature. Meanwhile, the English taste for real ale is as unquenchable as ever.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Sunday roast:</strong> Beef, lamb, pork or chicken, served with roast potatoes, veg, gravy and other accompaniments.<br />
<strong>Cream tea:</strong> Scones, jam, butter, clotted or double cream and, of course, tea.<br />
<strong>Spotted dick:</strong> Suet pudding with currants and raisins.<br />
<strong>Bakewell pudding:</strong> Pastry base covered with jam, almond filling and topped with icing.<br />
<strong>Cheese:</strong> Popular kinds include Cheddar, Wensleydale, Lancashire and Stilton.<br />
<strong>Fish and chips:</strong> Battered and deep fried fish with chipped potatoes. Still widely found.<br />
<strong>Curry:</strong> The English have a passion for Indian and Bangladeshi food. In fact chicken tikka masala is considered the national dish.<br />
<strong>Full English breakfast:</strong> Commonly a combination of bacon, sausage, egg, beans, mushrooms, black pudding, tomato and toast.<br />
<strong>Lancashire hotpot:</strong> A lamb and onion stew, slow-cooked and topped with sliced potatoes.<br />
<strong>Cornish pasty:</strong> Crusted pastry filled with meat and vegetables. An iconic snack in the West Country.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A service charge (usually 10-12.5%) might be included in the prices stated on the menu, but it is more likely to be added to the bill at the end. This is technically an optional charge. Where service is not included, a tip of at least 10% is expected.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From cinema and concerts to theatre and ballet, visitors are spoilt for choice when it comes to entertainment in England. And of course, no visit is complete without a trip to the pub.</p>
<p>Most cities have a theatre - <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> is packed is packed with to the rafters with them. Musicals and big budget plays are the remit of the West  End, whilst newer material is staged at the National and the Royal Court. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england/bristol-airport">Bristol</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bath">Bath</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/manchester/manchester-airport">Manchester</a>, Sheffield and Hull also have strong dramatic traditions and well-regarded theatres.</p>
<p>Going to the cinema is also popular. Most cinemas belong to the popular chains but for a different experience look out for Picturehouse cinemas, which tend to show more arthouse films. Alternatively find one of the few remaining independents, which tend to be set in glorious surroundings &ndash; The UK&rsquo;s oldest cinema, The Electric in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england/birmingham-airport">Birmingham</a>, dates from 1909 and is an art deco gem.</p>
<p>Most big towns have a club or two for night owls who want to stay out dancing. Musical genres vary but most clubs will play a decent variety of styles. A night out however, usually starts in the pub.</p>
<p>The whole country is peppered with historic pubs, and a visit is a quintessential British experience. A &lsquo;trip down the local&rsquo; must include a pint of locally brewed beer, a packet of peanuts or pork scratchings, and a long chat with the locals. Give the touristy areas a miss - the oldest part of a city is often the best bet for good, old-fashioned pubs. Try sinking a pint in the canal district of Birmingham, or visit the oldest pub in historic, medieval <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england/norwich-international-airport">Norwich</a>, the cosy Adam and Eve, built in 1248.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shopping is a national past time in England, and there's lots of choice whether it&rsquo;s food, fashion or something else whetting your appetite. The English high street is one of the most diverse in the world, with lots of international brands available nationwide. Traditional British brands such as John Lewis and Marks &amp; Spencer are a byword for quality whilst chic department stores like Selfridges and Harvey Nichols have spread their wings beyond the capital into Northern cities such as <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/leeds">Leeds</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england/birmingham-airport">Birmingham</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/manchester/manchester-airport">Manchester</a>. High street brands like Topshop produce on-trend fashion at accessible prices but there are still lots of places where independent labels and boutiques thrive. Find vintage and retro clothes in the charming boutiques of Totnes in Devon, Birmingham&rsquo;s Custard Factory or the Brighton Lanes. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>, it goes without saying, has shopping to suit all tastes.</p>
<p>On the foodie front, specialities include jams, marmalades and fruit chutneys, whilst legendary cakes such as Victoria sponge and gingerbread are perennial favourites and tea is a national drink. Farmers' markets up and down the country are the places to buy home-grown treasures. Borough market in <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/i/london">London</a>, and the Bristol Farmers market on Corn   Street are good hunting grounds, whilst Winchester farmer&rsquo;s market is the largest in the country.</p>
<p>England has a strong bookshop culture, and small and specialist shops can be found all over the country. Old university towns <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/oxford">Oxford</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cambridge">Cambridge</a> are particularly good places to find and quirky bookshops where obscure gems may be found.</p>
<p><strong>Tax-free shopping:</strong> Many shops throughout the country now operate a tax-free shopping scheme for overseas visitors. The store provides a form that should be completed at the time of purchase. Upon arrival at customs, present the goods and the forms (within three months) to be entitled to a refund of Value Added Tax (VAT).</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900/0930-1730; in London and other large shopping centres, shops may stay open to 2000. Most cities have at least one night a week of late night shopping until 2000, usually on Thursday. Large shops and supermarkets shops open Sun 1000/1100-1600/1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>England's hotels have changed beyond recognition in recent years, with smart boutique hotels steadily replacing the grotty bed and breakfast and excellent hotel chains expanding to major cities outside the capital. It is rare to find a town in England, however small, which does not have at least one hotel. Some grand <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> hotels, for example the Savoy, are famous the world over, and there is an increasing amount of stylish and modern accommodation across the country.<br /><strong>Grading:</strong>VisitBritain, the AA and RAC (as well as VisitWales and VisitScotland) have agreed common standards for quality assessment. Hotels and guesthouses are classified by use of a 1- to 5-star rating system.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are thousands of guest houses and bed and breakfast facilities throughout England – these range from the cheap and cheerful places where you can bed down for a night, to much grander residences where all mod-cons are provided and customer service is at the fore. The traditional image of the dingy B&B has been elevated as properties are spruced up to withstand the high expectations of paying guests (and avoid the wrath of TripAdvisor), and many B&Bs compete with hotels in terms of the level of service provided. Guest houses, inns and farmhouses providing bed and breakfast services are classified by a star-rating system.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>England's hotels have changed beyond recognition in recent years, with smart boutique hotels steadily replacing the grotty bed and breakfast and excellent hotel chains expanding to major cities outside the capital. It is rare to find a town in England, however small, which does not have at least one hotel. Some grand <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> hotels, for example the Savoy, are famous the world over, and there is an increasing amount of stylish and modern accommodation across the country.<br /><strong>Grading:</strong>VisitBritain, the AA and RAC (as well as VisitWales and VisitScotland) have agreed common standards for quality assessment. Hotels and guesthouses are classified by use of a 1- to 5-star rating system.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>England's hotels have changed beyond recognition in recent years, with smart boutique hotels steadily replacing the grotty bed and breakfast and excellent hotel chains expanding to major cities outside the capital. It is rare to find a town in England, however small, which does not have at least one hotel. Some grand <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> hotels, for example the Savoy, are famous the world over, and there is an increasing amount of stylish and modern accommodation across the country.<br /><strong>Grading:</strong>VisitBritain, the AA and RAC (as well as VisitWales and VisitScotland) have agreed common standards for quality assessment. Hotels and guesthouses are classified by use of a 1- to 5-star rating system.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[52.019029]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-0.770427]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>130,395 sq km (50,346 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>65.14 million (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>416.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>London.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mainland England makes up around two-thirds of the British Isles. There are also several small islands including the Isle of Wight and the Isles of Scilly both of which lie off the south coast. In the south, much of the landscape is made up of undulating green hills given over to agriculture, with the South Downs and Cotswolds being prime examples of this. The east and north of England is flat and low lying &ndash; most notably in the east are the Fens, flat marshland that surrounds the East Anglian towns of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cambridge">Cambridge</a> and Peterborough. The coastline is endlessly varied, with northern England&rsquo;s coast made up mainly of flat sand dunes, whereas the south is notable for the Jurassic Coast of Dorset, a World Heritage site where the cliffs span 153km (95 miles) and 185 million years of history, and numerous fossil discoveries have been made.</p>
<p>Further north, the landscape becomes more dramatic. The mountain ranges of the Yorkshire Dales and Lake District in the northwest afford picturesque views of valleys, lakes, forest and mountains, making both destinations popular with hikers. The Pennine mountain range (also known as the &lsquo;backbone of England&rsquo;) bisects the northern region, creating a natural divide between the North West and North East. Traversed by the Pennine Way, the UK&rsquo;s longest footpath, hikers can get up close to one of the most scenic in England and take in the most scenic part of England.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Predominantly Christian (Church of England, Roman Catholic, Presbyterian, Methodist), sizeable Muslim, Sikh, Jewish and Hindu minorities. Around 15% of the population have no religion.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The monarchy, though now only symbolic politically, is a powerful and often subconscious unifying force. Members of the Royal Family are the subject of unceasing fascination, with their every move avidly followed and reported by the popular press, both in the UK and abroad.<br />
<br />
Handshaking is customary when introduced to someone for the first time. Normal social courtesies should be observed when visiting someone's home and a small present such as flowers or chocolates is appreciated. It is polite to wait until everyone has been served before eating.<br />
<br />
<strong>Clothing:</strong> Some nightclubs and restaurants do not allow jeans and trainers, otherwise casual wear is widely acceptable.<br />
<br />
<strong>Use of public places:</strong> Topless sunbathing is allowed on certain beaches and tolerated in some parks. Smoking is banned in all enclosed public places, including stations, pubs and restaurants, throughout the UK.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with three square pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Theresa May since July 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Little is known of the country&rsquo;s pre-Roman settlers but it&rsquo;s believed that ancient Britons were a Celtic people who migrated to Britain by a now-submerged land bridge. The Romans first attempted to conquer Britannia (as they knew it) in 55 BC but it wasn&rsquo;t until 43 AD that Claudius successfully led an invasion.</p>
<p>Within years the Romans ruled the land, setting up cities, roads and spas. However, by the 5th century the Roman Empire withdrew from Britain, leaving the way clear for an influx of Anglo-Saxons and, later, Vikings. The Norman Conquest, initially marked by the Battle of Hastings in 1066, caused many Anglo-Saxons to flee. The Normans carried out a huge census of England, documented in the Domesday Book.</p>
<p>Of the many royal houses that subsequently ruled, it was arguably the Tudors in the 1500s that had the most profound impact. King Henry VIII broke away from Catholicism and created the Church of England, essentially in order to be granted a divorce. This decision had huge implications for England&rsquo;s future and led to prolonged religious tensions.</p>
<p>Around a century later, the English Civil War saw dividing lines drawn up again, this time between parliamentary forces and royalist supporters. The war led to King Charles I&rsquo;s execution and left a framework for rule by parliamentary democracy which remains today.</p>
<p>By the early 20th century the British Empire had become the largest in the world, with numerous overseas colonies. The onset of WWI and WWII signalled change, and by the 1950s Britain had begun to divest itself of its colonies. Post-war Britain looked very different, as many women came into the workforce for the first time. Significant social change also brought free healthcare, better housing and more access to education.</p>
<p>In the &lsquo;swinging 60s&rsquo;, London caught world attention through its music, fashion and culture as Twiggy, The Beatles and the Rolling Stones made headlines.</p>
<p>Tory Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher was a divisive figure in the 1980s, polarising opinion with her measures to tackle England&rsquo;s economic woes. Tony Blair&rsquo;s New Labour came to power in 1997 promising change, but his tenure was tarnished by his support of a US-led war with Iraq.</p>
<p>The last decade has seen a shifting political and economic landscape, with the effects of the global financial crisis still reverberating. David Cameron&rsquo;s Conservatives won a resounding, if surprising, victory in the 2015 general election. His tenure was been characterised by tough austerity measures that hit poor communities the hardest. Cameron called a referendum on the UK leaving the EU in 2016, and resigned after the result - to leave, colloquially known as Brexit - was not what he had anticipated. Theresa May took over as prime minister and called a snap election in 2017, expecting a landslide victory, but a surge of support for the Labour party under Jeremy Corbyn resulted in a hung parliament.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Only six people died in the Great Fire of London in 1666. <br />
&bull;	The Cornish pasty is said to be worth &pound;150m annually to the Cornish economy. <br />
&bull;	London was reportedly the first city on the planet to reach a population of one million, a figure it reached in 1811. <br />
&bull;	The Liverpool and Manchester Railway, which opened in 1830, was the first fully timetabled rail service in the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Despite its small size, England remains stubbornly impossible to encapsulate in a neat sound bite. It&rsquo;s a delectable mosaic of cultures, cities and landscapes, and any holiday in England will add up to an experience that&rsquo;s way more than the sum of its parts.</p>
<p>Okay, so if you&rsquo;re looking for reliable weather, this is not the place to come. But on every other stereotype, England will have you doing an about-face. Come expecting a nation of tea drinkers and pub goers, antiquated traditions and Sunday roasts &ndash; and leave knowing there&rsquo;s so much more to it than that.</p>
<p>For one thing, there are the cities. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> hardly requires an introduction &ndash; its reputation as a global cultural heavyweight is well-established &ndash; but England&rsquo;s regional cities warrant further attention. Though woven together by a shared history, these vibrant metropolises have fiercely individual characters and continue to make indelible marks on the fabric of this nation &ndash; and indeed the rest of the world.</p>
<p>The old industrial powerhouses of Birmingham, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/liverpool">Liverpool</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/manchester">Manchester</a> have made outstanding contributions to music (think Black Sabbath, The Beatles, Oasis) and continue to punch above their weight culturally. And then there are the grandiose seats of learning, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/oxford">Oxford</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cambridge">Cambridge</a>, where medieval architecture and cobbled streets evoke a powerful sense of history at every turn.</p>
<p>England&rsquo;s eccentricities can bewilder (as a visit to the annual cheese rolling competition in Gloucestershire will prove), but despite the odd clash between tradition and modernity, the two make comfortable bedfellows. Visit England and you&rsquo;ll see a place where liberal values have fostered a culture of tolerance and diversity, where self-deprecation is the modus operandi and where witty words beat correct answers almost every time.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s a country that rewards the curious, whether that means ducking into a pub for a chat with the locals or heading out into the wilds. Speaking of the wilds, England&rsquo;s landscapes have it all: from the dramatic dales of Yorkshire and the rugged fells of the Lake District, to the bucolic hills of the Cotswolds and Cornwall&rsquo;s dramatic coast. No wonder it&rsquo;s one of the world&rsquo;s most popular destinations.</p><p>Despite its small size, England remains stubbornly impossible to encapsulate in a neat sound bite. It&rsquo;s a delectable mosaic of cultures, cities and landscapes, and any holiday in England will add up to an experience that&rsquo;s way more than the sum of its parts. Okay, so if you&rsquo;re looking for reliable weather, this is not the place to come. But on every other stereotype, England will have you doing an about-face. Come expecting a nation of tea drinkers and pub goers, antiquated traditions and Sunday roasts &ndash; and leave knowing there&rsquo;s so much more to it than that.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
