<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Alaska" ColCode="ask" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ak" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Alaska]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate varies widely throughout the state. Anchorage's summer weather is pleasant and the winters are mild. Fairbanks, the Interior and parts of the Bush region experience Alaska's most extreme weather conditions with average temperatures ranging from 22ºC (72°F) in high summer to -28ºC (-19°F) in winter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the Anchorage area, a layered wardrobe is the best option, with a light jacket in summer and a warm coat in winter. Elsewhere, very warm winter clothing is required in the coldest months, and heavily insulated shoes. Lightweight and layered clothing is recommended during the summer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airplanes are usually the fastest, most efficient way to get around Alaska, particularly if you plan to travel to remote Alaska Native communities in the far north. Jet service is available from Anchorage, Fairbanks, Juneau and Ketchikan to communities in Adak, Barrow, Bethel, and Cordova. However, many tour operators offer flights or helicopter tours, combined with adventure activities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Day cruises are available from major towns to popular tourist destinations such as Misty Fjords National Monument, Glacier Bay National Park, Prince William Sound, and Kenai Fjords National Park.<br/><br/>Ferries are also an important water-based transport option. Alaska's Marine Highway offers scheduled services to the Inside Passage, Prince William Sound, the Kenai Peninsula, Kodiak Island and the Aleutian Islands. Book in advance during the summer, especially if you're traveling with a car or RV.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Alaska Railroad (tel: +1 800 544 0552; <a href="http://www.alaskarailroad.com" target="_blank">www.alaskarailroad.com</a>) extends from Seward in the south to Fairbanks in central Alaska.</p>
<p>Built more than 100 years ago, the Alaska Railroad now operates five routes: Coastal Classic Train, Denali Star Train, Glacier Discovery Train, Hurricane Turn Train and Aurora Winter Train. There are daily passenger services between May and September, these drop to weekly services between October and April.</p>
<p>The White Pass and Yukon Route (tel: +1 800 343 7373; <a href="http://www.wpyr.com" target="_blank">www.wpyr.com</a>) is the only railroad to link Alaska with Canada. The tourist route departs the Alaskan port town of Skagway and winds north for Fraser Meadows in BC and then onwards to Carcross, Yukon.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>You can rent a vehicle in Alaska through all major US car hire companies: Hertz, Avis, Thrifty, Dollar, Budget, Enterprise, Alamo and National.<br /><br />Although Alaska's largest city, Anchorage, has the greatest selection of car hire firms, most are represented in smaller towns and cities, including Seward, Wasilla, Juneau, Fairbanks, and Homer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roads are few in Alaska, due to mountains, tundra and inhospitable terrain. The most common way to get around this wilderness state is by air, most small aircraft being equipped with floats. Several airlines, largely based at Anchorage, operate services to almost every Alaskan village. Alaska Airlines (tel: +1 800 252 7522, in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> only; <a href="http://www.alaskaair.com/" target="_blank">www.alaskaair.com</a>) flies to Alaska's largest cities (Anchorage, Fairbanks, Juneau and Ketchikan), as well as a number of bush communities throughout the state. A number of smaller, regional airlines provide statewide services.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/alaska/anchorage-ted-stevens-international-airport">Ted Stevens Anchorage International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Ted Stevens Anchorage International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.anchorageairport.com<p>Ted Stevens Anchorage International Airport is situated 3km (2 miles) southwest of Anchorage.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 907 266 2526.</p>]]><b>Fairbanks International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://dot.alaska.gov<p>The airport  is 3 miles (5km) southwest of central Fairbanks.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Juneau International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.juneau.org/airport<p>The airport is located 14km (9 miles) north of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/juneau">Juneau</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Ketchikan International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.borough.ketchikan.ak.us/airport/airport.htm]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The scenic, historic and expensive Alaska Railroad (tel: +1 907 265 2494; <a href="http://www.alaskarailroad.com" target="_blank">www.alaskarailroad.com</a>) operates daily between Anchorage, Fairbanks, Grandview, Hurricane and Seward. At the southern end of the rail corridor, connections with the state ferry system can be made at Seward and Whittier. Except for the Anchorage-Seward and Anchorage-Grandview routes, the railway operates all year round, with reduced services from September to May. There is also the White Pass & Yukon Route from Skagway.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cars are available for hire statewide, with major chains featured in most cities. The road system is in good condition and if drivers use common sense, and are prepared for changes in the weather, the Alaska Highway is an ideal way to explore the state. Other roads only reach a quarter of the state's vast area, and treacherous weather conditions can make driving a hazardous option. Further information and suggested itineraries may be found online (<a href="http://www.northtoalaska.com/" target="_blank">www.northtoalaska.com</a>).</p><p>Drivers should note that weather conditions can be hazardous, and create visibility and navigational challenges.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bear spotting</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Kodiak Island (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.kodiakisland.org/">www.kodiakisland.org</a>), home of Alaska's largest fishing fleet. View its Russian legacy at the Baranov Museum (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.baranovmuseum.org">www.baranovmuseum.org</a>), and the island's native people at Alutiiq Museum (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.alutiiqmuseum.org">www.alutiiqmuseum.org</a>). The Kodiak National Wildlife Refuge (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.fws.gov/refuge/kodiak">www.fws.gov/refuge/kodiak</a>) is a protected habitat for Kodiak brown bears.</p>]]><p><b>Columbia Glacier</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Experience the most popular excursion, Columbia Glacier, a 6km- (4-mile-) wide piece of ice. This world's fastest-moving glacier can be reached via day cruises, charter boats, flight-seeing tours and the state ferry.</p>]]><p><b>Denali National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Denali National Park and Preserve (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.denali.national-park.com/">www.denali.national-park.com</a>), famous for its panoramic views of the Alaska Range and Mount McKinley, highest mountain in North America at 6,194m (20,320ft). You can take a popular day excursion through the wilderness to see caribou, grizzly bears, wolves and moose.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the native history </b></p><![CDATA[<p>Delight in the wealth of local history that can be seen at the Heritage Library and Museum, the Anchorage Museum of History and Art (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.anchoragemuseum.org/">www.anchoragemuseum.org</a>), the Oscar Anderson House Museum, and the Alaska Native Heritage Center.</p>]]><p><b>Fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head off by floatplane on a hunting or fishing expedition, and stay in a fly-in wilderness lodge.</p>]]><p><b>Gold rush trail</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Follow the 1890s gold rush trail from Skagway to Whitehorse (Canada) along the 177km (110 mile) Klondike Highway.</p>]]><p><b>Hiking</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hike in Juneau on one of the many scenic hiking trails. Just a short walk or ride from downtown, enthusiasts can be scaling mountain peaks, rock climbing, walking across glaciers, hunting, biking, fishing or kayaking. There are many opportunities to view whales, bears and eagles.</p>]]><p><b>Hot springs and icy seas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Soak in Chena Hot Springs (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.chenahotsprings.com/">www.chenahotsprings.com</a>), 97km (60 miles) east of Fairbanks, and visit their year-round ice museum, or brave the icy waters in the annual June Polar Bear Swim (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.visitnomealaska.com">www.visitnomealaska.com</a>) in Nome, on the Bering Sea.</p>]]><p><b>Husky sledging</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sign on for sled-dog racing. The official sport of Alaska is dog mushing. Visitors can take a team of spirited huskies on a sled-dog tour or watch the experts at work in one of the many annual sled-dog races. Cheer on your favorites during the annual Yukon Quest International Sled Dog Race (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.yukonquest.com/">www.yukonquest.com</a>), held every February. Covering 1,600km (1,000 miles) between Whitehorse, Yukon Territory and Fairbanks during the depths of the Arctic winter, the Yukon Quest is the 'Toughest Sled Dog Race in the World'.</p>]]><p><b>Iditarod Race</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Watch March's world-famous Iditarod Race (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.iditarod.com/">www.iditarod.com</a>), which traverses 1,851km (1,150 miles) of rugged terrain from Anchorage to Nome, on the Bering Sea. The K-300 (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.k300.org/">www.k300.org</a>), out of Bethel in the Yukon Delta, puts up the largest purse for a mid-length 300-mile sled dog race every January.</p>]]><p><b>Inside Passage</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cruise the world-famous Inside Passage and visit cliff-hugging coastal towns, see glaciers calving, whales leaping out of icy waters, sea lions and seals basking on ice floes, and spot eagles and enjoy an amazing variety of birdlife.</p>]]><p><b>Pan for gold</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Try your luck panning for gold nuggets at Crow Creek Mine (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.akmining.com/mine/crow.htm">www.akmining.com/mine/crow.htm</a>), an hour's drive south of Anchorage on the Seward Highway.</p>]]><p><b>Totem poles</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the world's largest collection of totem poles at Ketchikan, nestled between oceans and mountains. Infamous Creek Street's bars and bordellos of fishing and silver-mining days are now galleries and restaurants.</p>]]><p><b>Valdez</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Choose from the many available outdoor pursuits (such as hiking, rafting and fishing) in Valdez, situated on the edge of the Prince William Sound.</p>]]><p><b>Wildlife</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the local wildlife museums including Anchorage's Alaska Zoo (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.alaskazoo.org/">www.alaskazoo.org</a>), the Imaginarium (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.imaginarium.org/">www.imaginarium.org</a>) and Potter's Marsh, where up to 130 species of waterfowl can be viewed from a boardwalk.</p>]]><p><b>Wonder at the Northern Lights</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the Northern Lights (aurora borealis) dancing across the cold winter night skies between December-March. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Alaskan cuisine features freshly caught seafood, moose and caribou. Salmon, halibut and trout feature heavily on most menus.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Smoked salmon.<br />
&bull; Caribou stew. <br />
&bull; Moose steaks.<br />
&bull; Akutaq - Eskimo ice cream.<br />
&bull; Muktuk.<br />
&bull; Sourdough bread.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>21</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Live music is very popular in Alaska. Many bars offer a wide choice of late-night sounds, ranging from rock to jazz and blues. Anchorage has a bigger nightlife scene than the interior city of Fairbanks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unique Alaskan products and crafts include: gold nugget jewellery; items carved from jade; handmade clothing and toys; and woven baskets of beach grass, bark and baleen. Native sea-oil candles, beaded mittens and miniature hand-carved totem poles are also popular souvenirs. The 'Made in Alaska' logo indicates that an item has been genuinely manufactured in Alaska, and the 'silver hand' logo identifies Native Alaskan handicrafts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Alaska hotels cover everything from chain hotels such as Best Western and Westmark Hotels to independently-run properties. Hotel prices are highest in the summer, when reservations are recommended. Cheap hotels are found outside this peak travel period. If you prefer bed and breakfast options, hstoric homes and mountaintop cottages are among the options available in Alaska.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Alaska hotels cover everything from chain hotels such as Best Western and Westmark Hotels to independently-run properties. Hotel prices are highest in the summer, when reservations are recommended. Cheap hotels are found outside this peak travel period. If you prefer bed and breakfast options, hstoric homes and mountaintop cottages are among the options available in Alaska.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Alaska hotels cover everything from chain hotels such as Best Western and Westmark Hotels to independently-run properties. Hotel prices are highest in the summer, when reservations are recommended. Cheap hotels are found outside this peak travel period. If you prefer bed and breakfast options, hstoric homes and mountaintop cottages are among the options available in Alaska.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[63.588753]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-154.493062]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,596,054 sq km (616,240 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>738,432 (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>0.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Juneau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Protestants make up the largest group in Alaska, though it is considered one of the least religious states in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">United States</a>. After Protestant, Catholicism, The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, and Southern Baptist are the next largest. The state also has a fairly large Eastern Orthodox population due to its early Russian colonization.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Because Alaska is one of the newest states, they have a still developing culture; many residents are originally from other states. The native cultures also remain a large part of the Alaskan culture overall, with indigenous peoples comprising nearly 15% of the population in 2011.<br />
<br />
The &ldquo;Eskimo kiss,&rdquo; where two people rub the tips of their noses together, originated from a traditional native greeting known as a kunik, an expression of affection between friends and family that involves pressing the nose and upper lip against the cheeks.]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Alaska, the largest, yet least densely populated US state, was the 49th state admitted to the United States in 1959 after being bought from Russia in 1867.</p>
<p>Alaska was home to many native groups including the Aleut, Tlingit and Eskimos. Russian traders were the first outsiders to reach Alaska and the first permanent settlement was established in the Three Saints Bay in on Kodiak Island in 1784. <br />
<br />
Russia gained a monopoly on the American fur trade and created the Russian-American Company. British merchants also began trading in Alaska and although banned by the Russo-American Treaty of 1824, so did Americans.<br />
<br />
As Russia&rsquo;s hold on Alaska weakened throughout the 1800s, by the 1860s they were ready to sell the territory. The US duly obliged and splashed out $7.2m on the territory.<br />
<br />
In the 1890s, gold was discovered in the neighbouring Yukon Territory in Canada and an exodus of people flocked to nearby Alaska to join in the hunt. Then in 1899 gold was found in Alaska itself and an even larger influx of hopefuls joined the rush.<br />
<br />
A few years later in 1902 construction on the Alaska Railroad began, making transport from the lower 48 states to the Alaskan territory many days shorter and much easier. Industry also began to develop and commercial fishing took over as the leading industry.<br />
<br />
Alaska played its own part during World War 2 with Japanese troops occupying Attu and Kiska, two of the Aleutian Islands. US forces managed to expel the Japanese by 1943 and the federal government resettled those native peoples affected by the fighting.<br />
<br />
President Eisenhower signed Alaska into statehood in 1958 after the discovery of oil on the Kenai Peninsula. More oil was discovered in Prudhoe Bay in 1968 and the government began the construction of the Trans-Alaska Pipeline, which was completed in 1977. Ever since, tensions have run high between wildlife preservation groups against the expansion of the oil industry and those in favour of further development.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; Alaska once lived the same day twice. The state's transfer from the Russian Empire took place on 18 October 1867 (6 October in Russia where the Julian calendar was used) and its time zone changed from GMT +14 hours to GMT -10 hours, so enjoyed the same day twice. It&rsquo;s the only place on Earth where this has happened.</p>
<p>&bull; The battle to liberate Attu Island in 1943 was the only action of World War 2 fought on incorporated territory of the US &ndash; nearly all the Japanese defenders, some 3000 men, were killed with only 28 prisoners taken.</p>
<p>&bull; Akutaq, the Eskimo ice cream, is made of seal oil, reindeer fat, dried fish and berries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Known, appropriately, as the Last Frontier, Alaska is a land of unfathomable natural beauty, a state so vast and wild that parts of it remain unmapped today.</p>
<p>Everything about Alaska nudges the extreme end of the scale. The largest state in the USA, it boasts some 3 million lakes, 3,000 rivers, 100,000 glaciers and 17 of America&rsquo;s 20 highest peaks.</p>
<p>These untamed landscapes harbour a diverse range of wildlife, including Kodiak bears, giant moose and the iconic bald eagle, whose shrill call echoes the grandeur of this state.</p>
<p>For adrenaline junkies, Alaska offers a big hit. Mt McKinley, the highest point on the continent, rises 6,194m (20,320ft) in Denali National Park and tempts climbers from around the world to tackle its snowy peak.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, kayakers paddle beneath jumbo glaciers with humpback whales, while skiers and snowboarders whoosh up the Chugach Mountains by helicopter and glide back down on virgin powder.</p>
<p>Sailors favour the legendary Inside Passage, a scenic coastal route that is becoming increasingly popular with cruise passengers, who can moor up at aboriginal villages and dock at the former Russian city of Sitka. Further afield anglers hunker down in rustic fishing lodges, hooking Pacific halibut and king salmon for supper.</p>
<p>Whatever visitors come for, most kick off their trip in Anchorage, Alaska's largest city, home to 40% of the state&rsquo;s population. But it&rsquo;s not long before they are lured away from the lights and into the vast wilderness, which brings out the trailblazer in even the most sedentary traveller.</p><p>Known, appropriately, as the Last Frontier, Alaska is a land of unfathomable natural beauty, a state so vast and wild that parts of it remain unmapped today.</p>
<p>Everything about Alaska nudges the extreme end of the scale. The largest state in the USA, it boasts some 3 million lakes, 3,000 rivers, 100,000 glaciers and 17 of America&rsquo;s 20 highest peaks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
