<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="United States of America" ColCode="usa" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="us" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[United States of America]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The United States has varied weather conditions, and the best time to visit depends both upon the location and the season. Spring (March- May) and autumn (September-November) are generally cooler, more comfortable times to visit. The summer months (June-August) are generally hot regardless of the region, but winter temperatures (December-February) can vary substantially depending upon the part of the US you are visiting.</p>
<p>The southern part of the country tends to be warmer than the north. The general climate of the continental US is temperate, but keep in mind that <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/hawaii">Hawaii</a> is tropical and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/alaska">Alaska</a> is arctic. Many of the country's dependent territories, such as <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guam">Guam</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/puerto-rico">Puerto Rico</a>, and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/us-virgin-islands">US Virgin Islands</a>, are also tropical.</p>
<p>Summer is considered the peak tourist season throughout the country; other popular travel times are major American holidays, especially Thanksgiving and Christmas, as well as Easter Week and the school holiday known as Spring Break. Certain destinations, such as <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a>, are perennial favourites and are busy year-round; even when the weather may not be pleasant, these destinations have particular attractions or experiences that always draw travellers.</p>
<p>In some parts of the country, travel services may be limited during the low or off-season, largely due to weather conditions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As the US is a vast country with varying climates and four distinct seasons, packing clothing that allows you to layer for warmer and cooler conditions is recommended, especially if you plan to travel to different regions of the country. What you pack will largely depend upon the kinds of activities you plan to enjoy. Outdoor-lovers will need clothing and shoes that are appropriate for the terrain and the activities they have planned; visitors to cities will need a range of casual outfits and perhaps one smarter outfit for a night of fine dining or theatre.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The USA can be crossed within five hours from east to west and within two to three hours from north to south. Strong competition between airlines has resulted in a wide variance in airfares. Categories of fares include first-class, economy, excursion and discount. Night flights are generally cheaper. </p><p>Budget airlines offering domestic flights have expanded service as larger national airlines have struggled financially in recent years. If travelling domestically, check fares for Frontier (<a href="http://www.flyfrontier.com" target="_blank">www.flyfrontier.com</a>), JetBlue (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.jetblue.com">www.jetblue.com</a>), Southwest (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.southwest.com">www.southwest.com</a>), Spirit (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.spirit.com">www.spirit.com</a>) and Virgin America (<a href="http://www.virginamerica.com" target="_blank">www.virginamerica.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are extensive water communications along the coastline and along the grand rivers and lakes. The Ohio River is said to carry more water traffic than any other inland waterway in the world. Tour ships and passenger and freight lines crisscross all the Great Lakes from ports in Duluth, Sault Sainte Marie, Milwaukee, Chicago, Detroit, Buffalo, Rochester, Cleveland and Toronto.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nearly all the long-distance trains are operated by Amtrak. Rail is not considered the best way to travel within the USA, as trains can be slow, infrequent and expensive.</p>
<p>The Acela Express high-speed rail service can travel up to 240kph (150mph), reducing the standard three-hour trip between Washington, D.C. and New York by 30 minutes and the New York to Boston journey from four hours and 30 minutes to just three hours.</p>
<p>Other routes from Washington, D.C. run south to Miami and New Orleans, and from Boston, New York or Washington, D.C. to Chicago. From Chicago, daily services radiate to Seattle, Portland, Oakland, San Francisco, Los Angeles, New Orleans and San Antonio (via Fort Worth). A coast-to-coast train service is provided between Jacksonville and Los Angeles via Tucson, El Paso, San Antonio, Houston and New Orleans.</p>
<p>Short-distance and commuter rail lines exist in various urban centres, many connected to Amtrak line stops. Amtrak also operates a Thruway bus service, which connects to some cities and towns not on its rail grid. A number of independent companies offer short routes, often in scenic locations, onboard vintage trains. These routes are often a good idea for travellers wishing to reach wilderness locations that are off the beaten track.</p>
<p>For full details on schedules and prices, contact Amtrak (tel: +1 800 872 7245; <a href="http://www.amtrak.com" target="_blank">www.amtrak.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The USA Rail Pass (tel: +1 800 872 7245; www.amtrak.com/rail-passes) is specifically designed for international travellers from outside the USA or Canada. It offers 15, 30, or 45 days of unlimited national travel.</p>
<p>The California Rail Pass allows seven days of travel in a 21-day period within California.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving is a marvellous way to see the USA but distances can be huge, eg 4,716km (2,930 miles) between San Francisco and New York City. Nevertheless, for those visitors with ample time, travelling by road is an ideal way to get a sense of both the vastness and the diversity of the country. Besides, road tripping is a favourite method of travel for Americans, and some of its great roads are iconic, such as the famous Route 66.</p>
<p>Hiring self-drive campers or motorhomes, called 'recreational vehicles' or RVs in the USA, is easy, and there are at least four different sizes of RV, from compact to large. Prices for RV rentals vary considerably, much according to the same kinds of factors that affect flight pricing: seasonality, location of rental and destination, and current availability. Booking early is recommended. Cruise America (<a href="http://www.cruiseamerica.com" target="_blank">www.cruiseamerica.com</a>) has more than 100 rental sites across the USA where you can pick up or drop off vehicles.</p>r<p>Streets and roads in towns and cities are typically maintained by local authorities. Interstates are managed and maintained by state and federal authorities.</p><p>As with trains, coach is not a particularly fast method of travel in the USA, but there are many service options, especially in the northeastern United States.</p>
<p>Greyhound (tel: +1 214 849 8100; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.greyhound.com">www.greyhound.com</a>) and Trailways (tel: +1 877 908 9330; <a target="_blank" href="http://trailways.com">trailways.com</a>) provide national service. 'Budget buses' such as BoltBus (tel: +1 877 265 8287; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.boltbus.com">www.boltbus.com</a>) and Megabus (tel: +1 877 462 6342; <a target="_blank" href="http://us.megabus.com">us.megabus.com</a>) provide regular service between major cities.</p><p>Taxi service varies considerably from one city to another, and is often not available in rural areas at all. In big cities, taxis are readily identifiable and easily found. In smaller cities and towns with taxi service, you may need to call a company to request a taxi. If staying in a hotel, your concierge should be able to assist you with such a request.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is recommended, though not legally required. A full national driving licence is accepted for up to one year. All travellers intending to hire or drive vehicles in the USA are advised to ensure that the insurance policy covers all drivers and passengers</p>
<p>A yellow 'non-resident, interstate liability insurance card', which acts as evidence of financial responsibility, is available through motor insurance agents. Additional Collision Damage Waiver covering the car itself is also strongly recommended; in some states this extra insurance is included in hire rates by law.</p><p>The speed limit is usually 105-112kph (65-70mph) on interstate highways (motorways), but varies from state to state. Speed limits are clearly indicated and strictly enforced, with heavy fines imposed. It is illegal for drivers not to have their licences immediately to hand.&nbsp;Vehicle registration (usually found in the glove box of rental cars) is also typically requested by police officers during traffic stops.</p>
<p>If stopped, do not attempt to pay a driving fine on the spot (unless it is demanded), as it may be interpreted as an attempt to bribe. There are extremely tough laws against drinking and driving throughout the USA. Seatbelts must legally be worn in most states.</p><p>AAA (American Automobile Association) (tel: +1 800 222 4357; <a href="http://www.aaa.com" target="_blank">www.aaa.com</a>). Service charges apply. Major national rental car agencies generally provide roadside assistance in the event of a problem with your rental.</p><p>Major international companies have offices at all gateway airports and in most cities. A drop-off charge is likely to be added if the car is deposited in a different city from the one in which it was hired. The minimum age for hirers is 25, but some companies allow younger drivers for an additional fee. Be sure to ask in advance about insurance policies; coverage requirements vary by state.</p><p>Travelling by bike is not the easiest way to see the USA, as interstates and many major roadways prohibit cyclists from riding alongside vehicles. Within cities and towns however, there is a growing bike culture, with the addition or expansion of bike lanes. Should you choose to travel by two wheels, be sure to wear a helmet and have appropriate safety equipment, such as lights, on your bike.</p><p>The speed limit is usually 105-112kph (65-70mph) on interstate highways (motorways), but varies from state to state. Speed limits are clearly indicated and strictly enforced, with heavy fines imposed. It is illegal for drivers not to have their licences immediately to hand.&nbsp;Vehicle registration (usually found in the glove box of rental cars) is also typically requested by police officers during traffic stops.</p>
<p>If stopped, do not attempt to pay a driving fine on the spot (unless it is demanded), as it may be interpreted as an attempt to bribe. There are extremely tough laws against drinking and driving throughout the USA. Seatbelts must legally be worn in most states.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are numerous underground train systems in operation in major cities including New York (subway), Washington, DC (metro), Boston ('T'), Chicago (train) and San Francisco (BART - Bay Area Rapid Transit); others are being planned or built. There are also several tramway and trolleybus systems, including the much-loved antique trams found in San Francisco, although in many cities a car is needed to get around, due to lack of public transport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The principal US airlines operating international services are American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>), Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) and United (<a href="http://www.united.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>). From the UK, British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) and Virgin Atlantic (<a href="http://www.virgin-atlantic.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.virgin-atlantic.com</a>) also offer multiple routes to the USA.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/alabama/mobile-regional-airport">Mobile Regional Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/alabama/birmingham-shuttlesworth-international-airport">Birmingham-Shuttlesworth International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/alaska/anchorage-ted-stevens-international-airport">Ted Stevens Anchorage International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/arizona/phoenix-sky-harbor-international-airport">Phoenix Sky Harbor International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/arizona/tucson-international-airport&gt;Tucson International Airport&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=" i="" united-states-america="" california="">Los Angeles International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/san-diego-international-airport">San Diego International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/oakland-international-airport">Oakland International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/san-francisco-international-airport">San Francisco International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/burbank-bob-hope-airport">Burbank Bob Hope Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/ontario-international-airport">LA/Ontario&nbsp;International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/san-jose-mineta-san-jose-international-airport">Norman Y Mineta San Jose International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/john-wayne-airport-orange-county">John Wayne Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/palm-springs-international-airport">Palm Springs International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/sacramento-international-airport">Sacramento International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/colorado/denver-international-airport">Denver International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/colorado/colorado-springs-airport">Colorado Springs Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/connecticut/bradley-international-airport">Bradley International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida/miami-international-airport">Miami International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/orlando/orlando-international-airport">Orlando International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida/southwest-florida-international-airport">Southwest Florida International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida/palm-beach-international-airport">Palm Beach International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida/sarasota-bradenton-international-airport">Sarasota Bradenton International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida/tampa-international-airport">Tampa International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida/daytona-beach-international-airport">Daytona Beach International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida/jacksonville-international-airport">Jacksonville International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida/fort-lauderdale-hollywood-international-airport">Fort Lauderdale Hollywood International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/georgia/atlanta-hartsfield-jackson-international-airport">Atlanta Hartsfield-Jackson International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/hawaii/honolulu-international-airport">Honolulu International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/illinois/chicago-ohare-international-airport">Chicago O'Hare International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/ohio/chicago-midway-international-airport">Chicago Midway International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/indiana/indianapolis-international-airport">Indianapolis International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/iowa/des-moines-international-airport">Des Moines International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/missouri/kansas-city-international-airport">Kansas City International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/kentucky/louisville-international-airport">Louisville International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/kentucky/blue-grass-airport">Blue Grass Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/kentucky/cincinnati-northern-kentucky-international-airport">Cincinnati Northern Kentucky International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/louisiana/new-orleans-louis-armstrong-new-orleans-international-airport">New Orleans Louis Armstrong International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/oregon/portland-international-airport">Portland International Jetport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/maryland/baltimore-washington-international-thurgood-marshall-airport">Baltimore-Washington International Thurgood Marshall Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/massachusetts/boston-logan-international-airport">Boston Logan International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/massachusetts/manchester-boston-regional-airport">Manchester - Boston Regional Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/michigan/detroit-metro-airport">Detroit Metro Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/michigan/lansing-capital-city-airport">Lansing Capital Region International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/michigan/bishop-international-airport">Bishop International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/minnesota/minneapolis-st-paul-international-airport">Minneapolis-St Paul International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/minnesota/duluth-international-airport">Duluth International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/minnesota/rochester-international-airport">Rochester International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/missouri/st-louis-lambert-st-louis-international-airport">Lambert-St Louis International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/nevada/las-vegas-mccarran-international-airport">Las Vegas McCarran International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/nevada/reno-tahoe-international-airport">Reno-Tahoe International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-jersey/atlantic-city-international">Atlantic City International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-mexico/albuquerque-international-sunport">Albuquerque International Sunport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york/new-york-la-guardia-airport">New York LaGuardi Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york/long-island-macarthur-airport">Long Island MacArthur Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york/new-york-john-f-kennedy-international-airport">New York John F Kennedy International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-jersey/newark-liberty-international-airport">Newark Liberty International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york/westchester-county-airport">Westchester County Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york/buffalo-niagara-international-airport">Buffalo Niagara International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/north-carolina/raleigh-durham-international-airport">Raleigh Durham International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/north-carolina/piedmont-triad-international-airport">Piedmont Triad International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/north-carolina/charlotte-douglas-international-airport">Charlotte Douglas International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/north-dakota/hector-international-airport">Hector International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/ohio/akron-canton-airport">Akron-Canton Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/ohio/cleveland-hopkins-international-airport">Cleveland Hopkins International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/ohio/port-columbus-international-airport">Port Columbus Ohio International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/ohio/dayton-international-airport">Dayton International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/oklahoma/oklahoma-city-will-rogers-world-airport">Oklahoma City Will Rogers World Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/oregon/portland-international-airport">Portland International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/pennsylvania/philadelphia-international-airport">Philadelphia International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/pennsylvania/pittsburgh-international-airport">Pittsburgh International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/rhode-island/tf-green-airport">T. F. Green Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/south-carolina/columbia-metropolitan-airport">Columbia Metropolitan Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/south-dakota/sioux-falls-regional-airport">Sioux Falls Regional Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/tennessee/memphis-international-airport">Memphis International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/tennessee/nashville-international-airport">Nashville International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/texas/austin-bergstrom-international-airport">Austin Bergstrom International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/texas/dallas-fort-worth-international-airport">Dallas-Fort Worth International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/texas/houston-george-bush-intercontinental-airport">Houston George Bush Intercontinental Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/texas/houston-william-p-hobby-airport">Houston William P Hobby Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/texas/el-paso-international-airport">El Paso International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/texas/san-antonio-international-airport">San Antonio International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/utah/salt-lake-city-international-airport">Salt Lake City International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/virginia/richmond-international-airport">Richmond International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/virginia/washington-dulles-international-airport">Washington Dulles International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/virginia/ronald-reagan-washington-national-airport">Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/washington-state/seattle-tacoma-international-airport">Seattle Tacoma International Airport</a>,&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/wisconsin/dane-county-regional-airport">Dane County Regional Airport</a>, and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/wisconsin/milwaukee-general-mitchell-international-airport">Milwaukee General Mitchell International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London: to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/miami">Miami</a>&nbsp;- 9 hours 45 minutes; to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a>&nbsp;- 8 hours; to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/san-francisco">San Francisco</a>&nbsp;- 11 hours; to&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/seattle">Seattle</a>&nbsp;- 9 hours 45 minutes; to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/washington-dc">Washington, D.C.</a> - 8 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Boston Logan International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.massport.com<p>Boston Logan International Airport is located 5.3km (3.3 miles) northeast of Boston.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 800 235 6426</p>]]><b>Houston George Bush Intercontinental Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airport-houston.com<p>Houston George Bush Intercontinental Airport is located 37km (23 miles) north of Houston.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 281 230 3100</p>]]><b>New York John F. Kennedy International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.panynj.gov<p>New York John F. Kennedy International Airport is located 25km (15.5 miles) southeast of Manhattan.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 718 244 4444</p>]]><b>New York LaGuardia Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.laguardiaairport.com<p>New York LaGuardia Airport is located 13km (8 miles) east of Manhattan, in the Flushing neighbourhood in the borough of Queens.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 718 533 3400</p>]]><b>Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.flyreagan.com<p>Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport is situated 7km (4 miles) south of Washington, DC in Arlington County, Virginia.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 703 417 8000</p>]]><b>Chicago O'Hare International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.flychicago.com<p>Chicago O'Hare International Airport is situated 29km (18 miles) northwest of Chicago.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 800 832 6352</p>]]><b>Dallas-Fort Worth International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.dfwairport.com<p>Dallas-Fort Worth International Airport is located 24km (15 miles) northwest of Dallas and 29km (18 miles) northeast of Fort Worth.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 972 973 3112</p>]]><b>Los Angeles International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.flylax.com/<p>Los Angeles International Airport is located 32km (20 miles) southwest of downtown Los Angeles.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 855 463 5252</p>]]><b>Philadelphia International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.phl.org<p>Philadelphia International Airport is located 11km (7 miles) southwest of central <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/philadelphia">Philadelphia</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(215) 937 6937.</p>]]><b>San Francisco International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.flysfo.com<p>San Francisco International Airport is located 22km (14 miles) south of downtown San Francisco.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 650 821 8211.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some of the US ports that welcome passengers in addition to cargo are Port of Anchorage (<a href="http://www.portofanc.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.portofanc.com</a>), <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/honolulu">Honolulu</a>, Port of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-orleans">New Orleans</a> (<a target="_blank" rel="nofollow" href="http://www.portno.com">www.portno.com</a>), New York (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.panynj.gov">www.panynj.gov</a>), Port of Miami (<a target="_blank" rel="nofollow" href="http://www.miamidade.gov/portofmiami">www.miamidade.gov/portofmiami</a>), and Tampa Port Authority (<a target="_blank" rel="nofollow" href="http://www.tampaport.com">www.tampaport.com</a>). You can find a complete list of US ports on the Customs and Border Protection website (<a href="http://www.cbp.gov/contact/ports" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.cbp.gov/contact/ports</a>).</p><p>Alaskan ports may have seasonal arrivals only, and do not operate year-round for passenger arrivals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rail travel in the United States is not as well developed as it is in Europe, and is not a popular way to travel, as service is typically slow and often inconvenient.</p>
<p>Amtrak (tel: +1 800 872 7245; <a href="http://www.amtrak.com" target="_blank">www.amtrak.com</a>)  is the only commercial railway in the US providing passenger travel  service across the country.&nbsp; The US and Mexican rail networks connect at Yuma (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/arizona">Arizona</a>), El Paso (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/texas">Texas</a>) and Del Rio (Texas), with limited scheduled passenger services.  There are several connections with the Canadian network, including New  York-Montreal, Chicago-Toronto and Seattle-Vancouver services.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Amtrak (<a href="http://www.amtrak.com" target="_blank">www.amtrak.com</a>) offers USA rail passes in 15-, 30-, and 45- day increments.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>By road, you can enter the United States from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada">Canada</a> to the north and from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mexico">Mexico</a> to the south. Delays  at border crossings are common and may last for hours, particularly at busy checkpoints between the US and Mexico. For a full list of Canada-US and Mexico-US points of entry, their operating hours, and estimated wait times, consult the Customs and Border Protection (<a href="http://bwt.cbp.gov" target="_blank">bwt.cbp.gov</a>).</p><p>In general, roadways in the USA are safe and well-maintained. The USA has a well-developed interstate system linking states; odd numbered interstates run north to south and even-numbered interstates run east to west. Many states, including <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida">Florida</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-jersey">New Jersey</a>, have state 'turnpikes' that impose tolls on portions of their roadways.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Though usage is declining payphones are still relatively common in the US. Most are coin operated. For emergency police, fire or medical services in major cities, dial 911. The following codes denote toll-free (freephone) numbers: 800, 855, 866, 877 and 888.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign mobile telephones only work if they are tri-band or quad-band; charges are high. Visitors can also hire a mobile telephone. Pre-pay cell phones can be purchased from a variety of retail outlets, including drug stores.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most hotels, restaurants and public buildings offer free Wi-Fi. There are Internet cafés in most urban areas, and an increasing number of Wi-Fi hotspots in larger towns and cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Freedom of expression in the US is guaranteed by the constitution. The USA has the most highly developed mass media in the world. Public broadcasting is partly government-funded, but also supported by private grants.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are numerous post offices throughout the states. Stamps can also be bought at stamp machines in hotels and shops. Airmail to Europe takes up to one week.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Graceland</p><![CDATA[<p>The sprawling estate of Elvis Presley, also known as the king of rock-n-roll, has been open to the public since 1982 and receives more than half a million visitors every year. Presley and many members of his family are also buried here, and many fans make annual pilgrimages to pay their respects on the anniversary of his death.</p>]]><br/><p>Grand Canyon National Park</p><![CDATA[<p>With more than 5 million visitors each year, the Grand Canyon is one of the most popular national parks in the US. It's also one of the most visually impressive; its sheer size overwhelms, up to 1.6km (1 mile) deep, 29km (18 miles) wide at some points, and 446km (277 miles) long. Most visitors see the canyon from their vehicles by driving along the South Rim; the North Rim is more rugged. It is also possible to go into the canyon by mule, foot, or non-motorised watercraft, and many tour groups offer guided excursions for the fit traveller.</p>]]><br/><p>Independence National Historical Park - Liberty Bell Center</p><![CDATA[<p>The expansion of this national park, which celebrates many aspects of the country's founding, was completed in late 2010. One of the most significant aspects of this expansion was the creation of a new exhibit that highlights slavery and the abolition movement in Philadelphia's and the country's history. The famed cracked Liberty Bell is also on display here.</p>]]><br/><p>National September 11 Memorial and Museum </p><![CDATA[<p>Dedicated on the tenth anniversary of the terrorist attacks on the World Trade Center's twin towers, this memorial and museum sit on the site of those buildings, which were completely destroyed during the attacks. The memorial is a tribute to the lives of nearly 3,000 people who were killed in both the 2001 attack and the earlier attack on the centre that occurred in 1993. The names of victims are etched into panels surrounding two reflecting pools.</p>]]><br/><p>The Gateway Arch</p><![CDATA[<p>Arcing to 192m (630ft), this is the nation's tallest monument, standing as a tribute to Thomas Jefferson's role in the westward expansion of the United States, as well as the geographical significance of St. Louis in that expansionary period. The Arch is operated by the National Parks Service.</p>]]><br/><p>The Martin Luther King, Jr.  National Historic Site </p><![CDATA[<p>Not to be confused with the Martin Luther King, Jr. Memorial that opened in Washington, D.C. in 2011, the National Historic Site, located in Atlanta, Georgia, is where visitors can see the civil rights leader's birth home and his tomb, as well as a museum.</p>]]><br/><p>The White House</p><![CDATA[<p>Though it's not easy to visit the White House, which serves as the President's official residence, citizens of foreign countries can submit a request for a free, guided visit through their embassy in Washington, D.C. Tours are offered daily, except for Sundays and Mondays. Once a tour has been secured, all foreign visitors must present their passport on the day of the tour to be admitted.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Niagara Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The 12,000 year old falls straddle the Canada-US border and are accessible by both sides. Various look-out points offer birds-eye views of the falls, though tour operators are also available to provide closer access by boat or helicopter.</p>]]><p><b>The Mall of America</b></p><![CDATA[<p>America's largest mall, the Mall of American Bloomington, Minnesota, has more than 400 stores, 20+ restaurants, an aquarium, 14 theatres, 12,000 employees; it's a place that's easy to get lost in. It has been a tourist attraction in its own right, both for domestic and international travellers, since opening in 1992.</p>]]><p><b>The Vegas Strip</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Vegas isn't for everyone, but touring its iconic "Strip," the main street running through Sin City, is a memorable experience. With flashing neon lights, casinos built to look like Egyptian pyramids and Parisian and New York landscapes, the Strip offers plenty to keep visitors busy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$18.03 trillion (2015).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Agricultural products, industrial goods, computers and electrical machinery, vehicles, consumer goods, and military equipment and aircraft.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Agricultural products, industrial supplies, computers, telecommunications equipment, automobiles and clothing.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Canada, China, Mexico, Japan and Germany.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The US economy is the world's largest, most technologically powerful and diverse. Distinct benefits arise from a unique combination of mass immigration, technological and marketing innovations, vast natural resources, expansion of international trade, historical fortune and an economic system designed to reinforce professional and personal enterprise.<br />
<br />
The enormous influence of US-based multinational companies within the world economy affords unparalleled global influence and allows its currency unique international status.<br />
<br />
Large areas of the USA, particularly in the Midwest, are under cultivation and produce a wide range of commodities: important are cotton, grain and tobacco, all exported on a large scale. Principal mining operations produce oil, gas, coal, copper, iron, uranium and silver. US industry leads in steel production, automotive manufacturing, aerospace technology, telecommunications, chemical engineering, electronics, computer-based commerce and manufactured goods.<br />
<br />
The largest employment is in the service sector, finance, leisure and tourism. The unemployment rate in 2011 was 9.1%, with growth at 2.5% and inflation at 3%.</p>
<p>If for no other reason than its role in the world economy, the USA is an important conference destination; there are state, city and regional travel and convention organisations in every part of the country, each actively promoting its own assets. There are several magazines aimed at helping the conference organiser; they include <em>Meeting &amp; Conventions Magazine</em> (<a href="http://www.meetings-conventions.com" target="_blank">www.meetings-conventions.com</a>) and&nbsp;<em>Successful Meetings Magazine</em> (<a href="http://www.successfulmeetings.com" target="_blank">www.successfulmeetings.com</a>).</p>
<p>Three of the largest convention and trade show venues in the USA are Las Vegas, New York and Chicago, with Las Vegas holding the top position for a number of years. <br />
<br />
Organisers interested in US venues should contact the US Travel Association  (<a href="http://www.ustravel.org" target="_blank">www.ustravel.org</a>) or the travel organisations listed in the individual state sections. In addition to the state organisations, addresses of travel and convention organisations for cities and counties are also included.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businesspeople are generally expected to dress smartly. Western business courtesies should be observed, although Americans tend to be less formal than Europeans. Appointments and punctuality are expected procedure and business cards are widely used. Dates in the US are written month-day-year.</p>
<p>It is quite common for meetings to be held over lunch, although the prohibitive cost of eating out in major cities at traditional business venues means that some companies bring in outside caterers to the office for important, large-scale lunch meetings. For lunch meetings, alcohol, in moderation, is acceptable. Business dinners tend to take place in restaurants rather than at home. Cocktails after work are commonplace.</p><p>Business hours are officially Mon-Fri 0900-1730, although an extended working day is very common in certain sectors and it is not unusual for people to be working well into the night or over the weekend.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>The Trade Information Center - US Department of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 1 800 872 8723
					Website:http://www.tradeinfo.doc.gov/
					Address: ,,,]]><b>The Partnership for New York City</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (212) 493 7400
					Website:http://www.pfnyc.org/
					Address: 5th Floor,1 Battery Park Plaza,New York,10004]]><b>The US Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (202) 659 6000 ,1 800 638 6582
					Website:http://www.uschamber.rg/
					Address: NW,1615 H Street,Washington,20062]]><b>British American Business Inc</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (212) 661 4060
					Website:http://www.babinc.org/
					Address: 20th Floor,52 Vanderbilt Avenue,New York,10017]]><b>The National Foreign Trade Council</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (202) 887 0278
					Website:http://www.nftc.org/
					Address: Suite 200,1625 K Street,NW,Washington,20006]]><b>British American Business Inc in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 7290 9888
					Website:http://www.babinc.org/
					Address: ,75 Brook Street,London W1K 4AD,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Frequent eating out is a relative novelty for many Americans, particularly in suburban areas, and is just one of many consequences of the popularization of television shows that feature celebrity chefs and a focus on culinary history and popular culture. Americans' appetite for learning more about food and becoming familiar with diverse cuisines has grown exponentially in the past decade&mdash;along with their waistlines.</p>
<p>In large cities, restaurants are mostly modern and very clean, offering a vast range of cuisines, prices and facilities. Restaurants come in all shapes and sizes, ranging from fast-food, self-service and counter service, to drive-thru and table service. There are numerous options for casual and fine dining alike. 'Diners', now a fading US institution, consist of simple food served from the counter. These are often located in smaller towns, and although they have been replaced by fast food chains in many areas, can still be found along the east coast and in parts of the southern US, midwest and southwest.</p>
<p>Given the country's diverse cultural groups, the range of cuisines available in the US is large. In fact, many people believe the US does not have its own distinct cuisine, and that its primary attribute is its tendency to fuse various influences. Within cities especially, cultural enclaves often have entire neighbourhoods devoted to specialized global cuisines: Vietnamese in parts of New Orleans; Somali and Ethiopian on the outskirts of Minneapolis; and, of course Chinese and Italian in New York City's Chinatown and Little Italy, which are adjoining neighbourhoods in lower Manhattan.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>As the country has become more culturally diverse, so has the average palate. Today every imaginable dish can be found coast to coast, with an increasing emphasis on fresh and healthy. Nevertheless, many Americans still love the foods that are most often associated with the US, even if they're not the healthiest options. These favourites include:<br />
&bull; Hamburgers.<br />
&bull; Fried chicken.<br />
&bull; Barbecue.<br />
&bull; Reuben sandwich.<br />
&bull; Cheesecake.<br />
&bull; Key lime pie.<br />
&bull; Cobbler.<br />
&bull; Apple pie.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>There are also many types of bars, cocktail lounges, caf&eacute;-style bars and English-style pubs. Generally speaking, waiter/waitress service costs more than self-service or take-out. Drinking laws are set by the individual states, counties, municipalities and towns; on average, closing time in bars is between midnight and 0300.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Widely practised, as service charges are not usually included in the bill and waiters depend heavily on tips for their income. Waiters generally expect 15 to 20% gratuity. Often, service charges <em>are</em> included for larger parties; if the restaurant's policy is not clearly stated on its menu, ask the server. It should be noted that a cover charge is for admission to an establishment, not a tip for service.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>The legal age for alcoholic consumption varies from 18 to 21 years, varying from state to state. Laws on the availability of alcohol run from New Orleans' policy of anytime, anywhere and anyone, to localities, such as parts of Utah, where drinking is strictly prohibited. Verification of age is frequently required prior to service, provided in the form of an identification card; in the case of foreigners, this would be a passport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Given the size and variety of the country, nightlife options vary considerably from one place to another. Nightlife is typically limited in smaller towns, both in terms of activities available and how late they are offered.&nbsp;Clubs generally stay open until the early hours in cities, where one can find music and theatre of all descriptions. Theatre tickets for Broadway, New York's equivalent of London's West End 'Theatreland', can be booked through the Group Sales Box Office (tel: +1 212 541 8457&nbsp;<em>or +</em>1 800 223 7565 in the USA and Canada only; <a href="http://www.bestofbroadway.com/" target="_blank">www.bestofbroadway.com</a>). Gambling is only allowed in licensed casinos and the legal minimum age for gamblers is 21.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shopping is an important part of many travellers' visits to the US. Variety, late-closing hours, competitive prices and an abundance of retail goods typify US shopping. Many small stores, speciality food shops and hypermarkets are open 24 hours a day in larger towns and cities.</p>
<p>Clothes and electronic goods can often be bought direct from factory outlet stores. Retail outlets range from flea markets and bargain stores to large chain department stores. Malls are a popular way of shopping in the USA and consist of a cluster of different shops in one building, often multi-level, connected by indoor plazas and eateries. The largest mall in the country, Mall of America, has more than 400 shops; it is located in Minnesota.</p>
<p>New York City is one of the shopping hubs of the US. The flagship stores of many familiar brands, such as Coach, Tiffany &amp; Co., Prada, and the like, are located in the United States, many of them on New York City's Fifth Avenue, and are popular tourist stops. Other popular stores for locals and tourists alike that are located in New York City include B&amp;H, a camera superstore; Century 21, a bargain clothing retailer; and Strand Books, &ldquo;home to 18 miles of books.&rdquo; The city also supports independent artists and allows licensed vendors to sell their wares in some of the city's parks; Union Square is one such park.</p>
<p>Though America is dominated by so-called &ldquo;big box&rdquo; chain retail stores like Walmart, many Americans are increasingly supporting smaller local businesses, and boutique shops are flourishing in big and small cities alike. Such shops can be great places to pick up souvenirs that are representative of the place being visited.</p>
<p>Note that a sales tax is levied on most items in most states, and the addition is not included on the price label; sales tax can be anywhere from 2 to 12%, variable by state. If the tax amount is not clearly marked, be sure to ask a sales clerk for information.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-2000. There may be late-night shopping one or two evenings a week. Some states permit Sunday trading; hours vary.</p><p>Most stores and shops accept credit and bank-affiliated debit cards. An official form of identification, such as a passport, may be required to confirm you are the authorised holder of the credit or debit card.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is lots of great accommodation in the USA, including a majority of modern national and international hotel and motel chains, often with reasonable prices. In general, the quality of accommodation is high, with standard amenities such as television, telephone and very often broadband or Wi-Fi in each room. Hotels expect payment in advance and reservations are held until around 1800, unless late arrival is requested. Check-out is often at 1100 or noon. <br />
<br />
Several hospitality companies offer a pre-paid voucher programme for use at various hotel and motel chains throughout the USA.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Basic categories fall into Super, Deluxe, Standard, Moderate and Economy. Prices vary according to standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>This long-established tradition in the UK is now spreading across the USA. Bed & Breakfast signs are not generally displayed by individual homes, but most homes offering this service are listed in directories, which may be purchased by interested travellers. 'Bed & Breakfast inns' have up to 20 or so rooms, and are distinguished from 'country inns' in that the latter offer meals as well as breakfast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is lots of great accommodation in the USA, including a majority of modern national and international hotel and motel chains, often with reasonable prices. In general, the quality of accommodation is high, with standard amenities such as television, telephone and very often broadband or Wi-Fi in each room. Hotels expect payment in advance and reservations are held until around 1800, unless late arrival is requested. Check-out is often at 1100 or noon. <br />
<br />
Several hospitality companies offer a pre-paid voucher programme for use at various hotel and motel chains throughout the USA.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Basic categories fall into Super, Deluxe, Standard, Moderate and Economy. Prices vary according to standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is lots of great accommodation in the USA, including a majority of modern national and international hotel and motel chains, often with reasonable prices. In general, the quality of accommodation is high, with standard amenities such as television, telephone and very often broadband or Wi-Fi in each room. Hotels expect payment in advance and reservations are held until around 1800, unless late arrival is requested. Check-out is often at 1100 or noon. <br />
<br />
Several hospitality companies offer a pre-paid voucher programme for use at various hotel and motel chains throughout the USA.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Basic categories fall into Super, Deluxe, Standard, Moderate and Economy. Prices vary according to standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Travel insurance that provides medical coverage is strongly advised for visitors to the US. Only emergency cases are treated without prior payment and treatment may be refused without evidence of insurance or a deposit. All receipts for services rendered must be kept in order to make a claim. Medical care in the United States tends to be quite expensive, especially for emergency treatment provided in hospital settings, paid for out of pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medical facilities in the US are generally of a high standard, and most major cities have specialty hospitals and clinics to treat specific illnesses. Clinics and hospitals are run by both public and private entities and are highly regulated by local, state, and federal agencies. Health care tends toward the traditional, medical-oriented model of care conventionally practiced in the West, and care is provided by doctors, nurses, nurse practitioners, depending on both the setting and the procedure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many medications available over the counter in other countries require a prescription in the US. Visitors from outside the US are advised to bring an adequate supply of prescription medication for their entire stay. It can be difficult to get medication that was prescribed abroad in the US. Visitors may also want to bring the contact information for their home physician should they need to consult with him or her whilst abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those visiting the USA for long periods with school-age children should be aware that school entry requirements include proof of immunisation against diphtheria, measles, poliomyelitis and rubella throughout the USA; schools in many states also require immunisation against tetanus, pertussis (whooping cough) and mumps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HIV-positive visitors are no longer required to obtain or present a waiver of inadmissibility, under the so-called &amp;ldquo;HIV Final Rule&amp;rdquo; of 2009.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Food in the US is safe to eat, and the conditions under which food is prepared and served are regulated by city, state, and federal health and hygiene agencies. In many jurisdictions, it is mandatory for restaurants to have a certificate of health or hygiene, as well as the current grade they have been assigned, posted visibly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although America is famous for its fast food and obesity rates, the local and fresh food movement is very popular in many areas, especially cities, making it easy to eat healthy. A variety of options also makes it easy for people with special dietary needs to find food that suits them, whether their needs are due to health reasons or religious requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tap water is considered safe to drink in the US and is often offered in restaurants before bottled water. Bottled water is available throughout the country, however, both in restaurants and shops, for those who prefer not to drink tap water.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;The US is generally considered a safe destination for world visitors. Occasional outbreaks of disease, such as West Nile Virus (a mosquito-borne illness), H1N1 and the plague have occurred in recent years, however.   Frequent hand-washing and general practices of good hygiene are encouraged to protect oneself against all types of illness. There have been rare cases of rabies, but special precautions are not necessary.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another concern with regard to safety is the ubiquity of firearms, which remains a contentious issue in the United States. Terrorism also poses a small risk, although city, state, and federal agencies have stringent anti-terrorism practices in place.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here. In addition to federal holidays, each state will traditionally observe their own official state holidays.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Martin Luther King, Jr. Day :
							2018<br/>15 January </p><p>Presidents' Day :
							19 February </p><p>Memorial Day :
							28 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							04 July </p><p>Labour Day :
							03 September </p><p>Columbus Day :
							08 October </p><p>Veterans' Day :
							11 November </p><p>Thanksgiving Day :
							22 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported by visitors over 21 years of age into the USA without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigars.<br />
&bull; 1L of alcoholic beverage.<br />
&bull; Goods up to a value of US$800 (returning residents who have been out of the country for at least 48 hours; this limit is applicable once every 30 days and is reduced to US$200 for travellers who have already used the allowance or have been out of the USA for less than 48 hours).<br />
&bull; Goods up to a value of US$100 (non-residents visiting the USA for at least 72 hours).</p>
<p>Travellers arriving from certain Caribbean and Latin American countries may import up to 2L of alcoholic beverages, as long as at least 1L was produced in one of the applicable countries.</p>
<p>US residents returning from a US insular possession (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/american-samoa">American Samoa</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guam">Guam</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/us-virgin-islands">US Virgin Islands</a>) have a duty-free allowance of US$1,600, including up to 1,000 cigarettes (at least 800 of which must have been bought in the insular possession) and 5L of alcoholic beverages, one of which must be a product of the insular possession.</p>
<p>Further information on US customs regulations is available online (<a target="_blank" style="color: rgb(2, 122, 198); text-decoration: none; " href="http://www.cbp.gov">www.cbp.gov</a>).&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following are either banned or may only be imported under licence:</p>
<p>&bull; Narcotics and dangerous drugs, unless for medical purposes (doctor's certificate required). <br />
&bull; Absinthe.<br />
&bull; Biological materials, some seeds, fruits and plants (including endangered species of plants and vegetables and their products). <br />
&bull; Firearms and ammunition (with some exceptions - consult the customs website). <br />
&bull; Meat and poultry products - fresh, dried or canned. <br />
&bull; Certain fish (unless certified as disease free).<br />
&bull; Dairy products and eggs. <br />
&bull; Wildlife and endangered species, including crustaceans, molluscs, eggs, game and hunting trophies and crafted articles of any part thereof. <br />
&bull; Dog and cat fur. <br />
&bull; Some art and artefacts. <br />
&bull; Haitian animal hide drums.&nbsp;<br />
&bull; Some automobiles. <br />
&bull; More than one article (limited to once every 30 days) displaying a counterfeit or confusingly similar logo to trademarked and copyrighted articles. <br />
&bull; Merchandise from embargoed countries: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cuba">Cuba</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iran">Iran</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/myanmar">Myanmar</a> and most of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sudan">Sudan</a>; information materials (pamphlets, books, tapes, films and recordings) are permitted.</p>
<p>Note that although the embargo against Cuba has not been lifted, authorised US travellers visiting Cuba may now purchase up to US$400 of goods for personal use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Weapons and drugs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar (USD;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a> symbol $) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of $100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1, though the $2 bill is rare and is not in high circulation. Coins are in denominations of $1, and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels do not, as a rule, exchange currency and only a few major banks will exchange foreign currency, so it is advisable to arrive with US Dollars, or exchange foreign currency at the airport upon arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major credit cards are accepted throughout the USA, including American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa. Visitors are advised to carry at least one major credit card, as it is common to request pre-payment or a credit card imprint for hotel rooms and car hire, even when final payment is not by credit card. Be sure to check with your card issuer for current surcharge rates imposed for use of the card outside your home country. You should also inform your issuer that you are travelling for a specified period so your card is not flagged or temporarily suspended.</p>
<p>Bank-issued debit cards are accepted at many businesses in the US; however, using them to pay for many travel-related expenses, such as car hire and hotel rooms, often incurs a surcharge, deposit, or a hold on your account. </p><p>ATMs are widely available across the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Widely accepted in US Dollar cheques; Pound Sterling traveller's cheques are rarely accepted and few banks will honour them. Change is issued in US Dollars. One or two items of identification (passport, credit card, driving licence) will be required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Variable, but generally Mon-Fri 0830-1700. In major cities such as <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a>, newer banks are competing with one another and have extended hours, including weekend service.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>N/A</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>N/A</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>N/A</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter the United States of America, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by nationals in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Children travelling with adults who are not their legal guardians and/or who are travelling with one parent rather than both parents are advised to bring a signed letter from the legal guardian(s) indicating that permission has been granted to leave their country of citizenship and enter the USA. If a single parent has sole custody, it's advisable to bring a court custody document to substantiate this.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers who are visa-free under the Visa Waiver Program do not require a transit visa, but must obtain ESTA-authorisation prior to travel.</p>
<p>Travellers whose home country is not included in the Visa Waiver Program must obtain a transit visa (C-visa) from your nearest embassy or consulate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The USA does not participate in the Schengen visa scheme.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist, business, transit and student visas: US$160.</p>
<p>For ESTA, it costs US$14 if you apply directly on the ESTA website (<a href="https://esta.cbp.dhs.gov/esta/">esta.cbp.dhs.gov</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An ESTA is valid for two years from the date of authorization, or until your passport expires, whichever comes first.</p>
<p>Some types of visa like B1 may <strong>not</strong> expire with the expiry of the holder's passport. An unexpired, endorsed visa in an expired passport may be presented for entry into the USA, as long as the visa itself has not been cancelled, is undamaged, is less than 10 years old and is presented with a valid non-expired passport, provided that both passports are for the same nationality.</p>
<p>Some visas (like B1) are valid for multiple entries. The length of stay in the USA is determined by US immigration officials at the time of entry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For ESTA, you can apply directly on the ESTA website (<a href="https://esta.cbp.dhs.gov/esta/">esta.cbp.dhs.gov</a>).</p>
<p>For other types of visa, visit an embassy or consulate near you.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Typically, temporary residence must be applied for in the individual's home country at the local US embassy or consulate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you're an ESTA applicant, you will get an answer within 72 hours.</p>
<p>For other visa types, the length of time it takes to process your visa varies widely. At the US Embassy in the UK, you are advised to allow 60 working days from the date of the visa interview for your application to be processed.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Customs and Border Protection requires that visitors from abroad substantiate they have sufficient funds to enter the USA. The amount is not a fixed number, however, and does not have to be solely in cash; credit cards, traveller's cheques and other currency equivalents are considered. For more information, check the USCBP's website (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.cbp.gov">www.cbp.gov</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Citizens of visa waiver countries may not apply to extend their stay. Citizens of other countries must file a request with US Citizenship and Immigration Services using Form I-539; the form must be submitted prior to the expiration of the original visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A general certificate of health is not required by CDC for pet cats and dogs entering the United States, although some airlines or states may require them. Certain states require vaccination for rabies, check with state and local health authorities at your final destination. Dogs must have a certificate showing they have been vaccinated against rabies greater than or equal to 30 days prior to entry into the United States, unless they're coming from rabies free countries.  All pet cats and dogs arriving in the state of Hawaii and the territory of Guam are subject to locally imposed quarantine requirements.  Many animals are not allowed to be brought into the USA; you can find a complete list on the US&nbsp;Customs and Border Protection website (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.cbp.gov">www.cbp.gov</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[37.090240]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-95.712891]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>9,826,675 sq km (3,794,100 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>324,118,787 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>32.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Washington, DC.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Federal republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Covering a large part of the North American continent, the USA shares borders with Canada to the north and Mexico to the south. The country has coasts on the Atlantic, Pacific and Arctic oceans, the Caribbean Sea and the Gulf of Mexico. The State of Alaska, in the northwest corner of the US, is not part of the continental US; it is separated from the rest of the USA by Canada. Similarly, Hawaii is not part of the 'lower 48' states; it lies in the central Pacific Ocean.</p>
<p>The country's dependent territories are offshore and have distinct geographies of their own; the majority are islands. The third-largest country in the world (after the Russian Federation and Canada), the USA has an enormous diversity of geographical features, including mountains, plains, and coastal zones. Though there are many cities that are densely populated with more manmade features than natural ones, there are also vast rural areas that are far more sparsely populated. The climate ranges from subtropical to arctic, with a corresponding breadth of flora and fauna. For a more detailed description of each region's geographical characteristics, see the individual state sections.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nearly half of all Americans are Protestant with Roman Catholic, Mormon, Jewish and many ethnic minorities. An increasing percentage of Americans are distancing themselves from formal religious affiliations; more than 19% declared no affiliation in 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Americans are renowned for their openness and friendliness to visitors.</p>
<p>Shaking hands is the usual form of greeting. A relaxed and informal atmosphere is usually the norm. As long as the fundamental rules of courtesy are observed, there need be no fear of offending anyone of any background. Gifts are appreciated if one is invited to a private home. As a rule, dress is casual. High-end restaurants, hotels and clubs may require more formal attire.</p>
<p>Smoking is increasingly unpopular in the US; it is essential to ask permission before lighting up. Smoking is not allowed on city transport and restricted or forbidden in public buildings in most states. An increasing number of states (including <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california">California</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a>) have banned smoking altogether in many public places.</p>
<p>The wide variety of national origins and the USA's relatively short history has resulted in numerous cultural and traditional customs living alongside each other. In large cities, people of the same ethnic background often live within the same communities, although race relations remain fraught in certain regions, as highlighted by the Ferguson riots in 2014 and Baltimore protests in 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>120 volts AC, 60Hz. Plugs have two flat pins with or without a third round grounding pin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Donald Trump since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Donald Trump since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Following the arrival of Christopher Columbus in North America in 1492, waves of European settlers, mainly English, French and Dutch, crossed the Atlantic and by the 17th century had colonised the Eastern Seaboard. The American War of Independence (1775&ndash;1783) ended colonial rule and by 1853, the boundaries of the mainland United States were, with the exception of Alaska, as they are today. Economic activity in the southern States centred on plantation agriculture where attempts to end slavery were fiercely opposed and the election of Lincoln to the presidency in 1861 resulted in the American Civil War as the southern States seceded from the Union. After four years of bloody fighting the more powerful Union forces prevailed and the country entered a period of consolidation, building up an industrial economy. The mid- and late-19th century also saw the development of foreign policy as formal links were established with the old colonial powers.</p>
<p>In Europe, US intervention in 1917 proved decisive for the Allies in WWI and signalled the emergence of the USA as a global power. Driven by free-market economics and innovative production methods the USA became the world&rsquo;s leading economy. It entered WWII and by its end had developed nuclear weapons and the superpower conflict that dominated the late 20th century.</p>
<p>Its post-war foreign policy saw the US increase its global military presence, fighting in Korea, Vietnam and multiple interventions in the Middle East. Relations between the USA and the USSR improved greatly after 1985 under the new Gorbachev government.</p>
<p>In 1988, George Bush was elected to the White House as the Eastern Bloc collapsed and the Cold War thawed. He was followed by Bill Clinton who served two terms characterised by a growing economy before George W Bush won the 2000 presidential election in controversial circumstances and shaped a more aggressive and jingoistic US foreign policy, particularly after the terrorist attacks on the United States in 2001. In November 2008 a record turnout returned Barack Obama as the country&rsquo;s first black president who also served two terms in the White House. In late 2016, businessman and television personality Donald Trump defeated Hilary Clinton to become the 45th president of the United States.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; The United States of America is made up of 50 states, the federal district of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/washington-dc">Washington, D.C.</a>, five major self-governing territories and a range of other assets.</p>
<p>&bull; Famously called America&rsquo;s only true art form, jazz grew out of the sounds and rhythms brought over by African slaves mixed with European folk traditions and popular songs.</p>
<p>&bull; Among the inventions claimed by Americans are the telephone, the phonograph, the electric light bulb, the movie camera, the assembly line and the aeroplane.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the UK in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 588 6500.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-embassy-washington</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 588 6500.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Public access by appointment only. The telephone line operates from 0900-1600, Monday to Friday. UK Consulates in: Atlanta, Boston, Chicago, Houston, Miami, New York, San Francisco and Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>3100 Massachusetts Avenue NW<br/>Washington, D.C.<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the United States of America in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7499 9000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.usembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7499 9000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0800-1730 (only applicants with visa appointments admitted).&lt;br /&gt;Consulates in: Belfast (223 Stranmillis Road) and Edinburgh (3 Regent Terrace).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>24 Grosvenor Square<br/>London<br/>W1A 1AE<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From the soaring skyscrapers of New York City to the dramatic mesas of Arizona, the United States of America is a place of staggering beauty and extraordinary diversity. Nothing prepares you for your first glimpse of Manhattan&rsquo;s iconic skyline, the yawning expanses of the Grand Canyon or the neon-lit excesses of Las Vegas, just some of the country's many highlights.</p>
<p>You could easily spend a lifetime in the US and still feel like you&rsquo;ve just scratched the surface. It&rsquo;s epic on every scale. After all, this is a place where you can watch the thunderous spectacle of Niagara Falls, trek through the soaring Black Hills of South Dakota and cruise along California&rsquo;s glorious Pacific Coast; where you can ski at Lake Tahoe, go cattle ranching in the Midwest and imbibe live jazz in New Orleans. The options, it seems, are endless.</p>
<p>The USA&rsquo;s manmade landscapes are nearly as spectacular as the natural ones. New York City&nbsp;boasts some of the most impressive skyscrapers on the planet (think Empire State Building, Chrysler Building, Rockefeller Centre), although the skylines of Seattle, Chicago, LA and Vegas are no less recognisable.</p>
<p>The American people are similarly diverse; from the colourful Cubans of the southeast to the gun-slinging wranglers of Texas and hardy Inuits of Alaska, the country is a melting pot of cultures. Generations of immigrants have shaped the national identity in everything from food and language to music and manners.</p>
<p>Once derided for being boring, the resurgent capital, Washington, D.C, boasts hip new bars, chic boutiques and a burgeoning culinary scene, which are welcome diversions in this theatre of politics. In spring, the city turns pink with cherry blossom &ndash; the legacy of a peace offering sent by Japan.</p>
<p>The glorious East Coast retreat of Cape Cod is also not to be missed. Looking around this exquisite peninsula it&rsquo;s easy to see why the founding fathers, who stepped off the Mayflower here, chose to make this extraordinary land their home. &quot;God bless America,&quot; they sang. And God blessed her indeed.</p><p>From the soaring skyscrapers of New York City to the dramatic mesas of Arizona, the United States of America is a place of staggering beauty and extraordinary diversity. Nothing prepares you for your first glimpse of Manhattan&rsquo;s iconic skyline, the yawning expanses of the Grand Canyon or the neon-lit excesses of Las Vegas, just some of the country's many highlights.&nbsp;You could easily spend a lifetime in the US and still feel like you&rsquo;ve just scratched the surface. It&rsquo;s epic on every scale. After all, this is a place where you can watch the thunderous spectacle of Niagara Falls, trek through the soaring Black Hills of South Dakota and cruise along California&rsquo;s glorious Pacific Coast; where you can ski at Lake Tahoe, go cattle ranching in the Midwest and imbibe live jazz in New Orleans. The options, it seems, are endless.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
