<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="United Arab Emirates" ColCode="are" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ae" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[United Arab Emirates]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The UAE draws sunseekers from all corners of the globe due to the fact that it is blessed with year-round sunshine, blue skies and very little rain. The best time to visit is between October and April, when temperatures hover at a pleasant 25-28&deg;C (77-82&deg;F) and the Gulf is perfect for swimming. The hottest time of year is during the sweltering summer months of June to September, when humidity can seem unbearable and temperatures can skyrocket to 45&deg;C (113&deg;F). The country is well prepared for hot weather, however, with temperature controlled swimming pools and permanently air-conditioned hotels, malls, taxis and metros. Rain and wind can occur in January through March.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Layering is your best bet; wear light clothing outside and bring a jumper or sweatshirt for the heavily air-conditioned buildings around the cities. During November to March, warmer clothes are advised for evening. A hat and high factor sun block is also advisable - a day on the beach in the strong summer sun is an easy recipe for sunstroke and sunburn. If visiting during the summer, make like the residents and visit the beaches early in the morning and later in the evening.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Daily flights link Abu Dhabi, Dubai and Sharjah. Flights can also be chartered and there are small landing fields throughout the United Arab Emirates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Abra boats trips across the creek from the Deira Old Souk and Sabkha Abra Station at Dubai Old Souk Abra Station cost AED1 per passenger. The Dubai Ferry runs between Al Ghubaib and Dubai Marina. In Abu Dhabi there is a ferry service from Jebel Al Dhanna port to Delma Island. There are also a number of private boat journeys from Abu Dhabi to various islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Well lit, tarmac roads connect all emirates. Dubai is notorious for traffic and dangerous driving, but things can slow to a crawl during peak hour in some congested parts of the city. Most roads are well maintained, with one long highway known as Sheikh Zayed Road connecting Abu Dhabi and Dubai.</p>r<p>There are good tarmac roads running along the west coast between Abu Dhabi and Dubai, Sharjah and Ras al-Khaimah; between Sharjah and Dhaid; and linking Dubai with other northern states and the interior. Roads are clearly signposted in Arabic and English.</p><p>Coach services in the UAE are of the luxury variety and many come with mini bars, massage chairs and TVs. Etihad offers an express service between Abu Dhabi, Dubai and Al Ain. This is a free service for Etihad customers. There are also a number of bus companies offering a hop-on, hop-off sightseeing trip around Dubai or Abu Dhabi.</p><p>Taxis are a quick and convenient method of travel within the UAE, as they are available everywhere with metered fares. Make sure you carry smaller notes &ndash; anything over Dhs50 note will inspire grumbling. Taxis are scarce around 1700. This is when the taxi drivers change shift and deliver their cars back to the depot.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is recommended, although it is not legally required. A valid national driving licence from the UK, Australia or the USA is acceptable.</p><p>Speed limits are clearly displayed on road signs and are usually up to 60kph (37mph) in built-up areas, up to 120kph (75mph) on major roads, and up to 120kph (75mph) on motorways. Don&rsquo;t be surprised when other drivers seem to ignore this.</p><p>Most international car hire companies have offices at airports, hotels and malls. A passport, credit card and either a valid international or national licence are necessary for tourists.</p><p>Cycling has been slow to take off in the UAE, but the Dubai government recently started a campaign to promote cycling as a way of maintaining fitness. However, that does not mean drivers will recognize cyclists as road partners - many drivers have very little regard for the safety of cyclists. Bikes are prohibited on major roads and highways, and cyclists are encouraged to use smaller roads or UAE's growing number of dedicated bikeways. In addition, cyclists should take into account the brutally high temperatures in the Dubai desert summer and make sure to stay hydrated before, during, and after a ride.</p><p>Speed limits are clearly displayed on road signs and are usually up to 60kph (37mph) in built-up areas, up to 120kph (75mph) on major roads, and up to 120kph (75mph) on motorways. Don&rsquo;t be surprised when other drivers seem to ignore this.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flights to the UAE are operated by the national airlines Emirates (<a href="http://www.emirates.com/" target="_blank">www.emirates.com</a>) and Etihad (<a href="http://www.etihad.com" target="_blank">www.etihad.com</a>). Low-cost carriers Flydubai (<a href="http://www.flydubai.com" target="_blank">www.flydubai.com</a>) and Air Arabia (<a href="http://www.airarabia.com/" target="_blank">www.airarabia.com</a>) also fly between the emirates and neighbouring countries.</p>
<p>British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), Qantas (<a href="http://www.qantas.com" target="_blank">www.qantas.com</a>) and Virgin Atlantic (<a href="http://www.virgin-atlantic.com" target="_blank">www.virgin-atlantic.com</a>) all offer direct flights to the UAE from the UK.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-arab-emirates/abu-dhabi-international-airport">Abu Dhabi International Airport, Dubai International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-arab-emirates/al-ain-international-airport">Al Ain International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dubai">Dubai</a>/<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/abu-dhabi">Abu Dhabi</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 7 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 13 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Abu Dhabi International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.abudhabiairport.ae<p>Abu Dhabi International Airport is located 38km (24 miles) southeast of central Abu Dhabi city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+971 2 505 5555</p>]]><b>Al Ain International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.adac.ae<p>Al Ain International Airport is located 18km (11 miles) northwest of the Al Ain city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+971 2 505 5000</p>]]><b>Dubai International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.dubaiairports.ae<p>Dubai International Airport is located 4km (2.5 miles) southeast of Dubai.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+971 4224 5555</p>]]><b>Dubai Al Maktoum International Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Ras al-Khaimah Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.rakairport.com<p>The airport  is 15km (9 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Sharjah International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.shj-airport.gov.ae/<p>The airport  is 10km (6 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are currently no international rail links with the UAE. However the Etihad Rail network (<a href="http://www.etihadrail.ae" target="_blank">www.etihadrail.ae</a>) will expand from cargo services into passenger transportation across UAE by 2020 with a view to expand and introduce rail links with neighboring countries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Border crossings between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/saudi-arabia">Saudi Arabia</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/oman">Oman</a> are easy and quick with your passport. You can enter the UAE via the border town of Sila from Saudi Arabia or Hili in Al Ain from Oman and Hatta from Oman. Note that you must pay a departure tax when leaving by road.</p><p>Make sure you have your car insured for the UAE, Oman or Saudi before you cross the road border. You can buy insurance at select border crossings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Main area codes: Abu Dhabi 2; Ajman, Sharjah and Umm al-Quwain 6; Al-Ain 3; Dubai 4; Fujairah 9; Jebel Ali 4; and Ras al-Khaimah 7. There is a good local telephone network. Telephone calls within each state are free.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone operators. Coverage is excellent. Tourists can purchase pre-paid mobile SIM cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are numerous internet and Wi-Fi caf&eacute;s in the UAE but VoIP telephone systems, such as Skype, are officially blocked. Websites deemed culturally or religiously insensitive are also blocked.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Newswires such as Reuters and major news stations like CNN International have residency in the UAE, along with numerous English television and radio stations. English-language magazines are available including <em>Time Out Dubai</em>, <em>Time Out Abu Dhabi</em>, <em>Time Out Sharjah</em>, <em>What&rsquo;s On</em>, <em>Grazia</em>, <em>Cosmopolitan</em> and <em>Esquire</em>. However, media content is controlled and the government will censor certain political, religious, and sexual content. Foreign publications may also be censored before distribution with the notorious black marker.<br />
<br />
In the press there is a broad range of English-language state-owned and privately owned newspapers including <em>The National&nbsp;</em>(<a href="http://www.thenational.ae" target="_blank">www.thenational.ae</a>), <em>Gulf News</em> (<a href="http://www.gulfnews.com/news/uae" target="_blank">www.gulfnews.com/news/uae</a>), <em>Emirates Today</em> (<a href="http://www.emirates247.com" target="_blank">www.emirates247.com</a>) and <em>Khaleej Times</em> (<a href="http://www.khaleejtimes.com" target="_blank">www.khaleejtimes.com</a>)<em>.</em> Free-to-air English channels include <em>Dubai One, MBC 4, MBC Action, MBC 2</em>. The cable network is named <em>OSN </em>(<em>Orbit Showtime Network</em>) and airs popular US, UK and Australian programmes. English radio stations include commercial stations <em>Radio 1 and Radio 2</em>. The main news, talk and sport station is <em>Dubai</em><em> Eye 103.8</em>, and the latest addition to the airways is <em>Rock Radio 90.7.</em></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail letters and parcels take about five days to reach Europe. In order to receive mail you usually need a PO Box number, as there is no door-to-door postal system.</p><p>Vary from Sun-Thurs 0730-1500 and 0730-2100, depending on the branch.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Abu Dhabi's islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The eight natural islands off the coast of Abu Dhabi include the spectacular Sir Bani Yas, home to the swanky Anantara Desert Islands Resort &amp; Spa and around 30 free roaming Arabian and African animal species.</p>]]><p><b>Al-Ain</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head east through spectacular scenery from Abu Dhabi or Dubai to the resort and former caravan stop of Al-Ain. The resort includes a camel market, zoo and museum containing old and new artefacts and Mesopotamian pottery. The lush oasis village also offers excellent hiking at nearby Jebel Hafeet.</p>]]><p><b>Ancient Hatta</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The ancient fortressed villages of Hatta and Wadi Hatta are close to Dubai, in a surprisingly lush and attractive valley in the foothills of the Hajar Mountains. The area also has a number of naturally formed pools to cool off in.</p>]]><p><b>Archaeological sites</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the important archaeological digs at Hili, 10km (6 miles) from Al Ain. The stone tombs, including the famous Great Sepulchre, date back 5,000 years. Al-Ain also includes a camel market, zoo and museum containing old and new artefacts and Mesopotamian pottery. There's also offers excellent hiking at nearby Jebel Hafeet.</p>]]><p><b>Bastakiya, Dubai</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The historic Bastakiya alongside Dubai Creek is Dubai's Bohemian quarter, with some wonderful cafés, and eclectic art galleries. It's particularly pleasant during the evening when the mosques sound their call to prayer.</p>]]><p><b>Beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The beaches offer white sand and warm, clear waters but in Dubai, Fujairah and Abu Dhabi, the best are to be found at luxury hotels. You can pay a few dirhams to visit beaches with toilet facilities, such as Jumeirah Beach Park, Dubai, and Sandy Beach, Fujairah (for incredible snorkelling opportunities). Excellent beaches include JBR Beach, Jumeirah Open Beach (a favourite for surfers), and Kite Beach (a favourite for kite-surfers). Topless bathing is not permitted anywhere, but women are free to wear bikinis at the beach.</p>]]><p><b>Deep-sea fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The waters of the Gulf are excellent fishing grounds. Fully-equipped boats with crew can be hired for deep-sea fishing trips from all marinas, via hotels and local tour companies.</p>]]><p><b>Desert driving</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Off-road driving in the desert is excellent for thrillseekers. Vehicles are available for hire either with or without guides at nearly every hotel. Adventurous travellers can view the dunes by air, in a hot air balloon.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]><p><b>Dhow cruise</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a traditional dhow cruise from the Abu Dhabi or Dubai Creek marina, or book a fully-equipped boat for deep-sea fishing trips. Alternatively, catch a traditional spluttering <em>abra</em> (small boat) along Dubai Creek for only a few dirhams each way. Yacht trips are also available from the Dubai Marine Yacht Club.</p>]]><p><b>Dubai World Cup horse race</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go to the races at the annual Dubai World Cup (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.dubaiworldcup.com/">www.dubaiworldcup.com</a>), or learn more about the Arabs' passion for horses at the Abu Dhabi Equestrian Club (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.adec-web.com/">www.adec-web.com</a>) close to the UAE's capital.</p>]]><p><b>First-class golf courses</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dubai is unequivocally one of the world's top golfing destinations. Venues like the Emirates Golf Club (<a href="http://www.dubaigolf.com">www.dubaigolf.com</a>) regularly host top international competitions, and there are scores of others dotted around the UAE, though the bulk and the best are in Dubai. You can even try your hand at sand golf.</p>]]><p><b>Iconic buildings</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At more than 828m (2,716.5ft), Dubai&rsquo;s Burj Khalifa&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.burjkhalifa.ae">www.burjkhalifa.ae</a>)&nbsp;is the tallest building in the world and if you reserve ahead you can visit the observation deck on Level 124. Tours of the sail-shaped Burj al-Arab or Abu Dhabi&rsquo;s sprawling Emirates Palace hotel (reportedly the most expensive in the world) can also be arranged.</p>]]><p><b>Mosques and forts</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Don't miss the many historic mosques and forts dotted around the older parts of Abu Dhabi and Dubai, notably the incredible Sheikh Zayed Mosque in Abu Dhabi and Jumeirah Mosque in Dubai. Non-Muslims are welcome to enter during certain visiting times, however women must cover their hair and body. Sheilas (head scarf) and abayas (traditional black dress for women) are available to borrow.</p>]]><p><b>Palm Jumeirah</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dubai's manmade palm-shaped island is rumoured to be visible from the moon, and it truly does have a wow-factor – especially when seen flying low over the city. The built up areas consist of residential and hotel projects including the awesome Atlantis The Palm, home to Aquaventure water park – an absolute must for a hilariously wet, fun day out.</p>]]><p><b>Ras al-Khaimah</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Outdoor lovers will enjoy Ras al-Khaimah (<a href="https://en.rasalkhaimah.ae/">www.rasalkhaimah.ae</a>), which has coastline, the rugged Hajar Mountains and Khatt mineral springs.</p>]]><p><b>Remote beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Aside from the main cities, there are remote stretches of coastline to be found dotted around the country – one of the most peaceful parts include the harbour at Dibba (around 90 minutes from Dubai) and Khor Kalba, where you can kayak through mangroves. Umm-al Quwain also has some beautiful beaches with small, coastal hotels offering boat trips and crab-hunting.</p>]]><p><b>Souk shopping</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go haggling in Dubai's famous souks, magnets for those in search of gold and jewellery bargains, and also for photographers or those who just want to experience the sights, smells and hubbub.</p>]]><p><b>Wadis and Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wadis are dried out river beds and Emiratis love to explore them in four-wheel drive cars, a past time known as wadi bashing. The best areas are in Hatta and Jebel Hafeet mountain in Al Ain, or head for the hills in Ras al-Khaimah.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$407.52 billion (2017).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude oil, natural gas, gold, diamonds.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and transport equipment, jewellery, chemicals and food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China, Germany, India, Japan, Korea and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Oil and gas are the main industries, and underpin the country's considerable prosperity. Outside the oil and gas sector, which includes refining and the production of oil-derived chemicals, most economic activity is government sponsored, and designed to reduce dependence on oil. The UAE is rapidly establishing itself as a major conference and incentive destination, with major venues such as the Dubai World Trade Centre, Abu Dhabi's ADNEC Exhibition Centre and the Al Ain Convention Centre catering for large events and exhibitions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Emirati businessmen are urbane enough to understand and tolerate the mores of their overseas counterparts; nevertheless, a few courtesies can help oil the wheels of business. Smart conservative clothing, which covers the upper arm and lower leg, is expected, despite the often soaring heat.</p>
<p>Arabic is the official business language, but English is widely used.&nbsp;Meetings often start late; this is an accepted part of local custom, this should not be commented on. Visitors should note that when greeting Arab women they should not offer their hand unless the woman extends hers first.</p>
<p>Friday is considered a day of prayer and rest, so meetings should not be scheduled and calls to Arab people should be avoided on this day.</p>
<p>Sometimes business meals will be served at venues that do not serve alcohol. Asking for alcohol may cause embarrassment and even insult. Visitors are strongly advised not to initiate discussions on politics, sex or religion. If drawn into any of these topics of conversation, try to avoid personalising your comments.</p><p>The official working week is 0900-1700 Sunday to Thursday, though many government offices have limited hours &ndash; most are open between Saturday-Wednesday 0800-1300 and 1500/1600-1800/1900, Thurs 0730-1200. Many offices are closed every afternoon during the month of Ramadan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Federation of UAE Chambers of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (02) 621 4144
					Website:http://www.fcci.gov.ae/
					Address: ,PO Box 3014,Abu Dhabi,]]><b>Dubai Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (04) 228 0000
					Website:http://www.dubaichamber.ae
					Address: ,PO Box 1457,Dubai,]]><b>Dubai World Trade Centre</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (04) 332 1000.
					Website:http://www.dwtc.com
					Address: ,,Dubai,PO Box 9292]]><b>ADNEC (Abu Dhabi National Exhibitions Company)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (02) 444 6900
					Website:http://www.adnec.ae/
					Address: ,PO Box 5546,Abu Dhabi,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Whether you&rsquo;re searching for sashimi, Italian, fish and chips or a nine-course degustation journey at a fancy French restaurant, you will find it in the UAE. Visitors to the country really are spoiled for choice, with a wide range of cuisines available. In addition, many celebrity chefs have launched their namesake branches in the UAE, including Nobu Matsuhisa, Gary Rhodes and Giorgio Locatelli. Supermarkets and grocery stores stock home comforts and nearly everything that is available in Australia, USA and the UK, while hotels serve both Arab and European food. There is also a fantastic range of Arabic, Persian, Indian, Pakistani restaurants &ndash; especially in areas like Satwa, Deira and Bur Dubai.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>Modern Emirati cuisine fuses a number of regional flavours, yet the nation&rsquo;s staples have remained the same for centuries. You&rsquo;ll likely find lamb, beef, goat, fish and rice in any of Middle Eastern themed eateries as well as the selection below:</p>
<p>&bull; Hummus (chickpea and sesame paste).<br />
&bull; Tabbouleh(bulghur wheat with mint and parsley).<br />
&bull;<em> Ghuzi</em> (roast lamb with rice and nuts).<br />
&bull;<em> Warak enab</em> (stuffed vine leaves).<br />
&bull; Dates (there are more than 30 million date palms in the UAE).<br />
&bull; Shawarma (spit cooked meat in pitta bread with thick garlic sauce).<br />
&bull; <em>Khameer</em> and <em>chebab</em>  (local bread often eaten for breakfast with eggs).<br />
&bull; Falafel (fried or grilled balls of herby chickpeas).<br />
&bull; <em>Hamour</em> (local grouper fished in Gulf waters).<br />
&bull; <em>Luqaimat</em> (Crispy deep fried batter dumpling balls served with syrup).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>All the Emirates, with the exception of Sharjah, permit the consumption of alcohol by non-Muslims in designated areas. Designated areas are usually restaurants or bars located inside hotels. It is illegal to drink alcohol in the street or to buy it for a UAE citizen. Muslims don&rsquo;t consume pork, so it is not on the menu at many restaurants. If it&rsquo;s served at a buffet or sold at a supermarket it will be separate from other food and clearly labelled. During the month of Ramadan, it is illegal to eat, drink or smoke in any public spaces during daylight. Regulations have tightened recently regarding food and drink consumption in public during Ramadan, and punishments are harsh; expect to be slapped with a fine of AED2000 or face up to one month in jail.</p>
<p>Note: It is possible to buy alcohol, provided you have a permit. Look out for bottle shops identifiable by their blacked out windows.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Most hotels and restaurants add service charges to the bill. Tipping is welcomed at local restaurants where service charges are not applied.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>Over 21 for non-UAE nationals or non-Muslims.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The large Western expat community has transformed Abu Dhabi and Dubai into party towns, with a huge range of bars and nightclubs. Smaller, local establishments with Arabic singers or troupes of Filipino bands and dancers exist alongside classy cocktail bars and nightclubs, which regularly host international DJs and bands from all around the world. Due to the strict alcohol laws, most venues are located in hotels and range from sophisticated cocktail lounges such as Jetty Lounge, set on The One &amp; Only Royal Mirage&rsquo;s private beach, which attracts a young, professional crowd who laze around on its crisp white couches listening to a chill out DJ set.</p>
<p>English-style or Irish pubs include the Irish Village, designed like a village to hark straight back to the bonnie green land filled. Barasti is the Aussie, Kiwi and Saffa choice, and is decked out on the beach like a giant tiki bar with poi dancing into the night. Ladies nights in the UAE are an institution, with many offering free or heavily discounted drinks to female patrons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tax-free prices and an abundance of cheaper luxury brands means shopping is a national pastime for Emiratis, with thousands of people flocking to the UAE each year for the annual Dubai Shopping Festival. The Dubai Mall and Mall of the Emirates are among the largest malls in the world, and are famous for their incredible extras, including an aquarium and ski slope, whilst the newly opened Galleria on Al Maryah Island in Abu Dhabi offers more than 130 luxury brands. Shopping here really is an attraction in itself, with a whole host of other activities including ice rinks, cinemas and arcades.</p>
<p>Aside from malls, visitors can experience a traditional Middle Eastern shopping vibe at the souks (bazaars), where leather goods, gold, silver and clothing like silk pashminas can be bought at rock bottom prices. Karama, in Dubai, is a good place to start practising your haggling, as store holders expect visitors to go there hunting for a bargain! You can ask for &lsquo;special&rsquo; versions of bags or clothing in many of the shops here, and you will be taken to a back room filled with knock-off goods. Alternatively, the souks on either side of the Creek offer a kind of Morroco-lite shopping experience, offering a taste of the region. Here you can purchase spices, and local coffee as well as fascinating memorabilia from Arabic chests and swords, old maps of the local area and trinkets.</p>
<p>As you would expect in this billionaires playground there are also high-end souks, such as The Souk, Abu Dhabi Central Market, which is a beautiful, luxury modern take on a market from the region, here shopkeepers sell high-end home ware, fashion and gifts. Alternatively, Souk Madinat offers an intricate warren of stalls, bars and restaurants.</p><p>Most of the malls have extended shopping hours &ndash; some of them are even open until midnight. Some stores close for prayers on Fridays. The souks are best during the evening, with many stalls closed on Fridays and in the morning.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major hotel chains have locations in the UAE. When it comes to hotels, there&rsquo;s luxury and then there&rsquo;s the UAE standard of luxury. Visitors can opt to experience the nation&rsquo;s over-the-top accommodation, with many of the hotels offering gaudy d&eacute;cor, decadent spas and five-star amenities. The Burj al-Arab, the Emirates Palace and the Al Maha Desert Resort &amp; Spa are some of the more luxurious places to stay, but there always seems to be another opulent property opening, including the Armani hotel in the Burj Khalifa, the tallest building in the world.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;d rather pass up Ali Baba&rsquo;s grotto for understated class try the grand Al Qasr, for its tasteful Arabic flavor (think: Middle Eastern patterns and antique fixtures). The grand lobby smells of sweet rose petals, which are scattered into a water feature in the centre, while rooms look out onto the sparkling Gulf waters. Emirates Palace, on the other hand, is all about decadence. Live like Arab royalty in the AED11.2 billion property in a room slathered with gold and marble fittings, while being waited on hand and foot.</p>
<p>One thing&rsquo;s for sure, hotels in the UAE are creative. Right here in the desert you can bed up in a winter-themed hotel, with rooms decorated chalet-style and look out onto a ski slope with penguins. Kempinski Mall of the Emirates is dotted with windows looking onto Ski Dubai inside Mall of the Emirates, meaning you&rsquo;ll never miss colder climes. Dubai is also set to unveil the Water Discus Hotel. Not only will it look like a space ship hovering in the sky, it will have rooms 10m (33ft) beneath the water's surface.<br />
<br />
Hotel rates tend to be cheaper in the sweltering summer months, when many of the UAE&rsquo;s residents escape to cooler climes. Smaller, non-descript, budget hotels do exist, concentrated around Deira and Bur Dubai in Dubai. There are a number of no-frills, inexpensive chain hotels such as Ibis and Holiday Inn, plus the new Canadian chain City Max, which is keeping prices competitive. The City Max Barsha branch has a lively American-themed rock bar on the ground floor and a very reasonably priced brunch at weekends.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major hotel chains have locations in the UAE. When it comes to hotels, there&rsquo;s luxury and then there&rsquo;s the UAE standard of luxury. Visitors can opt to experience the nation&rsquo;s over-the-top accommodation, with many of the hotels offering gaudy d&eacute;cor, decadent spas and five-star amenities. The Burj al-Arab, the Emirates Palace and the Al Maha Desert Resort &amp; Spa are some of the more luxurious places to stay, but there always seems to be another opulent property opening, including the Armani hotel in the Burj Khalifa, the tallest building in the world.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;d rather pass up Ali Baba&rsquo;s grotto for understated class try the grand Al Qasr, for its tasteful Arabic flavor (think: Middle Eastern patterns and antique fixtures). The grand lobby smells of sweet rose petals, which are scattered into a water feature in the centre, while rooms look out onto the sparkling Gulf waters. Emirates Palace, on the other hand, is all about decadence. Live like Arab royalty in the AED11.2 billion property in a room slathered with gold and marble fittings, while being waited on hand and foot.</p>
<p>One thing&rsquo;s for sure, hotels in the UAE are creative. Right here in the desert you can bed up in a winter-themed hotel, with rooms decorated chalet-style and look out onto a ski slope with penguins. Kempinski Mall of the Emirates is dotted with windows looking onto Ski Dubai inside Mall of the Emirates, meaning you&rsquo;ll never miss colder climes. Dubai is also set to unveil the Water Discus Hotel. Not only will it look like a space ship hovering in the sky, it will have rooms 10m (33ft) beneath the water's surface.<br />
<br />
Hotel rates tend to be cheaper in the sweltering summer months, when many of the UAE&rsquo;s residents escape to cooler climes. Smaller, non-descript, budget hotels do exist, concentrated around Deira and Bur Dubai in Dubai. There are a number of no-frills, inexpensive chain hotels such as Ibis and Holiday Inn, plus the new Canadian chain City Max, which is keeping prices competitive. The City Max Barsha branch has a lively American-themed rock bar on the ground floor and a very reasonably priced brunch at weekends.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major hotel chains have locations in the UAE. When it comes to hotels, there&rsquo;s luxury and then there&rsquo;s the UAE standard of luxury. Visitors can opt to experience the nation&rsquo;s over-the-top accommodation, with many of the hotels offering gaudy d&eacute;cor, decadent spas and five-star amenities. The Burj al-Arab, the Emirates Palace and the Al Maha Desert Resort &amp; Spa are some of the more luxurious places to stay, but there always seems to be another opulent property opening, including the Armani hotel in the Burj Khalifa, the tallest building in the world.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;d rather pass up Ali Baba&rsquo;s grotto for understated class try the grand Al Qasr, for its tasteful Arabic flavor (think: Middle Eastern patterns and antique fixtures). The grand lobby smells of sweet rose petals, which are scattered into a water feature in the centre, while rooms look out onto the sparkling Gulf waters. Emirates Palace, on the other hand, is all about decadence. Live like Arab royalty in the AED11.2 billion property in a room slathered with gold and marble fittings, while being waited on hand and foot.</p>
<p>One thing&rsquo;s for sure, hotels in the UAE are creative. Right here in the desert you can bed up in a winter-themed hotel, with rooms decorated chalet-style and look out onto a ski slope with penguins. Kempinski Mall of the Emirates is dotted with windows looking onto Ski Dubai inside Mall of the Emirates, meaning you&rsquo;ll never miss colder climes. Dubai is also set to unveil the Water Discus Hotel. Not only will it look like a space ship hovering in the sky, it will have rooms 10m (33ft) beneath the water's surface.<br />
<br />
Hotel rates tend to be cheaper in the sweltering summer months, when many of the UAE&rsquo;s residents escape to cooler climes. Smaller, non-descript, budget hotels do exist, concentrated around Deira and Bur Dubai in Dubai. There are a number of no-frills, inexpensive chain hotels such as Ibis and Holiday Inn, plus the new Canadian chain City Max, which is keeping prices competitive. The City Max Barsha branch has a lively American-themed rock bar on the ground floor and a very reasonably priced brunch at weekends.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;It is recommended that any necessary vaccinations are done before your trip. However, emergency vaccinations are also available in the UAE from places such as the Dubai London Clinic (&lt;a href="http://www.dubailondonclinic.com" target="_blank"&gt;www.dubailondonclinic.com&lt;/a&gt;) and the Gulf Diagnostic Centre Hospital (&lt;a href="http://www.gdc-hospital.com" target="_blank"&gt;www.gdc-hospital.com&lt;/a&gt;) for various fees, depending on the vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medical facilities in the UAE are of a very high quality but it is important to bear in mind that they are expensive. Private healthcare and/or travel insurance is highly recommended when travelling to this region. Recommended clinics include the Al Noor Hospital, (+971 2 626 52 65, &lt;a href="http://www.mediclinic.ae/AlNoor/PageContent.aspx?pageid=7979&amp;amp;groupid=1" target="_blank"&gt;www.alnoorhospital.com&lt;/a&gt;) and the Aster Medical Centre (+971 4 400 500, &lt;a href="http://www.astermedicalcentre.com/" target="_blank"&gt;www.astermedicalcentre.com&lt;/a&gt;) in Abu Dhabi and the American Hospital Dubai (+971 4 336 7777, &lt;a href="http://www.ahdubai.com/" target="_blank"&gt;www.ahdubai.com&lt;/a&gt;) in Dubai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The UAE is often in the press for arresting tourists who haven&amp;rsquo;t done their homework on banned medicines. Some UK prescriptions and over the counter medicines in the West are known to be illegal in the UAE. These include codeine (which is often found in cold and flu medicines), lithium, diazepam (found in Valium), methadone and alprazolam (found in Xanax). Other banned substances include food derivatives of opium such as poppy seeds, plus substances qat leaf, betel leaf or nuts, &lt;em&gt;niswar&lt;/em&gt; and gutkha. There is zero tolerance for importing illegal drugs, and doing so can lead to a four-year prison sentence. However, the banned drugs list does change, so make sure you visit the Government of Dubai website for an up to date list (&lt;a href="http://www.dubai.ae" target="_blank"&gt;www.dubai.ae&lt;/a&gt;) or consult your embassy before you travel. The British embassy also advises travellers to always carry their prescriptions with them when travelling with medicine, in case they are questioned or detained at the airport. No anti-malarial tablets are required when visiting UAE.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Though the water in the UAE will taste different, it is safe to drink. However, bottled water is so cheap to buy in the emirates that most visitors opt to drink it instead of tap water. A 500ml bottle of water costs between AED1-6, while a one-gallon bottle of water costs approximately AED12. Food standards are high in Abu Dhabi and Dubai, both of which have international cuisine and world-class restaurants. Care should be taken in smaller desert towns, where hygiene restrictions are not enforced as often. Be aware when eating meat, particularly spit cooked shawarma (kebab) meat, that has been sitting in the stifling summer sun for hours.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis, hepatitis A, hepatitis B, polio, measles and diphtheria are sometimes advised when travelling to this region. If you are snorkelling or scuba diving and get a coral cut, it is advisable to disinfect the wound immediately to avoid infection, as the coral contain a high amount of bacteria. If disinfectant is not readily available, a course of antibiotics may be required.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given  below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>National Day :
							02 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into the United Arab Emirates without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 400 cigarettes and 50 cigars and 500g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine or spirits or 48 cans of beer.<br />
&bull; Goods to the value of AED3,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics, goods from boycotted countries (eg <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/middle-east/israel/">Israel</a>), ivory, rhino horn, gambling devices, original engravings, prints or sculptures, any immoral publications or media contradicting Islamic teachings, counterfeit currency, and cooked or homemade food.</p>
<p>If you are planning to carry medication into the country, check with your embassy in advance, as some common, over-the-counter medicines that are freely available elsewhere in the world are prohibited in the UAE. Penalties are severe - you could go to prison if you&rsquo;re caught.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>UAE Dirham (AED, also written as Dhs) = 100 fils. Notes are in denominations of AED1,000, 500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of AED1, and 50, 25, 10 and 5 fils (10 and 5 fils coins are rarely used).<br />
<br />
The Dirham is tied to the US Dollar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most hotels will handle the exchange of foreign currency as well as many major banks. Many of the large shopping malls have bureaux de change. Recommended bureaux de change include UAE Exchange located at  Dubai Mall and Marina Mall, both in Dubai, or Hamdan Street, Abu Dhabi.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted. ATMs are found across the UAE, mostly in the major cities of <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/middle-east/united-arab-emirates/abu-dhabi/">Abu Dhabi</a> and <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/middle-east/united-arab-emirates/dubai/">Dubai</a>.</p><p>ATMs accept foreign debit and credit cards including Switch, Maestro, Visa, Union Pay and Cirrus, and can be found throughout the UAE, in shopping malls, hotels and petrol stations. However, cash back is not commonly available in the UAE. Plan ahead if you are taking taxis, they will only accept cash and often only small notes and change.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are widely accepted, though not often used. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars or Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These vary depending on the branch and bank, however a rule of thumb is Sat-Wed between 0800-1300 and Thursdays 0800-noon. Some open later in the evening from 1600-1830. All are closed on Fridays and public holidays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter the United Arab Emirates, a passport valid for a minimum of six months beyond the end date of the stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You don't need a transit visa if you're connecting to another flight within 12 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visit visa on arrival (for eligible nationals only): free.</p>
<p>Short visit visa (for those not eligible for the visa on arrival): &pound;60. A sponsor (eg travel agency, hotel, company or individual) must apply for this on your behalf and you must collect it on arrival at the airport.</p>
<p>Long visit visa: &pound;125. Again, a sponsor must apply for this on your behalf.</p>
<p>Multiple-entry visa: &pound;121 for 30 days; &pound;303 for 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visit visa on arrival: 30 or 90 days.</p>
<p>Short visit visa: valid for two months before entering the UAE and for a stay of up to 30 days.</p>
<p>Long visit visa: valid for two months before entering the UAE and for a stay of up to 90 days.</p>
<p>Multiple-entry visa: valid for multiple stays of up to 14 days in a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>On arrival (if eligible), through a sponsor in the UAE, or at the embassy in your country.</p>
<p>If you require a pre-arranged visa and are flying to or via Dubai with Emirates, you can also apply for a visa online when booking your flight; more information is available from VFS Global (<a href="http://dubaivisa.net">http://dubaivisa.net</a>). Visas are available for 96 hours, 14 days, 30 days or 90 days and you must apply at least 10 working days before you travel to Dubai. You can also obtain 30- or 90-day multiple-entry visas. This option is only available to Emirates passengers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unless you are a UAE national, residency is temporary and usually valid for three years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow between three and five days for visa processing when arranged through a sponsor. However, allowances should be made for possible delays in approval procedure. It is strongly advised to apply well in advance of your departure date.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some nationals may require proof that they have sufficient funds in their bank account to travel to the UAE. Check with the UAE Embassy in your home country for details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Certain nationalities can extend their 30-day visa for an additional period of 30 days. Visit the General Directorate of Residency and Foreigner Affairs website for further details (<a target="_blank" href="http://dnrd.ae/en">http://dnrd.ae/en</a>). Alternatively extend a 30-day tourist visa on arrival by driving across the land borders to Oman. Overstaying your visa may result in a fine.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing a pet, you should arrange a microchip and a rabies vaccination certificate 30 days prior to travel. You should also obtain an import permit from the Ministry of Environment and Water.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[23.685020]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[54.204020]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>83,600 sq km (32,278 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>9,269,612 (2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>99 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Abu Dhabi.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Federation of seven autonomous emirates. The highest federal authority is the Supreme Council of Rulers comprising the absolute rulers of the seven emirates. Decisions reached by the council must have the agreement of at least five members, including Abu Dhabi and Dubai, the two largest members. The council appoints a president to act as head of state. There are no political parties.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The UAE sits at the top right hand corner of the Arabian Peninsula bordered by Oman in the east and Saudi Arabia in the south. All of the Emirates bar one sit on the on the Persian Gulf opposite Iran, and cover a distance spanning 650 km (404 miles) along the coastline<strong>. </strong>Fujairah is the only Emirate that sits on the Gulf of Oman.&nbsp;The UAE covers an area of 83,600 sq km (32,300 sq miles), Abu Dhabi covers 87% of the country's land mass, which has a consistent terrain of mainly desert. It is home to native animals such as gazelles and the Arabian oryx, which was reintegrated into the area 40 years after it was hunted to extinction. Whilst 80% of the land mass is desert, other ecological terrain includes mountain areas and marine coastal areas.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The highest recorded point in the country is an unnamed peak stretching 1,910m (6266ft) high near the Jabal Bil Ays in Oman (but within the UAE border). The lowest point is at the Persian  Gulf. The country only has 3.8% forest and woodlands due to the arid conditions. In an oasis is it common to find date palms, acacia and eucalyptus trees. Sand storms are common in the UAE, and this can cause traffic on the roads due to the poor visibility.</p>
<p>Off the coast of Fujairah the waters are rich in calcium carbonate, and make the ideal breeding ground for coral reefs such as alveopora coral, African pillow coral, brain coral, raspberry-rice coral and more. The marine life in the area is rich due to these diverse coral formations and species in the area include Arabian carpet sharks, areloate groupers, black-finned melon butterfly fish, blacktip reef sharks, parrot fish and even whale sharks, which can be spotted by snorkellers and divers between the months of April and July.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The vast majority of Emirati nationals are muslims, approximately 90% Sunni and 10%  Shia. The UAE  follows a policy of tolerating existence of other religions, through the Ministry of Tolerance. Based on the latest Ministry of Economy census in 2005, 76% of the total population is Muslim, 9% Christian, and 15% are recorded as other (mainly Hindu).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The UAE is an Islamic country and women may feel more comfortable when dressed modestly. Even though foreign women can dress as they please, covering the shoulders and knees is a requirement in public areas like shopping centres and also during periods of religious significance. Men are also expected to dress with respect. Homosexuality and adultery are both illegal and while non-married couples aren&rsquo;t lawfully permitted to stay together in the same hotel room, it is common practice and rarely enforced.</p>
<p>Alcohol is tolerated, with non-Muslims allowed to drink alcohol in the cities&rsquo; plentiful hotel bars and restaurants (except for Sharjah). Tourists are permitted to bring four litres of alcohol into the country, though under 20s are not allowed to drink alcohol or buy cigarettes. It is illegal for everyone to eat, drink or smoke in public during daylight hours of the holy month of Ramadan, and on the day or eve of days of national importance, alcohol isn&rsquo;t sold and bars are shut. As in all Muslim countries, it&rsquo;s best to keep displays of affection private &ndash; kissing or embracing in public is not only considered disrespectful, it could lead to police caution or even arrest. Holding hands is generally fine, but swearing, rude gestures and drink driving are all punishable by imprisonment. Drugs are a strict no-no and could land you in serious trouble. It&rsquo;s worth checking what medicine and painkillers you bring into the country, as even some common pain medications like codeine are prohibited.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vice President and Prime Minister of the United Arab Emirates and Ruler of Dubai Crown Prince Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid al-Maktoum since 2006.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed al-Nahyan since 2004.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It can be fascinating to examine the UAE&rsquo;s foray into the modern world when only decades ago, the country was occupied by desert roaming, nomadic Bedouin tribes, who enjoyed simple existences in fishing villages and the peaceful, expansive desert.</p>
<p>The Bedouin people traded with merchants from Iran, China and India before the arrival of Europeans in the 1400s.&nbsp;From the late 1400s, the Portuguese had control over much of the coastal emirates. But in an 1892 treaty, the sheiks that had control over what we now know as the UAE gave up much of their foreign relations power to the British government.</p>
<p>Trading of the UAE&rsquo;s &quot;black gold&quot; (crude oil) &ndash; the source of the country&rsquo;s infallible wealth - commenced in 1962,&nbsp;after years of hardship that followed the downfall of the pearling industry in the 1930s.  It was soon obvious that the British government could no longer administer and protect the emirates, so in March 1971 the treaties ended and the nine Persian Gulf sheikdoms began negotiations to form a union of Arab emirates. On 2 December 1971, Abu Dhabi and Dubai joined forces with four other emirates to form the United Arab Emirates. Sheikh Zayed bin Sultan Al Nahyan, the former ruler of Abu Dhabi, became the UAE&rsquo;s first president. After he passed away in 2004, his eldest son, Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan, took over and he has been president ever since.</p>
<p>●&nbsp;The Dubai police force use Lamborghinis and Ferraris so that they can catch speeders.<br />
● Dubai has no address system and no postal codes. For a package to arrive at the desired location, the sender would have to leave instructions about the destination of the package, or send it to a PO Box.<br />
●&nbsp;The world&rsquo;s fastest roller coaster is housed at Ferrari World, Abu Dhabi&rsquo;s indoor theme park.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Abu Dhabi]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+971 (2) 610 1100.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ukinuae.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+971 (2) 610 1100.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Sun-Thurs 0730-1430, (0800-1100 for consular services).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Khalid bin Al Waleed St(Street 22), PO Box 248<br/>Abu Dhabi<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the United Arab Emirates in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7581 1281 </p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.mofa.gov.ae/EN/DiplomaticMissions/Embassies/London/Pages/home.aspx</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7581 1281 </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1600&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Belgravia<br/>1-2 Grosvenor Crescent<br/>London<br/>SW1X 7EE<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Dubai]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+971 4 309 4444.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ukinuae.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+971 4 309 4444.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Sun-Thurs 0730-1430; (0800-1100 for consular services).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Al Seef Road, PO Box 65<br/>Dubai<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the United Arab Emirates in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 243 2400.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.uae-embassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 243 2400.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1600. Consular services (legalisation, visas, passports) Mon–Thurs 0930-1300 and Fri 0930-1230.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3522 International Court, Suite 400<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Comprised of little more than sand dunes, crumbling forts and fishing villages a century ago, the United Arab Emirates (UAE) has grown into a show-stopping, headline-grabbing destination which offers an intriguing blend of traditional Islamic culture and rampant consumerism.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Powered largely (but by no means exclusively) by oil wealth, the UAE today is defined by opulent resort hotels, ultra-modern architecture and a seemingly unending thirst for new and innovative mega-projects. Manmade islands in the shape of palm trees? Tick. Billionaire royals taking over Premiership football clubs? Tick. Tallest building on the planet? Naturally.</p>
<p>Seven separate emirates make up the country, but visitor attention falls mainly on Dubai and Abu Dhabi. Both are home to an ever-growing spread of luxury accommodation, gourmet restaurants, branded nightclubs and gleaming shopping malls. Dubai&rsquo;s most iconic sights include the sail-shaped &ldquo;7-star&rdquo; hotel Burj Al Arab, the Burj Khalifa skyscraper and the sea-themed Atlantis Resort, which are microcosms of the UAE&rsquo;s lofty ambitions.</p>
<p>The regular fountain show in the Downtown area rivals that of the Bellagio in Las Vegas, while vast shopping complexes like Dubai Mall (complete with one of the world&rsquo;s largest aquariums) and Mall of the Emirates (complete with ski slope) are packed with premium international labels.</p>
<p>Abu Dhabi, meanwhile, doesn&rsquo;t have quite the same verve but boasts some remarkable attractions, from the Sheikh Zayed Grand Mosque to the Ferrari World theme park. And in both destinations, there&rsquo;s the option to delve into the UAE&rsquo;s blend of Islamic culture and modernity, from spice souks to falcon hospitals. Meanwhile, the vast natural desert offers endless discoveries via exciting modes of transport from hot air balloon and quad bike to helicopter or sandboard.</p>
<p>And don&rsquo;t be dazzled by Abu Dhabi and Dubai alone &ndash; the other emirates are also worthy of exploration. Among them, coastal Fujairah offers nature walks and a host of outdoor adventures, including mountain biking and scuba diving, while Ras al-Khamiah has excellent off-road driving and hiking in the rugged Hajar Mountains.</p><p>Comprised of little more than sand dunes, crumbling forts and fishing villages a century ago, the United Arab Emirates (UAE) has grown into a show-stopping, headline-grabbing destination that offers an intriguing blend of traditional Islamic culture and rampant consumerism. Powered largely (but by no means exclusively) by oil wealth, the UAE today is defined by opulent resort hotels, ultra-modern architecture and a seemingly unending thirst for new and innovative mega-projects. Manmade islands in the shape of palm trees? Tick. Billionaire royals taking over Premiership football clubs? Tick. Tallest building on the planet? Naturally.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
