<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Isle of Man" ColCode="ism" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="im" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Isle of Man]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[The climate of the Isle of Man is temperate, with cool summers and mild winters. There is a considerable variation in rainfall over the island, although the average is high in comparison to the rest of the British isles, as the isle of Man is located to the west of mainland <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">Britain</a> and far enough from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ireland">Ireland</a> for moisture to accumulate on the prevailing south-westerly winds. The driest parts of the island are in the extreme south and over the northern plain, whilst the wettest are the hilly interior and Snaefell. However, frost and snow occur much less frequently than in other parts of the British Isles. Temperatures are consistently cool, although the recorded maximum is almost 29C. The north of the island lies in a rain shadow and has higher levels of sunshine in general.</p><p>With consistent temperatures, the Isle of Man is a good year-round destination. However, April, May and June are the driest months, whilst May, June and July are the sunniest and July and August are the warmest.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You ought to take a range of clothing suitable for a variety of weather conditions. Ensure that you have waterproof and windproof layers as well as warmer clothing for the evenings. If you are going walking, make sure that you have comfortable, well-broken-in boots with good ankle support.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Horse trams run along the 3km (2 miles) of the Douglas Promenade during the summer; they are essentially a novelty rather than a serious means of getting anywhere but they do allow you to enjoy the views in a certain style. The Steam Railway operates from Douglas to Port Erin and the Manx Electric Railway runs from Douglas to Ramsey.</p>
<p>Other rail services include original 19th century electric and steam services; an historic narrow gauge steam train rumbles from Douglas to Port Erin via Castletown, whilst an electric service travels from Douglas to Ramsey via Laxey.</p>
<p>The unique Snaefell Mountain Railway, which runs to the summit of Snaefell mountain, and the Groudle Glen Railway (a narrow gauge system), which provides a limited service along a scenic track near Douglas in the summer months are two other interesting train trips to take. For more information, contact the rail and bus information line (<a href="http://www.iombusandrail.info" target="_blank">www.iombusandrail.info</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is some very good driving to be had on the Isle of Man, with superb, scenic sweeping bends and exciting stretches of tarmac to follow. The road network is extensive and outside of Douglas there is very little congestion. The most popular driving route is to follow the course of the TT race.</p>l<p>Roads on the Isle of Man are generally well-maintained.</p><p>There is a comprehensive bus service, Bus Vannin, on the Isle of Man that means you can go almost everywhere on public transport. There is a timetable available at the tourist office in Douglas. You can also buy tickets here. For the best value, buy an 'Island Explorer' ticket, which entitles you to free rides on all public transport, including trams.</p><p>Taxis can be found in most of the main towns and are a convenient way of getting around the island.</p><p>Full UK driving licence is acceptable.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 16. In derestricted zones there is no speed limit, so outside of towns it is possible to drive as fast as you like although you may still be stopped for dangerous driving. Be aware that petrol on the Isle of Man is expensive. There is plenty of parking on the island and you can park for free with a hire car if you display a parking disc, included with your hire vehicle. It is a criminal offence to drive whilst using a mobile phone.</p><p>There are a number of breakdown and recovery services operating on the island – check with your car hire company for what to do in case of emergency.</p><p>Private taxis operate all year round and there are a number of car hire firms, most of which have offices or desks at the airport or sea terminal. Most international car hire firms are represented on the island. You will need a full, clean license to hire a car. Satellite navigation systems and children's seats are also available to hire.</p><p>Bicycles are available for hire in the summer months. Eurocycles (<a href="http://www.eurocycles.co.im">www.eurocycles.co.im</a>) have bikes available to hire per day.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 16. In derestricted zones there is no speed limit, so outside of towns it is possible to drive as fast as you like although you may still be stopped for dangerous driving. Be aware that petrol on the Isle of Man is expensive. There is plenty of parking on the island and you can park for free with a hire car if you display a parking disc, included with your hire vehicle. It is a criminal offence to drive whilst using a mobile phone.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most towns and cities, even Douglas, are small and compact meaning that you can comfortably explore them on foot. For something different, try the horse trams that ply their trade on the Douglas Promenade.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Isle of Man has good air links. The international airport, Ronaldsway Airport, is 16km (10 miles) south of Douglas, near Castletown. There are regular flights to the Isle of Man from regional British airports, with some flights from the north west taking less than half an hour. The busiest routes to and from the Isle of Man operate between Ronaldsway and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/manchester/manchester-airport">Manchester</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england/london-gatwick-airport">London Gatwick</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/liverpool">Liverpool</a>. The airport has full banking facilities, post and telephone access, internet access, a left luggage facility, a number of shops and several restaurants and bars in which to wait.</p>
<p>British Airways (BA) (<a href="http://www.britishairways.com" target="_blank">www.britishairways.com</a>) operates between the Isle of Man and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/glasgow-airport">Glasgow</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland/edinburgh-airport">Edinburgh</a> and Manchester. Flybe (BE) (<a href="http://www.flybe.com" target="_blank">www.flybe.com</a>) maintain routes from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england/birmingham-airport">Birmingham</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england/bristol-airport">Bristol</a>, Luton, Liverpool, Manchester, Glasgow, Edinburgh and London Gatwick whilst manx2 (<a href="http://www.manx2.com" target="_blank">www.manx2.com</a>) also operate services to the Isle of Man from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/northern-ireland/belfast-international-airport">Belfast</a>, Blackpool, Leeds-Bradford, Gloucester and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england/newcastle-international-airport">Newcastle</a> airports. Aer Arran (<a href="http://www.aerarann.com" target="_blank">www.aerarann.com</a>) operates from and Blue Islands (<a href="http://www.blueislands.com" target="_blank">www.blueislands.com</a>) have connections between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/channel-islands/guernsey">Guernsey</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jersey-airport">Jersey</a> and the Isle of Man.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flight time from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england/london-city-airport">London City</a> is about 1 hour 15 minutes, from where you can pick up connections to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/europe">Europe</a> and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">United States</a>. There are also direct flights from Edinburgh (55 minutes).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A regular shuttle bus service links the airport and Douglas, with services every 30 minutes from 0700–2300. Taxis are also readily available to make the journey; there is a rank situated outside the entrance of the terminal building and taxis meet all flights. Most destinations are covered by fixed tarif charges.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A regular shuttle bus service links the airport and Douglas, with services every 30 minutes from 0700–2300. Taxis are also readily available to make the journey; there is a rank situated outside the entrance of the terminal building and taxis meet all flights. Most destinations are covered by fixed tarif charges.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main port and point of arrival for ferries, cruise ships and people sailing is Douglas, which has extensive facilities for both commercial and private vessels. Douglas is the only port with dedicated passenger handling facilities and roll-on, roll-off vehicle services. The marina offers a small number of berths for visiting leisure craft. There are further berths at Castletown, Laxey, Peel and Ramsey. Coastguard stations can be found at Douglas, Castletown, Peel, Port Erin and Ramsey.</p><p>It's often cheaper to buy a return ticket than to pay a single fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>The main telephone provider on the island is Manx Telecom. The island does not have its own country code but is accessed via the UK's country code (+44). The island's telephone numbers are part of the UK telephone numbering plan, with local dialling code 01624 for landlines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are two mobile operators, Manx Telecom and Sure. Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a number of internet caf&eacute;s on the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local papers include the <em>Isle of Man Courier</em>, the <em>Manx Independent</em> and the <em>Isle of Man Examiner</em>; all three are owned by Isle of Man Newspapers, part of the media group Johnston Press, and published weekly. The Isle of Man was a pioneer of commercial radio in the British Isles thanks to its local laws. Manx radio (Radio Vannin in Manx) is funded by advertising and a government grant; it launched in 1964, long before the UK authorities gave the green light to commercial radio. It carries some programmes in Manx. Other local radio stations include Energy FM and 3FM. There are no TV stations based on the Isle of Man; residents can receive UK channels. Although there has been talk of a Manx TV station, nothing has yet come to pass.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Services are administered by Isle of Man Post, which issues its own postage stamps.</p><p>vary, but most are open Mon-Fri 0900-1730 and Sat 0900-1230. Some have half days on Wed or Thurs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Castle Rushen</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the centre of the Island's former capital Castletown, find this wonderfully preserved 13th century castle. Clamber up the spiral staircase, browse ancient tapestries, and explore all that lies within these ancient limestone walls. From the flag tower you can get especially good views of the coast and town below.</p>]]><p><b>Climb Snaefell</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Reaching 621m (2,036 ft) at its peak, Snaefell is an attractive proposition for walkers. There's a simple 1.5hr walk to the top or some trickier routes across more rugged and boggier ground. Alternatively you can cheat and catch the electric tram from Laxey. From the summit you can see all of the island and the bodies of water surrounding it; the local claim is that you can see seven surrounding kingdoms: Mann, Scotland, Ireland, Wales, England, Neptune and Heaven although the last two are more debatable, even if you get clear weather.</p>]]><p><b>Discover Manx stone crosses</b></p><![CDATA[<p>All across the island you'll discover fascinating sixth century crosses that represent grave markers and memorial stones; there are more than 200 to see. The earliest examples show Celtic styles using complicated interlacing and inscriptions whilst later, Norse sculptors used pagan images and mythology to decorate their stones.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the Manx Glens</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are 17 glens all over the island, each with a distinct character. Many lead to the sea or to secret beaches. Explore them on foot to get a feel for some of the Isle of Man's hidden corners. Ballaglass is carpeted in bluebells during the spring; Groudle has a small railway running through it; Glen Maye is full of verdant vegetation and has a magnificent waterfall although Dhoon Glen, one of the steepest, hides the island's highest waterfall.</p>]]><p><b>Douglas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Home to around a third of the island's population, Douglas is the capital of the Isle of Man and the centre of commerce. In its heyday during the mid-19th century the town was a favourite with Victorian visitors. Less popular and less pretty now, it still has a faded air of elegance, especially along the promenade. It's also home to many of the island's best hotels and restaurants.</p>]]><p><b>Go mountain biking</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its varied terrain, quiet country lanes and challenging off-road, the Isle of Man is one of the best places in Britain for mountain biking. There are six designated off-road trails around the island, each of varying difficulty.</p>]]><p><b>Lady Isabella Laxey Wheel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Built in 1854 to pump water from a mine, this giant wheel measures 22m (72.1ft) across and draws up to 1140L of water per minute from 550m (1,804ft) below the surface. Well-maintained and visually impressive, this is the largest wheel in the world of its kind. It is named after the wife of the then lieutenant-governor.</p>]]><p><b>Music festivals</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Manx National Festival, Yn Chruinnaght (<a href="http://www.ynchruinnaght.com" target="_blank">www.ynchruinnaght.com</a>) is a celebration of Manx culture and its relationship with what it calls the other 'five Celtic countries', namely Scotland, Ireland, Wales, Cornwall and Brittany (!), usually held in the middle of July. Expect crafts, dance and music. Also check out Shennaghys Jiu (<a href="http://www.shennaghys.org/" target="_blank">www.shennaghys.org</a>) in April for ceilidhs and concerts.</p>]]><p><b>Peel Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This Viking relic stands proudly atop St Patrick's Isle and is connected to Peel by a causeway. It is open to visitors in the summer months. The ruins of the castle are surrounded by emerald grounds, and look out towards the water; stroll here at dusk for particularly spectacular sunsets. Keep a look out for basking sharks and seals along the breakwaters as well.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the rails</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Isle of Man is known for its narrow-gauge railways, but even those not sporting an anorak and carrying a notebook will enjoy a scenic ride on the variety of railways that trundle around the island. Snaefell Mountain Railway climbs to the summit of Man's highest peak.</p>]]><p><b>Sample some seafood</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There's plenty of fishing off the coast of the Isle of Man and you can enjoy great fresh seafood straight off the boats, often cooked over a hot grill or served simply. Chomp on one of Man's famous kippers (smoked herring), to which Moore's Traditional Museum in Peel is dedicated. So they must be good.</p>]]><p><b>See a Manx ghost</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mythology is an important part of Manx culture and ghosts, of course, form a major part of this. Across the main settlements of Ramsey, Douglas, Peel and Castletown, local guides will take you on a chilling journey around the island's most haunted spots to hear about the White Lady of Castle Rushen and the Black Dog of Peel Castle.</p>]]><p><b>The House of Manannan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Based in the City of Peel, the House of Manannan examines the seafaring heritage of Celtic, Viking and modern day islanders. Using multimedia displays, the guide for the tour is Manannan, the island's mythological sea god shape-shifter.</p>]]><p><b>The Manx Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Variously a Norse stronghold, Scottish outpost and English protectorate, the history of long and complex, but the Manx Museum in Douglas, where interactive displays explain the Isle of Man's background background and take visitors up to the present, detailing even the latest TT winners.</p>]]><p><b>The Sound and the Calf of Man</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A small islet off Creyneash, in the southwest of the island, the Calf of Man is a rugged, picturesque spot. It is a bird sanctuary and home to a variety of seabird colonies. Seals, dolphins and basking sharks can often be seen in the Sound too. You can cruise around the Calf from Port Erin with Calf Island Cruises and can also stay on the island in the warden's farmhouse with prior permission during summer. Drop into the Sound Visitor Centre in Port St Mary to learn about the ships that sank in the area and the subsequent wrecks that divers now explore.</p>]]><p><b>Walking</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The whole island has tracks allowing you to explore on foot and the Isle of Man is often described as having some of the best walking in Britain. The Millennium Way runs the length of the country amidst spectacular scenery and the Road of the Gull (Raad ny Foillan) is a 153km (95 mile) circuit of the island; fairly tough, it meanders all around the coast, over cliffs, through glens and down steep gorges; it typically takes five days to complete. The best sections include Bradda Head, where a stone tower has panoramic views over Port Erin, and Maughold Head, which is home to puffins. Tynwald National Park and Arboretum offers a more relaxed walk.</p>]]><p><b>Watch the races</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The most famous event on the Isle of Man are the TT Races (<a href="http://www.iomtt.com" target="_blank">www.iomtt.com</a>). The series of motorbike races, is one of the most important meetings in the world. The riders hurl along the closed roads at cheek-wobbling speeds, and has its fair share of spills, especially on 'Mad Sunday' when anyone can ride the mountain section.</p>]]><p><b>Whale watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Basking sharks and dolphins love the waters around the Isle of Man and can frequently be seen, often within one kilometre of the coast. The best time to see them is from mid-May to mid-August. Find out how many have been seen at   <a href="http://www.manxbaskingsharkwatch.com" target="_blank">www.manxbaskingsharkwatch.com</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$2.1 billion (2010).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Tweeds, herring, processed shellfish, beef and lamb.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Timber, fertilisers and fish.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>UK. The Isle of Man has free access to the European Union markets for goods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The island's economy relies principally on financial services; banking accounts for around 15% of the economy with insurance and other financial services accounting for a further 20% or so. Financial service businesses are attracted by banking secrecy laws that render assets deposited on the island less vulnerable to disclosure requirements than those on the mainland. That said, the Manx government has made strides to shake off the island&rsquo;s reputation as a shady tax haven by improving financial transparency and signing tax information exchange deals with a dozen countries.<br />
<br />
Taxation rates are also, on the whole, lower than those of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>. There&rsquo;s no capital gains tax, wealth tax, stamp duty, death duty or inheritance tax on the island. Tourism accounts for around 5% of GDP, a figure that is improving all the time. The island has also attracted online gambling sites, a fact that has led to information technology being the fastest growing sector here.</p>
<p>There is a small agricultural and fishing sector, and limited manufacturing; once the mainstays of the local economy, the importance of these sectors continues to diminish. Financial incentives offered to film and television producers have led to an increase in the number of major productions shot on the island in recent years. The island&rsquo;s landscape has starred in a number of movie genres, from sci-fi thrillers, romantic comedies, action adventures and period dramas as the sweeping coastlines, pretty towns and rustic countryside provide a wide variety of locations on which to shoot. The 19th century crofter&rsquo;s cottages of Cregneash, the oldest village on the island, stood in for an Irish village in Waking Ned when filmmakers failed to find anywhere in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ireland">Ireland</a> that was &lsquo;Irish enough&rsquo;.</p>
<p>The unemployment rate was a mere 2.3% in 2012, substantially lower than elsewhere in the UK, and growth was a healthy 4-5% in 2011, a fact attributed to the island&rsquo;s diverse economy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businesspeople are generally expected to dress smartly (suits are the norm). Appointments should be made and the exchange of business cards is customary. A knowledge of English is essential.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700/1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Isle of Man Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (01624) 674 941
					Website:http://www.iomchamber.org.im
					Address: ,17 Drinkwater Street,Douglas IM1 1PP,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Food on the Isle of Man is generally good, with the emphasis on a blend of seafood and local game. As the emphasis shifts to better quality, sustainability, organic and local food, the Isle of Man has started to garner a bit of a foodie reputation for itself; there&rsquo;s even an annual Food &amp; Drink Festival celebrating the quality and variety of local produce.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>&nbsp;With its rolling hills, fertile land and clear, clean surrounding seas there is much to choose from and all of it packs a flavour punch. Most farms sell garden produce such as milk and eggs, whilst there are a number of grocers, fishmongers, butchers and farmers markets around the island specialising in local fare. Alternatively stop at a country pub, quayside caf&eacute; or fine restaurant to enjoy the rich pickings.</p>
<br />
<p>&nbsp;The island has a host of its own local products and ingredients to show off, from local bread, flour, full-flavoured cheeses and luscious lamb to 60 flavours of creamy, rich Manx ice cream. The same people who make the ice cream, Davisons, are also responsible for producing delicious local chocolates. Another local favourite is bonnag, a type of crumbly, fruity cake not dissimilar to a scone.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>Perhaps the island&rsquo;s most famous food though is the Manx kipper, which has been a tradition since the late 1800s; herrings are caught locally in the Irish Sea, then cut, salted and smoked with oak chips to give them a unique flavour. Smoked salmon is a speciality here as well. Look out too for Manx Queenies, queen scallops served with a white or cheese sauce. Crab and lobster are commercially fished. Cod, ling and mackerel are often fished for the table and freshwater trout and salmon can be taken from the local rivers and lakes.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull;</em> Queen scallops.<br /><em>&bull;</em> Spuds and Herrin (boiled potatoes and herring).<br />&bull; Manx kippers (smoked herring).<br />&bull; <em>Bonnag</em> (a flat loaf of bread).<br />&bull; Davison's ice cream, made in Peel.<br />&bull; Chips, cheese and gravy somewhat like Quebec's <em>poutine</em>.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Pubs usually open Mon-Thurs 1000-2300, Fri-Sat 1000-2400. On Sunday, pubs open 1200-2300. These times can vary according to individual pubs, as 24-hour licensing is now permitted. Special opening hours apply to the Easter and Christmas/New Year periods.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>In hotels, a service charge of 10 to 12% is usual, which may be added to the bill. 10 to 15% is usual for restaurants; if this has already been added to the bill, a further tip is not required.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Douglas is the island's centre of nightlife with its clubs, restaurants and bars. There is a wide variety of entertainment to suit all tastes and ages on offer. For those who like to stay out late, or spend an evening on a tasty tour centred on the island's finest fodder, the island's capital has pretty coastal caf&eacute;s and sea-facing restaurants. It is also home to the Gaiety Theatre and the Villa Marina, (the biggest entertainment centre on the island), with plenty of films and live music shows. For culture elsewhere, visitors should attend the Centenary Centre in Peel or the Erin Arts Centre in Port Erin, where there is often a range of classical music recitals, comedy and drama productions and more modern concerts as well.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>For good pubs offering more traditional entertainment with a view, serving a great pint, try Port Erin and Ramsey, while Peel is home to an award-winning real ale pub. Pubs occasionally host live music or comedy events as well. Many visitors to the island come to enjoy countryside walks, rather than a raucous nightlife; so a friendly pub with lashings of good local ale, is an ideal way for walkers to wind down after a day out in the elements.</p>
<br />]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Head to the two major shopping centres in Douglas for a high street shopping trip. The Tower House and The Strand, both on Strand Street, have a range of leading high street shops catering for fashion, homewares, technology, entertainment and gifts; most British chain stores are represented although the Isle of Man has its own supermarket chain, Shoprite, as well as national chains.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>For local crafts, head to Ramsey to find a great selection of boutique shops including the Crafts Centre in St Paul's Square, or go to Castletown to find a range of craft shops lining the cobble streets here alongside a health food store, wine cellar and old fashioned sweet shop. If you are looking to take home some wool, linen or cloth, then Castletown Textiles if worth a stop. Peel and Port Erin are good if you are on the look out for quirky items, antiques or collectables.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>Special purchases from the island include; gifts themed around the TT motorbikes races, Manx tartan, silver jewellery and fairy dolls. Unusual and practical gifts and heritage souvenirs often have a sense of the Isle of Man&rsquo;s rich Celtic and Viking past. Manx kippers are also packaged so they can be carried home as gifts. Enjoy the island&rsquo;s local drinks by taking away supplies of Manx Ale or ManX whiskey too.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>Woollen jumpers are very good quality and can make a nice present. Travel to the Laxey Woolen Mills on the north east coast to visit the last remaining working woollen mill, which is also home to the traditional Manx tartan containing the colours of the island including purple to represent heather, blue for the skies, yellow for the Manx gorse, green for the hills and white for the clouds. Pick up rugs and scarves here too.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1730. Early closing times on Thursdays during the winter months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide variety of accommodation available all across the Isle of Man. In general there is plenty to go round, except during the summer high season and during the TT races when you must book a long way in advance to secure a bed. Rates vary considerably according to season and location and there are sometimes different prices for online or telephone reservations as well.<br />
<br />
There are a wealth of hotels to choose from, catering to all types of taste and budget. The majority of the hotels are located in Douglas, with a large number found on the promenade, overlooking the sea. They often have their own restaurants, offering local and international cuisine. The larger hotels also boast leisure facilities such as swimming pools, gyms and saunas. Prices are based per person, per night sharing a twin or double room; single supplements may be applicable. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Grading of accommodation follows <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> standards from 1<strong> </strong>to 5 stars, and ranges from basic to deluxe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The B&B is a great institution. There is a wide range of bed and breakfast and guesthouse accommodation, often found in attractive locations around the island. Whether you stay in the capital Douglas, overlooking the promenade, the pretty seaside towns of Peel or Port Erin or stay deep in the countryside in Ramsey, you'll enjoy a warm welcome and friendly service. Accommodation is essentially a room in someones house, either with shared or en suite bathroom facilties. Breakfasts include delicious home cooked local produce such as Manx kippers. Places to stay in this category are usually good value, with prices charged per person, per night, sharing a twin or double room. You should make sure that you book in advance though, especially during popular, summer months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide variety of accommodation available all across the Isle of Man. In general there is plenty to go round, except during the summer high season and during the TT races when you must book a long way in advance to secure a bed. Rates vary considerably according to season and location and there are sometimes different prices for online or telephone reservations as well.<br />
<br />
There are a wealth of hotels to choose from, catering to all types of taste and budget. The majority of the hotels are located in Douglas, with a large number found on the promenade, overlooking the sea. They often have their own restaurants, offering local and international cuisine. The larger hotels also boast leisure facilities such as swimming pools, gyms and saunas. Prices are based per person, per night sharing a twin or double room; single supplements may be applicable. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Grading of accommodation follows <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> standards from 1<strong> </strong>to 5 stars, and ranges from basic to deluxe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide variety of accommodation available all across the Isle of Man. In general there is plenty to go round, except during the summer high season and during the TT races when you must book a long way in advance to secure a bed. Rates vary considerably according to season and location and there are sometimes different prices for online or telephone reservations as well.<br />
<br />
There are a wealth of hotels to choose from, catering to all types of taste and budget. The majority of the hotels are located in Douglas, with a large number found on the promenade, overlooking the sea. They often have their own restaurants, offering local and international cuisine. The larger hotels also boast leisure facilities such as swimming pools, gyms and saunas. Prices are based per person, per night sharing a twin or double room; single supplements may be applicable. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Grading of accommodation follows <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> standards from 1<strong> </strong>to 5 stars, and ranges from basic to deluxe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>No vaccination certificates are required to enter the Isle of Man. The British government ended the long standing bilateral health care agreement between the two countries in 2010, meaning that the Isle of Man Health Service is not part of the &lt;a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom"&gt;UK&lt;/a&gt; NHS and except for immediately necessary and emergency treatment that does not require admission to hospital, visitors to the island who require treatment will be expected to pay for it. It is therefore recommended that all visitors to the Isle of Man ensure that they have appropriate insurance in place. This ought to cover any treatment costs as well as repatriation to the UK by air ambulance should that prove necessary. Dental treatment and prescribed medicines must be paid for. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a hospital, which is modern and provides a high quality service as well as a number of dental practices. Pharmacies are found throughout the island in the larger towns, with a variety in Douglas, Castletown, Peel, Port Erin and Ramsey amongst other places.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Food on the Isle of Man is of a high standard and can be consumed without fear. Water is clean and can be drunk from the taps unless there's a sign to the contrary. You shouldn't drink from streams in the countryside in case there's an issue with the water upstream.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;There are very few natural hazards although high winds, rough seas and dense fog that reduces visibility drastically can potentially cause visitors problems. There are also risks from flooding, both from heavy rain and from high seas. It is a good idea to listen to weather forecasts and in particular pay attention to wind and gale warnings as these can be relevant to people walking on the coast or the open sections of the interior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When out walking on the island, be aware that it is possible to get sunburnt even on slightly overcast days; wear suncream and a hat if outside for prolonged periods. If you have fair skin, wear a light, long-sleeved top and trousers. On colder, wetter days there&amp;rsquo;s the risk of exposure and possibly hypothermia if you do not take the appropriate clothing and kit for the conditions. Whatever the weather, make sure that you take care of your feet when out walking; warm and dry them properly at the end of the day and work on preventing blisters by reducing the friction between your foot and shoe. If you&amp;rsquo;ve left it too late and already have a blister, cover it with Compeed or a second skin style plaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are not a strong or experienced swimmer familiar with the sea, be aware that there can be strong tides and awkward currents off the Isle of Man. Always be aware of changing conditions and tidal movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global warming and rising sea levels are potential longer-term threats as all the island&amp;rsquo;s towns are at risk from increased sea levels. The northern plain, made up of soft marine sediment is also in danger of being lost to the sea over time.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are observed the next working day.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Early May Bank Holiday :
							07 May </p><p>Spring Bank Holiday :
							28 May </p><p>Tynwald Day (National Day) :
							05 July </p><p>Summer Bank Holiday :
							27 August </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Isle of Man Pound (IMP, symbol £) has parity with Sterling. £1 = 100 pence. Notes are in denominations of £50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of £2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 pence. British currency circulates freely and Scottish and northern Irish notes are also acceptable; Manx notes and coins are not generally accepted in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> however.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can exchange foreign currency in banks, bureaus or post offices in main towns and cities across the island. Check rates first and make sure you understand the commission fee being levied.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, MasterCard and Visa are all widely accepted. Cash can be obtained from a multitude of ATMs.</p><p>Cash can be obtained from a multitude of ATMs, available across the island.  To help those that are travelling to the UK, the ATMs at the Sea Terminal and the airport issue English notes only. Watch out for machines that have been tampered with; a common trick is to attach a card reader to the slot.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers cheques are safer than cash but are becoming less and less frequently used as credit or debit cards and ATMs have become the preferred method of obtaining cash. They are rarely accepted for purchases so will still need to be changed into cash at a bank, bureau or post office. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0930-1630 (there may be some variations in closing times). Some banks are open Saturday morning; some all day Saturday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For passport and visa regulations for the Isle of Man, please see the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> passport &amp; visa section. Although the Isle of Man is not part of the UK, British overseas missions process visas on its behalf; fees for the Isle of Man visitor visas are the same as for UK visitor visas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can bring a pet dog, cat or ferret onto the Isle of Man from a rabies-free country or a country with a low incidence of rabies if the pet has been resident there for at least six months, has been microchipped and has been vaccinated at least 21 days prior to entry. If you are coming from a country with a high incidence of rabies your pet will require a blood titer test four months prior to entering the Isle of Man or it will be subject to quarantine. Before arrival your pet must also be treated against certain tapeworms 24-48 hours prior to entering the island, using an approved treatment; any licensed vet can do this.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[54.225002]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-4.561967]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>572 sq km (221 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>87,545 (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>153.1 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Douglas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Self-governed dependency of the British Crown.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Isle of Man is an island situated in the Irish Sea, between the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">United Kingdom</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ireland">Ireland</a>; modest in size, it is just 53km (33 miles) long and 21km (13 miles) wide. The main towns are located along the coastline, which totals 161km (100 miles) and is dented with small bays. Legend has it that the Isle of Man was created when the Irish giant Finn MacCooill hurled a boulder from Ireland&rsquo;s coastline towards <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland">Scotland</a> during a fight. The boulder fell into the sea and became the island.</p>
<p>The island&rsquo;s terrain is varied; the larger part is formed from highly faulted and folded sedimentary rocks although there is an area of sandstone around Peel. Substantial deposits of copper, lead, silver, zinc and iron can be found on the island and there are also quarries of black marble, limestone, clay and granite. Over two-thirds of the land mass is cultivated.</p>
<p>There are two main mountainous areas separated by a central valley that runs from Douglas to Peel. The northern end of the island is a flat plain made up of glacial tills and marine sediment, which leads gently to the sea and long sandy beaches that contrast with the rocky cliffs found elsewhere. At 621m (2,036ft), Snaefell is the only mountain and the highest point on the island. In the south, the island is generally hillier, with distinct valleys. Wooded glens can be found all over the island, often leading to the sea. The longest river on the island is the Sulby, which is 16.9km (10.5 miles) long. Smaller islands and outcrops can be found off the coast, including the Calf of Man at the southern tip and St Patrick&rsquo;s Isle by Peel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Predominantly Christian (Church of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england">England</a>, Roman Catholic, Presbyterian, Methodist), sizeable Muslim, Sikh, Jewish and Hindu minorities. Around 15% of the population have no religion.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The monarchy, though now only symbolic politically, is a powerful and often subconscious unifying force. Members of the Royal Family are the subject of unceasing fascination, with their every move avidly followed and reported by the popular press, both in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> and abroad.</p>
<p>Handshaking is customary when introduced to someone for the first time. One kiss on the cheek is gaining popularity for close friends. Normal social courtesies should be observed when visiting someone's home and a small present such as flowers or chocolates is appreciated. It is polite to wait until everyone has been served before eating.</p><br />]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with three square pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chief Minister Allan Bell since 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Lieutenant Governor Adam Wood since 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A British Crown dependency in the Irish Sea, the Isle of Man is self-governing but with HM The Queen as Head of State represented locally by a Lieutenant Governor.</p>
<p>The original inhabitants of the Isle of Man were Neolithic and Mesolithic tribes, followed by Bronze Age dwellers and the Celts (whose civilisation is the basis of Manx culture). Christianity was introduced during the 5th and 6th centuries as the local language, Manx, began to emerge.</p>
<p>The Vikings arrived more than 1,000 years ago and Norse rule prevailed in the establishment of the Kingdom of Mann and the Isles, which also included the Hebrides and the islands of the Firth of Clyde, from 979 to 1266.</p>
<p>The Vikings founded the Tynwald parliament, which celebrated its millennium in 1979. Although there is no firm evidence for its having been founded in 979 it is one of the world&rsquo;s oldest parliaments and annual outdoor sittings date back to the 8th century.</p>
<p>After a brief period during which the Kingdom of Mann passed between English and Scottish rule, in 1333 Edward III renounced English claims and recognised it as an independent kingdom.</p>
<p>In 1399 the island&rsquo;s king, William, Earl of Wiltshire was executed for treason by Henry IV and his lands, including the Isle of Man, passed back to the English Crown. In 1405 the kingdom was given to Sir John Stanley whose descendants held it for 360 years before the 1765 Isle of Man Purchase Act, which returned the island to the British Crown.</p>
<p>In recent years, the Isle of Man has become famous for its distinct tax status, capitalising on its independent standing to build up a thriving offshore banking and financial services sector. It&rsquo;s also revered for the gruelling Isle of Man TT, a motorcycle race that has been taking place on the island since 1907.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	There is no national speed limit on Isle of Man roads, only local limits.<br />
&bull;	The Isle of Man has become a centre for emerging private space travel companies and in 2012 was named the fifth most likely nation put the next man on the moon.<br />
&bull;	The island&rsquo;s distinctive &lsquo;Three legs of Mann&rsquo; symbol, a triskelion, is of uncertain origin but may relate to Sicily.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As quirky destinations go, you&rsquo;d be hard-pressed to beat the Isle of Man. Its mere existence is even a bit odd.&nbsp;Though officially part of the British Isles, the island is a self-governing kingdom that belongs to neither the United Kingdom nor European Union. Confused? You should be.</p>
<p>Things get stranger still, when you arrive on the island and find you&rsquo;ve travelled back in time &ndash; this is a place where it is possible to get a steam train to the airport.</p>
<p>Suffice to say the island&rsquo;s antiquity adds to the charm of this destination, which is also home to some spectacular scenery: lush valleys, rugged shores and fine sandy beaches abound, making it an adventure playground for outdoor enthusiasts.</p>
<p>Measuring 53km (33 miles) long and 21km (13 miles) wide, the Isle of Man floats in the middle of the Irish Sea, just off the Lancashire coastline. Killer whales, humpbacks, basking sharks, dolphins, seals and myriad bird species can be spotted in the surrounding waters, which are ripe for scuba diving.</p>
<p>The island&rsquo;s main draw, however, is the notoriously dangerous TT motorcycle race, which takes place annually. Too fast for you? Then hit one of the many hiking and mountain biking trails, which crisscross the island. Or delve into the island&rsquo;s curious history by exploring the prehistoric tombs, elaborate Celtic crosses and Iron Age hilltop forts, which are scattered across the wild landscape.</p>
<p>Beneath the time-warp surface, present-day Isle of Man has a contemporary edge. It&rsquo;s still heavily associated with the finance industry, yet film-making and tourism are increasingly important as people start to discover the island's quiet natural beauty and rich heritage.</p>
<p>All things considered, the Isle of Man is a curious destination and perhaps the best-kept secret in the British Isles.</p><p>As quirky destinations go, you&rsquo;d be hard-pressed to beat the Isle of Man. Its mere existence is even a bit odd.&nbsp;Though officially part of the British Isles, the island is a self-governing kingdom that belongs to neither the United Kingdom nor European Union. Confused? You should be, but one thing is for sure: the Isle of Man is well worthy of further exploration.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
