<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Florida" ColCode="flo" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="fl" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Florida]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Summers throughout the state are long, warm and fairly humid. Winters are mild with periodic invasions of cool to occasionally cold air. Coastal areas in all sections of Florida average slightly warmer temperatures in winter and cooler ones in summer. However, tropical storms in Florida are frequent throughout the summer months – the state is said to be as the thunderstorm capital of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a>. However, tornadoes are rather rarer. Northwestern coastal areas are more prone to high rainfall and those looking for drier parts of the stay should try southwestern coastal areas of the state or keep to the interior.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cotton and sun hats are recommended for summer, though air conditioning in many public places can push indoor temperatures down to what feel like Arctic levels. Light jackets are fine for cooler evenings and winter in South and Central Florida, while heavier coats may come in handy occasionally during winter in North Florida.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Florida has a number of regional airports, making flying by private plane an easy option across the state. United Airlines (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>) and Southwest Airlines (<a href="http://www.southwest.com">www.southwest.com</a>) have the most extensive intra-state operations of the major U.S. carriers.</p><p>Flights within Florida tend to be expensive, relative to their short distances.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is possible to get around parts of Florida by ferry; for example there is a year-round, high speed ferry service from Fort Myers and Marco Island to Key West provided by Key West Express (tel: 1 888 539 2628; www.seakeywestexpress.com). The crossing takes just over 3 hours and saves seven hours of driving each way. </p>
<p>There are water taxis in places like Fort Lauderdale, Jacksonville and Tampa. Several river boats ply the Saint Johns River, Florida's longest, flowing 500 km (310 miles) north from the Saint Johns Marsh in Central Florida to the Atlantic Ocean at Jacksonville.]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Amtrak (tel: 1 800 872 7245 in the USA and Canada only; <a href="http://www.amtrak.com" target="_blank">www.amtrak.com</a>) offers limited rail services in the state. There is a commuter service, Tri-Rail, in South Florida and there are plans for a similar rail service in Central Florida called SunRail which is due to open in 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Amtrak (tel: 1 800 872 7245 in the USA only; <a href="http://www.amtrak.com" target="_blank">www.amtrak.com</a>) offers multi-day rail passes good for travel throughout the United States with prices starting from $429 for the 15-day pass.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Florida has four major interstate highways within its borders: I-10, running east-west from Jacksonville to the Alabama border near Pensacola; I-75, running north-south from the Georgia border near Lake City and down the Gulf Coast to Naples before crossing the Everglades to Miami; I-95, running north-south from the Georgia border near Fernandina Beach along the Atlantic Coast to Miami; and I-4, running east-west from Daytona Beach to Tampa. Crossing the state diagonally, Florida's Turnpike, a toll motorway, runs southwest from I-75 near Ocala to Orlando, then south to Miami. Florida also has several interstate highway spurs and bypasses, including I-275 through Tampa and Saint Petersburg, I-295 around Jacksonville, I-595 near Fort Lauderdale, and I-195 and I-395 in Miami.</p>
<p>Most other high-speed motorways in and around Miami and Orlando are toll roads, many of which no longer feature cash toll booths. See the Florida Department of Transportation's SunPass prepaid toll programme website (<a href="http://www.sunpass.com">www.sunpass.com</a>) for more information.</p><p>Excellent. As with most of the US, there is a good network of highways and all roads are paved.</p><p>Greyhound Bus Lines (tel 1 800 231 2222, in the USA only; <a href="http://www.greyhound.com" target="_blank">www.greyhound.com</a>) operates intercity coach services in Florida. Average travel time between Miami and Orlando is 4 hours 30 minutes; between Orlando and Tampa is 1 hour 40 minutes; between Miami and Key West is 4 hours and 30 minutes. Fares, schedules and travel times between other city pairs are available on the Greyhound website.</p><p>Intercity taxi services are prohibitively expensive and best avoided.</p><p>Visitors may use a foreign or International driving license while in Florida for short trips. Any car driven in the state of Florida must be covered by insurance.</p><p>Driving in the USA is on the right side of the road. Legal speed limits are posted along the right side of the road. Turning right on a red light is permitted after coming to a complete stop, unless otherwise indicated. Headlights must be on from dusk to dawn, and in fog or rain. Seatbelts are mandatory for all car passengers and children under age 4 or weighing less than 15 kg (40 lbs) must be in a car seat. Driving under the influence of alcohol is illegal.</p><p>Drivers may dial *FHP on Florida interstates and highways in an emergency to reach the Florida Highway Patrol (state police). Speciality towing and roadside repair services can be arranged through *FHP (charges apply for these services).</p><p>Driving a car is the best way to get around Florida. Most people tend to hire a car if they want to travel across the state. Major national car rental companies like Alamo, National, Budget, Dollar and Hertz are available in Florida.</p><p>Florida is great for cycling, thanks to its flat topography. Head for the coastal biking paths or the dedicated long-distance trails in the centre of the state.</p><p>Driving in the USA is on the right side of the road. Legal speed limits are posted along the right side of the road. Turning right on a red light is permitted after coming to a complete stop, unless otherwise indicated. Headlights must be on from dusk to dawn, and in fog or rain. Seatbelts are mandatory for all car passengers and children under age 4 or weighing less than 15 kg (40 lbs) must be in a car seat. Driving under the influence of alcohol is illegal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are local bus and trolley operators in most of Florida's major cities. In Miami, express buses like the Airport Flyer connect Miami International Airport with South Beach, while the I-Trolley in Orlando operates as a tourist bus along International Drive.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flights to Florida's major airports (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/miami">Miami</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/orlando">Orlando</a>, Tampa, Fort Lauderdale, West Palm Beach, and Jacksonville) are served by all major U.S. carriers, including Delta Air Lines (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) and United Airlines (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>). Miami and Orlando are also served by European carriers, including British Airways (<a href="http://www.britishairways.com" target="_blank">www.britishairways.com</a>) and Virgin Atlantic Airways (<a href="http://www.virginatlantic.com" target="_blank">www.virginatlantic.com</a>).</p>
<p>As Florida is a year-round vacation destination, airfares can be just as high during summer and &ldquo;Spring Break&rdquo; (mid-to-late-March) as during the Christmas holidays. Tickets are lowest in the off-peak months: February-May (excluding Spring Break and Memorial Day weekend) and September-beginning of December (excluding Thanksgiving weekend).</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida/miami-international-airport">Miami International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/orlando/orlando-international-airport">Orlando International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida/southwest-florida-international-airport">Southwest Florida International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida/palm-beach-international-airport">Palm Beach International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida/sarasota-bradenton-international-airport">Sarasota Bradenton International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida/tampa-international-airport">Tampa International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida/daytona-beach-international-airport">Daytona Beach International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida/jacksonville-international-airport">Jacksonville International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida/fort-lauderdale-hollywood-international-airport">Fort Lauderdale Hollywood International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to Miami is 8 hours 10 minutes, and from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> is 2 hours 40 minutes. From London to Orlando is 9 hours, and from New York is 2 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consider flying into Fort Lauderdale-Hollywood International Airport (FLL), which is only 48km (30 miles) from Miami Beach, as an alternative to more expensive Miami International Airport (MIA).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consider flying into Fort Lauderdale-Hollywood International Airport (FLL), which is only 48km (30 miles) from Miami Beach, as an alternative to more expensive Miami International Airport (MIA).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Fort Lauderdale Hollywood International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.fll.net<p>Fort Lauderdale-Hollywood International Airport is situated 8km (5 miles) south of Fort Lauderdale and 32km (20 miles) north of Miami.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 866 435 9355</p>]]><b>Miami International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.iflymia.com<p>Miami International Airport is located 14km (9 miles) northwest of Miami.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 305 876 7000.</p>]]><b>Orlando International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.orlandoairports.net<p>Orlando International Airport is located 10.5km (6.5 miles) southeast of Orlando, in central Florida.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 407 825 2001</p>]]><b>Southwest Florida International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.flylcpa.com<p>Southwest Florida International Airport is situated 16km (10 miles) southeast of Fort Myers.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 239 590 4800</p>]]><b>Tampa International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://wwww.tampaairport.com<p>Tampa International Airport is situated 8km (5 miles) west of Tampa.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 813 870 8700.</p>]]><b>Daytona Beach International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.flydaytonafirst.com<p>Daytona Beach International Airport is located 3km (2 miles) west of central Daytona Beach.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 386 248 8030</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Miami, Port Everglades (Fort Lauderdale), Port Canaveral, Port of Palm Beach, Saint Petersburg, Tampa, and Jacksonville are the state's major ports of call. Information can be found at <a href="http://www.flaports.org" target="_blank">www.flaports.org</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Amtrak (tel: 1 800 872 7245, in the USA only; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.amtrak.com/">www.amtrak.com</a>) is the rail service provider. Amtrak's Miami Station is 11km (7 miles) northwest of the city centre. It is the southernmost point on the network, marking the southern end of the main east coast line from New York (and ultimately <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/boston">Boston</a>). Amtrak also serves Jacksonville, with services running through Orlando to Tampa (a branch line terminates at Sarasota, a few miles south of Tampa on the Gulf of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mexico">Mexico</a>), and west through Pensacola.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Amtrak (1 800 872 7245 in the USA only; <a href="http://www.amtrak.com" target="_blank">www.amtrak.com</a>) offers multi-day rail passes good for travel throughout the United States. Prices are $429 for the 15-day pass, $649 for the 30-day pass, and $829 for the 45-day pass.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving to Florida is relatively easy for those coming from within the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>, with its extensive interstate network. The state has plenty of highways, with frequent motels and resting places along the route should you need to stop. Traffic will be dense closer to large urban areas and it is recommended that drivers avoid getting to these areas during rush hour traffic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>For emergency police, fire or medical services in major cities, dial 911. The following codes denote toll free (freephone) numbers: 800, 855, 866, 877 and 888.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign mobile telephones only work if they are tri-band or quad-band; charges are high. Visitors can also hire a mobile telephone. Pre-pay cell phones can be purchased from a variety of retail outlets, including drug stores.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafés in most urban areas, and an increasing number of Wi-Fi hotspots. Many coffee shops offer free Wi-Fi. Many of the international airports offer internet access too.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Freedom of expression in the USA is guaranteed by the constitution. The USA has the most highly developed mass media in the world. Public broadcasting is partly government-funded, but also supported by private grants.</p>
<p>Major newspapers in Florida include the <em>Miami Herald</em> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.herald.com">www.herald.com</a>), the <em>Orlando Sentinel </em>(<a target="_blank" href="http://www.orlandosentinel.com">www.orlandosentinel.com</a>), the <em>Tampa Tribune</em> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.tampatribune.com">www.tampatribune.com</a>), the <em>Tampa Bay Times</em> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.tbt.com">www.tbt.com</a>), and the <em>Palm Beach Post</em> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.palmbeachpost.com">www.palmbeachpost.com</a>). <em>The Miami New Times</em> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.miaminewtimes.com">www.miaminewtimes.com</a>) is the city's premier weekly alternative/entertainment newspaper.</p>
<p>Major national news networks include ABC, CBS, and NBC. PBS is a government-funded network featuring educational programming. All networks have a local affiliate in Florida's major cities.</p>
<p>Various music and talk radio formats are represented across the state. The US Newspaper List website (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.usnpl.com/radio/flradio.php">www.usnpl.com/radio/flradio.php</a>) provides a list of Florida radio stations by city and format.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The United States Postal Service (USPS) provides national and international mail services. Post offices can be located via the website (<a href="http://www.usps.com" target="_top">www.usps.com</a>).</p><p>Most post offices are open Mon-Fri, 0830-1700, and Sat 0900-1300. In major cities, there is usually one main post office with extended and/or Sunday hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Everglades National Park</p><![CDATA[<p>Florida's Everglades make up the largest sub-tropical wilderness on the United States mainland, and were designated a national park in 1947. Both temperate and tropical plant communities are represented in the park's 610,684 hectares (1,509,000 acres), including cypress swamps, pinelands and sawgrass prairies. Florida Bay, the largest body of water within the park, covering 2072 sq km (800 sq miles), is home to fish, shellfish, coral and sponges. The park is particularly well known for its abundant birdlife. <br/>Other endangered species protected in the park are the Green turtle, the Key Largo Cotton mouse, the American crocodile and the Schaus swallowtail butterfly. The park's five visitor centres provide information on the flora and fauna in the Everglades, as well as details of various park trails. Hiking and canoeing trails start at Flamingo Visitor Centre, Gulf Coast Visitor Centre and Shark Valley Visitor Centre. Shark Valley Centre also hires out bicycles and visitors can take a narrated tram ride or a boat tour of the park.</p>]]><br/><p>Walt Disney World Resort</p><![CDATA[<p>The world's largest theme park, Walt Disney World Resort, covers a space twice the size of Manhattan, delivering the Disney promise of magical escapism and thrilling rides. It is divided into four theme parks, alongside water parks, restaurants, theatres and hotels.</p>
<p>The best-known of the theme parks is the Magic Kingdom, which provides traditional Disney rides and attractions and allows visitors to meet their favourite Disney characters. Disney's Animal Kingdom is an animal park, where visitors can learn about the animal kingdom, enjoy shows such as the 'Festival of the Lion King', and go on an animated jungle trek or African-style safari.</p>
<p>Disney-MGM Studios is a Hollywood-inspired theme park featuring rides, shows and tours of Hollywood sets, both real sets and reconstructions, including a children's playground adventure based on the film 'Honey, I Shrunk the Kids'. Epcot is a science-based park which explores the earth's natural phenomena and the human anatomy, as well as taking visitors on virtual trips around countries such as China and France (in World Showcase) and offering a glimpse into the technology of the future (in Future World).</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Everglades National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Florida's Everglades make up the largest sub-tropical wilderness on the United States mainland, and were designated a national park in 1947. Both temperate and tropical plant communities are represented in the park's 610,684 hectares (1,509,000 acres), including cypress swamps, pinelands and sawgrass prairies. Florida Bay, the largest body of water within the park, covering 2072 sq km (800 sq miles), is home to fish, shellfish, coral and sponges. The park is particularly well known for its abundant birdlife. Other endangered species protected in the park are the Green turtle, the Key Largo Cotton mouse, the American crocodile and the Schaus swallowtail butterfly. The park's five visitor centres provide information on the flora and fauna in the Everglades, as well as details of various park trails. Hiking and canoeing trails start at Flamingo Visitor Center, Gulf Coast Visitor Center and Shark Valley Visitor Center. Shark Valley Center also hires out bicycles and visitors can take a narrated tram ride or a boat tour of the park.</p>]]><p><b>Everglades National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Venture into the tangled wildness and sweeping sawgrass prairies of Florida's subtropical Everglades National Park (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/ever">www.nps.gov/ever</a>) by airboat tours, nature trails and safari vans. The Everglades is the USA's third-largest national park and home to wild alligators.</p>]]><p><b>Go fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cast out your line at the 'World's Luckiest Fishing Village', Destin's East Pass, for the best selection of deep-sea fishing excursions on the northern Gulf Coast. Join sportfishermen and anglers in The Keys (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.fla-keys.com">www.fla-keys.com</a>) for some of the best fishing off America's coast. Compete with world records for catches of sailfish, marlin, kingfish, snapper, barracuda and grouper.</p>]]><p><b>Head south</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Drive south of Miami to the Florida Keys, a long chain of coral reef islands linked by highway US-1 from Key Largo (<a href="http://www.fla-keys.com/keylargo" target="_blank">www.fla-keys.com/keylargo</a>) to Key West (<a href="http://www.floridakeys.com" target="_blank">www.floridakeys.com</a>). The keys offer diving, fishing, swimming with dolphins, eco-tours and birdwatching.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the heritage trail</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour St Augustine (<a href="http://www.floridashistoriccoast.com" target="_blank">www.floridashistoriccoast.com</a>), the USA's oldest city, originally settled by the Spanish. The town is a time capsule capturing nearly 500 years of fascinating history.</p>]]><p><b>Island living</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Marco Island (<a href="http://www.marco-island-florida.com/" target="_blank">www.marco-island-florida.com</a>), an area of stunning beauty and a retreat for the wealthy on the Gulf Coast. The exclusive island is nearly nestled among the Ten Thousand Islands, a maze of mangrove isles that stretch from Naples to the Florida Keys.</p>]]><p><b>Jewish history</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Walk through the Florida Holocaust Museum (<a href="http://www.flholocaustmuseum.org" target="_blank">www.flholocaustmuseum.org</a>) in St Petersburg, one of the largest museums in the country and dedicated to the memory of millions of innocent Jews who died or suffered in the Holocaust.</p>]]><p><b>Life's a beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Swim at New Smyrna Beach (<a href="http://www.nsbfla.com/" target="_blank">www.nsbfla.com</a>), billed as the 'World's Safest Bathing Beach' and 'Best Beach in Florida'. Enjoy backwater fishing, fresh seafood, historical sites and museums, and long seasons of sunshine.Get away to Fort Myers Beach, ideal for family holidays with its safe, gently sloping shoreline and numerous activities.</p>]]><p><b>Master strokes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit St Petersburg, home to world-class museums, including the Salvador Dali Museum (<a href="http://www.salvadordalimuseum.org/" target="_blank">www.salvadordalimuseum.org</a>), which contains the world's most comprehensive collection by this famous Spanish surrealist. See the Ringling Museum Complex (<a href="http://www.ringling.org" target="_blank">www.ringling.org</a>), the official State Museum of Florida. It is a major attraction with superb old masterpieces and a fine contemporary art collection.</p>]]><p><b>National parks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a glass-bottomed boat ride through mangroves and islands and out to tropical coral reefs rising 8m (25ft) in Biscayne National Park (<a href="http://www.nps.gov/bisc" target="_blank">www.nps.gov/bisc</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Outta this world</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Coincide a visit to Cape Canaveral with one of NASA's space shuttle launches from the Kennedy Space Center. See launchpads, astronaut training centres, museums and exhibits (<a href="http://www.kennedyspacecenter.com/" target="_blank">www.kennedyspacecenter.com</a>). IMAX presentations give visitors the illusion of space travel.</p>]]><p><b>Play golf</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tee off at one of southwest Florida's beautiful golf courses, where there are more golf holes per capita than any other destination in the USA.</p>]]><p><b>Potter around</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Experience The Wizarding World of Harry Potter or the terrifying attack of a great white shark on the Jaws Ride at Universal Studios, Orlando, (<a href="http://www.universalorlando.com/" target="_blank">www.universalorlando.com</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Presidential paraphernalia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the Florida International Museum (website: <a href="http://www.floridamuseum.org/" target="_blank">www.floridamuseum.org</a>), home to the largest private collection of John F Kennedy memorabilia, including a recreation of JFK's Oval Office.</p>]]><p><b>Seaside visit</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relax in Naples (<a href="http://www.naples-florida.com/" target="_blank">www.naples-florida.com</a>), a charming city of understated elegance, cosy beach cottages and 5-star resorts. Naples is also known for its pristine shoreline and abundant wildlife.</p>]]><p><b>Speed demons</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Thrill to the sounds of thunder at Daytona International Speedway (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.daytonainternationalspeedway.com">www.daytonainternationalspeedway.com</a>) which hosts the famous Daytona 500 race and the Winston Cup series each year.</p>]]><p><b>Swim with the dolphins</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For an unforgettable experience, head for Key Largo or sign on for Dolphin Camp (<a href="http://www.dolphinsplus.com/" target="_blank">www.dolphinsplus.com</a>) and learn about these amazing mammals from a resident marine biologist and trainers.</p>]]><p><b>Take a spin</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Drive down Ocean Drive and Lincoln Road in Miami's South Beach past over 800 candy-coloured art deco buildings in the Art Deco Historic District (<a href="http://www.visitsouthbeachonline.com/" target="_blank">www.visitsouthbeachonline.com</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Take the plunge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Dive in and experience the different watersports offered at Miami Beach (<a href="http://www.miamiandbeaches.com/" target="_blank">www.miamiandbeaches.com</a>), including kayaking, windsurfing, boogie-boarding and scuba-diving.</p>]]><p><b>Walt Disney World Resort</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take the family to Walt Disney World Resort (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.disney.go.com/">www.disney.go.com</a>), the biggest amusement park in the world. Visit Magic Kingdom; explore science at the Epcot Center; take a safari adventure through Animal Kingdom; see the world of movies at Disney MGM Studios.</p>]]><p><b>Waterways</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cruise Fort Lauderdale's canals and the Intracoastal Waterway by local water taxi past luxurious homes of the rich and famous. Discover the city's Riverwalk (<a href="http://www.goriverwalk.com/" target="_blank">www.goriverwalk.com</a>), a linear park linking hotels, restaurants and attractions along the banks of the New River.</p>]]><p><b>Wild encounters</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Venture to Busch Gardens (<a href="http://www.buschgardens.com/" target="_blank">www.buschgardens.com</a>), a huge amusement park in Tampa Bay featuring African wildlife. Giraffes, zebras and antelope roam freely through the park's 24-hectare (60-acre) plain, next to thrilling rides such as the Kumba.</p>]]><p><b>Wings Over Miami</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Catch an air show at Wings Over Miami (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.wingsovermiami.com/">www.wingsovermiami.com</a>), a museum with an extensive collection of military and classic aircraft on display.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>$748 billion (2010).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Manufactured goods, citrus fruit and juice, sugar cane, phosphate</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Oil, manufactured goods, metals, coffee.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Florida's economy is centred on tourism, light manufacturing, construction, international banking, health research, military defence and aerospace.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Florida's close proximity to Latin America makes it a fascinating place to do business. A large number of companies from the Caribbean, Central and South America have set up offices in the region. As a result, the workforce has grown younger, more multilingual and more culturally diverse. However, for business purposes, it is still essentially America. Therefore, dress code is smart and business is managed the American way; quickly, efficiently and frankly. Business cards should always be presented and appointments and punctuality are expected. Outside the boardroom, Americans are often informal and will use first names. Dates in America are written month-day-year.<br /><br />
Office hours are generally 0830-1730, although these can vary slightly from one organisation to the next. When public holidays occur on a weekday or weekend, they are usually celebrated on the nearest Friday or Monday, thereby creating a three-day weekend. Meetings often take place in social situations and, in keeping with the fast-paced business life of Americans, breakfast meetings are common. Lunch meetings are also popular, sometimes with alcohol. Meetings may also take place over the weekend.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Reflecting the indigenous, Spanish and African influences of the original populations that settled the state, Florida&rsquo;s cuisine is a mix of traditional Southern dishes with Caribbean and Latin flavours added for extra spice.</p>
<p>Southern &ldquo;pit&rdquo; barbecue (beef, pork or chicken smoked in brick barbecue pits or large metal drums with tangy sauce added before and after cooking), garlic-seasoned prawns and crab, black-eyed peas, baked or candied sweet potatoes, cornbread, fried frog&rsquo;s legs, fried alligator tail and fried conch (better known as &ldquo;conch fritters&rdquo;) are some of the old-style classics that Floridians native to the state have been eating for much of the Florida&rsquo;s recent history.</p>
<p>Transplants from other states and immigrants from the British West Indies, Haiti and Spanish-speaking Latin America have added yucca, plantains, mangoes, rice and beans, spices like curry and jerk, and other tropical delicacies to the state&rsquo;s palate. Many of the more authentic flavours can only be found at local barbecue joints, &ldquo;soul food&rdquo; restaurants and seafood shacks in out-of-the-way corners of the state; it&rsquo;s best to ask a long-time resident where the best place is to get whatever you&rsquo;re looking for.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the gastronomic scene in Miami is becoming world-class, with international and local chefs lending their names and expertise to the city&rsquo;s increasingly sophisticated culinary offerings. Gourmet and fusion Cuban, Mexican, Haitian, Jamaican and Brazilian restaurants abound, as do upscale pizzerias, vegetarian diners and seafood salons with price tags to match, the latter almost always offering fresh stone crabs - a delicacy available nowhere else in the USA.</p>
<p>Of course, Florida is overrun with national chain eateries, from fast-food franchises on every corner to ethnic-themed mega-restaurants to all-you-can-eat buffets. But if you can stomach the grease, some of these less-salubrious options can be quite tasty. Chicken Kitchen in Miami is home to a mean chicken-veggie-rice combo called the &ldquo;chop-chop.&rdquo; Wendy&rsquo;s crushes the two other big burger chains hands-down, not least of which because there is always a filling sandwich on offer for 99 cents (Five Guys are actually better, but they aren&rsquo;t nearly as ubiquitous). And warm, luscious Krispy Kreme doughnuts fresh from the oven are about as close to heaven on earth as one can get.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; Seafood. <br />&bull; Key Lime pie (lime, egg and condensed milk dessert topped by meringue).<br />&bull; Cuban sandwich (Cuban bread filled with cheese, ham, pickles and mustard).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>In many parts of the state, alcohol is not sold on Sundays.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>In the USA, tipping is customary for good service. Servers in restaurants, bars and nightclubs usually receive 15% of the total bill (before tax) for good service, or 20% for excellent service.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>21.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Miami&rsquo;s always-raucous nightlife scene starts early and ends late. Downtown Miami is home to warehouse-sized mega clubs where the party continues until almost noon. The Coconut Grove area, with its trendy nightclubs and cocktail bars, offers a swinging nightlife both inside the clubs and on the streets where many people just come for a stroll, in order to be where the action is. Glamorous South Beach pulses with salsa and electro from trendy dance clubs along Washington Avenue and swanky hotel bars on Ocean Drive, with the hip crowd spilling onto the streets and cruising the boulevards. South Beach is also home to several of the city&rsquo;s legendary gay and lesbian clubs.</p>
<p>Unique to Orlando, both Walt Disney World and Universal Orlando have built high-energy, night-time entertainment complexes to pull in the adults while the kiddies are asleep. Disney&rsquo;s Pleasure Island (<a href="http://disneyworld.disney.go.com" target="_blank">disneyworld.disney.go.com</a>) and Universal CityWalk (<a href="http://www.universalorlando.com" target="_blank">www.universalorlando.com</a>) both feature themed nightclubs, stage shows and live concerts. Downtown Orlando&rsquo;s Church Street Station has long been the go-to night spot for locals in the know. On the Gulf Coast, the best nightlife can be found in Ybor City (<a href="http://www.yborcityonline.com" target="_blank">www.yborcityonline.com</a>), Tampa's lively and historic Latin quarter. The action centres on Seventh Avenue, which closes to traffic at weekends to allow the party atmosphere to spill out on to the streets.</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> Florida&rsquo;s nightlife scene is largely limited to these three cities. Tallahassee offers collegiate night spots whilst Daytona Beach and Panama City are Spring Break meccas. Bars aside, quality nightlife options in the rest of the state are few and far between.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As many a Latin American or European tourist knows, Florida is a shopper&rsquo;s paradise. In Miami, for funky, urban kitsch, hit downtown Miami's main shopping areas Flagler Street, between Biscayne Bay and Miami Avenue, or Biscayne Boulevard, between Flagler Street and north to 16th Street. The Bayside Marketplace (www.baysidemarketplace.com), along Miami's downtown waterfront, offers live entertainment as well as a mix of retail shops and art and craft stalls. Upscale furnishings and art can be found in the Design District (<a href="http://www.miamidesigndistrict.net" target="_blank">www.miamidesigndistrict.net</a>), just north of the centre. Luxury and designer shops can be found at Village of Merrick Park (www.villageofmerrickpark.com)   or in downtown Coral Gables, south of Miami. Dolphin Mall (www.shopdolphinmall.com), on the city's western extremity, is a large outlet mall popular for its close proximity to the airport.</p>
<p>Other South Florida shopping options include pedestrian-friendly Lincoln Road Mall (<a href="http://www.lincolnroadmall.com" target="_blank">www.lincolnroadmall.com</a>) on Miami Beach, with stylish clothiers and an Apple store. Just north of Miami Beach, &uuml;ber-luxe shopping centre Bal Harbour Shops (<a href="http://www.balharbourshops.com" target="_top">www.balharbourshops.com</a>) houses one of the area&rsquo;s two Tiffany &amp; Co. locations. World-famous Sawgrass Mills Factory Outlet Mall (<a href="http://www.sawgrassmills.com" target="_blank">www.sawgrassmills.com</a>) is located in the Fort Lauderdale suburb of Sunrise and many boutiques can be found near the waterfront on Las Olas Boulevard (<a href="http://www.lasolasboulevard.com" target="_blank">www.lasolasboulevard.com</a>). Upscale shoppers in Palm Beach head to Worth Avenue (<a href="http://www.worth-avenue.com" target="_blank">www.worth-avenue.com</a>), the Rodeo Drive of the east coast.</p>
<p>Shoppers in Orlando can take advantage of a vast range of retail outlets from factory outlet malls such as Lake Buena Vista Factory Stores (<a href="http://www.lbvfs.com" target="_blank">www.lbvfs.com</a>) to designer malls such as Orlando Premium Outlets (<a href="http://www.premiumoutlets.com" target="_blank">www.premiumoutlets.com</a>) and the Mall at Millenia (<a href="http://www.mallatmillenia.com" target="_top">www.mallatmillenia.com</a>). Meanwhile, Tampa&rsquo;s Hyde Park Village (<a href="http://www.hydeparkvillage.net" target="_blank">www.hydeparkvillage.net</a>) offers a unique combination of upscale and local boutiques set amidst restored 19th century mansions and bungalows.</p><p>Main shopping hours are Mon-Sat 1000-2100 and Sun 1200-1800; check individual stores for specific hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a wealth of hotels to suit all pockets throughout Florida; the state boasts over 370,000 hotel rooms. The theme park hotels are family-friendly, whilst there are many beautiful resort properties to stay along Florida's 1,760km (1,100 miles) stretch of beaches, not forgetting spa and golf resorts.</p>
<p>Cheap hotels in Florida are available outside peak periods, which are Easter, half-term and summer school holidays. Cheap hotel rates are offered in the winter too. Budget hotel chains noted for cleanliness, consistency and value include Microtel Inns (<a href="http://www.microtel.com" target="_blank">www.microtel.com</a>) and Motel 6 (<a href="http://www.motel6.com" target="_blank">www.motel6.com</a>). Mid-range chains that score high marks in surveys include Holiday Inn Express (www.hiexpress.com), Hampton Inns (<a href="http://www.hamptoninn.com" target="_blank">www.hamptoninn.com</a>) and LaQuinta Inns (<a href="http://www.lq.com" target="_blank">www.lq.com</a>). Almost all international upscale and luxury chains can be found in Florida, in addition to unique destination hotels such as the legendary Fontainebleau (<a href="http://www.biltmorehotel.com" target="_blank">www.biltmorehotel.com</a>) in Miami Beach (<a href="http://www.fontainebleau.com" target="_blank">www.fontainebleau.com</a>), Biltmore in Coral Gables&nbsp; and The Breakers (<a href="http://www.thebreakers.com" target="_blank">www.thebreakers.com</a>) on Palm Beach.</p>
<p>In the Miami area, the main hotel districts are Downtown and Brickell (the city&rsquo;s financial district), Miami Beach (notably the Art Deco boutique hotels along Ocean Drive), Coral Gables and near the Miami airport. Fort Lauderdale&rsquo;s hotels are clustered downtown, along the beach, and near the Fort Lauderdale airport. Most of West Palm Beach&rsquo;s hotels are also in the general vicinity of downtown, the airport, and the beach.</p>
<p>Orlando has a much more widespread offering of hotels, especially south of the city along International Drive, near Disney World in Lake Buena Vista, and along US highway 192 in Kissimmee. Most other large cities in Florida have clusters of hotels near their airports, in the central business districts and along interstate highways. Coastal cities invariably have hotels along the beaches.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are plenty of small guesthouses throughout the state, in addition to self-catering villas, found mostly in historic locales such as Key West, Saint Augustine and Apalachicola. See Florida Bed &amp; Breakfast Inns (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.florida-inns.com">www.florida-inns.com</a>) for more information.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a wealth of hotels to suit all pockets throughout Florida; the state boasts over 370,000 hotel rooms. The theme park hotels are family-friendly, whilst there are many beautiful resort properties to stay along Florida's 1,760km (1,100 miles) stretch of beaches, not forgetting spa and golf resorts.</p>
<p>Cheap hotels in Florida are available outside peak periods, which are Easter, half-term and summer school holidays. Cheap hotel rates are offered in the winter too. Budget hotel chains noted for cleanliness, consistency and value include Microtel Inns (<a href="http://www.microtel.com" target="_blank">www.microtel.com</a>) and Motel 6 (<a href="http://www.motel6.com" target="_blank">www.motel6.com</a>). Mid-range chains that score high marks in surveys include Holiday Inn Express (www.hiexpress.com), Hampton Inns (<a href="http://www.hamptoninn.com" target="_blank">www.hamptoninn.com</a>) and LaQuinta Inns (<a href="http://www.lq.com" target="_blank">www.lq.com</a>). Almost all international upscale and luxury chains can be found in Florida, in addition to unique destination hotels such as the legendary Fontainebleau (<a href="http://www.biltmorehotel.com" target="_blank">www.biltmorehotel.com</a>) in Miami Beach (<a href="http://www.fontainebleau.com" target="_blank">www.fontainebleau.com</a>), Biltmore in Coral Gables&nbsp; and The Breakers (<a href="http://www.thebreakers.com" target="_blank">www.thebreakers.com</a>) on Palm Beach.</p>
<p>In the Miami area, the main hotel districts are Downtown and Brickell (the city&rsquo;s financial district), Miami Beach (notably the Art Deco boutique hotels along Ocean Drive), Coral Gables and near the Miami airport. Fort Lauderdale&rsquo;s hotels are clustered downtown, along the beach, and near the Fort Lauderdale airport. Most of West Palm Beach&rsquo;s hotels are also in the general vicinity of downtown, the airport, and the beach.</p>
<p>Orlando has a much more widespread offering of hotels, especially south of the city along International Drive, near Disney World in Lake Buena Vista, and along US highway 192 in Kissimmee. Most other large cities in Florida have clusters of hotels near their airports, in the central business districts and along interstate highways. Coastal cities invariably have hotels along the beaches.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a wealth of hotels to suit all pockets throughout Florida; the state boasts over 370,000 hotel rooms. The theme park hotels are family-friendly, whilst there are many beautiful resort properties to stay along Florida's 1,760km (1,100 miles) stretch of beaches, not forgetting spa and golf resorts.</p>
<p>Cheap hotels in Florida are available outside peak periods, which are Easter, half-term and summer school holidays. Cheap hotel rates are offered in the winter too. Budget hotel chains noted for cleanliness, consistency and value include Microtel Inns (<a href="http://www.microtel.com" target="_blank">www.microtel.com</a>) and Motel 6 (<a href="http://www.motel6.com" target="_blank">www.motel6.com</a>). Mid-range chains that score high marks in surveys include Holiday Inn Express (www.hiexpress.com), Hampton Inns (<a href="http://www.hamptoninn.com" target="_blank">www.hamptoninn.com</a>) and LaQuinta Inns (<a href="http://www.lq.com" target="_blank">www.lq.com</a>). Almost all international upscale and luxury chains can be found in Florida, in addition to unique destination hotels such as the legendary Fontainebleau (<a href="http://www.biltmorehotel.com" target="_blank">www.biltmorehotel.com</a>) in Miami Beach (<a href="http://www.fontainebleau.com" target="_blank">www.fontainebleau.com</a>), Biltmore in Coral Gables&nbsp; and The Breakers (<a href="http://www.thebreakers.com" target="_blank">www.thebreakers.com</a>) on Palm Beach.</p>
<p>In the Miami area, the main hotel districts are Downtown and Brickell (the city&rsquo;s financial district), Miami Beach (notably the Art Deco boutique hotels along Ocean Drive), Coral Gables and near the Miami airport. Fort Lauderdale&rsquo;s hotels are clustered downtown, along the beach, and near the Fort Lauderdale airport. Most of West Palm Beach&rsquo;s hotels are also in the general vicinity of downtown, the airport, and the beach.</p>
<p>Orlando has a much more widespread offering of hotels, especially south of the city along International Drive, near Disney World in Lake Buena Vista, and along US highway 192 in Kissimmee. Most other large cities in Florida have clusters of hotels near their airports, in the central business districts and along interstate highways. Coastal cities invariably have hotels along the beaches.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical insurance is strongly advised. Only emergency cases are treated without prior payment and treatment may be refused without evidence of insurance or a deposit. All receipts must be kept in order to make a claim. Medical facilities are generally of a high standard. Many medications available over the counter in other countries require a prescription in the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those visiting the USA for long periods with school-age children should be aware that school entry requirements include proof of immunisation against diphtheria, measles, poliomyelitis and rubella throughout the USA; schools in many states also require immunisation against tetanus, pertussis (whooping cough) and mumps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case of medical emergencies dial 911 from any telephone for ambulance, fire brigade and police emergencies only. The call is free. For less urgent matters, use the local telephone numbers of each agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to its higher-than-average geriatric population (17.3% of the population, which ranks first amongst all 50 states), Florida has a highly developed health care system. Nine of the 50 highest-ranked hospitals in the USA are located in the state, according to health industry analysts HealthGrades, and one of only three branches of the world-famous tertiary care facility, the Mayo Clinic, is in Florida (Jacksonville). Health care education is also an important element of Florida&amp;rsquo;s health care offerings, as both the University of Florida and the University of Miami operate large primary care hospitals in the state.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Food and drink are generally considered safe throughout Florida. General concern is to be taken for high levels of saturated fats and sodium in fast food, which is prevalent and cheap in the USA.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Protect yourself against ultraviolet sun rays by wearing sunglasses and by applying sunscreen at least 30 minutes before exposure. Use a sunscreen with at least SPF 15; SPF 45 for children. Reapply several times during the day, especially after swimming or exercise. Remember to drink sufficient amounts of water to avoid dehydration during prolonged exposure to heat and sun. Avoid direct contact with wild animals; never feed wild animals, particularly alligators. Use insect repellent in wooded areas and parks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be aware of the safety flag system at public beaches: blue or green represents calm waters and safe swimming; yellow means mild hazards, including light surf or currents; red indicates highly hazardous conditions; a double-red flag means the waters are closed to the public; purple means marine pests present, which might include jellyfish, stingrays or dangerous fish. In the absence of a flag, check conditions with a lifeguard. Entering the water in the absence of a lifeguard is not recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always lock car doors and lock purses, wallets, luggage or other valuables in the boot of your car if you won&amp;rsquo;t be carrying them with you. Do not leave car keys inside the car. Keep jewellery, cash, cameras, airline tickets, passports and other valuables in a hotel safe and always lock your room door.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar (USD; symbol $) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of $100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of $1, and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major credit cards are accepted throughout the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>, including American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa. Visitors are advised to carry at least one major credit card, as it is common to request prepayment or a credit card imprint for hotel rooms and car hire, even when final payment is not by credit card.</p><p>ATMs are widely available across the state.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Widely accepted in US Dollar cheques; Pound Sterling traveller's cheques are rarely accepted and few banks will honour them. Change is issued in US Dollars. One or two items of identification (passport, credit card, driving licence) will be required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Variable, but generally Mon-Fri 0830-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[27.955591]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-81.650391]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>155,164 sq km (59,909 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>20.3 million (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>130.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tallahassee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Much of Florida occupies a relatively flat peninsula extending 725km (447 miles) between the Atlantic Ocean, the Gulf of Mexico and the Florida Straits, with the remainder extending west along the northern coast of the Gulf. The states of Georgia and Alabama border Florida to the north, with a portion of Alabama bordering the state at the western tip of the Panhandle. The islands of the Bahamas (Bimini being the closest) lie a mere 81km (53 miles) due west of the state and the island of Cuba is 145km (90 miles) south of Key West.</p>
<p>The state boasts 13,560km (8,426 miles) of coastline, 1,066km (663 miles) of which are beaches, and more than 17,700km (11,000 miles) of rivers, streams and waterways. The Saint Johns River is the state&rsquo;s longest river, running northward for 500km (310 miles) from the Saint Johns Marsh in Indian River County to its outlet with the Atlantic Ocean at Jacksonville. Florida&rsquo;s largest lake is Lake Okeechobee at 1,175 sq km (739 sq miles), making it the second largest freshwater lake within the contiguous (ie 'lower 48') United States.  With a total area of 155,164 sq km, Florida ranks 23nd among the 50 states in size. Most of the state south of Orlando is low-lying and flat, while inland areas of North and Central Florida contain rolling hills. Florida&rsquo;s highest point is Britton Hill, near the Alabama border in Walton County, at 106m (345ft) above mean sea level, the lowest highpoint of any US state.</p>
<p>Florida, like most other states, is divided into smaller administrative units called counties. These counties number 67 in total. According to 2010 census figures, Miami-Dade County is the most populous (2,496,435 residents) and Liberty County the least populous (8,365 residents). The largest county in area is Palm Beach County whilst the smallest is Union County. The largest cities in Florida by population, according to the 2010 census, are Jacksonville, Miami and Tampa. The largest metropolitan areas in Florida (city proper and suburbs combined) by population are Miami-Fort Lauderdale-West Palm Beach, Tampa-Saint Petersburg and Orlando.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Like most of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>, the largest religious group in Florida is Protestant, comprised of Baptists, Methodists, Pentecostal, and other denominations. Roman Catholics, Jews, Muslims, other religions and the non-religious make up the remainder of the population.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Floridians are typically American in issuing a genuine 'Have a nice day' to visitors. Some of the old rules of chivalry – men holding doors open for women, the use of 'ma'am' to address a lady – hold fast in northern Florida; in southern and Central Florida, this is less the case.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Florida had been settled some 14,000 years ago, long before the earliest known European contact with the Spanish on 2 April 1513, when Juan Ponce de León caught sight of the peninsula and named it La Florida (florid land). The Spanish and French settled the region over the following two centuries with Spain retaining control until 1763 when the colony went to Great Britain. Spain re-took it in 1783.</p><p>After land grants had attracted many Americans to the territory president Andrew Jackson launched a campaign against the Seminole tribe in 1817, encouraging the Spanish to cede the territory to the United States in exchange for $5 million. In 1830 the Indian Removal Act pressured the federal government to remove Native Americans, a process aggravated by the runaway black slave communities that also resisted white settlement.</p><p>Florida became the 27th state of the union in 1845 and by 1858, most of the Indians in Florida had been forcibly removed and plantation slavery flourished to the extent that by 1860, 44 per cent of the population were enslaved. Florida seceded from the United States at the start of the civil war in 1861 and remained under military control from the end of the war in 1865 until 1868. Agriculture (citrus, sugar, cotton and cattle) and tourism were mainstays of the state's economy although many of its emancipated African-American population left.</p><p>In the 1920s, a couple of hurricanes and the Great Depression devastated the state, but the end of World War 2 marked the start of the state's recovery as the development of air conditioning and the low cost of living attracted a steady migration of people from other parts of the country. Following the Cuban Revolution of 1959, Florida became a haven for Latin American immigrants with Haitians, Jamaicans, Colombians and Venezuelans following in successive decades.</p><p>Orlando started its ascent as a centre of family tourism with the opening of the Magic Kingdom in 1971. The Mariel Boatlift in 1980, in which Fidel Castro allowed scores of immigrants to cross the Florida Straits, tilted the demographics of the region permanently.</p><p>Hurricane Andrew in 1992 was Florida's most expensive natural disaster, while the 2010 Gulf of Mexico oil spill became the state's biggest man-made disaster.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>• Florida's literary links include Tennessee Williams, Ernest Hemingway and Elmore Leonard.</p><p>• The state's felony disenfranchisement law meant that in 2014 more than one in ten Floridians – and one in four African-American Floridians – were excluded from voting.</p><p>• Florida-born musicians include Jim Morrison, Cannonball Adderley, Gram Parsons, Slim Whitman, the Bellamy Brothers, Lynrynd Skynryd, the Allman brothers, KC & the Sunshine Band, 2 Live Crew and, of course, Miami Sound Machine.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sizzling beaches or a theme park bonanza might tempt you to Florida, but there&rsquo;s more to the Sunshine State than golden sands and Disney shows.</p>
<p>That said, Miami is a fabulous place to kick off your sojourn. The city&rsquo;s sprawling South Beach delivers what the postcards promise: brightly coloured lifeguard huts, promenades of art deco architecture and a steady stream of tanned bods. It&rsquo;s a place to pedal a powder-blue cruiser, sip overpriced mojitos or shimmy in sultry clubs.</p>
<p>Miami&rsquo;s not all about the beach, though. Head to a Cuban block party on Calle Ocho, take a dip in the Venetian pool at Coral Gables, or peruses the wares in the Design District.</p>
<p>South of Miami, the Florida Keys archipelago is a Caribbean-flavoured getaway with beautiful beaches and clear blue waters. For something wilder head to the sprawling wetlands of the Everglades National Park, which are home to alligators, manatees and the endangered Florida panther.</p>
<p>Orlando is theme park central. You can whizz through Disney&rsquo;s Space Mountain, or see a real rocket at the Kennedy Space Center. Nearby Daytona Beach offers sandy resorts, seaside amusements and a packed calendar of motor racing events.</p>
<p>Along the Gulf Coast in western Florida, the cities of Sarasota, Fort Myers and Naples serve up culture and tranquillity alongside stellar sunsets, while Tampa and St Petersburg boast sweeping beaches and picturesque historical sites.</p>
<p>And tucked in among the rolling hills of North Florida, the state capital, Tallahassee, is a popular university town strictly Southern in tone, and gateway to the stunning beaches of Panhandle.</p><p>Sizzling beaches or a theme park bonanza might tempt you to Florida, but there&rsquo;s more to the Sunshine State than golden sands and Disney shows.&nbsp;That said, Miami is a fabulous place to kick off your sojourn. The city&rsquo;s sprawling South Beach delivers what the postcards promise: brightly coloured lifeguard huts, promenades of art deco architecture and a steady stream of tanned bods. It&rsquo;s a place to sip overpriced mojitos and shimmy in sultry clubs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
