<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Arizona" ColCode="ari" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="az" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Arizona]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mostly warm and comfortable all year round. Mountainous areas, such as Flagstaff at 2,134m (7,000ft), are colder, particularly in winter, and in summer, there are cool mountain breezes. Desert temperatures range from hot during the day to cold at night.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cotton clothing for all seasons, with a wrap for cool nights. Warmer clothing is needed in the mountains, especially in the ski areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[Phoenix Sky Harbor International Airport serves as the sixth-largest hub for American Airlines with 299 daily departures to nearly 90 destinations in 4 countries. Major national carriers, including Delta, Alaska Airlines, American Eagle, Southwest and United, also operate out of Arizona. Flights to Arizona from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> are offered by airlines including British Airways and US Airways.
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/arizona/phoenix-sky-harbor-international-airport">Phoenix Sky Harbor International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/arizona/tucson-international-airport">Tucson International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/phoenix">Phoenix</a> from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/los-angeles">Los Angeles</a> is 1 hour 25 minutes, from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/miami">Miami</a> is 4 hours 10 minutes and from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> is 4 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Phoenix Sky Harbor International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.skyharbor.com<p>Phoenix Sky Harbor International Airport is located in the centre of Phoenix.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(602) 273 3300.</p>]]><b>Tucson International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.flytucson.com<p>Tucson International Airport is situated 16km (10 miles) south of downtown Tucson.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 520 573 8100</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Amtrak (tel: +1 800 872 7245; <a href="http://www.amtrak.com/" target="_blank">www.amtrak.com</a>) trains run from downtown Tucson, on the 'Sunset Limited' and 'Texas Eagle' line between Los Angeles and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-orleans">New Orleans</a>. There is no rail link between Tucson and Phoenix, although an Amtrak Thruway bus service connects the cities. There is a service from Flagstaff on the 'Southwest Chief' line between Los Angeles and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/chicago">Chicago</a>. First-class sleeping cars can be reserved for an additional fee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>USA</strong><strong> Rail Pass:</strong> Available for 15 or 30 days unlimited travel within three different regions or across the entire USA for international visitors only.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Grand Canyon</p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the awe-inspiring Grand Canyon (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.grandcanyonchamber.org/">www.grandcanyonchamber.org</a>), one of the Seven Natural Wonders of the World. This massive rend in the earth cut thousands of years ago by the Colorado River can be experienced by helicopter or airplane, or the more adventurous can hike or ride a mule down to the canyon floor, then raft the Colorado.</p>]]><br/><p>Grayhawk Golf Club</p><![CDATA[<p>A golf club may not be a typical sightseeing location for holidaymakers, but when that golf club is home to more PGA events and world tours than you could shake a five iron at, and regularly features in the USA&rsquo;s top ten golfing locations, then visitors to Phoenix might just think again. The Grayhawk Golf Club is a favourite location of world class golfers who are spoilt for choice between the Talon and Raptor courses, and aside from the stunning views of the McDowall Mountains, visitors are treated to the culinary delights of the Quill Creek Cafe and the relaxing ambience of Phil&rsquo;s Grill.</p>]]><br/><p>Phoenix Zoo</p><![CDATA[<p>Over 1300 animals call the Phoenix Zoo home, including 200 species that are considered to be endangered. Visitors can learn about the zoo&rsquo;s participation in survival plans for 37 species which are facing extinction, as well as enjoy the less serious events hosted throughout the year. Daily activities include camel rides, trips on a safari train, and the recent edition of a Koala exhibit gives visitors the chance to get up close and personal with these cuddly creatures. A range of restaurants serve everything from pizzas to Mexican food, and coffee shop is the perfect watering hole for humans.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Apache Trail</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Travel the Apache Trail (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.americansouthwest.net/arizona/apache_trail">www.americansouthwest.net/arizona/apache_trail</a>), an extraordinary scenic drive. Attractions include Goldfield Ghost Town and Mine Tours (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.goldfieldghosttown.com/">www.goldfieldghosttown.com</a>), Superstition Mountain Museum, Lost Dutchman State Park and Tortilla Flat (an old stagecoach stop offering 'killer' chilli and prickly-pear cactus ice cream).</p>]]><p><b>Biosphere 2</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Be dazzled by the gargantuan bubble that is Biosphere 2 (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.biosphere2.org">www.biosphere2.org</a>) - a Plexiglas bubble laboratory containing five separate and self-contained ecosystems. Originally designed to help scientists colonise Mars, it is now leased by the University of Arizona to study climate and ecology. Guided tours are available.</p>]]><p><b>Get active</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy outdoor pursuits that include golf, hiking, rock climbing, tennis and mountain biking in the Lake Havasu area, or take desert jeep tours in the nearby Sonoran and Mojave Deserts or up into the Chemehuevi Mountains.</p>]]><p><b>Grand Canyon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the awe-inspiring Grand Canyon (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/grca">www.nps.gov/grca</a>), one of the Seven Natural Wonders of the World. This massive rend in the earth cut thousands of years ago by the Colorado River can be experienced by helicopter or airplane, or the more adventurous can hike or ride a mule down to the canyon floor, then raft the Colorado.</p>]]><p><b>Heard Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the Heard Museum (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.heard.org/">www.heard.org</a>) in Phoenix. Founded in 1929, the museum is devoted to the art, anthropology, history and Native American culture of Arizona.</p>]]><p><b>Hopi Reservation</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the smaller Hopi Reservation, accommodating 7,000 Hopis. They have lived in the region for 1,500 years and are known for being talented farmers. The Hopis live in snug pueblo-style villages on top of three mesas. This area is treasured for its outstanding natural beauty.</p>]]><p><b>Lake Powell</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hire a houseboat and float past the scenic wonderland of red rocks on Lake Powell, the second-largest man-made lake in the USA. The Rainbow Bridge, a spectacular natural stone bridge on the Navajo Reservation, can be reached by tour boat.</p>]]><p><b>London Bridge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Lake Havasu City (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.golakehavasu.com/">www.golakehavasu.com</a>), nestled amidst rugged desert peaks on the Colorado River. In 1971 London Bridge was dismantled stone by stone, brought over from England and reassembled in Arizona. It is now the focal point for an array of English-style shops, pubs and lodgings.</p>]]><p><b>Monument Valley by air</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Drift over spectacular Monument Valley, carved by wind and water, in a hot air balloon (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.monumentvalleyballooncompany.com/">www.monumentvalleyballooncompany.com</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Oak Creek Canyon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore beautiful Oak Creek Canyon in Sedona's Red Rock country (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.visitsedona.com/">www.visitsedona.com</a>). The canyon has natural swimming holes and lush forests beneath high sandstone cliffs. Prehistoric Native American ruins are nearby. Jeep tours, hiking and mountain biking are also available.</p>]]><p><b>Play golf</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tee off on one of the more challenging golf courses in Mesa, Phoenix or Tucson. The Phoenix-Scottsdale area, known as the Valley of the Sun, has a particular abundance of world-class golf courses and resorts, surrounded by desert and striking mountain scenery (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.golfarizona.com/">www.golfarizona.com</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Raft the Colorado River</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Shoot the rapids on a white-water rafting trip down the raging Colorado River; there are trips from short runs to two-week adventures.</p>]]><p><b>Road trips</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Drive down empty roads and see huge cacti, spring wildflowers and the Organ Pipe Cactus National Monument (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/orpi">www.nps.gov/orpi</a>) in the Sonoran Desert. Journey through the vast Navajo Reservation, home to 250,000 Navajos. Purchase native artwork and silver jewellery and visit settlements where they lived in <em>hogans</em> (dome-shaped houses of log and adobe). Navajo guides lead horse rides in the Canyon de Chelly National Monument (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/cach">www.nps.gov/cach</a>) and jeep tours through Monument Valley (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.desertusa.com/monvalley">www.desertusa.com/monvalley</a>), where many a Western was shot.</p>]]><p><b>Taliesin West</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit famous architect Frank Lloyd Wright's home and School of Architecture at Taliesin West, near Scottsdale.</p>]]><p><b>Tonto National Monument</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the Tonto National Monument (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/tont">www.nps.gov/tont</a>). The monument features well-preserved cliff dwellings occupied 500 years ago by the Salado Indians and examples of their weavings, jewellery, weapons and tools.</p>]]><p><b>Tucson</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover the cultural heritage of Tucson (<a href="http://www.tucsonaz.gov/" target="_blank">www.tucsonaz.gov</a>), one of the USA's oldest towns and now one of its fastest-growing resort cities. Surrounded by a ring of five mountain ranges in the Sonoran Desert, Tucson is known for its constant sunshine. Its proximity to the Mexican border is apparent in its architecture, cuisine, lively fiestas and festivals.</p>]]><p><b>Wild West</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Watch re-enactments of famous gunfights in the Wild West mining town of Tombstone, site of the brief showdown at the OK Corral, and movies such as <em>Wyatt Earp</em> and <em>Tombstone</em> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.tombstone.org/">www.tombstone.org</a>). Explore restored sites and attractions like the Boot Hill Cemetery, the Crystal Palace Saloon (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.crystalpalacesaloon.com/">www.crystalpalacesaloon.com</a>), and the Bird Cage Theatre.</p>]]><p><b>Yuma Territorial Prison</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover Arizona's most visited State Historic Park, the Yuma Territorial Prison, with its cells carved out of the rock. From 1876 to 1909, it housed many of Arizona's most dangerous and notorious criminals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business dress in Arizona depends upon the field of business a company is engaged in. Although some companies and businesses still promote the corporate suit image, the vast majority have relaxed and adopted a 'business casual' approach to dressing. This means no ties with button shirts for men or perhaps a jumper instead of a blazer, and more individuality for women when choosing suits. Prospective employers still prefer a formal suit for interviews.<br /><br />Greetings in Arizona are by handshake until you get to know your business contact better, and business lunches are often reserved for upper management or small firms. Appointments and punctuality are expected procedure and business cards are widely used. Dates in America are written month-day-year.<br /><br />A typical working day is between eight to 10 hours and can be anytime between 0630 and 1900. Most businesses do not work on weekends, although this does depend upon the nature of the work.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Most restaurants serve American or American/Continental food but Southwestern cuisine is the most popular, a fusion of Mexican with steak, ribs and cowboy fare, big on the use of Mexican spices.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; Chilli and <em>frijoles</em> (refried beans). <br />&bull; Steak.<br />&bull; Ribs.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Phoenix and Tucson have various nightclubs, and there is evening entertainment at many resorts in the area. Scottsdale's nightlife is more concentrated, while the university crowd go out in Tempe, where there are good jazz clubs on Mill Avenue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Phoenix has excellent shopping facilities, including Biltmore Fashion Park and the Arizona Center. Other good shopping centres in the metro area are at the Scottsdale Fashion Square and the upscale Italian-style Borgata, also in Scottsdale, and along pedestrianised Mill Avenue and at the Arizona Mills mall in Tempe.<br><br>Special buys in Arizona include Navajo silver and turquoise jewellery, sand paintings, rug weaving, Hopi silver jewellery, kachina carvings, pottery, basketry and paintings. Tucson is a good place to pick up many of these items, as well as reasonably priced goods from Mexican import stores.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arizona hotels offer something for every budget. In Phoenix or Scottsdale, there are hotels of world-class standards while resorts throughout the state offer superb 5-star properties, some of which include golf and spa facilities. Historic hotels or inns are available elsewhere while those looking for cheap Arizona hotels should aim for comfortable motel accommodation found along most major highways and towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arizona hotels offer something for every budget. In Phoenix or Scottsdale, there are hotels of world-class standards while resorts throughout the state offer superb 5-star properties, some of which include golf and spa facilities. Historic hotels or inns are available elsewhere while those looking for cheap Arizona hotels should aim for comfortable motel accommodation found along most major highways and towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arizona hotels offer something for every budget. In Phoenix or Scottsdale, there are hotels of world-class standards while resorts throughout the state offer superb 5-star properties, some of which include golf and spa facilities. Historic hotels or inns are available elsewhere while those looking for cheap Arizona hotels should aim for comfortable motel accommodation found along most major highways and towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[34.048928]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-111.093731]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>295,253 sq km (113,998 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>6.8 million (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>23.1 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Phoenix.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arizona is predominately Christian, with the largest groups being Roman Catholic, followed by Evangelical Protestant. Other smaller groups include Jewish, Mormon, and Buddhist.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Because Arizona recently passed the Arizona SB 1070 law which is considered the strictest law dealing with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> immigration, many assume that all residents of Arizona are extremely conservative. Though Arizona does tend to vote conservatively in local and national elections, there is a growing liberal population across the state.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arizona was first explored in the mid-1500s by several Spanish explorers, and became a part of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mexico">Mexico</a> in the early 1800s, though it had a very small population until later being settled by the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a>.</p>
<p>The Mexican-American War began in 1846 because of the US annexation of newly independent <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/texas">Texas</a>. At the end of the gruelling war in 1848, the Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo outlined the purchase of modern-day <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california">California</a>, New  Mexico, Arizona, and several other states by the United   States.</p>
<p>In 1849, the California Gold Rush began, and as miners flocked in extreme numbers to the west coast hoping to hit it big, the effect of this influx was a large population boom in Arizona. Shortly afterwards, Arizona and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-mexico">New Mexico</a> were consolidated into the New Mexico Territory, and a large strip of land was added to the area with the Gadsden Purchase in 1853.</p>
<p>The New Mexico Territory joined the Confederacy during the Civil War, but the territory was regained by the Union in 1862 and after the end of the war, was split into two parts, creating the Arizona Territory.</p>
<p>The Southern Pacific Railroad reached Arizona in 1880 and the Santa Fe Railroad reached the rim of the Grand  Canyon in 1901. Both made Arizona a much more accessible destination and Tucson became a major railroad epicentre for the southwest.</p>
<p>Arizona became the 48th and last contiguous state added to the US after President William Taft signed the statehood bill in 1912. A considerably liberal new state, Arizona women gained the right to vote that same year, eight years before the rest of the country. After WWII, Arizona&rsquo;s population boomed, and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/phoenix">Phoenix</a> became a hot industrial and manufacturing centre for the state as agriculture quickly declined. The agreeable weather and low costs continued to attract new residents through the remainder of the 20th century, a large number being retirees from colder, northern climates.</p>
<p>In the 21st century, Arizona has been in the headlines for their issues with illegal immigration from near-by Mexico. In 2010, the states passed Arizona SB 1070, a strict and strongly contested law that imposes harsh regulations and restrictions on aliens and immigrants.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Today, Arizona is a popular destination because of the agreeable winter weather and the beauty of the local terrain, most famously the Grand Canyon, one of the seven natural wonders of the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A jewel in the USA&rsquo;s crown, Arizona is a state of seemingly infinite possibilities; a place where you can hike from snow-capped mountains to the dusty depths of the Grand Canyon; where you can dance around campfires with Navajo tribesmen and rattle down Route 66 on a road trip to California.</p>
<p>While the north of the state is criss-crossed with mountain streams and canyons, the south and west offer eye-catching deserts with stunning rock formations, Native American tribes and ramshackle ghost towns from Arizona&rsquo;s mining days.</p>
<p>Phoenix, the bustling state capital, boasts world-class cultural attractions, restaurants and shopping, not to mention a buzzing nightlife. It borders swanky Scottsdale, one of Arizona&rsquo;s primary resorts, which is crammed with trendy hotels, spas and golf courses.</p>
<p>Chock-a-block with students, Tucson is a hip and culturally vibrant city. Surrounded by rugged mountains, it has a lively nightlife, heavy Hispanic influence and distinctive downtown.</p>
<p>Flagstaff, meanwhile, is the place for adventure, being as it is the gateway to some of the best hiking, biking and skiing in the state. And then there&rsquo;s Sedona, a small city in Yavapai County surrounded by stunning sandstone formations and scented pine forests.</p>
<p>For a taste of the Wild West, there&rsquo;s the notorious, frontier town of Tombstone, which offers visitors the chance to stroll down its saloon-lined high street and watch re-enactments of the famous shooting at OK Corral.</p>
<p>Of course, the Grand Canyon is the big draw, but dig deeper in Arizona, and you&rsquo;re in for a treat.</p><p>A jewel in the USA&rsquo;s crown, Arizona is a state of seemingly infinite possibilities; where you can hike from snow-capped mountains to the dusty depths of the Grand Canyon; where you can dance around campfires with Navajo tribesmen and rattle down Route 66 on a road trip to California.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
