<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Jersey" ColCode="jer" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Jersey]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The most popular holiday season is from May until the end of September, with temperatures averaging 20 to 21ºC (68-70ºF). Rainfall averages 84cm (33 inches) a year, most of which falls during the cooler months. Sea temperatures average over 17°C (63ºF) in deep water during the summer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normal beach and holidaywear for summer, with a jumper or similar as there are often sea breezes. Warm winterwear and rainwear are advised.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[l<p>Visitors who wish to drive must have a valid Certificate of Insurance or an International Green Card, and a valid driving licence or International (not UK International) Driving Permit (not photocopies). Nationality plates must be displayed.</p><p>There is a speed limit of 64kph (40mph). Motor caravans and trailers may not be imported.</p><p>Available in St Helier. Persons wishing to hire a car must: (a) be over 21 years of age; (b) have had a full licence for at least one year; and (c) have a valid full licence with no endorsements or disqualifications for dangerous driving or driving over the alcohol limit within the previous five years.</p><p>Mopeds can be hired from a number of companies in St Helier. Crash helmets must be worn. Addresses and telephone numbers of all these companies can be obtained from Jersey Tourism.</p><p>There is a speed limit of 64kph (40mph). Motor caravans and trailers may not be imported.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major airlines operating to Jersey include Flybe (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.flybe.com/">www.flybe.com</a>) (from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> and major <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> cities); easyJet (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.easyjet.com/">www.easyjet.com</a>) (from Luton and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/liverpool">Liverpool</a>); British Airways (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.ba.com">www.ba.com</a>) and Cityjet (<a href="http://www.cityjet.com" target="_blank">www.cityjet.com</a>) (from London). Airlines operating to Jersey from the French coast include Aurigny Air Services (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.aurigny.com">www.aurigny.com</a>); they also operate from Gatwick.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London to Jersey is 50 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Jersey Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.jerseyairport.com<p>The airport is located about 7km (4.3 miles) northwest of the island's capital, Saint Helier.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+44 1534 446 000</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Many 'Pay As You Go' phones will not work in Jersey.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a number of Internet caf&eacute;s, particularly in St Helier. Internet service is also available at some libraries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British media are free and able to report on all subjects. The variety of publications reflects the full spectrum of political opinion. Newspapers published in Jersey are the <em>Jersey Evening Post </em>and the <em>Jersey Weekly Post</em>. Jersey has two local TV stations, Channel TV and Spotlight Channel Islands. Cable and satellite channels are available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a standard one-price rate to the UK, which is, in general, as good as a first-class UK service, although the prices are lower than UK first class. There is also one rate for internal mail. UK stamps are not valid in Jersey. The main post office is in Broad Street, St Helier.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1730, Sat 0900-1230.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Cycling</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Jersey's network of 'Green Lanes', which have a 24kph (15mph) speed limit, are ideal for cyclists.</p>]]><p><b>Dining</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fresh seafood, quality country pubs and Michelin-starred restaurants mean Jersey is a great place for eating out. Whether you're tucking into steaming calamari, pan-seared veal or steak and chips, chances are it'll be delicious.</p>]]><p><b>Elizabeth Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In St Helier, admire Elizabeth Castle (<a href="http://www.jerseyheritagetrust.org/" target="_blank">www.jerseyheritagetrust.org</a>), which stands on an island in the bay, accessible by a causeway at low tide. This imposing fortress withstood Cromwell's forces for seven weeks in 1651, and housed occupying Germans during WWII.</p>]]><p><b>Fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sub-aqua enthusiasts and anglers should head for Bouley Bay on the northeast coast; it is a fishing harbour with an old fort and a small sandy beach.</p>]]><p><b>Flowers</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Marvel at the spectacle of flower-festooned floats and entertainers at the Battle of Flowers festival in August. The museum in St Ouen displays floats entered in the Battle of Flowers.</p>]]><p><b>Get crafty</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go on a pottery, candle-making or leatherwork course, which are very popular in Jersey.</p>]]><p><b>Golf</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Jersey has two famous 18-hole golf courses: La Moye in St Brelade and Royal Jersey in Grouville (<a href="http://www.royaljersey.com/" target="_blank">www.royaljersey.com</a>). Both require proof of handicap or membership in a recognised club. Anyone can play at 18-hole Les Mielles or Les Ormes and nine-hole Wheatlands or Greve D'Azette.</p>]]><p><b>Hamptonne</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore this restored traditional farm, representing Jersey's farming heritage between 17th-19th centuries. Walk round the thatched buildings and hear tales from Hamptonne's collection of characters.</p>]]><p><b>Jersey War Tunnels</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pay a visit to the Jersey War Tunnels (<a href="http://www.jerseywartunnels.com/" target="_blank">www.jerseywartunnels.com</a>); an underground hospital that now contains displays on and memorabilia from WWII. The tunnel complex was hewn out of the rock by forced labour during the occupation of Jersey by German Forces.</p>]]><p><b>Jersey Zoological Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover many endangered species at the Jersey Zoological Park, in Trinity, the headquarters of the Durrell Wildlife Conservation Trust (<a href="http://www.durrellwildlife.org/" target="_blank">www.durrellwildlife.org</a>), founded by the late Gerald Durrell.</p>]]><p><b>La Hougue Bie</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This museum housed in a massive neolithic tomb in Grouville dates back 5,000 years and has exhibitions on the agriculture, archaeology, geology and history of the island.</p>]]><p><b>Mont Orgeuil Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the mighty Mont Orgeuil Castle at Gorey, as well as a number of restored military bunkers dotted along the coast.</p>]]><p><b>Museums</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Also in St Helier, wander along Fort Regent's ramparts and go to the award-winning Jersey Museum, the Maritime Museum and the Occupation Tapestry Gallery.</p>]]><p><b>Ocean views</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy fine views from Jersey's 'Points', clifftop headlands overlooking the sea. Most of these are on the northern side of the island, notably those at Grosnez and Plemont on the northwest corner.</p>]]><p><b>Swimming</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The extensive beaches to either side of St Helier in the south; stretching 5km (3 miles) west around St Aubin's Bay and east to La Roque Point are the most picturesque. However, at all Jersey beaches, beware of very strong currents.</p>]]><p><b>Traditional skills</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Browse for traditional crafts in the island's many excellent workshops. Leatherwork at L'Etacq (St Ouen) and stoneground flour from local corn at Le Moulin de Quetivel, St Peter's Valley, and Grouville is home to Jersey Pottery, also renowned for its restaurant and gardens.</p>]]><p><b>Walking</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The north has the highest land and most rugged scenery, but gentler walks are possible inland and in the south. One suggested route round the island follows the line of the old Jersey Railway which runs from St Aubin to the lighthouse at Corbière on the island's southwestern tip.</p>]]><p><b>Watersports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Watersports such as windsurfing and water skiing are best attempted at one of the island's most popular and beautiful beaches, St Brelade's Bay, west of St Aubin.</p>]]><p><b>West coast surfing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visitors rave about the surfing found on the west coast; particularly off the sweeping 8km (5-mile) sandy beach on St Ouen's Bay.</p>]]><p><b>Wine tasting</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Drop by for a taste of local tipple at La Mare Vineyards, close to Devil's Hole. The vineyards are set in the grounds of an 18th-century farmhouse and visitors can enjoy displays from the local cider industry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$5.1 billion (2005).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, textiles, light industrial and electrical goods.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and transport equipment, manufactured goods, food, mineral fuels and chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>UK, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/channel-islands/guernsey">Guernsey</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although agriculture is still important as a source of employment and prestige (Jersey cows are renowned throughout the world) offshore banking and tourism are the mainstays of the economy: the former because of the island's exemption from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> tax system and the latter through continental influence and a benign climate.<br />
<br />
In 2005, finance and banking accounted for half of the GDP and were largely responsible for Jersey's 2006 unemployment rate of just 2.2%. New and highly regulated legislation designed to tighten up some of the less salubrious aspects of Jersey's financial environment should serve to strengthen its reputation in an era when offshore finance is coming under growing political pressure through its implication in money-laundering. In the last few years, Jersey has signed up to several international initiatives designed to tackle the problem while improving financial transparency. Jersey plays host each year to a large number of conferences and has a variety of venues; the main period is from October to May.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businesspeople are generally expected to dress smartly (suits are usual apart from Fridays when office workers generally 'dress down'). Appointments should be made and the exchange of business cards is customary. A knowledge of English is essential. <br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0900/0930-1700/1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Jersey Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (01534) 724 536
					Website:http://www.jerseychamber.com
					Address: St Helier,Chamber House,25 Pier Road,,]]><b>Jersey Conference Bureau</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (01534) 448 855
					Website:http://www.jerseyconferences.co.uk
					Address: St Helier,Liberation Square,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Jersey has an excellent range of restaurants to cater for every taste. Seafood is very popular and a wide selection of home-grown produce is available; scallops, oysters, spider crabs and lobster are particularly good. Fresh seafood can be bought from the local fish market. Jersey cows are renowned for their rich and creamy milk. The island has an enviable reputation for good cuisine whether in small pubs, wine bars or high-class restaurants.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; <em>Bean crock</em> (dried beans with onions, herbs and pig trotters).<br />&bull; <em>Fiottes</em> (balls of flour, sugar and eggs, cooked in milk).<br />&bull; <em>La Soupe d'anguilles</em> (conger eel soup).<br />&bull; Cream tea (served with strawberries).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Licensing hours are 0900-2300 for restaurants and 1100-2300 for pubs and bars.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>In general, this follows UK practice.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jersey's nightlife is centred on St Helier, although there are pubs and restaurants dotted around the island. There's also theatre, film and music to be enjoyed. </p><br />
<br />
<p>Four music and film festivals attract crowds at various times of the year, allowing island dwellers and visitors the chance to catch some big name acts. Live music gigs can be found in St Helier on most weekends, and jazz music is also a favourite.  Clubs in St Helier offer the chance to stay up late and dance the night away. For those who like more traditional dancing, there are ballroom dances most weekends, as well as Scottish country dance classes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The island is a low-duty area and there is no VAT. As well as St Helier (where there are two covered markets), there are shopping areas such as Red Houses, St Brelade and Gorey, St Martin. Luxury items such as spirits, cigarettes, jewellery and perfumes are popular buys. Local products such as knitwear, pottery, woodcrafts and even flowers are good value.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1730. The markets and some shops are closed on Thursday afternoons. During the summer months, many shops are open in the evenings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many hotels in Jersey and the official consumer information pack, compiled by the Jersey Hospitality Association, is available from Jersey Tourism. <br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in Jersey are graded from 1 to 5 stars and guest houses are graded from 1 to 4 diamonds. All hotels in Jersey are inspected and graded annually.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are more than 200 guest houses in Jersey, some offering bed, breakfast and evening meals, others just bed and breakfast. Despite the large number of establishments, advance booking is recommended as many guest houses in Jersey are not open throughout the whole year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many hotels in Jersey and the official consumer information pack, compiled by the Jersey Hospitality Association, is available from Jersey Tourism. <br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in Jersey are graded from 1 to 5 stars and guest houses are graded from 1 to 4 diamonds. All hotels in Jersey are inspected and graded annually.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many hotels in Jersey and the official consumer information pack, compiled by the Jersey Hospitality Association, is available from Jersey Tourism. <br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in Jersey are graded from 1 to 5 stars and guest houses are graded from 1 to 4 diamonds. All hotels in Jersey are inspected and graded annually.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are observed the next working day.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Early May Bank Holiday :
							07 May </p><p>Spring Bank Holiday :
							28 May </p><p>Summer Bank Holiday :
							27 August </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Channel Islands are not part of the UK or the EU and are subject to different allowances. To complicate matters further there are duty free differences between the Bailiwick of Jersey and the Bailiwick of Guernsey (which includes the islands of Alderney, Sark, Herm, Jethou and Lihou).</p><p>The following goods may be imported into the Bailiwick of Jersey by travellers over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p><p>• 200 cigarettes or 250g of other tobacco products.<br/>• 1L of spirits.<br/>• 4L of wine.<br/>• 16L of beer or cider.<br/>• Other goods to a value of £390 (reduced to £270 if arriving by private plane or boat).</p><p>Alternatively, you may import more wine or beer if you don't bring in any spirits or tobacco. In this case, you may import:</p><p>• 36L of table wine or 48 x 750ml bottles of wine or 110L of beer.</p><p>The following goods may be imported into Bailiwick of Guernsey by travellers over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p><p>• 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br/>• 4L of still table wine.<br/>• 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of fortified wine/sparkling wine/liqueurs or an additional 4L of still table wine.<br/>• 50L of beer of cider.<br/>• An unlimited value of other goods (if coming from within the EU) or goods to the value of £390 (if coming from a non-EU country; reduced to  £270 if arriving by private plane or boat).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted goods include unlicensed drugs, offensive weapons, obscene or pornographic material, and counterfeit goods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Channel Islands have their own notes – the Guernsey pound and the Jersey pound, both of which are at par with the UK pound. Pound Sterling (JEP; symbol £) = 100 pence. Notes are in denominations of £50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of £2, £1, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 pence.<br/><br/>Channel Islands notes and coins are not accepted in the UK, although they can be reconverted at parity in UK banks. Sark, Herm and Alderney use the Guernsey pound.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies can be exchanged at bureaux de change, in banks and at many hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are all widely accepted.</p><p>On the main islands of Jersey and Guernsey ATMs are widespread and accessible, whilst on Alderney there are two ATMs.</p><p>There are no cash machines on Sark or Herm, so visitors are advised to withdraw money before travelling to the islands - Guernsey has a multitude of ATMs. Sark has a NatWest bank (tel: (01481) 832 090;<a href="http://www.natwestinternational.com" target="_blank">www.natwestinternational.com</a>), which is open Mon-Fri 0930-1230 and 1400-1500, and an HSBC (tel: 0845 600 6161;<a href="http://www.hsbc.com" target="_blank">www.hsbc.com</a>), open Mon-Fri 0930-1230 and 1400-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted in larger establishments. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0930-1530. Some banks are open later on weekdays and Saturday mornings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[49.228982]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-2.123032]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>116 sq km (45 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>102,700 (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>869 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>St Helier.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Self-governing dependency of the British Crown.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jersey is the largest of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/channel-islands">Channel Islands</a>, lying approximately 160km (100 miles) south of the coast of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england">England</a> and 23km (14 miles) from the coast of Normandy in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a>. The island is roughly 14.5km (9 miles) by 8km (5 miles). It slopes from north to south and often appears to visitors to be largely composed of pink granite. Jersey has over 20 bays, many small harbours and magnificent beaches bathed by the warm waters of the Gulf Stream.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Each of Jersey's parishes has its own Anglican church, but some parishes, particularly St Helier, have been subdivided to provide more than one centre for Church of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england">England</a> worship. There are 12 Roman Catholic and 18 Methodist churches, as well as a wide range of free churches.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The monarchy, though now only symbolic politically, is a powerful and often subconscious unifying force. Members of the Royal Family are the subject of unceasing fascination, with their every move avidly followed and reported by the popular press, both in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> and abroad.<br /><br />Handshaking is customary when introduced to someone for the first time. Normal social courtesies should be observed when visiting someone's home and a small present such as flowers or chocolates is appreciated. It is polite to wait until everyone has been served before eating.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with three square pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chief Minister John Le Fondr&eacute; since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Lieutenant-Governor Sir Stephen Dalton since March 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jersey has been inhabited for thousands of years, as can be seen from the Neolithic tomb at La Houge Bie. Annexed to the Duchy of Normandy during the 10th century when William of Normandy gained the English Crown in 1066, the Channel Islands became part of the Anglo-Norman realm.</p>
<p>As a mark of his gratitude for its loyalty in 1204 King John granted Jersey the foundations of self-government, which exists to this day. The connection between the island and the English throne is expressed in the flag, which contains a crest surmounted by the Plantagenet Crown.</p>
<p>Like its neighbours, Jersey has been a haven for smugglers and pirates and, although its proximity to France has made it vulnerable to attack, the islanders fought off French invasions on numerous occasions, particularly during the 14th and 15th centuries. One of the most serious threats, led by the Baron de Rullecourt, was repelled in 1781.</p>
<p>Its darkest days though were during WWII when the Channel Islands became the only part of the Commonwealth to be occupied by German forces. Jersey has closely guarded its independence since WWII with strict criteria on rights of residency and an on-going reluctance to accept controls over its thriving financial services industry.</p>
<p>A number of online retailers and fulfilment companies continue to operate from the Channel Islands, enjoying lower rates of tax than they would expect in the UK.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Jersey is one of the world&rsquo;s top offshore financial centres &ndash; with its reduced tax burdens many describe it as a tax haven.<br />
&bull;	Jersey is not a part of the United Kingdom or the European Union, but as a British Crown Dependency is treated as such for the purposes of free trade in goods.<br />
&bull;	Based on ancient Norman, Jersey&rsquo;s once dominant J&egrave;rriais language is spoken by around 2,500 islanders.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The largest of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/channel-islands">Channel Islands</a>, Jersey's landscape is varied and breathtaking, from shimmering secluded coves and undulating farmland to magnificent cliff-top views. This is a place for cycling quiet country lanes, spending hours on beautiful beaches, and enjoying the quiet life.</p>
<p>Jersey's romantic past as a once infamous spot for smugglers and pirates adds to its sense of idyllic remoteness. Traffic is non-existent, nor is there a drone of city noise. It's easy to understand why Jersey is a favourite destination for visitors both young and old. Family friendly and perfect for outdoor pursuits, Jersey continues to pride itself on its renowned reputation.</p>The largest of the Channel Islands, Jersey's landscape is varied and breathtaking, from shimmering secluded coves and undulating farmland to magnificent cliff-top views.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
