<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Texas" ColCode="tex" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="tx" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Texas]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Texas is the second biggest state in America (Alaska is the largest state) with varying climates but, on average, temperatures rarely go above 35&deg;C (96&deg;F) or below 0-5&deg;C (32-45&deg;F).</p>
<p>Forest fires generally occur from June to August in the west. Tornadoes tend to occur in April, May and June in the north while there are risks of hurricanes and flooding in the south/southeast year round. The average precipitation varies - the west has 8.7 inches (220mm) annually, the north has 37 inches (940mm) annually, and the south has about 60 inches (1,500mm) annually.</p>

<p><strong>Austin</strong></p>
<p>Austin is the Texas capital, situated in the southeast and 234km (145m) west of Houston. Austin can reach highs of 36&deg;C (97&deg;F) in the summer months and lows of 5&deg;C (45&deg;F) in the winter months. Summers can be sweltering so pack some sun cream with you. For more information, see the <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/north-america/united-states-of-america/texas/austin/weather/">weather in Austin and the best time to go guide</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Dallas</strong></p>
<p>Dallas is a thriving metropolis in north Texas. Dallas can reach highs of 36&deg;C (96&deg;F) in the sweltering summer months and lows of 3&deg;C (37&deg;F) in the winter months with some snow in January and February. Expect mild temperatures for the rest of the year. For more information, see the <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/north-america/united-states-of-america/texas/dallas/weather/">weather in Dallas and the best time to go guide</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Houston</strong></p>
<p>Houston is the most populous city in Texas and covering a large part of the gulf coastal plain where the terrain is mostly flat and marshy. Houston has a humid subtropical climate with long hot summers and mild winters. August is the hottest month with temperatures ranging from 24&deg;C (75&deg;F) to 34&deg;C (93&deg;F) while January is the coldest month with temperatures ranging from 7&deg;C (45&deg;F) to 17&deg;C (63&deg;F) – which is still comfortable to many. Extreme weather is likely to occur around this area with frequent tornadoes and hurricanes. For more information, see the <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/north-america/united-states-of-america/texas/houston/weather/">weather in Houston and the best time to go guide</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For summer, bring lightweight clothing to keep yourself cool. Sunglasses, hats and sun cream are advisable. For winter, bring layers to keep yourself warm. Hats, scarves and gloves are advised. Bring waterproof clothing if you're going down south.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/texas/austin-bergstrom-international-airport">Austin Bergstrom International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/texas/dallas-fort-worth-international-airport">Dallas-Fort Worth International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/texas/houston-george-bush-intercontinental-airport">Houston George Bush Intercontinental Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/texas/houston-william-p-hobby-airport">Houston William P Hobby Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/texas/el-paso-international-airport">El Paso International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/texas/san-antonio-international-airport">San Antonio International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to Dallas/Fort Worth is 9 hours, and from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> is 3 hours 30 minutes. Flight times to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/houston">Houston</a> are similar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Houston George Bush Intercontinental Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airport-houston.com<p>Houston George Bush Intercontinental Airport is located 37km (23 miles) north of Houston.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 281 230 3100</p>]]><b>Houston William P. Hobby Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.fly2houston.com/hobby<p>Houston William P. Hobby Airport is situated 11km (7 miles) southeast of Houston.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 713 640 3000</p>]]><b>Austin-Bergstrom International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.austintexas.gov/airport<p>Austin-Bergstrom International Airport is situated 8km (5 miles) southeast of Austin.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 512 530 2242.</p>]]><b>Dallas-Fort Worth International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.dfwairport.com<p>Dallas-Fort Worth International Airport is located 24km (15 miles) northwest of Dallas and 29km (18 miles) northeast of Fort Worth.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 972 973 3112</p>]]><b>El Paso International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.elpasointernationalairport.com<p>El Paso International Airport is situated 10km (6 miles) northeast of El Paso and 19km (12 miles) north of Ciudad Juárez.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 915 212 0330</p>]]><b>San Antonio International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.sanantonio.gov/sat<p>San Antonio International Airport is situated 13km (8 miles) north of San Antonio, in central Texas.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 210 207 3433</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Main harbours: Houston, Corpus Christi, Galveston, Beaumont, Port Arthur and Brownsville.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Amtrak (tel: 1 800 872 7245, in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> only; <a href="http://www.amtrak.com/" target="_blank">www.amtrak.com</a>) journeys between main cities are difficult and (except for <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dallas">Dallas</a> to Fort Worth) can only be made on the long-distance trains. The 'Texas Eagle' service from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/chicago">Chicago</a> passes through Dallas and Fort Worth on its way to San Antonio, where transfers to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/los-angeles">Los Angeles</a> are possible on the 'Sunset Limited', which arrives from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/orlando">Orlando</a> via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-orleans">New Orleans</a> and Houston. The 'Heartland Flyer' links Oklahoma City and Fort Worth.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Texas is well connected to neighbouring states via Interstate Highways. The I-40 runs from New Mexico in the west to Oklahoma in the east, the I-35 connects Oklahoma in the north via Dallas and San Antonio with the Mexican border in the south of Texas.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Border crossings between Texas and Mexico are at McAllen, Brownsville, Laredo and El Paso.</p>
<p>Toll road is charged mainly around larger cities like Dallas, Austin and Houston. The <a href="http://www.txdot.gov/inside-txdot/division/toll-operations/roads.html" target="www.txdot.gov/inside-txdot/division/toll-operations/roads.html">Texas Department of Transportation</a> provides an overview of where toll road is charged in Texas on its map <a href="http://ftp.dot.state.tx.us/pub/txdot-info/tod/toll-roads-bridges.pdf" target="ftp.dot.state.tx.us/pub/txdot-info/tod/toll-roads-bridges.pdf">'Toll Roads and Toll Bridges in Texas'</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Alamo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the historic Alamo (<a href="http://www.thealamo.org/" target="_blank">www.thealamo.org</a>), the 1836 site of a furious battle between a handful of independence-seeking Texans (led by Davy Crockett) and a large Mexican army. Today it is a shrine to Texan courage and patriotism.</p>]]><p><b>Become a cowboy</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Become a real cowboy on a working ranch holiday in the hill country to the west of San Antonio, near Bandera (<a href="http://www.banderacowboycapital.com/" target="_blank">www.banderacowboycapital.com</a>), the 'Cowboy Capital of the World'.</p>]]><p><b>Big Bend National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See spectacular views of stark desert, forests, mountains and canyons carved by the Rio Grande at Big Bend National Park (<a href="http://www.nps.gov/bibe" target="_blank">www.nps.gov/bibe</a>), south of El Paso. Hiking and rafting, especially in the Santa Elena canyon, are popular.</p>]]><p><b>Buffalo Gap Historic Village</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Time warp back to the frontier days at Buffalo Gap Historic Village (<a href="http://www.buffalogap.com/" target="_blank">www.buffalogap.com</a>), a reconstructed frontier settlement that tracks the history of Indians, buffalo hunters and settlers.</p>]]><p><b>Dealey Plaza</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See Dealey Plaza (<a href="http://www.jfk.org/" target="_blank">www.jfk.org</a>), the site of President John F Kennedy's Dallas assassination. There is a dramatic exhibit of the event at the Sixth Floor Museum. The John F Kennedy Memorial at Main and Market Streets is open all year round.</p>]]><p><b>Fair Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Fair Park (<a href="http://www.fairpark.org/" target="_blank">www.fairpark.org</a>), home to the Age of Steam Museum, Dallas Aquarium, the Museum of Natural History (with a superb dinosaur exhibition), the Texas Hall of State and The Women's Museum: An Institute for the Future.</p>]]><p><b>Galveston Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit romantic Galveston Island (<a href="http://www.galveston.com/" target="_blank">www.galveston.com</a>), just 40 minutes south of Houston. The island is rich in history and pirate lore and noted for its sandy beaches, fishing, watersports and turn-of-the-century architecture.</p>]]><p><b>Gulf Coast</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover the Texas Gulf Coast playground of Padre Island (<a href="http://www.nps.gov/pais" target="_blank">www.nps.gov/pais</a>), a narrow 170km (95-mile) barrier island with watersports, fishing centres and an impressive expanse of protected National Seashore, wildlife refuges and birdlife sites. It is connected to Corpus Christi by a causeway.</p>]]><p><b>Highland Lakes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy fishing, boating and swimming at Highland Lakes, in central Texas (<a href="http://www.highlandlakes.com/" target="_blank">www.highlandlakes.com</a>). Take a wine-tasting trip to award-winning wineries in the surrounding scenic hill country.</p>]]><p><b>Lone Star Flight Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Aviation buffs will enjoy a visit to the Lone Star Flight Museum (<a href="http://www.lsfm.org/" target="_blank">www.lsfm.org</a>) and Texas Aviation Hall of Fame in Galveston, one of the finest collections of restored aircraft and aviation exhibits in the nation.</p>]]><p><b>Odessa Meteor Crater</b></p><![CDATA[<p>View the Odessa Meteor Crater, the second-largest meteor crater in the USA at approximately 168m (550ft) in diameter. It was created when a barrage of meteors crashed to the earth between 20,000 and 30,000 years ago.</p>]]><p><b>Old City Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the Old City Park (<a href="http://www.oldcitypark.org/" target="_blank">www.oldcitypark.org</a>), a pioneer community in Dallas featuring homes, a church, a schoolhouse and Main Street as it was in the days of the original settlers.</p>]]><p><b>Palo Duro Canyon State Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Palo Duro Canyon State Park, near Amarillo. The park has dramatic coloured rock formations, is popular for hiking, picnicking, camping and horse riding, and has a rich history of nomadic tribes that hunted mammoth and large game animals.</p>]]><p><b>Reunion Tower</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ride the glass elevator to the top of the 50-storey Reunion Tower, belonging to the Hyatt Regency Hotel in Dallas. It has observation terraces and a revolving restaurant with nighttime dancing.</p>]]><p><b>San Antonio Missions National Historic Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Learn about the early efforts of the Spanish to Christianise the native population in southern Texas along the San Antonio River. Tour the four mission churches in San Antonio Missions National Historic Park (<a href="http://www.nps.gov/saan" target="_blank">www.nps.gov/saan</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Santa Ana National Wildlife Refuge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go bird watching at the Santa Ana National Wildlife Refuge, and see birds migrating to South and Central America along the Central and Mississippi Flyways.</p>]]><p><b>Southfork Ranch</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go and see the famous Southfork Ranch (<a href="http://www.southforkranch.com/" target="_blank">www.southforkranch.com</a>), home of the famous TV series' Ewing clan. The ranch is open daily, year-round for guided tours.</p>]]><p><b>Space Center Houston</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Space Center Houston (<a href="http://www.spacecenter.org/" target="_blank">www.spacecenter.org</a>) - the official visitor center of NASA's Johnson Space Center. Climb aboard a computer simulator, touch a moon rock, see a full-size space shuttle replica, see astronauts train for missions, or take a behind-the-scenes tour of NASA.</p>]]><p><b>Take a river walk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour San Antonio's Paseo del Rio (Riverwalk) (<a href="http://www.thesanantonioriverwalk.com/" target="_blank">www.thesanantonioriverwalk.com</a>), a unique shopping and entertainment area that sparkles like a fairyland at night.</p>]]><p><b>West End Historic District</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Step into the past in Dallas' West End Historic District (<a href="http://www.dallaswestend.org/" target="_blank">www.dallaswestend.org</a>), a collection of beautifully restored 100-year-old historical buildings turned into museums, shops, restaurants and nightlife.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Americans can often be less formal than Europeans (both in dress and manners) but in Texas, it is harder to anticipate the norm. Dallas regards itself as stylish and sophisticated and there is already a tradition of formality in the South. However, Texans can dress exceptionally informally, even looking to the newcomer like TV cowboys.</p>
<p>In Houston, business attire for both men and women is usually a suit, especially in the large corporations. Some of the smaller companies have adopted a more relaxed approach to dress and allow employees to wear smart-casual clothes, although usually not jeans.</p>
<p>The degree of office formality often reflects the nature of the business - banking and legal professions will be more formal than computer ('Silicon Prairie') and media companies. Americans quickly use first-name terms, while still remaining focused on the business in hand. As a visitor, there is nothing wrong in being as formal as in Europe and then relaxing once the attitudes of the host have been established.</p>
<p>Punctuality for business meetings is expected; visitors should always allow for traffic delays. Meetings can be at all times of the day, even a working breakfast or an evening meal, which can be a relaxed social affair or a more formal business meal.</p>
<p>Alcohol consumption is treated as a personal choice in Dallas whereas a lunch time meeting in Houston tends to be an alcohol free affair. This is different in the evenings when after-work drinking is commonplace.</p>
<p>If invited to a colleague's home for dinner, a small gift (such as a bottle of wine or something from one's own country, a neatly wrapped box of chocolates or similar confectionery) will often be appropriate as a gesture of thanks. A 'thank you' card sent by post after the event would be appreciated. In Houston however, the exchange of gifts is not common. <br />
&nbsp;</p><p>Business hours can start as early as 0800 in weekdays, although 0830 is more likely. The working day usually ends between 1700 and 1800. Working late is nonetheless common, nor is it unusual for people to be working well into the night or over the weekend. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Beef is widely featured - this being cattle country - but there is also a great variety of international cuisine including Chinese, French, Italian, Mexican and Spanish.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; Steak. <br />&bull; Tex-Mex dishes. <br />&bull; Barbequed ribs.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dallas has clubs, cabarets, discos, singles bars and corner pubs, with music ranging from classical to jazz and from country to contemporary rock. Some clubs are listed as 'private' - they are located in a 'dry' area and membership (usually available for a nominal fee) is required to be served alcohol.<br />
<br />
There are also some comedy clubs sprinkled throughout the city and others offer comedy and drama while customers dine. Fort Worth also has a number of nightclubs, but the musical emphasis here is on country &amp; western music. Billy Bob's Texas (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.billybobstexas.com/">www.billybobstexas.com</a>), the world's largest honky-tonk nightclub, with a 6,000-person capacity, plays host to some of the biggest names in country music in addition to having live bull riding.<br />
<br />
Houston's many nightspots range from big-name entertainment to supper club revues, pavement caf&eacute;s, discos and singles bars. Austin is noted for its nightly live music venues. Historic 6th Street takes on a lively atmosphere in the evenings as people go pub-crawling between venues catering for country &amp; western, soul, R &amp; B, rock 'n' roll and jazz music. San Antonio offers all sorts of musical entertainment, including traditional 'Tejano' sounds, Dixieland jazz, symphony concerts, country &amp; western and college music.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dallas has more shopping centres per capita than any other US city and some of the largest shopping malls in the southwest. The elegant and original Neiman Marcus department store is now a popular tourist attraction. Dallas Market Center is one of the world's largest wholesale trade shopping centres and also offers fine restaurants. Both Dallas and Fort Worth have fine specialty shops. Nearby Grapevine Mills Outlet Mall sells discounted merchandise.<br><br>World-class shopping is available in more than 300 stores at the Galleria shopping centre in Houston. The best buys are western-style clothes, hats, boots, saddles and riding equipment. Katy Mills Outlet Mall carries discount name-brand fashions. Authentic Mexican folk art can be found throughout San Antonio, especially at El Mercado, patterned after an authentic Mexican market. Between San Antonio and Austin lies San Marcos, where the Prime Outlet Mall and Tanger Outlet Mall offer plenty of bargains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many good hotels in Texas including a majority of modern national and international hotel and motel chains, often with standard prices. In general, the quality of accommodation is high, with standard amenities such as television, telephone and very often broadband or Wi-Fi in each room. Hotels expect payment in advance and reservations are held until around 1800, unless late arrival is requested.<br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> Basic categories fall into Super, Deluxe, Standard, Moderate and Economy. Prices vary according to standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is bed and brekfast accomodation across Texas. Signs are not generally displayed by individual homes, but most homes offering this service are listed in directories, which may be purchased by interested travellers. 'Bed & Breakfast inns' have up to 20 or so rooms, and are distinguished from 'country inns' in that the latter offer meals in addition to breakfast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many good hotels in Texas including a majority of modern national and international hotel and motel chains, often with standard prices. In general, the quality of accommodation is high, with standard amenities such as television, telephone and very often broadband or Wi-Fi in each room. Hotels expect payment in advance and reservations are held until around 1800, unless late arrival is requested.<br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> Basic categories fall into Super, Deluxe, Standard, Moderate and Economy. Prices vary according to standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many good hotels in Texas including a majority of modern national and international hotel and motel chains, often with standard prices. In general, the quality of accommodation is high, with standard amenities such as television, telephone and very often broadband or Wi-Fi in each room. Hotels expect payment in advance and reservations are held until around 1800, unless late arrival is requested.<br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> Basic categories fall into Super, Deluxe, Standard, Moderate and Economy. Prices vary according to standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[31.968599]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-99.901813]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>692,190 sq km (267,256 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>27.5 million (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>39.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Austin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Texas borders Louisiana, Oklahoma, New Mexico and Arkansas as well as Mexico. Texas shares three rivers with its neighbours. The Rio Grande river borders Chihuahua, Coahuila, Nuevo León and Tamaulipas in Mexico. The Red River borders Oklahoma and Arkansas, and the Sabine River borders Louisiana in the United States. Due to the size of Texas, the terrain is different across Texas, with deserts in the northwest, piney woods in the southeast and mountains and hills in central Texas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unlike the rest of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">United States</a>, the majority of the religion that is practiced in Texas is Roman Catholicism. Other denominations include Baptists and Methodists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Texans can be described as typical southerners as their values generally tend to to be conservative, although pockets such as <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/austin">Austin</a>, may be described as somewhat more liberal. Greetings can include a quick, "How do you do?" Traditional customs such as men holding doors open for women are commonplace, as are somewhat conservative views about gender roles within society. Topics such as abortion and politics are likely to be highly controversial due to the state's highly religious demographics.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Before the arrival of any European settlers, the area we call Texas is thought to have been habited by the indigenous Native American population. The beginning of the European colonisers began with the arrival of the Spanish exploration headed by Alonso &Aacute;lvarez de Pineda in 1520. After settling, there were many attempts from the French to ambush the Spanish and to colonize the land for French ownership.&nbsp; However this wasn&rsquo;t successful and the Spanish declared Texas as a colony and in 1691 appointed Texas with its first governor Domingo Ter&aacute;n de los R&iacute;os.<br />
<br />
In 1799 the Spanish ceded control of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/louisiana">Louisiana</a> to the French but the agreement was unclear over borders. So much so, that when the French later sold the state of Louisiana to the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> in1803, the US believed that the deal also included the Texas area due to boundary confusions. Due to this, the Napoleon demanded that the king of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a> should abdicate. The result of this, was an attempt by both Mexican and US revolutionaries to declare <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mexico">Mexico</a> and Texas independent. Although unsuccessful, eventually, in 1821 Texas became a part of Mexico, which was newly independent from Spain. The state&rsquo;s Hispanic legacy has left its mark with place names such as San Antonio and from names of rivers such as Rio Grande. <br />
<br />
Within years of becoming part of Mexico, unrest began to take place over political disputes of land and colonialism which created the Texan revolution in 1835. In only three months, Texan forces successfully defeated the Mexican forces and so a year later signed the Texas Declaration of Independence, effectively making Texas a new republic. Continued disagreements rumbled on but in 1845, the US congress passed a bill allowing it to annex the Republic of Texas, thus making it a US state. Mexico strongly opposed annexation and the Mexican-American war took hold. <br />
<br />
In 1861, Texas joined the Confederate States of America siding with the south during the Civil War between the North and South. However, by 1865 the Confederacy&nbsp; had collapsed, in part due to the economic difficulties caused by war. After the war Texas grew increasely prosperous due to the growth of industries such as ranching and banking, leading to wealthier citizens and higher standards of living. <br />
<br />
WWII affected Texas significantly, creating more jobs for people working within new military factories, and less people working on traditional ranches. The shortage in farm workers meant that Mexican migrants were brought in, due to their acceptance of lower wages.<br />
<br />
When the war ended, Texas began its transformation and modernized to what it is today along with the rest of the US. This included the oil boom that brought along huge economic benefits for the local economy and for citizens of Texas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Home to vast mountain ranges, broad plains, beautiful beaches, rolling countryside and countless miles of uninhabitable desert, Texas is arguably one of the most awe-inspiring states in the USA. &ldquo;Everything is bigger in Texas,&rdquo; goes the slogan &ndash; and there&rsquo;s some truth in it. Similar in size to France, almost everything in Texas appears larger than life: the mountains, the cities, the food portions, and yes, some of the people too.</p>
<p>The so-called Lone Star State is world renowned for its Wild West spirit and a brazen &ldquo;don&rsquo;t mess with Texas&rdquo; attitude. But there is more to this state than big-headed cowboys, small-town girls and nationalistic defiance. Texas is home to cosmopolitan cities, sprinkled with creative businesses, smart urban types, internet millionaires and artistic communities.</p>
<p>The capital Austin is dynamic and happening, with a lively music scene, retro vibe and boutique stores. The state&rsquo;s largest city, Houston, is an expansive, multi-ethnic metropolis with plenty of charm and is famously the home of NASA. Dallas glitters with a shimmering high-rise skyline, elegant stores, fine restaurants and a rich cultural and sporting life.</p>
<p>The beautiful city of San Antonio is home to the stunning River Walk &ndash; a picturesque riverbank lined with caf&eacute;s and restaurant &ndash; plus one of the state&rsquo;s most famous historical monuments, The Alamo. If you&rsquo;re after a small-town America experience, visit sleepy Fort Worth, with its Old West charm, Saturday night rodeos and country western line dancing.</p>
<p>For an altogether wilder experience, saddle up at a working cattle ranch, lounge on unspoilt Gulf Coast beaches and discover national parks such as Big Bend or Guadalupe Mountains. Whatever you do, a warm welcome awaits. Texans are friendly folk and their indomitable spirit is bound to bowl you over.</p><p>Home to vast mountain ranges, broad plains, beautiful beaches, rolling countryside and countless miles of uninhabitable desert, Texas is arguably one of the most awe-inspiring states in the USA. &ldquo;Everything is bigger in Texas,&rdquo; goes the slogan &ndash; and there&rsquo;s some truth in it. Similar in size to France, almost everything in this state appears larger than life: the mountains, the cities, the food portions, and yes, some of the people too.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
