<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Hawaii" ColCode="haw" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="hi" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Hawaii]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hawaii is warm throughout the year, with an average temperature of 25.5 to 29&deg;C (78 to 85&deg;F), and no appreciable difference between 'summer' and 'winter.' Heavy rainfall can occur in the mountainous areas from December to February, but most regions only receive short showers, while others remain totally arid.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights are advised throughout the year, with slightly warmer clothes for winter. Beachwear is popular, and protection from the midday sun, such as sunglasses and sun hats, is advisable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Oahu is the gateway for flights to Hawaii's neighbouring islands such as Lanai and Molokai.<br />
<br />
Frequent inter-island services are delivered by Hawaiian Airlines (<a href="http://www.hawaiianair.com" target="_blank">www.hawaiianair.com</a>), which also offers several discount plans for tourists and businesspeople looking to travel between the islands on a flexible schedule.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are daily ferry services from Lahaina Harbor in Maui to both Manele Bay in Lanai and Kaunakakai Harbor in Molokai.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Hawaiian Railway Society (<a href="http://www.hawaiianrailway.com" target="_blank">www.hawaiianrailway.com</a>) on Oahu offers 90-minute journeys on a historical diesel-electric locomotive formerly used to haul sugar cane from Ewa Plantation Village to Ko'olina. <br />
<br />
On Maui, the Lahaina-Kaanapali &amp; Pacific Railroad, also known as the Sugar Cane Train (<a href="http://www.sugarcanetrain.com" target="_blank">www.sugarcanetrain.com</a>), offers daily 30-minute rides between Old Town Lahaina and Kaanapali Beach Resort, and a special Holiday Express in the month of December.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p><strong>Taxi:</strong> Metered taxis are available throughout the main islands.</p><p>Documentation: Foreign driving licence required.</p><p><strong>Regulations:</strong> Right-hand turns are permitted in the right lane at a 'stop' light unless otherwise indicated. Pedestrians are given the right of way most of the time.</p><p><strong>Car hire:</strong> Available through local and international agencies. Drivers must be over 21 years of age for car hire. Book car rental reservations in advance, particularly on the smaller islands. You can also rent a convertible jeep, an SUV, or a motor scooter on some islands, and if the fancy strikes you, a Harley Davidson motorcycle on Big Island. Some attractions are accessible only by rough, off trail roads but check your car rental agreement to ensure you are entitled to drive in these areas. <br />
<br />
Beware that congestion can be a problem in Oahu in rush hour.</p><p><strong>Regulations:</strong> Right-hand turns are permitted in the right lane at a 'stop' light unless otherwise indicated. Pedestrians are given the right of way most of the time.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Good local bus services are provided on Oahu by TheBus (tel: (808) 848 5555; <a href="http://www.thebus.org" target="_blank">www.thebus.org</a>), which covers the entire island with over 60 routes. An exact flat-fare system operates and free transfers are available on request. <br />
<br />
On other islands, taxis are available and car hire is possible. Limited public bus services operate on Kauai and Hawaii.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Honolulu International Airport (HNL) on Oahu is Hawaii's major international airport for all foreign visitors. Cheap flights to Hawaii are available during the spring and autumn. Flights to Hawaii are served by a number of different airlines including Continental Airlines, Delta Airlines and Air Canada.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/hawaii/honolulu-international-airport">Honolulu International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/honolulu">Honolulu</a> is 17 to 19 hours (including stopover, and depending on route taken).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Honolulu International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://airports.hawaii.gov/hnl/<p>Honolulu International Airport is situated 9.6km (6 miles) northwest of Honolulu's central business district.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 808 836 6411</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports<br />
</strong><strong>Hawaii</strong>:  Hilo, Kawaihae. <strong>Kauai:</strong> Nawiliwili, Port Allen. <strong>Maui:</strong> Kahului. <strong>Molokai:</strong> Kaunakakai. <strong>Oahu:</strong> Honolulu, Kalaeloa Barber's Point, Kewalo Basin. <strong>Lanai:</strong> Kaumalapau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Hawaii Volcanoes National Park</p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the Hawaii Volcanoes National Park (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/havo">www.nps.gov/havo</a>), one of the world's natural wonders. At 4,103m (13,677ft), Mauna Loa is the largest single mountain mass in the world, while at 1,200m (4,000ft), the still-active Kilauea's steaming vents and frequent eruptions provide an unusual (and safe) spectator sport. The volcano is continuously erupting, and lava can be seen hissing into the ocean.&nbsp;</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Aloha Tower Marketplace</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Shop or dine at the Aloha Tower Marketplace (<a href="http://www.alohatower.com/" target="_blank">www.alohatower.com</a>), an attractive and modern waterfront development in Honolulu. It is one of the major attractions in the area, with shopping plazas, restaurants, and pavement entertainers.</p>]]><p><b>Charter a boat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sail the tropical waters surrounding Hawaii on a skippered or bareboat charter, or crew on one of the America's Cup yachts berthed in Lahaina Harbour, Maui (<a href="https://www.sailmaui.com/" target="_blank">www.sailmaui.com/</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Circle Island Tour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a full-day Circle Island Tour around Oahu, offered by several different agencies. Possible attractions en route include Waimea Falls Park (<a href="https://www.waimeavalley.net" target="_blank">www.waimeavalley.net</a>), Pearl Harbor, the Polynesian Cultural Centre (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.polynesia.com/">www.polynesia.com</a>), Sea Life Park (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.sealifeparkhawaii.com/">www.sealifeparkhawaii.com</a>) where you can swim with the dolphins, the Waialua Coffee Visitors' Center (<a href="http://www.waialuaestate.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.waialuaestate.com</a>) constructed on a former plantation, and Sunset Beach.</p>]]><p><b>Fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go deep-sea fishing off the Kona coast of Hawaii's Big Island.</p>]]><p><b>Hanauma Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Snorkel and feed the tropical fish in Hanauma Bay (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.hanaumabay-hawaii.com/">www.hanaumabay-hawaii.com</a>), 10 miles east of Waikiki. Or swim with green sea turtles off the coast of Maui.</p>]]><p><b>Hawaii Volcanoes National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the Hawaii Volcanoes National Park (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/havo">www.nps.gov/havo</a>), one of the world's natural wonders. At 4,103m (13,677ft), Mauna Loa is the largest single mountain mass in the world, while at 1,200m (4,000ft), the still-active Kilauea's steaming vents and frequent eruptions provide an unusual (and safe) spectator sport. The volcano is continuously erupting, and lava can be seen hissing into the ocean.&nbsp;</p>]]><p><b>Hawaii by helicopter</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An island helicopter flight (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.helicopters-kauai.com">www.helicopters-kauai.com</a>) is the perfect way to view pristine forests, plunging waterfalls and verdant valleys.</p>]]><p><b>Hawaiian luau festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Join in the festivities of a Hawaiian luau. A whole roast pig is ceremoniously removed from a hot stone cooking pit and served with traditional Hawaiian fare, followed by a Polynesian pageant of authentic hula dancing.</p>]]><p><b>Honolulu Academy of Arts</b></p><![CDATA[<p>View the fine collection of Asian art at the Honolulu Museum of Art (<a href="http://honolulumuseum.org/visit/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">http://honolulumuseum.org</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Honolulu Zoo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the Honolulu Zoo (<a href="http://www.honoluluzoo.org/" target="_blank">www.honoluluzoo.org</a>), home to over 1,230 mammals, birds and reptiles. The zoo is part of Queen Kapiolani Park, where the Honolulu Marathon is concluded annually. The entire 120-hectare (300-acre) park was created by King David Kalakaua in the 1870s and is listed on the state's Historic Register.</p>]]><p><b>Lanai Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Delight in the spectacular natural attractions of Lanai Island (<a href="http://www.lanaicity.com/" target="_blank">www.lanaicity.com</a>), including the dramatic Kaiolohia, also known as Shipwreck Beach, which sports petroglyph rock carvings, and the mystical Garden of the Gods north of Lanai City.</p>]]><p><b>Maui's Ka'eleku Caverns</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover a weird and wonderful collection of rock forms in Maui's Ka'eleku Caverns (<a href="http://www.mauicave.com/" target="_blank">www.mauicave.com</a>), located beneath the Hana Rainforest, where you can take a self-guided tour through this astonishing lavascape.</p>]]><p><b>Molokai Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>On Molokai (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.molokai-hawaii.com/">www.molokai-hawaii.com</a>) there are endless options for adventure.  Visitors love to explore the quaint and colourful shops of the harbour town of Kaunakakai, horseback ride the spectacular coastline, take mule-drawn tours of coffee plantations, or hike the trails to Moaula Falls.</p>]]><p><b>Na Pali Coast</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hike the rugged and beautiful Na Pali Coast on Kauai, and explore secluded coves and idyllic sandy beaches.</p>]]><p><b>Waikiki Beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relax on Waikiki Beach, Oahu, probably the most famous sunning and surfing beach in the world. Learn to surf, parasail, or ride the waves on a surf outrigger or catamaran. If watersports aren&rsquo;t your style, simply laze on the shining sand and people-watch in this tropical paradise.</p>]]><p><b>War memorials</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour Honolulu&rsquo;s National Memorial Cemetery of the Pacific, also known as Punchbowl, a memorial and cemetery for US military veterans (<a href="https://www.cem.va.gov/cems/nchp/nmcp.asp" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.cem.va.gov/</a>). Visit Pearl Harbor (<a href="http://www.pearlharbormemorial.com" target="_blank">www.pearlharbormemorial.com</a>) and the USS Arizona Memorial (<a href="http://www.nps.gov/usar" target="_blank">www.nps.gov/usar</a>), the scene of Japan's surprise attack that brought the USA into WWII. Free boat tours take visitors to the memorial, which spans the wreck of the Battleship Arizona where 1,177 sailors and marines lost their lives.</p>]]><p><b>Wet 'n' Wild Hawaii</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Wet'n' Wild Hawaii (<a href="http://www.wetnwildhawaii.com">www.wetnwildhawaii.com</a>) on the leeward coast of Oahu to enjoy fun for all the family. The 12-hectare (30-acre) water park has waterslides, wave and river rafting pools, a play area, a food court, a video game arcade plus a swimming pool, hot tub, and bar for adults.</p>]]><p><b>Whale watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a whale-watching cruise to Lanai from December to April. Once known as the 'Pineapple Isle,' Lanai is the perfect place for whale watching, as humpback whales make the waters around the island their winter breeding and calving grounds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Hawaiian food offers the best of 'Pacific Rim' and 'New American' cooking styles, influenced by Chinese, Mediterranean, Mexican and other Asian countries. Many dishes are based on chicken, pork, seafood, and local fruit and vegetables cooked using traditional methods. The classic traditional Hawaiian feast is the<em> luau,</em> based around a <em>puaa kalua</em> (whole pig) that has been shaved and rubbed with rock salt on the inside. It is then placed on chicken wire, filled with hot stones from the fire, and cooked in an <em>imu</em> (pit) along with sweet potatoes, plantains, and sometimes <em>laulau</em> (pork, butterfish and spinach-like taro shoots wrapped in leaves and steamed). Served with traditional Hawai'ian <em>poi</em> (thick paste made from ground taro).</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; Local seafood includes <em>moi</em> (mullet) <em>ulua</em>, <em>opakapaka</em> (pink snapper), lobster, yellowfin tuna, and mahi-mahi.<br />
&bull; Hawaiian breakfast specialties include macadamia nuts, and banana and coconut pancakes with coconut syrup. <br />
&bull; Pineapple and other tropical fruit.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>21</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bars and nightclubs abound, especially on Oahu and Maui. Top international stars are booked, whilst <em>luau </em>shows (traditional Hawaiian banquets followed by live performances of music and dancing) are in themselves a great attraction. Jazz, big band music, tea dances, and hula groups are all available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Aloha Tower Marketplace, Royal Hawaiian Shopping Center and the Ala Moana Shopping Center near Waikiki Beach, Honolulu, are popular shopping areas.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-2100. Some shops may open Sun 1000-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hawaii has a wide selection of accommodation choices. The hotels in Hawaii range from historic properties to luxury resorts to charming boutique guesthouses. Cheap accomodations can be found in the spring and autumn.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hawaii has a wide selection of accommodation choices. The hotels in Hawaii range from historic properties to luxury resorts to charming boutique guesthouses. Cheap accomodations can be found in the spring and autumn.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hawaii has a wide selection of accommodation choices. The hotels in Hawaii range from historic properties to luxury resorts to charming boutique guesthouses. Cheap accomodations can be found in the spring and autumn.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[19.542915]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-155.665857]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>16,635 sq km (6,423 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1.4 million (2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>82.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Honolulu.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Hawaii, the majority of residents are Christian; Roman Catholicism and Pentecostalism are the two largest denominations. There are also a fairly large number of Mormon residents and those who affiliate with Eastern religions, such as Buddhism or Hinduism. Only a small number of residents practice the traditional Hawaiian religion originated by the ancient Hawaiians.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><em>Leis</em> are often handed outout, and available on arriving at the airport, as a gesture of &ldquo;aloha,&rdquo; or hello, in Hawaii. They can also be used as congratulations. The gifting of a lei is usually accompanied by a kiss on the cheek.<br />
<br />
It is customary when entering someone&rsquo;s home to remove your shoes and leave them outdoors. Not doing so is considered rude and disrespectful. Similarly, referring to the continental <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> as &ldquo;The States,&rdquo; is also found highly insulting because it implies that Hawaii is not considered a state.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Polynesians were the first to travel to and inhabit Hawaii, though there are several opposing theories about their initial migration. The European discovery of the islands was made by James Cook on his voyage to discover the Northwest Passage, and he dubbed them the Sandwich Islands (after the Earl of Sandwich).<br />
<br />
Hawaii was united in 1810 under Kamehameha the Great, and became known as the Kingdom of Hawaii. Many outside powers influenced the islands during these years, including <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a>, and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">Great Britain</a>.<br />
<br />
In 1875, the Kingdom of Hawaii and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">United States</a> signed the Reciprocity Treaty, which allowed duty free importation of Hawaiian sugar and rice to the US. In exchange the US gained Pearl Harbour and the surrounding 6 km (4 miles), free of cost.<br />
<br />
American and Hawaiian plantation workers revolted against the increasingly unpopular Hawaiian monarchy in 1887 with the assistance of US troops. The revolt resulted in a new constitution, limiting the monarchy&rsquo;s power and lessening its sphere of influence.<br />
<br />
In 1893, the unpopular Queen drafted a new constitution in an attempt to increase her power; meanwhile, a group of residents were plotting to overthrow her reign. The US government sent sailors to impose the Provisional Government of Hawaii to maintain order over the islands once the queen had been dethroned by revolutionaries.<br />
<br />
President William McKinley signed the Newlands Resolution in 1898 which annexed Hawaii, despite opposition from the Japanese and some Amerocans.<br />
<br />
At the start of WWII, the US identified itself as a neutral nation. However, on December 7, 1941, Pearl Harbour was attacked by the Japanese to prevent future US involvement in the Pacific. This surprise assault prompted the US to enter the war on the side of the Allies, the eventual victors.<br />
<br />
Backed by popular support, President Dwight Eisenhower signed Hawaii into statehood in 1959, making it the 50th and final state admitted to the US. Since gaining statehood, Hawaii has become a popular tourist destination known for its good climate, pristine beaches, and phenomenal surfing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Smouldering volcanoes, tropical rainforests, idyllic beaches, legendary surf and blistering sunshine: you need a good excuse <em>not</em> to visit Hawaii.</p>
<p>Oahu, home to the state capital Honolulu, is the most popular island. Big-wave surfing took off here in the 1950s and the pros still pilgrimage to Waimea Bay for its epic swells. You don't have to be a veteran boarder to take advantage of the conditions, though: Waikiki Beach offers an easier ride for those still finding their feet.</p>
<p>The second largest of Hawaii&rsquo;s islands, Maui seems to win every best beach award going. But those looking to sizzle on the sand will struggle to beat Makena Beach, which is a regular Instagram star. If you&rsquo;re not content lounging by the shore, ascend nearby Haleakalā, the island&rsquo;s highest peak, to marvel at some exquisite panoramas.</p>
<p>Just across the water, tiny Lanai&rsquo;s luxury resorts and golf courses may bleed your wallet dry, but go for the day and you can rumble across lunar like landscapes in a 4-wheel drive, gaze at ghostly shipwrecks, and hike through virgin rainforests. Unspoiled Molokai is also a short ferry hop from Maui and lays claim to the world&rsquo;s highest sea cliffs.</p>
<p>Visitors can get as close as they dare to an active volcano on Hawaii Island, where hyperactive Kilauea of Hawaii Volcanoes National Park has been spewing copious amounts of lava every day since 1983.</p>
<p>And then there&rsquo;s Kauai, Hawaii&rsquo;s northernmost island. Offering jagged cliffs, primal rainforests, and barrelling waterfalls, it&rsquo;s paradise for adventure travellers, who can spot green sea turtles off Poipu Beach, hike through Waimea Canyon, and kayak down the raging Waimea River. The only disappointment is leaving.</p><p>Smouldering volcanoes, tropical rainforests, idyllic beaches, legendary surf and blistering sunshine: you need a good excuse <em>not</em> to visit Hawaii.&nbsp;Oahu, home to the state capital Honolulu, is the most popular island. Big-wave surfing took off here in the 1950s and pros still pilgrimage to Waimea Bay for its epic swells. You don't have to be a veteran boarder to take advantage of the conditions, though: Waikiki Beach offers an easier ride for those still finding their feet.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
