<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Tennessee" ColCode="ten" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="tn" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Tennessee]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tennessee has a generally mild climate year round, but still enjoys four distinct seasons. The average high temperature in winter is 9.4°C (49°F) and the average low is -1°C (30°F). In the summer, the average high temperature is 31.7°C (89°F) and the average low is 19.4°C (67°F). The average annual rainfall in Tennessee is 1,247mm (49.7in).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cottons and linens for the summer months and more substantial clothing for the winter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British Airways (BA) connects London with Nashville five times per week.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/tennessee/memphis-international-airport">Memphis International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/tennessee/nashville-international-airport">Nashville International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Memphis International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.mscaa.com<p>Memphis International Airport is located 12km (8 miles) south of central Memphis.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(901) 922 8000.</p>]]><b>Nashville International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.flynashville.com<p>Nashville International Airport is located 13km (8 miles) southeast of Nashville.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 615 275 1675</p>]]><b>Chattanooga Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.chattairport.com]]><b>Tel: </b><b>McGhee Tyson Airport</b><![CDATA[http://tys.org<p>The airport  is located 7.5km (12 miles) south of central Knoxville.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Memphis and Newbern-Dyersberg, on the Chicago-New Orleans line, are the only stations on the national Amtrak rail network (tel: 1 800 872 7245; <a href="http://www.amtrak.com" target="_blank">www.amtrak.com</a>). <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/nashville">Nashville</a> and Chattanooga have connecting Thruway bus services (operated by Greyhound) to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/atlanta">Atlanta</a>, which is on the New Orleans-Washington, DC-New York City route. Car hire is available at the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/memphis">Memphis</a> station. The Tennessee Valley Railroad runs a 10km (6-mile) round trip from Chattanooga.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Beale Street</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See where critics claim that the blues were born, on Beale Street (<a href="http://www.bealestreet.com" target="_blank">www.bealestreet.com</a>) in Memphis. Find restaurants, gift shops, boutiques, parks and nightclubs, as well as the Beale Street Police Museum and A Schwab's Dry Goods Store, a small department store which has been in the same family since 1876 and still offers old-fashioned bargains.</p>]]><p><b>Blount Mansion</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the Blount Mansion (<a href="http://www.blountmansion.org" target="_blank">www.blountmansion.org</a>) in Knoxville, the 1792 frame house of Governor William Blount. The mansion is a National Historic Landmark.</p>]]><p><b>Cumberland Plateau</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the ancient Cumberland Plateau, which forms a natural boundary between Middle and East Tennessee. Waterfalls, deep river canyons, parks and resorts characterise this historic region.</p>]]><p><b>Dollywood</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Die-hard country fans will want to visit this all-American attraction in the Tennessee hills, created by the Queen of Country herself - Dolly Parton. The park's newest attraction is Timber Tower, the first and only ride of its kind in North America.</p>]]><p><b>Gatlinburg</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a trip to Gatlinburg (<a href="http://www.gatlinburg.com" target="_blank">www.gatlinburg.com</a>). At the base of the Great Smoky Mountains, Gatlinburg offers miniature golf courses, haunted houses, restaurants, the Ripley's Aquarium, and more.</p>]]><p><b>Get cultural</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the many galleries and museums which reflect Tennessee's Antebellum and plantation history, including the Carl Van Vechten Gallery in Nashville, which exhibits collections by Cézanne, Picasso and Renoir as well as displays of work by Georgia O'Keeffe and Alfred Steiglitz.</p>]]><p><b>Go wild</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy the bald eagles at Reelfoot Lake (<a href="http://www.reelfootlake.com" target="_blank">www.reelfootlake.com</a>), the recreational opportunities of Kentucky Lake (<a href="http://www.kentuckylake.org" target="_blank">www.kentuckylake.org</a>), or the quiet, sombre atmosphere of the battlefields at Shiloh National Military Park (<a href="http://www.nps.gov/shil" target="_blank">www.nps.gov/shil</a>). Explore the Rock City Gardens (<a href="http://www.seerockcity.com" target="_blank">www.seerockcity.com</a>) in Chattanooga. The subterranean black-lit gnome dioramas and Mother Goose theme areas are constructed around several interesting rock formations.</p>]]><p><b>Grand Ole Opry</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hear good ole country music at the Grand Ole Opry (<a href="http://www.opry.com" target="_blank">www.opry.com</a>) in Nashville. The opry is the setting for the nation's longest-running live radio show, which moved here in 1976 (the original setting, Ryman, has been renovated and is also open to the public) and is the place to hear country music on Friday and Saturday nights.</p>]]><p><b>Jack Daniel Distillery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>View the process of bourbon-making at the famous Jack Daniel Distillery (<a href="http://www.jackdaniels.com" target="_blank">www.jackdaniels.com</a>), 120km (75 miles) southeast of Nashville. Much insight into Mister Jack's famous distilling process is offered during the daily guided tours.</p>]]><p><b>James White's Fort</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Walk through James White's Fort (<a href="http://www.jameswhitesfort.org/" target="_blank">www.jameswhitesfort.org</a>). The fort still exhibits portions of the original stockade built in 1786 by Knoxville's founder.</p>]]><p><b>Nashville</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to 'Music City USA' - Nashville. The centre of Nashville's music industry is Music Row, around Division and Demonbreun streets. Spanning an entire city block, the Country Music Hall of Fame (<a href="http://www.countrymusichalloffame.com" target="_blank">www.countrymusichalloffame.com</a>) is located in the revitalised entertainment district of central Nashville.</p>]]><p><b>Pigeon Forge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Stay in Pigeon Forge (<a href="http://www.mypigeonforge.com" target="_blank">www.mypigeonforge.com</a>). In addition to Dollywood, miniature raceways, arcades, Boyds Bear Country (where you can make your own bear), major shopping outlet malls and more are available. The city celebrates the culture of the East Tennessee mountains and you will find craftspeople demonstrating their skills and selling their wares.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the Incline</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ride the Incline in Chattanooga, which propels its passengers up a stomach-churning gradient of 72.7° - the world's record-holding, steepest passenger railway. The journey is worthwhile, especially on a clear day, when the territories of seven states are visible from Lookout Mountain (www.lookoutmountain.com).  <strong>Spot marine life</strong>View denizens of the deep at the Tennessee Aquarium (<a href="http://www.tennis.org" target="_blank">www.tennis.org</a>) in Chattanooga. The aquarium houses one of the world's largest collections of freshwater marine life.</p>]]><p><b>Ruby Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Experience Chattanooga's Ruby Falls (<a href="http://www.rubyfalls.com" target="_blank">www.rubyfalls.com</a>), a spectacular 44m- (145ft-) high underground waterfall which flows 341m (1120ft) below the surface of Lookout Mountain.</p>]]><p><b>Taste Appalachia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Try the authentic tastes of Appalachia at the Farmer's Market, 24km (15 miles) from downtown Knoxville. The pavilion sells local produce, plants, jams, jellies, arts and crafts.  <strong>Explore the Great Smoky Mountains</strong>The largest wilderness area in the USA, this national park extends over half a million acres of the Appalachian Mountains, bordered by North Carolina and the Tennessee valleys. The park is home to bears, white-tailed deer, wild turkeys and more than 1,500 species of flowering plants. The mountains are beautiful in all seasons, but perhaps the best time to see them is in October when they are showered in colour.  <strong>Pay your respects to the King</strong> Elvis Presley's beloved Memphis home, Graceland (<a href="http://www.elvis.com/graceland" target="_blank">www.elvis.com/graceland</a>), is a Mecca to the pilgrims of rock 'n' roll. The impressive Trophy Room effectively documents his impact on the music industry as a singer and entertainer.</p>]]><p><b>The Delta</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Journey on The Delta, an indoor, quarter-mile river, complete with four 25-passenger flatboats featured inside Nashville's award-winning Opryland Hotel and Convention Center.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businesspeople are generally expected to dress smartly. Western business courtesies should be observed, although Americans tend to be less formal than Europeans. Appointments and punctuality are expected procedure and business cards are widely used. Dates in America are written month-day-year.</p>
<p>Memphis is a friendly, laid-back city and this relaxed attitude often extends into the business world. There are no strict dress codes. At some companies, such as banks and law offices, men are expected to wear suits and ties every day. But in other firms, male employees wear smart-casual clothes, such as polo shirts and chinos. Sandals, shorts or jeans should be avoided, however.</p>
<p>In a city used to seeing entertainment industry folk dressed down, the Nashville approach tends to be more casual. Some meetings will be conducted in jeans, although the city's financial and healthcare executives can be formal. Few restaurants or clubs require a jacket and tie.</p>
<p>Memphis people enjoy a drink, although they avoid consumption at lunchtime. Exceptions are bars and clubs that restrict clientele to over 21 years of age. In Nashville, more formal colleagues will prefer a business lunch to dinner, while in the entertainment industry, a social drink after work would not be out of the ordinary. Southern hospitality may often lead to an invitation to a host's home -an invitation sincerely meant and one that should be gratefully accepted.</p>
<p>Southern states tend to be more conservative than the north, so visitors should limit themselves to moderate social drinking until they know their hosts. Bad language tends to be frowned upon, although again, the music business has its own rules. Courtesies are all-important and &lsquo;Sir' and &lsquo;Ma'am' will be frequently heard. Southerners tend to stick together too and side with fellow Southerners, so visitors should avoid talking about politics until they know whom they are dealing with.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p>Business hours are generally Monday to Friday 0830-1700, although the entertainment businesses usually start and finish later. Breakfast meetings are common, although their timing varies, and the entertainment businesses usually start and finish later. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; Barbecue. <br />&bull; Country ham. <br />&bull; Blackberry cobbler.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Nashville, good venues for live music include Caffé Milano (jazz, bluegrass and rock), Henry's Coffee House, with acoustic performances, and Canyon Country Saloon, which features up-and-coming artists. Lucy's Record Shop sells music during the day, but on Friday and Saturday hosts the latest alternative performers, and the funky Radio Cafe, an old pharmacy, features national artists playing blues, country, jazz and rock. The Nashville Scene or the Tennessean newspapers list all live music events. Memphis has many nightclubs along Beale Street.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pigeon Forge is known for its many major outlet malls. Opry Mills is a shopping and entertainment resort covering more than 304 hectares (750 acres) on the site of former Opryland USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[35.517491]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-86.580447]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>109,150 sq km (42,143 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>6.6 million (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>60.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nashville.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tennessee is Christian country with 82% of the population ascribing to Christianity and Catholicism.  As a part of the Bible belt, religion is particularly important to people. The largest denominations are the Southern Baptist Convention which is headquartered in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/tennessee/nashville-international-airport">Nashville</a>, the United Methodist Church, the Churches of Christ and the Roman Catholic Church.  While a small percentage practice other religions, the largest other affiliation is non-religious at 9%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The unofficial music capital of the world, Tennessee has given rise to many talented musicians ranging from Elvis to Justin Timberlake. Nashville is the birthplace of country music, while <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/tennessee/memphis-international-airport">Memphis</a>, where you can find Presley&rsquo;s Graceland, is the home of blues and jazz. <br />
<br />
Southern hospitality reigns supreme with friendly people and a wide appreciation for sweet tea. It is also the proud purveyor of NASCAR, an annual two-weekend car race. There is a minority Ku Klux Klan presence, as with several southern states.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Inhabited firstly by the Muscogee people and then the Cherokee nation, the area called Tennessee first saw Europeans in the form of Spanish explorers, led by Hernando de Soto in 1540.&nbsp; More expeditions were held in 1559 by Tristan de Luna and 1567 by Juan Pardo.&nbsp; It was Pardo&rsquo;s recording of the name &ldquo;Tanasqui&rdquo; from a local tribal village, that has evolved into the state&rsquo;s current name. <br />
<br />
Europeans began to flow in, bringing with them disease, and the Cherokee population moved south.&nbsp; The settlers then forcibly removed the Muscogee, Yuchi, Chickasaw and Choctaw peoples to make way for their colonies.&nbsp; In 1756, the British established their first settlement, Fort Loudoun, but it wasn&rsquo;t until the late 1760s that permanent European settlers arrived in Tennessee. <br />
<br />
Taking place alongside and after the American Revolutionary War, the Chickamauga Wars saw a warring faction of Cherokee led by Dragging Canoe (who were aligned with British Loyalists) fight for the return of their lands which had been sold illegally in 1775 as part of the Henderson Purchase. Conflict continued until in 1794, at treaty was signed to reaffirm the boundary lines that had been set out in the 1785 Treaty of Hopewell. Two years later, Tennessee was admitted to the Union, becoming the 16th state.<br />
<br />
With statehood came more woe for the Cherokees residing in the area.&nbsp; Between 1838 and 1839, nearly 17,000 Cherokees and around 2,000 of their slaves were uprooted and forcibly marched to emigration depots, to be moved west of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/arkansas">Arkansas</a>.&nbsp; It is estimated that 4,000 Cherokee died along the way and the march is remembered as Nunna daul Isunyi &ndash; The Trail Where We Cried. The Trail of Tears is used to describe many of the forced emigrations across America around this time. <br />
<br />
During the American Civil War, Tennessee sided with the Confederates, and it became a site for many major battles. Whilst the Union won most of the battles in Tennessee, it was held by Confederates until 1864, when President Abraham Lincoln appointed Andrew Johnson military governor of the state. &nbsp;<br />
<br />
Since it was held by Union forces, Tennessee was not included in the Emancipation Proclamation, so no slaves were freed. However slaves who escaped to the Union lines gained freedom, and many went on to join the fighting on the Union side.&nbsp; In 1865, slavery was officially prohibited in Tennessee. That year also saw the explosion of the SS Sultana, a steamboat on the Mississippi River, the greatest maritime disaster in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> history.<br />
<br />
Despite the ending of slavery, Tennessee, controlled by White Democrats in the 1880s, continued to pass restrictive laws, preventing African Americans from voting and enjoying other civil liberties and essentially disenfranchising them. In 1920 Tennessee became the 36th and final state to give women the vote.&nbsp; However, poll taxes and registration requirements still kept African Americans and poor men and women off the voter rolls. It wasn&rsquo;t until after the passage of national civil rights legislation in the 1960s that all citizens were afforded an equal opportunity to vote.<br />
<br />
With the Great Depression bearing down upon the US and the majority of the population out of work, the government created the Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) in 1933, leading to Tennessee becoming the largest public utility supplier in the nation. This resulted in the Manhattan Project (the government programme which developed the first atomic bombs) using Tennessee as one of the principal sites for production of fissile material. <br />
<br />
Tennessee&rsquo;s current economy relies on the output of textiles, cotton, cattle and electrical power.&nbsp; Agriculture is prominent and over half of the state&rsquo;s farms accommodate beef cattle. Tennessee has yet to ratify same-sex marriage and is considered conservative.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Boot-stomping music lures you to Tennessee, but if you manage to tear yourself away from a never-ending roster of stellar gigs, there&rsquo;s no shortage of alternative entertainment.</p>
<p>First though, cast your peepers over an incredible line-up of 2 million artefacts at the snazzy Country Music Hall of Fame in Nashville, which boasts its own songwriting stations where you can pen a tune of your own.</p>
<p>Hit Beale Street in Memphis, home of the blues and the birthplace of rock 'n' roll, where the likes of BB King and Isaac Hayes have wowed audiences. Or visit Bristol in September for the phenomenal Rhythm &amp; Roots Reunion, three days of electrifying musical magic. Be sure to visit the fabulous Birthplace of Country Music Museum while in town.</p>
<p>Powerful as Tennessee&rsquo;s musical roots are however, be bold and dip your toes into something different. Arrive in Knoxville in summer, and you can chuck a blanket on the grass for an evening of Shakespeare, gratis. Cruise round the 13km (8mile) Gatlinburg loop and stuff your suitcases with stained glass, jewellery and watercolours produced by the Great Smoky Arts &amp; Crafts Community, the continent&rsquo;s largest group of independent artisans.</p>
<p>Soar like an eagle on a 21-storey-high rollercoaster at Dollywood, roar like a bear at a Memphis Grizzlies home game or follow in the footsteps of Native Americans and Civil War soldiers along legendary trail Natchez Trace.</p>
<p>Whatever you do, you&rsquo;ll find Tennessee to be one big adventure playground, encompassing forested mountains, cypress swamps, white-water rapids and cascading waterfalls. The Great Smoky National Park alone racks up 1,300km (800 miles) of hiking trails (and 1,500 bears). Humming Elvis as you hike is entirely optional.</p><p>Boot-stomping music lures you to Tennessee, but if you manage to tear yourself away from a never-ending roster of stellar gigs, there&rsquo;s no shortage of alternative entertainment. First though, cast your peepers over an incredible line-up of 2 million artefacts at the snazzy Country Music Hall of Fame in Nashville, which boasts its own songwriting stations where you can pen a tune of your own.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
