<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Colorado" ColCode="crd" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="co" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Colorado]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The capital, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/denver">Denver</a>,&nbsp;has a mild, dry climate with an average of 300 sunny days a year. Spring is mild, with warm days and cool evenings; summer has very warm days with low humidity and cool evening breezes. Denver often enjoys an Indian Summer right into November, while winter is cold, sunny, and crisp, with an average snowfall of 1,397mm (55 inches). The mountains boast warm summer days with cool evenings.  Autumn arrives early in the high ground, with abundant snowfall from December to April and temperatures around freezing point.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Extra warm clothing, especially in the mountains, from November to March/April. Cottons and linens during the summer months, and usually a light jacket at night.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Holidaymakers can fly from Denver International Airport to 12 other smaller airports within the state.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Amtrak's California Zephyr line from Chicago to California makes a stop in Denver and passes through other tourist spots in Colorado, including Fort Morgan, Fraser, Granby, Glenwood Springs and Grand Junction.<br />
<br />
The state also has nine scenic rail journeys, including the Cripple Creek and Victor Narrow Gauge Railroad, a family-owned railway through several old mining sites and the gold-rush town of Cripple Creek. Another favourite is the Cumbres &amp; Tolec Scenic Railroad, which is USA's longest and highest narrow-gauge line in North America, stretching 103km (64 miles) from Antonito, Colorado to Chama, New Mexico.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/colorado/denver-international-airport">Denver International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/colorado/colorado-springs-airport">Colorado Springs Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/denver">Denver</a> is 10 hours, and from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> is 4 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Denver International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.flydenver.com<p>Denver International Airport is located 40km (25 miles) northeast of Denver.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 303 342 2000</p>]]><b>Colorado Springs Airport</b><![CDATA[https://flycos.coloradosprings.gov<p>Colorado Springs Airport is located 10km (6 miles) southeast of central Colorado Springs.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 719 550 1900</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Denver's growth is historically linked to its importance as a rail centre. It is a hub on the major Amtrak east-west route (tel: +1 800 872 7245, in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> only; <a href="http://www.amtrak.com/" target="_blank">www.amtrak.com</a>), with daily services to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/chicago">Chicago</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/san-francisco">San Francisco</a> on the 'California Zephyr.' Westbound trains pass through Glenwood Canyon, which is one of the most beautiful railway routes in the USA. The 'Southwest Chief,' which links Chicago with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/los-angeles">Los Angeles</a>, passes through the southeast corner of the State, where a bus link to Denver is available. The Amtrak Winter Park Express (tel: +1 888 923 7275;<a href="https://www.amtrak.com/" target="_blank">www.amtrak.com/</a>) makes a scenic two-hour journey through the Rockies to the Winter Park Ski Resort on weekends during the skiing season, January 5th-March 25th, 2018. <br />
<br />
<strong>Approximate rail journey times:</strong><br />
From Denver to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/salt-lake-city">Salt Lake City</a> is 15 hours 30 minutes, to Chicago is 19 hours and to San Francisco is 34 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>16th Street Mall</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the 16th Street Mall, a tree-lined promenade in the heart of Denver, running between the city&rsquo;s Downtown and Union Station. Popular among shoppers, it is always bustling with pedestrians, cafes, street performers, and fountains.</p>]]><p><b>American football</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cheer for a classic American football team, the Denver Broncos (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.denverbroncos.com/">www.denverbroncos.com</a>), to victory at the Sports AuthorityField, Mile High Stadium.</p>]]><p><b>Colorado National Monument</b></p><![CDATA[<p>View the plains from Colorado National Monument (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/colm">www.nps.gov/colm</a>), west of Grand Junction<strong>,</strong> an area of fantastic red rock canyons, monoliths, pillars and cliffs. Dinosaur National Monument (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/dino">www.nps.gov/dino</a>) in Colorado's northwest corner, is a plateau cut by two rivers and home to one of the world's richest deposits of dinosaur and reptile fossils.</p>]]><p><b>Colorado State Capitol</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Behold the Denver skyline from the Colorado State Capitol Building, with its spectacular genuine gold roof and sweeping views over the city and the Rockies.</p>]]><p><b>Coors Brewery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the Coors Brewery at Golden and sample the famous beer made from Rocky Mountain spring water (<a href="http://visitgolden.com/coors-brewery/" target="_blank">visitgolden.com</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Flora and fauna</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wander through the Denver Botanic Gardens (<a href="http://www.botanicgardens.org/" target="_blank">www.botanicgardens.org</a>), boasting water gardens, a Japanese garden, a rock alpine garden and conservatory housing a collection of orchids and bromeliads.</p>]]><p><b>Garden of the Gods</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hike, bike or horse ride around the dramatically sculpted red sandstone pinnacles of the Garden of the Gods (<a href="http://www.gardenofgods.com/" target="_blank">www.gardenofgods.com</a>), a National Natural Monument.</p>]]><p><b>Glenwood Springs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Soak in the world's largest natural hot springs pool at Glenwood Springs (<a href="http://www.hotspringspool.com/" target="_blank">www.hotspringspool.com</a>), surrounded by soaring mountain peaks.</p>]]><p><b>Great Sand Dunes National Monument</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the Great Sand Dunes National Monument (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/grsa">www.nps.gov/grsa</a>), with some of the highest inland sand dunes in North America.</p>]]><p><b>Native Indian homes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour Indian cliff dwellings in Mesa Verde National Park (<a href="http://www.nps.gov/meve" target="_blank">www.nps.gov/meve</a>), in the high plateau country of southwestern Colorado, 56km (35 miles) west of Durango. The 21,044-hectare (52,000-acre) park, a World Heritage Site, contains dramatic Anasazi culture's cliff dwellings built over 700 years ago.</p>]]><p><b>Rocky Mountain National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Rocky Mountain National Park (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/romo">www.nps.gov/romo</a>) and the resort village of Estes Park (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.estesparkresort.com/">www.estesparkresort.com</a>). The Trail Ridge Road, one of the highest continuous highways in North America, traverses this breathtaking landscape, strung with massive peaks, rugged canyons, flower-strewn meadows, peaceful lakes and thundering waterfalls.</p>]]><p><b>Santa Fe Trail</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Follow the path of early traders and stagecoaches along the Santa Fe Trail (<a href="http://www.santafetrailco.com" target="_blank">www.santafetrailco.com</a>), now designated a National Historic Trail, which is dotted with historic trading posts. Along the way, step back in time by exploring St Elmo's, Colorado's best preserved ghost town built around a mining camp in Chalk Creek Canyon.</p>]]><p><b>Scenic drives</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Drive the Black Canyon of the Gunnison National Park (<a href="http://www.nps.gov/blca" target="_blank">www.nps.gov/blca</a>). It preserves the most spectacular 19km (12-mile) stretch of the 85km (53-mile) gorge carved by the Gunnison River. A paved road circles the rim of the canyon, at some points nearly half a mile deep.</p>]]><p><b>See Colorado by rail</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Travel on the Manitou &amp; Pikes Peak Cog Railway (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.cograilway.com/">www.cograilway.com</a>), which offers views of the Continental Divide from the 4,302m (14,115ft) summit of Pikes Peak. Or head to Ca&ntilde;on City, where you can ride the scenic Royal Gorge Railway in Ca&ntilde;on City (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.canoncitycolorado.com">www.canoncitycolorado.com</a>), and then experience the thrill of whitewater rafting down the Arkansas River.</p>]]><p><b>Skiing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Rocky Mountains (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/romo">www.nps.gov/romo</a>) are renowned the world over for unparalleled skiing, quaint mountain towns, world-class accommodation and spectacular scenery. Aspen (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.aspenchamber.org/">www.aspenchamber.org</a>) is America's most sophisticated ski resort, offering a full range of winter and summer activities and countless restaurants and shops.&nbsp;Winter sports also abound  in Summit County, home to the popular ski resorts of Arapahoe Basin (<a href="http://www.arapahoebasin.com" target="_blank">www.arapahoebasin.com</a>), Copper Mountain (<a href="http://www.coppercolorado.com" target="_blank">www.coppercolorado.com</a>),  Breckenridge (<a href="http://www.breckenridge.com" target="_blank">www.breckenridge.com</a>), and Keystone (<a href="http://www.keystoneresort.com" target="_blank">www.keystoneresort.com</a>), which offers the longest ski season in the state,</p>]]><p><b>Steamboat Springs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Try your hand at fly fishing, float over mountain vistas in a hot air balloon, or go tubing on the Yampa River: all these adventures are waiting in the popular western-style town of Steamboat Springs (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.steamboat-chamber.com/">www.steamboat-chamber.com</a>). In winter, hit the ski slopes for unforgettable champagne powder snow.</p>]]><p><b>US Mint</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the US Mint, the second-largest storehouse of gold bullion in the USA after Fort Knox in Kentucky (<a target="_blank" href="https://www.usmint.gov/about/mint-tours-facilities/denver" rel="nofollow">www.usmint.gov</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>There are restaurants offering Asian cuisine, innovative New Southwestern cuisine, and international fare in every price range. For a distinctly Colorado-style meal, visitors can visit Denver, Boulder or any large mountain town for freshly brewed local beer and delicious food.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; Fresh rainbow trout.<br />
&bull; Buffalo and elk steaks.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Denver Performing Arts Complex houses seven theatres ten performance spaces,&nbsp;including the Boettcher Concert Hall (<a href="http://www.artscomplex.com" target="_blank">www.artscomplex.com</a>). Among the other varied entertainments in the city are a number of smaller venues staging performances of theatre, dance, comedy, and music ranging from jazz to country to western. The vibrant nightlife scene features something for everyone (<a href="http://www.denver.com/nightlife" target="_blank">www.denver.com/nightlife</a>). For detailed information on scheduled events, visitors can consult The <em>Denver Post </em>or the <em>Rocky Mountain News</em>. Beyond city limits, any of the ski resorts, notably Aspen and Vail, have countless restaurants, bars and other<strong> </strong>apr&egrave;s-ski diversions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shopping opportunities in Denver are extensive. Cherry Creek Shopping Center, the Denver Pavillions  on 16th Street Mall, Park Meadows Center (the first shopping centre in the USA that resembles a beautiful mountain lodge) and Larimer Square all offer a pleasant shopping environment.  </p>
<p>Colorado now has three factory outlet shopping centres: Castle Rock, situated 30 minutes south of Denver, Silverthorne in Summit County, and Rocky Mountain Factory Outlets in Loveland. There is also a number of other great places to shop scattered around the state.  The Colorado Mills complex in Lakewood, near Denver, has been described as 'Disneyland meets outlet mall.' The city of Aspen in the Rocky Mountains has an unsurpassed range of shops and upmarket boutiques selling top designer lines. Special buys in Colorado include gold earrings and necklaces, Native American jewellery, Navajo rugs and handicrafts such as pottery, wind chimes and wildlife sculptures.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From 5-star hotels to mountain resorts to historic bed and breakfast or rustic ski lodges, the range of hotels in Colorado will suit every interest. At the top end, luxury hotels can be found by the state's golf courses or within spa resorts. Top hotels are also available near Colorado's hot springs, particularly in Glenwood Springs and Pagosa Springs. If you're looking for cheap hotels in Colorado, there are a number of bed and breakfast options available too.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From 5-star hotels to mountain resorts to historic bed and breakfast or rustic ski lodges, the range of hotels in Colorado will suit every interest. At the top end, luxury hotels can be found by the state's golf courses or within spa resorts. Top hotels are also available near Colorado's hot springs, particularly in Glenwood Springs and Pagosa Springs. If you're looking for cheap hotels in Colorado, there are a number of bed and breakfast options available too.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From 5-star hotels to mountain resorts to historic bed and breakfast or rustic ski lodges, the range of hotels in Colorado will suit every interest. At the top end, luxury hotels can be found by the state's golf courses or within spa resorts. Top hotels are also available near Colorado's hot springs, particularly in Glenwood Springs and Pagosa Springs. If you're looking for cheap hotels in Colorado, there are a number of bed and breakfast options available too.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[39.550051]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-105.782067]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>269,600 sq km (104,093 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>5.5 million (2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>19.9 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Denver.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Christianity is the most popular religion in Colorado, with the majority of the population being Roman Catholic, followed by Baptist. There are also small populations of Jews, Mormons, and Muslims, among other religions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many residents are quite laid back and enjoy nature, which has contributed to the often-resented concept of Colorado as a haven for &ldquo;hippies.&rdquo; In the 2012 election, Colorado voted to legalise recreational marijuana use for adults, further contributing to the &ldquo;hippie&rdquo; stereotype.</p>
<p>  A large ski culture exists in Colorado, revolving around the Rockies and the countless ski resorts in the state. Residents are often given discounts on lift passes and season passes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Long before any Europeans set food in the New World, Colorado was inhabited by various Native American tribes including the Arapaho, Apache, Ute and Cheyenne.<br />
<br />
Spanish explorers were the first Europeans to work their way to present-day Colorado, though they never formed any long lasting settlements in the area. A permanent settlement wasn&rsquo;t established until trading posts were created by traders and trappers along the Arkansas River in the mid-19th century.<br />
<br />
When the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> won the Mexican-American War in 1848, the southern portion of the Rocky Mountains (including parts of Colorado) were opened for American settlement. The first permanent European town, San Luis, was established by Hispanic settlers in 1851. <br />
<br />
Like many other territories in the region, Colorado witnessed a population boom in the wake of the California Gold Rush in 1849 and 1850. Initially, no gold was found in Colorado and gold seekers overlooked this state for the western coast. Those who stayed however, had their patience rewarded, as in 1859 gold was found, along with silver and minerals, throughout the Rocky Mountains. <br />
<br />
The Territory of Colorado was created in 1861. Until that point, modern day Colorado had been divided between the territories of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/kansas">Kansas</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-mexico">New Mexico</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/utah">Utah</a>, and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/nevada">Nevada</a>. Colorado became the 38th state after President Ulysses S. Grant signed the territory into statehood in 1876. <br />
<br />
As the 19th century progressed, Colorado became one of the major mining hubs of the US. Silver, gold, and mineral mining was rich throughout the state, and the continued discovery of gold fields drew people, goods, and services from far and wide. Due to Colorado&rsquo;s wealth in metals, the US Treasury established a money mint in the capital, Denver, in 1906; it is still in operation today.</p>
<p>In the 20th century, the mining boom died down as deposits of metals and minerals dwindled across Colorado. The state&rsquo;s focus shifted to manufacturing and industry to boost the economy, and a huge influx of workers flowed into the state&rsquo;s growing cities. Today, Colorado is one of the US&rsquo;s best states for business, home to federal facilities, a booming agricultural industry, and a rich industrial industry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Prepare for epic mountain ranges, great plains, enchanting national parks, ancient ruins, lively cities, and lavish ski resorts: Colorado will knock your socks off. Known as the Centennial State, Colorado is perhaps most famous for its beautiful Rocky Mountains, which are quite literally the backbone of the state.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Colorado&rsquo;s capital, Denver, is a city you wish you could move to, set upon high rolling plains with a spectacular mountain backdrop. It&rsquo;s home to a buzzing arts scene and beautifully restored Victorian architecture. But if you think Denver is cool, wait until you visit hip-and-happening Boulder. Here you can hike towards the famous Flatirons that overlook the city, chill out in one of the city&rsquo;s parks or caf&eacute;s, cycle around like a local, enjoy a night out on the Hill amid partying students, or take in one of many film and music festivals.</p>
<p>For pure luxury, grab your platinum card and head to Aspen. Beloved retreat of A-list celebrities and the ultra-wealthy, Aspen boasts first-class ski lodges, luxurious shopping and dining, and a beautiful, redbrick downtown area. If Aspen is a bit too exclusive (or expensive), try Telluride, a picturesque, Old West town turned outdoor Mecca. Ski down fluffy powder in winter, then hike, bike and raft to your heart&rsquo;s content in summer.</p>
<p>Colorado&rsquo;s national parks are equally exhilarating. The must-see Rocky Mountain National Park crams in colossal peaks, lush green forests, glistening lakes, and endless meadows. Mesa Verde&rsquo;s impeccably preserved ancestral Pueblo cliff dwellings are a sight to behold, while the mesmerising high desert of Great Sand Dunes National Park can&rsquo;t fail to impress.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p><p>Prepare for epic mountain ranges, great plains, enchanting national parks, ancient ruins, lively cities, and lavish ski resorts: Colorado will knock your socks off. Known as the Centennial State, Colorado is perhaps most famous for its beautiful Rocky Mountains, which are quite literally the backbone of the state.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
