<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="California" ColCode="cal" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ca" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[California]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Summers are very warm, with cool evenings, while the spring and autumn months are mild, with cool evenings. The winter 'rainy season' is gentle and occurs between January and March. Much of the state has a Mediterranean climate, with hot, dry summers and mild, rainy winters. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/san-francisco">San Francisco</a> is known for its characteristic fog in spring and early summer. Northern California and the high mountains have snow in winter, while the deserts experience very hot summers and mild winters.</p>
<p>For the best skiing in Lake Tahoe, the end of January and the beginning of February offer good snow and a break from the swelling crowds at Christmas and through mid-January. For prime sunny beach weather in Southern California, July and August offer lots of sun and heat, but there will be crowds. Avoid the &ldquo;May Gray&rdquo; and &ldquo;June Gloom,&rdquo; which bring a low-lying marine layer of clouds over the coastline for most of the day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight during the summer with warmer wear for the cooler winter period. Hiking boots and gear are needed for more adventurous mountain climbing and hiking in Yosemite and parts of Joshua Tree. Skiing in Lake Tahoe is warmer than most mountains, so dress in layers, and don't be surprised to see skiers show-off in t-shirts.<br/>
Beachwear is acceptable in restaurants and shops near the beach, but shirts and shoes are required by law. Men should not wear shorts away from the beach. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/los-angeles">Los Angeles</a> is a fashion-conscious city, especially for women and dressier clothes are required for many nightclubs and restaurants. Men don't have to wear formal suits, but shirts and trousers are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>California is the third largest state in USA and has more than 15 international and commuters airports, with many scheduled and low cost carriers linking cities across the state. Southwest airlines (<a href="http://www.southwest.com" target="_blank">www.southwest.com</a>) flies to nine airports across the state, whilst Jet Blue airlines (<a href="http://www.jetblue.com" target="_blank">www.jetblue.com</a>) flies to nine airports across California.</p><p>Flying from southern to northern California is advisable to save time but not necessary. Rates generally remain the same throughout the year, though deals can be booked in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the Los Angeles area, the Catalina Express (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.catalinaexpress.com">www.catalinaexpress.com</a>) is a daily, low-fare cruise service from Long Beach to Catalina Island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Amtrak (tel: +1 800 872 7245; <a href="http://www.amtrak.com" target="_blank">www.amtrak.com</a>) offers three key scenic rail routes through California. They include: the Pacific Surfliner route connecting San Diego, Los Angeles, Oxnard, Santa Barbara, and San Luis Obispo; the Capitol Corridor linking the Sierra foothills, Sacramento, the San Francisco Bay Area and Silicon Valley and San Joaquin which slices its way from Bakersfield through Fresno to the Bay Area. Amtrak also offers four routes that travel out of state.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The California Rail Pass allows 7 days of travel within a 21-day period. For further information about routes, prices and timetables see Amtrack (<a href="http://www.amtrak.com" target="_blank">www.amtrak.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving in California can be a pleasurable activity along the famously beautiful Highway 1, or an exercise in frustration in Los Angeles at rush hour.</p>r<p>The roads and highways are well maintained. Driving around California is simple, thanks to its network of interstates and highways.</p><p>Greyhound (<a href="http://www.greyhound.com" target="_blank">www.greyhound.com</a>) historically offers the most destinations for the best price, but the buses are not always pleasant or comfortable.</p><p>Taxis are available on the street in major cities. The safe ones licensed by the state are yellow and have meters but can be expensive for long drives.</p><p>Foreign drivers need a valid driver's license and proof of ownership or permission to drive a rental car.</p><p>California takes driving laws very seriously and violators will be ticketed for speeding, driving without a seatbelt, or using a mobile phone while driving. Drink driving penalties are also severe. Drive on the right hand side of the road.</p><p>Dial 911 for all emergencies.</p><p>Minimum age for hirers is 25. You need a valid driver's licence, a passport (for non-US citizens) and a credit card for a security deposit. Alamo, Budget, Thrifty and Dollar are among the wealth of car hire companies in California. The hire of self-drive campers or motorhomes is also recommended.</p><p>Most of the major cities have numerous bike rental facilities, with Los Angeles, San Diego, and San Francisco offering dedicated cycling paths.</p><p>California takes driving laws very seriously and violators will be ticketed for speeding, driving without a seatbelt, or using a mobile phone while driving. Drink driving penalties are also severe. Drive on the right hand side of the road.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Los Angeles and San Francisco both have subway and light rail networks. Metrolink commuter rail covers large swathes of Southern California, while BART and Caltrain commuter rail link the Bay Area suburbs to San Francisco. San Jose and Sacramento have light rail, and San Diego has a Trolley light rail system. The majority of counties and cities operate their own bus lines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of flights to California are operated by US carriers JetBlue Airlines (<a href="http://www.jetblue.com" target="_blank">www.jetblue.com</a>), American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>), Delta Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.delta.com">www.delta.com</a>) and United Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.united.com">www.united.com</a>).
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/los-angeles-international-airport">Los Angeles International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/san-diego-international-airport">San Diego International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/oakland-international-airport">Oakland International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/san-francisco-international-airport">San Francisco International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/burbank-bob-hope-airport">Burbank Bob Hope Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/ontario-international-airport">LA/Ontario  international Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/san-jose-mineta-san-jose-international-airport">Norman Y Mineta San Jose International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/john-wayne-airport-orange-county">John Wayne Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/palm-springs-international-airport">Palm Springs International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/sacramento-international-airport">Sacramento International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/los-angeles">Los Angeles</a> is 11 hours 15 minutes. To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/san-francisco">San Francisco</a> from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> is 5 hours 50 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rules and regulations for flights in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">United States</a> are more strict than those in Europe. Check the TSA website (<a href="http://www.tsa.gov" target="_blank">www.tsa.gov</a>) for specific advice on what is and isn&rsquo;t allowed onboard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rules and regulations for flights in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">United States</a> are more strict than those in Europe. Check the TSA website (<a href="http://www.tsa.gov" target="_blank">www.tsa.gov</a>) for specific advice on what is and isn&rsquo;t allowed onboard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Hollywood Burbank Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.bobhopeairport.com<p>Hollywood Burbank Airport is located 5km (3 miles) northwest of Burbank and 20km (12 miles) north of Los Angeles.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 818 840 8840</p>]]><b>Los Angeles International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.flylax.com/<p>Los Angeles International Airport is located 32km (20 miles) southwest of downtown Los Angeles.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 855 463 5252</p>]]><b>Oakland International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.oaklandairport.com<p>Oakland International Airport is located 8km (5 miles) southeast of the city of Oakland, in the US state of California.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 510 563 3300</p>]]><b>LA/Ontario International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.lawa.org<p>LA/Ontario International Airport is located 55km (35 miles) east of central Los Angeles and 30km (18 miles) west of San Bernardino.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 909 937 2700</p>]]><b>San Diego International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.san.org<p>San Diego International Airport is located 3km (2 miles) northwest of San Diego, in southwest California.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 619 400 2404</p>]]><b>San Francisco International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.flysfo.com<p>San Francisco International Airport is located 22km (14 miles) south of downtown San Francisco.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 650 821 8211.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>California&rsquo;s entire western border is the Pacific Ocean with major ports in Los Angeles, Long Beach, and San Diego. See <a href="http://www.portoflosangeles.org" target="_blank">www.portoflosangeles.org</a> for further information.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Amtrak (tel: +1 800 872 7245; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.amtrak.com/">www.amtrak.com</a>) terminal in Los Angeles is Union Station, at 800 North Alameda Street, on the edge of the business district. It is at the western end of several major routes across the southern Rockies, is the southern terminus of the West Coast line to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/seattle">Seattle</a> (although there are frequent shuttle services heading further south to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/san-diego">San Diego</a>), and at the western end of east-west routes from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/chicago">Chicago</a>, St Louis and New Orleans. <br />
<br />
In San Francisco, the Embarcadero BART station and the Transbay Transit Terminal, at 200 Folsom Street, are used only for limited suburban services. The Amtrak Terminal at Emeryville, across the Bay, is the central node on the West Coast line and also the western terminus of a line running across the high Rockies to Salt Lake City and beyond. Amtrak<em> </em>provides free shuttles between their Oakland station and the Transbay Terminal. <br />
<br />
San Diego is served by Amtrak<em> </em>trains from Los Angeles, with its Santa Fe Depot&nbsp;station located downtown on 1050 Kettner Boulevard and its Old Town Transit Center situated on 4005 Taylor Street.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>California is easily accessed by road from surrounding states and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mexico">Mexico</a> via the John J. Mongtomery freeway (Interstate 5). Greyhound bus service (tel: +1 214 849 8100; <a href="http://www.greyhound.com" target="_blank">www.greyhound.com</a>) has several daily departures.</p><p>Drivers with international licenses are legally allowed to drive in California.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Yosemite National Park</p><![CDATA[<p>Designated a national park in 1890, Yosemite National Park stretches along California&rsquo;s eastern flank and covers almost 3108 sq kilometres (1200 sq miles) of alpine meadows, rivers, lakes, cliffs and waterfalls in the central Sierra Nevada mountain range. The park is well known for its giant sequoia trees, particularly in Mariposa Grove where some of the trees are over 3000 years old and reach 80m (219ft) in height. Until 1969, when the tree fell during a heavy storm, it was possible to drive through the 3.4-metre (11.2-foot) tunnel carved through the trunk of the famous Wawona Tunnel Tree. <br />
<br />
Other scenic highlights include Yosemite Falls, which cascade 739m (2425ft) into the valley below and Glacier Point, which offers spectacular views of the park. The area is also home to abundant wildlife and provides a natural habitat for approximately 250 species of bird, 80 species of mammal &ndash; including black bears, squirrels and chipmunks &ndash; and 24 species of amphibian and reptile. Visitors can stay at lodges and campsites situated around the park and enjoy activities such as hiking, fishing, climbing, horseriding and cross-country skiing.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Alcatraz</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Try to escape from Alcatraz (<a href="https://www.nps.gov/alca" target="_blank">www.nps.gov/alca</a>), once the site of the USA's toughest maximum security prison and now a national park built on an isolated island in the San Francisco Bay. Alcatraz offers a close-up look at the infamous federal penitentiary via an audio tour, walking tour, and lectures by historians. Ferries depart regularly for the island but bear in mind the only way to get to Alcatraz is by a ferry operated by Alcatraz Cruises, LLC. They're located on Pier 33 in San Francisco. Nighttime tours sell out quickly but add a spooky element to the island.</p>]]><p><b>Ancient forests</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In Sequoia and Kings Canyon National Parks (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/seki">www.nps.gov/seki</a>), famed for their forests of giant sequoia trees, see the 2,500-year-old General Sherman Tree Giant Forest, the largest tree in the world (by volume) with a circumference of 31m (103ft). Kings Canyon is the deepest canyon in the USA. Joshua Tree National Park was named as a National Monument in 1936. The Park is 234,000 acres of protected wilderness with a variety of hiking trails for beginners and experts, campgrounds, two deserts, and mountain ranges. Geologists believe the area is over a million years old. Joshua Trees themselves are giant members of the lily family. Bobcats, coyotes, and roadrunners call the park home.</p>]]><p><b>Beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>La Jolla is one of San Diego&rsquo;s best and most popular beaches. Somewhat protected from the prevailing southwest wind, it's a safe, gentle spot to learn or enjoy surfing. Most of the formal surf schools operate here for this reason, and a lot of local kids practice their basics at the Shores before graduating to bigger and better breaks.&nbsp; Laguna Beach (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.lagunabeachinfo.org/">www.lagunabeachinfo.org</a>), is the 'Riviera of the West Coast' and jewel of Southern Californian beach cities. This charming seaside village is filled with bistros, shops and art galleries, including the famous Laguna Art Museum. Other famous beaches in California include Malibu,where you can enjoy the picturesque coves, or Marina del Rey (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.visitthemarina.com">www.visitthemarina.com</a>) for those wanting to admire the flocks of sailboats. Venice Beach (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.venicebeach.com">www.venicebeach.com</a>) is an eclectic mix of skaters, street performers and buzzing crowds.</p>]]><p><b>Big Sur coastal highway</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Drive the ruggedly beautiful Big Sur coastal highway (<a href="http://www.bigsurcalifornia.org/" target="_blank">www.bigsurcalifornia.org</a>) south of San Francisco. Visit the quaint historic coastal towns of Carmel and Monterey, and eat fresh seafood in waterfront restaurants. Be sure to pull over at one of the lookouts or beaches and scan the sky for California condors and the water for gray whales. Renting a convertible for the picturesque trip is highly recommended.</p>]]><p><b>Cannery Row and Old Fisherman's Wharf</b></p><![CDATA[<p>View the famous 1920s sardine factory, Cannery Row (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.canneryrow.com/">www.canneryrow.com</a>) and Old Fisherman's Wharf (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.montereywharf.com/">www.montereywharf.com</a>) in historic Monterey. Sample the traditional clam chowder and sourdough bread. See where John Steinbeck found inspiration for many of his classic works and look for seals sunning on the rocks. Be sure to sample at least one bowl of clam chowder.</p>]]><p><b>Clear Lake</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fish for bass at Clear Lake (<a href="http://www.lakecounty.com/" target="_blank">www.lakecounty.com</a>), the largest natural freshwater lake in California, known as the 'bass capital of the world.' Clear Lake is one of the most ancient lakes in California, at approximately 2.5 million years old, and has over 160km (100 miles) of shoreline. Attend a local festival, or go waterskiing, fishing, swimming, boating, cycling, birdwatching or rock collecting.</p>]]><p><b>Disneyland</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Experience the magic of Disneyland (<a href="http://www.disney.go.com/" target="_blank">www.disney.go.com</a>) where the imagination is the destination. Become a kid again in an enchanted kingdom home to Mickey Mouse and all of the famous Disney Characters. Restaurants, shopping, shows, and one-of-a-kind rides are fun for kids of all ages and adults who are really kids at heart.</p>]]><p><b>Hearst Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Hearst Castle (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.hearstcastle.org/">www.hearstcastle.org</a>) built by newspaper magnate William Randolph Hearst on an enchanted hill overlooking the Pacific Ocean. The property is 40,000 acres of ranch land that includes three guest houses, a renowned European and Mediterranean art collection, magnificent gardens and pools, and an abandoned zoo. Hearst Castle is one of America's greatest palaces.</p>]]><p><b>Hiking</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hike or camp in Yosemite National Park (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.yosemitepark.com">www.yosemitepark.com</a>), which contains the world's best-known glacier-carved valley, spectacular waterfalls, granite monoliths and the Mariposa Grove of Giant Sequoias. Hike or rock climb the eerily remote Joshua Tree National Park (<a target="_blank" href="https://www.nps.gov/jotr">www.nps.gov/jotr</a>). Cross the Mojave Desert to Death Valley (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/deva">www.nps.gov/deva</a>), the hottest and lowest place in the continental United States at 86m (282 ft) below sea level.</p>]]><p><b>Hollywood</b></p><![CDATA[<p>View the famous Hollywood sign in the hills above the city. Film crews can be found on location all over the region, though most of the filming happens behind the well-guarded gates of the various studios scattered across the city. See which celebrity handprints fit yours at The Hollywood Walk of Fame or hop on a guided bus tour to see where the movie stars live.</p>]]><p><b>Lake Tahoe</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Lake Tahoe (<a href="http://www.visitinglaketahoe.com" target="_blank">www.visitinglaketahoe.com</a>), set 1,800m (6,000ft) above sea level. Enjoy clear blue skies, snow-capped mountains, and rich culture and history. Ski Squaw Valley and Alpine Meadows (<a href="http://www.skialpine.com/" target="_blank">www.skialpine.com</a>) or take a paddle-wheeler cruise across the lake.</p>]]><p><b>Little Saigon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Little Saigon, the largest Vietnamese business district in the USA. The area features an Asian Garden and a wide variety of French, Vietnamese and Asian shops and restaurants.</p>]]><p><b>Marshall Gold Discovery State Historic Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pan for gold at the Marshall Gold Discovery State Historic Park (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.coloma.com/">www.coloma.com</a>) where California's 1848 gold rush began. Visit the museum and original and restored buildings at Sutter's Mill in Coloma.</p>]]><p><b>Play golf</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tee off on one of the greens at Pebble Beach (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.pebblebeach.com/">www.pebblebeach.com</a>), which has hosted the U.S. Open five times and is one of the most famous golf courses in the world. This world-class resort has four golf courses with impeccably manicured greens overlooking the ocean. Professional staff offers individual and group instructions.</p>]]><p><b>Ride a cable car</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ride a cable car up and down the steep hills of San Francisco, overlooking the city's glistening bay and Golden Gate Bridge. Cable cars are an iconic part of San Francisco's past that have been preserved as an ideal and fun way to view the city. If you want to ride in the exterior of the car, hang on to the poles and watch out for potential hazards. View the actual cable-winding machinery at the San Francisco Cable Car Museum (<a href="http://www.cablecarmuseum.org" target="_blank">www.cablecarmuseum.org</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Roy Rogers-Dale Evans Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the Roy Rogers-Dale Evans Museum, a frontier fortress full of mementoes from the Western stars' films and television shows. The Route 66 Museum (<a href="http://www.califrt66museum.org/" target="_blank">www.califrt66museum.org</a>) displays a collection of artifacts and photographs related to the famous highway.</p>]]><p><b>San Diego Maritime Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy the San Diego Maritime Museum (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.sdmaritime.com/">www.sdmaritime.com</a>) anchored along Harbour Drive, or take an excursion into Mission Bay on a yacht or excursion boat.</p>]]><p><b>San Diego Zoo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the world-famous San Diego Zoo (<a href="http://www.sandiegozoo.org/" target="_blank">www.sandiegozoo.org</a>), which houses 800 different species. The entire zoo is designed as a 40-hectare (100-acre) tropical garden, and offers many educational programs including nighttime sleepovers and wild animal camps.</p>]]><p><b>Santa Monica Pier</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Walk the Santa Monica Pier (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.santamonicapier.org/">www.santamonicapier.org</a>), the West Coast's oldest pleasure pier, built in 1908, and now an entertainment park with roller coasters and giant Ferris wheel (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.pacpark.com/">www.pacpark.com</a>). The pier draws over four million visitors annually who enjoy watching a variety of street performers and artists with a Pacific Ocean backdrop. Below the Pier's eastern deck is the Santa Monica Pier aquarium.</p>]]><p><b>Shasta Lake</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the breathtaking natural wonders of the beautiful Shasta Lake (<a href="http://www.shastalake.com" target="_blank">www.shastalake.com</a>), and the dramatic, snow-capped Mount Shasta (<a href="http://www.mtshastachamber.com" target="_blank">www.mtshastachamber.com</a>), one of the nation's tallest mountains at 4,248m (14,162ft).</p>]]><p><b>Shopping in Beverly Hills</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Shop in Beverly Hills (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.beverlyhills.org/">www.beverlyhills.org</a>), the world's most famous shopping district, and look out for Hollywood celebrities.</p>]]><p><b>Wine tasting</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Taste premium California wines (<a href="http://www.winecountrygetaways.com/" target="_blank">www.winecountrygetaways.com</a>) in the Napa and Sonoma Valleys, north of San Francisco. Mumm Napa (<a href="http://www.mummnapa.com" target="_blank">www.mummnapa.com</a>) is a working winery and vineyard in Napa California with award winning grapes and a picturesque outdoor patio for table service wine tastings. The property also offers guided tours and a photography gallery. Sonoma and Napa Valleys are world famous for their wines and many vineyards are open to the public for tastings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>$1.89 trillion.</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>California's economy is the biggest in the United States and the 9th largest in the world. The state was hit hard by the 2007-2009 recession and continues to lag in unemployment. 2012 forecasts predict a slight increase in jobs, especially through companies such as Google and Facebook, which are located in Silicon Valley.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The wide variety of businesses in California encourages a variety of styles, depending on the industry involved. In general, Californians cultivate a relaxed, informal atmosphere in keeping with the climate and the California way of life: 'casual-smart' dress is a good rule of thumb, especially within industries such as film and TV, computing or multimedia. More conservative suits and business dress are the norm in legal and financial institutions. <br /><br />Appointments and punctuality are expected procedure and business cards are widely used. Southern Californians tend to be open and laid back and it is not uncommon to be invited to someone's home for dinner as a prelude or conclusion to a business meeting. In San Diego for instance, a business meeting may include brunch at a popular seaside restaurant or dinner beside the pool at the host's hillside residence. In San Francisco and Los Angeles, however, 'power' breakfasts, catered lunches and coffee meetings are more common, while dinners at private homes are rare. Where alcohol is concerned, it is best to wait and check the preferences of the host. Many Americans stick to soft drinks and Californians in particular are very health-conscious. <br /><br />Non-smoking bylaws are enforced in most of California's public establishments and many Southern California residents do not smoke and are sometimes sensitive about smoking in their house. When making a private visit, gifts of wine, sweets from home or flowers are a good bet.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1730. Though in Los Angeles, job hours are more relaxed and can start as late as 1000, continuing until 1900.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>California has always been a social melting pot, and this is reflected in its modern, cosmopolitan cuisine with an endless variety of ethnic influences. Northern California spawned America&rsquo;s local food movement, with an emphasis on fresh and seasonal fruits and vegetables, grass fed beef and humanely raised animals - virtually changing the way America eats.</p>
<p>Food trucks, or mobile restaurants, have become a California phenomena - you can find them parked outside of office buildings, universities, public parks, and sporting events - usually with long lines. Some customers even follow their favourite food truck on Twitter so they&rsquo;ll always know where to find their favourite foods.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Steak. California is an historic haven for cattle and cattle ranchers, today the tradition lives on with filet mignon and porterhouse cuts at steakhouses across the state. <br />
&bull; Seafood. Californians consume far more seafood per capita than the rest of the country, and fishermen bring 300 different species to market each year. Dungeness crab, shrimp, and swordfish are especially popular. <br />
&bull; Clam chowder. San Francisco is known for serving thick clam chowder in a bread bowl. <br />
&bull; California wines. Northern California is famous for wines and vineyards dating back to 1855, especially white wine. <br />
&bull; Ghirardelli chocolate. Another speciality from San Francisco, Ghirardelli has been making speciality chocolate since 1852 using a unique manufacturing process. <br />
&bull; Sourdough bread. This was the bread made in Northern California during the California Gold Rush. Today, Sourdough Sam is the mascot of the San Francisco 49ers football team. <br />
&bull; Tofu. California is a health conscious culture with a variety of vegetarian and vegan options, including bean curd called tofu. <br />
&bull; Sparkling wine. White California sparkling wines are made in the Methode Champenoise style in Northern California where the temperatures can be cooler. <br />
&bull; Tacos. California shares a border with Mexico and offers some of the most authentic and spicy Mexican food in the United States, especially in San Diego where fish tacos can be as cheap as one dollar each. <br />
&bull; Fruit. California&rsquo;s climate is ideal for growing fruit year around, especially citrus like lemons and oranges. Avocados, grapes, apples, and strawberries also grow especially well.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>All fresh fruit should be washed or peeled before consuming to prevent the consumption of pesticides.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>15% of the bill is customary, 20% for excellent service. Bartenders should be tipped at least one dollar per drink, regardless of the beverage price.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>Drinking laws in California are very strict and widely followed. Individuals must have government ID showing they are over 21 years old to purchase, order or drink alcohol.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are few places in the world that can rival California's nightlife. Los Angeles is home to an array of illustrious clubs with rich and famous patrons. You can rent a table at an exclusive nightclub, like Le Deux, for VIP bottle service or wait in long lines with the masses. Dress smart and you can get in before midnight. Alternatively, there are more mellow bars near the beach where the clientele drinks draft beer while listening to an acoustic band. For some of Los Angeles&rsquo; famous sex, drugs, and rock and roll history, check out The Viper Room (<a href="http://www.viperroom.com" target="_blank">www.viperroom.com</a>) on the infamous Sunset Strip, where bands from around the world vie for stage time. The bar crowd runs more grungy than glamorous. For laughs, head to The Laugh Factory, where legions of famous comedians get their start and continue to entertain after making hit TV shows and movies (<a href="http://www.laughfactory.com" target="_blank">www.laughfactory.com</a>).</p>
<p>San Francisco, with its young, lively population, is known around the world as a great party town, especially for the LGBT population, with all night dance clubs and an underground rave scene leftover from the 90s. Club lines aren&rsquo;t as long as in Los Angeles, and the dress code isn&rsquo;t as strict. San Diego is the best city to check out independent and local bands who give free (or at least cheap) before they head to Los Angeles, sign a record deal, and make it big.</p>
<p>For those travellers looking for a more sophisticated nightlife experience, Northern California wineries often host evening tastings to the mellow soundtrack of a string quartet or jazz band.</p>
<p>One trend that&rsquo;s happening throughout California is the faux-dive bar: a well stocked and professionally staffed bar that&rsquo;s been decorated to look like something left over from the 1970s or earlier. Think deer heads on the wall, vintage video game machines, and graffiti in the bathrooms. The only thing modern is the high price for a drink.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some visitors come to California just for the shopping. Whether they are after the latest fashions or quaint handicrafts, the state's vast range of shops and malls will satisfy any consumer.</p>
<p>The boutiques and department stores of Los Angeles are famous worldwide. Rodeo Drive is as much an iconic tourist destination as it is an uber-luxurious street dedicated to some of the most expensive and outrageous fashions in the world. Be warned, Rodeo is not pronounced like the event for cowboys, correct pronunciation is &lsquo;roh-DAY-oh&rsquo;. For some of the best luxury and bargain retail stores in a beautiful outdoor mall, drive over to The Grove: a movie theatre, multiple restaurants, and a farmer&rsquo;s market round out the activities.</p>
<p>Orange County and Santa Barbara are also known for the quality and variety of their shopping. Good souvenirs include bottles of wine from northern California, surf gear and equipment in San Diego, and high fashion from Los Angeles. Street artists sell a variety of art, photographs, and handicrafts up and down the beach through most of the state. Look for organic and all-natural bath and beauty products made in California and sold in most drug stores or gift shops. </p><p>Mon-Sat 1000-2000 or later. Malls close earlier on Sundays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Whether you're heading to California's cities, wine regions, beaches, mountains or desert resorts, hotels in California are world-class, ranging from boutique properties to upmarket spa retreats. There is still a range of cheap California hotel options if you're on a budget. Homestays or couch surfing are becoming common practices, and are a great way to enjoy a private home in California at a fraction of the price.<br />
Resorts: Luxury resorts abound in California, especially on the coast and in Napa and Sonoma Valleys. Resorts in Los Angeles and San Diego tend to be smaller but no less luxurious, and often serve as second homes for Hollywood producers, directors, and actors. Swimming pools, outdoor bars and restaurants, and magnificent gardens are all par for the course at a California resort.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>California has a wealth of bed & breakfast inns to choose from, housed in homes, country cottages and historic buildings. A full breakfast is typically included in the price of a room. Bed & breakfasts are much smaller and more intimate than a typical hotel option.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Whether you're heading to California's cities, wine regions, beaches, mountains or desert resorts, hotels in California are world-class, ranging from boutique properties to upmarket spa retreats. There is still a range of cheap California hotel options if you're on a budget. Homestays or couch surfing are becoming common practices, and are a great way to enjoy a private home in California at a fraction of the price.<br />
Resorts: Luxury resorts abound in California, especially on the coast and in Napa and Sonoma Valleys. Resorts in Los Angeles and San Diego tend to be smaller but no less luxurious, and often serve as second homes for Hollywood producers, directors, and actors. Swimming pools, outdoor bars and restaurants, and magnificent gardens are all par for the course at a California resort.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Whether you're heading to California's cities, wine regions, beaches, mountains or desert resorts, hotels in California are world-class, ranging from boutique properties to upmarket spa retreats. There is still a range of cheap California hotel options if you're on a budget. Homestays or couch surfing are becoming common practices, and are a great way to enjoy a private home in California at a fraction of the price.<br />
Resorts: Luxury resorts abound in California, especially on the coast and in Napa and Sonoma Valleys. Resorts in Los Angeles and San Diego tend to be smaller but no less luxurious, and often serve as second homes for Hollywood producers, directors, and actors. Swimming pools, outdoor bars and restaurants, and magnificent gardens are all par for the course at a California resort.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical insurance is strongly advised. Only emergency cases are treated without prior payment and treatment may be refused without evidence of insurance or a deposit. All receipts must be kept in order to make a claim. Medical facilities are generally of a high standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case of an emergency or accident, dial 911 from any public or private phone to be put in touch with paramedics, fire fighters, and police officers. Stay on the line until the operator instructs you to hang up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many medications available over the counter in other countries require a prescription in the US. Those visiting the USA for long periods with school-age children should be aware that school entry requirements in California include proof of immunisation against diphtheria, measles, mumps, tetanus, poliomyelitis, polio, rubella and pertussis (whooping cough). As of 2010, all restrictions against people with HIV have been lifted.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All restaurants in California are graded by the US health inspector with a letter rating system that must be hung in the front window. Any restaurant without an A or B rating is best avoided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food trucks, (mobile kitchens that sell food) are an increasingly popular option especially in Los Angeles and San Francisco. By law, food trucks are subject to the same health code requirements, inspections, and letter grade system that stationary restaurants are.&lt;br /&gt;
Tap water in California is very safe and governed by strict municipal laws that monitor purity and filtration. In 2011, several clean water bills were signed into law that guarantee clean drinking water in California, even in remote and disadvantaged communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though the tap water is safe, drinking bottled water is very fashionable, especially water infused with vitamins or antioxidants. Many high end restaurants don&amp;rsquo;t offer water from the tap. Public drinking fountains are available in airports, parks, and schools but with increasing irregularity. Water bowls for pets are commonly placed on the sidewalk by local merchants, especially during the hotter months.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Raw fruits and vegetables should be washed with clean water before consuming for the removal of pesticides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health risks in California, especially Los Angeles which is smog prone, include air pollution. Asthma sufferers should take extra precaution and use a mask if biking in the city. Traffic accidents are also high due to the number of cars and motorists on the road. Sunburn and dehydration are common concerns during the hottest months and can be avoided by drinking lots of water, reapplying sunscreen, and staying out of direct sun from ten in the morning until two in the afternoon. Some beaches have riptides and high waves which means visitors should proceed with caution and only swim and surf at approved beaches where there are lifeguards and flag warning systems. &lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[34.127055]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-117.341081]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>411,429 sq km (158,854 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>39.25 million (2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>92.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sacramento.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>California is a geographically diverse area of the USA. The state is usually divided into Northern and Southern California, though there are isn&rsquo;t a well defined boundary. San Francisco is a northern city, while San Diego and Los Angeles are southern, but the areas in between aren&rsquo;t easily defined &ndash; rather, the distinction is more between the differing attitudes and lifestyles in different areas, than a physical boundary. Southern California is generally a developed urban environment, with major cities and sprawling suburbs accessible only by car. Northern California is more rugged and natural, with vineyards, mountains, and agricultural regions.</p>
<p>California is bordered to the north by Oregon state, to the east by the states of Nevada and Arizona across the Colorado River, to the south by Mexico, and to the west by the Pacific Ocean.  Earth scientists have divided the state into eleven distinct mountain ranges, plateaus, deserts, basins, and valleys. The most notable mountains are the Sierra Nevada range which run north-south for 640 km (398 miles) and contain the highest peak in the United States: Mount Whitney. The Mojave Desert contains the lowest and hottest place in America: Death Valley, where the temperatures hover around 49&deg;C (120&deg;F).&nbsp;in mid-summer. Earthquakes are a regular (but rarely deadly) occurrence throughout the state, especially near San Francisco.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>California is the most populous state in the union and therefore has people practising a variety of religions. The state has the most Roman Catholics of any other state, as well as large Protestant, Jewish, and Muslim populations. California also has the largest Mormon population outside of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/utah">Utah</a>. Many Californians practise no religion, defining themselves as agnostic, atheist, or simply spiritual.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>California is known for a laid back and relaxed attitude with an emphasis on individuality. Southern California has an almost island feel to business and social dynamics, with a less strict emphasis on time and appearance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The history of California can be traced back to the Native American period before Christ. What's interesting about this time was how native people lived in an area surrounded by mountains, deserts and forests that isolated them from the rest of the world. These extreme living conditions led California's original inhabitants to develop unique cultures, which can still be seen today, as the state has the greatest native population of any in the US.<br/><br/>In the 1700s, after Spanish explorers found no gold or cities to exploit, they left California to the missionaries and colonists who launched a campaign of genocide on the indigenous population. Mexico acquired the area in 1821 and built small ranches and used the indigenous population for labour. At the end of the Mexican-American War, the territory was handed over to the US government just in time for the California Gold Rush, which increased the area's population to over 100,000 by 1850. The increased population and promise of wealth helped make California an official state in 1850. From there, California began to boom and hasn't stopped since.<br/><br/>The opening of the Panama Canal and the transcontinental railroad made California a shipping centre for the rest of the world, while advances in agriculture and farming opened up the state to successful cattle ranches and fruit plantations. With the first decades of the 20th century came the rise of the movie studios as MGM, Universal, and Warner Brothers bought cheap land in Hollywood to build sets and hired fresh faces from the Midwest as leading ladies. After World War 2, land developers began to build estates for soldiers who wanted to buy homes and start families.</p><p>The 1980s were characterised by continuing economic boom as well as urban sprawl and air pollution. The state responded by passing clean air legislation and expanding carpool lanes.</p><p>California can lay claim to being the birthplace of surfing, the movie business, hippies and the dot-com business boom with hi-tech companies based in Silicon Valley, including Google and Facebook. If California were a country in its own right it would be the sixth largest economy in the world and the 35th most populous.</p><p>As it is, the population is growing as more and more people move to California for the weather, perceived job opportunities and laid back lifestyle.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p> California is home to the highest (Pount Whitney) and lowest (Death Valley) points in the mainland United States.</p><p> In 1579 the English explorer Francis Drake claimed a section of the California coast, but it is no longer known where.</p><p> Some 37,000 earthquakes are recorded each year, although the vast majority are too small to be felt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arrive in California and you are opening a treasure chest of stellar scenery, super-cool cities, innovative dining and theme parks guaranteed to unleash your inner kid. Everything glitters here; from the snow-capped Sierra Nevada to the sparkling sands of SoCal&rsquo;s surf beaches, via the diamond-clad fashionistas of Rodeo Drive.</p>
<p>Gold diggers, hippies, techie geeks, surf dudes and wannabe stars have all sought their piece of California&rsquo;s good life, and its cities are hubs of aspiration and inspiration. Cosmopolitan San Francisco chucks eye-popping scenery and start-up ventures at you like a tennis ball machine. In Los Angeles, celebrity spotting in chic boutiques, exclusive restaurants, or even the gas station is a regular and fun occurrence.&nbsp;</p>
<p>California's ruggedly beautiful coastline curves north of Los Angeles along coastal Highway 1, an iconic American drive. At Big Sur, dramatic cliffs plunge into the Pacific Ocean where California grey whales migrate and condors soar overhead. Visitors come to hike through humongous redwoods, participate in the local artist scene, and escape anything manmade.&nbsp;Meanwhile, surfers and sun worshippers enjoy sand and swells along San Diego's sweeping shores.</p>
<p>To the east, the Sierra Nevada is an extraordinary playground of sky-scraping mountains, towering sequoias and plummeting waterfalls. Skiers float through powder above Lake Tahoe, climbers inch up Yosemite&rsquo;s El Capitan, and hikers trek the long-distance John Muir Trail. You can travel in the same day from Mt Whitney, the highest mountain in the lower 48 states,&nbsp;at 4,418m (14,494ft), to Death Valley, the lowest place in North America at 86m (282ft) below sea level.</p>
<p>With its never-ending stream of foodie fads and inventions, Californian dining is an adventure too. And the Napa and Sonoma Valleys produce excellent wines, but keep the quaffing until after you&rsquo;ve ridden Disneyland&rsquo;s spinning teacups.</p><p>Arrive in California and you are opening a treasure chest of stellar scenery, super-cool cities, innovative dining and theme parks guaranteed to unleash your inner kid. Everything glitters here; from the snow-capped Sierra Nevada to the sparkling sands of SoCal&rsquo;s surf beaches, via the diamond-clad fashionistas of Rodeo Drive. Gold diggers, hippies, techie geeks, surf dudes and wannabe stars have all sought their piece of California&rsquo;s good life, and its cities are hubs of aspiration and inspiration.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
