<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="New Jersey" ColCode="nwj" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="nj" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[New Jersey]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flanked by the Atlantic Ocean and the Delaware River, New Jersey has a fairly moderate climate, with cold winters and warm, humid summers. The state's temperature ranges from a July average of 23째C (74째F) to -1째C (30째F) in January, with a more pronounced difference between north and south in the winter. Annual snowfall averages 41cm (16 inches). There is moderate rainfall throughout the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Heavyweights with extra bundling for the winter months. Lightweights for the summer. Raingear might come in handy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-jersey/atlantic-city-international">Atlantic City International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-jersey/newark-liberty-international-airport">Newark Liberty International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Newark Liberty International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.panynj.gov<p>Newark Liberty International Airport is located 3km (2 miles) south of Newark and 26km (16 miles) southwest of New York City.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 973 961 6000</p>]]><b>Atlantic City International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.sjta.com/acairport<p>The Atlantic City International Airport is situated 16km (10 miles) northwest of Atlantic City, New Jersey.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 609 645 7895</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rail services to Manhattan are available at Newark Liberty International Airport Station and Newark Penn Station (see above). <em>Newark Liberty Airport Express</em> runs frequent bus services to Midtown Manhattan, stopping at the Port Authority Bus Terminal and Grand Central Station Terminal (both of which are also served by New York Airport Service express buses running to JFK and La Guardia airports - see <em><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a></em> section) and Penn Station (journey time - 30 to 60 minutes).</p>
<p><em>NJ Transit</em> buses from Newark arrive at the Port Authority Terminal in Manhattan. Shared minibuses that stop on demand are run by <em>SuperShuttle Manhattan</em>, which stops anywhere south of 227th Street (24 hours), and also serves the area between 23rd and 63rd Streets<em> Gray Line Air Shuttles</em> run from Newark to Manhattan.<br />
<br />
Penn Station in Newark serves <em><a href="http://www.njtransit.com" target="www.njtransit.com">NJ Transit</a></em> trains as well as most <em><a href="https://www.amtrak.com" target="www.amtrak.com">Amtrak</a></em> (tel: 1 800 872 7245, in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> only) services along the New York-Philadelphia-Washington corridor, including high-speed Acela Express trains. For train times on these routes, see the <em>New York</em> section; trains from Newark to New York take 15 to 20 minutes. Trains between Atlantic City and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/philadelphia">Philadelphia</a> are operated by<em> NJ Transit</em> and <em>Amtrak</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The three major motorways of New Jersey are the Atlantic City Expressway, the Garden State Parkway and the New Jersey Turnpike. All three of them are toll roads. The toll can be paid in cash. For longer stays it is advisable that you equip your car with a transponder so that the toll can be charged automatically using an <a href="https://www.ezpassnj.com/en/signup/step1.shtml" target="www.ezpassnj.com/en/signup/step1.shtml">E-ZPass</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Adventure Aquarium</b></p><![CDATA[<p>View ocean life at the Adventure Aquarium (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.adventureaquarium.com/">www.adventureaquarium.com</a>) on the Camden waterfront. The experience combines entertainment, science and cutting-edge technology with some 5,000 aquatic animals and over 80 individual fresh and salt water exhibits.</p>]]><p><b>Allaire State Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spend the day at Allaire State Park in Farmingdale. The park is a restored 18th-century bog-iron mining village with period shops, bakeries, churches, the Pinecreek Railroad train, craft and antique shows. Join in square-dancing on weekends.</p>]]><p><b>Atlantic City Boardwalk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Play the casinos and attractions at the Atlantic City Boardwalk. It is lined with dazzling casinos, amusement rides, games and shops on one side, and 10km (6 miles) of sand beach and surf on the other.</p>]]><p><b>Branch Brook Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Branch Brook Park (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.branchbrookpark.org/">www.branchbrookpark.org</a>) in Newark, which plays host to the annual cherry blossom festival, and has more cherry blossoms than Washington, DC in the springtime.</p>]]><p><b>Cape May</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relax at the popular Victorian seaside town of Cape May (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.capemay.com/">www.capemay.com</a>). This National Historic Landmark has many bed &amp; breakfast inns, trolley tours and the superb Cape May County Zoo.</p>]]><p><b>Circle Line ferry</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ride the Circle Line ferry (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.statueoflibertyferry.com/">www.statueoflibertyferry.com</a>) to the Statue of Liberty (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/stli">www.nps.gov/stli</a>) and Ellis Island (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/elis">www.nps.gov/elis</a>). The ferry services operate from Liberty State Park in Jersey City.</p>]]><p><b>Delaware River</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Raft on the Delaware River. Hiking, canoeing and fishing can also be organised during the summer. Ice-skating, tobogganing, snowmobiling, skiing and ice fishing are available during the winter.</p>]]><p><b>Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pack up the camping gear for a summer trip to the Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/dewa">www.nps.gov/dewa</a>). Enjoy a variety of watersports in one of the cleanest rivers in the area.</p>]]><p><b>Edison National Historic Site</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the Edison National Historic Site (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/edis">www.nps.gov/edis</a>) in West Orange, and take a tour of Thomas Edison's home, laboratory and library. See the equipment and chemicals with which Edison invented the first incandescent lightbulb, photograph and motion picture.</p>]]><p><b>Einstein</b></p><![CDATA[<p>View the house where Einstein lived during the years he was a Princeton University lecturer, until his death in 1955 (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.princetonhistory.org/historic_sites.cfm">www.princetonhistory.org/historic_sites.cfm</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Land of Make Believe</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the Land of Make Believe (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.lomb.com/">www.lomb.com</a>) in Hope. This 12-hectare (30-acre) park fulfills childhood fantasies with rides, attractions and a waterpark.</p>]]><p><b>Liberty Science Center</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the Liberty Science Center (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.lsc.org/">www.lsc.org</a>) in Liberty State Park, Jersey City. It offers a hands-on science museum with an IMAX Dome Theater, plus exhibits on inventions, technology, environment and health.</p>]]><p><b>Morristown National Historic Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See battle re-enactments at the Morristown National Historic Park (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nps.gov/morr">www.nps.gov/morr</a>). This historic park is the site of George Washington's winter encampments, and the Ford Mansion is now a museum.</p>]]><p><b>Mountain Creek</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ski or snowboard the slopes at Mountain Creek (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.mountaincreek.com/">www.mountaincreek.com</a>), New Jersey's four-season resort destination only an hour and a half's drive from Manhattan.</p>]]><p><b>New Jersey State Planetarium and Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Delve into New Jersey's history (dating back to 500BC) at the <strong>New Jersey State Planetarium and Museum</strong> (website: <a href="http://www.state.nj.us/state/museum" target="_blank">www.state.nj.us/state/museum</a>) in Trenton.</p>]]><p><b>Newark Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the Newark Museum (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.newarkmuseum.com/">www.newarkmuseum.com</a>), one of the nation's most comprehensive fine arts museums and the largest museum complex in the state, with 80 art and science galleries, a planetarium and a mini-zoo.</p>]]><p><b>Old Barracks Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Step back in time at the Old Barracks Museum (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.barracks.org/">www.barracks.org</a>) in Trenton, the site of the famous day-after-Christmas battle during the Revolutionary War. Walk through restored soldiers' quarters, 18th-century period rooms and antiques.</p>]]><p><b>Palisades Interstate Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore <strong>Palisades Interstate Park</strong> (website: <a href="http://www.njpalisades.org/" target="_blank">www.njpalisades.org</a>), with its enormous children's fun park. Located north of Newark, the park has 1,012 hectares (2,500 acres) of scenic roads, stunning views, picnic areas, a historic museum, nature sanctuary, and hiking and skiing trails.</p>]]><p><b>Pine Barrens</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Camp, canoe, swim, fish, ride horses or hike in a venture to the <strong>Pine Barrens</strong> (website: <a href="http://www.pineypower.com/" target="_blank">www.pineypower.com</a>), the largest wilderness area east of the Mississippi River. The <strong>New Jersey Pinelands National Reserve</strong> (website: <a href="http://www.nps.gov/pine" target="_blank">www.nps.gov/pine</a>) was recognised by UNESCO as a Biosphere Reserve in 1983.</p>]]><p><b>Point Pleasant Beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cruise off Point Pleasant Beach aboard the stern-wheelers <em>River Belle</em> or <em>River Queen</em> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.pointpleasantbeach.com/">www.pointpleasantbeach.com</a>), or take a deep-sea fishing boats charter.</p>]]><p><b>Princeton University</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a walking tour of Princeton University and the battlefield where Washington's army defeated the British in 1777 (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.visitprinceton.org/">www.visitprinceton.org</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Renault Winery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Taste the grapes from one of the oldest vineyards in the USA - the Renault Winery (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.renaultwinery.com/">www.renaultwinery.com</a>) in Egg Harbor. Visit the nearby Museum of American Glass (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.wheatonvillage.org/">www.wheatonvillage.org</a>) for a dazzling display of glass from talented artisans.</p>]]><p><b>Shore Region</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the Shore Region (home to rock stars Bruce Springsteen and Jon Bon Jovi), which boasts white sandy beaches, rolling farmland, quaint seaside resort towns and historic sites. Seaside Heights and Point Pleasant have boardwalk amusement rides and games, while quieter towns like Spring Lake and Ocean Grove offer charming bed &amp; breakfast inns (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.state.nj.us/travel/regions_shr.html">www.state.nj.us/travel/regions_shr.html</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Six Flags Great Adventure and Wild Safari</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Thrill to adrenaline rides and see the world's largest safari park at Six Flags Great Adventure and Wild Safari (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.sixflags.com/">www.sixflags.com</a>) in Jackson. Splash into more fun at Hurricane Harbor waterpark.</p>]]><p><b>Trump Plaza Hotel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Step into Atlantic City's opulent Trump Plaza Hotel, then try your luck at Trump Taj Mahal Casino (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.trumptaj.com/">www.trumptaj.com</a>), one of the largest in the world.</p>]]><p><b>USS New Jersey Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Climb aboard a battleship at the USS New Jersey Museum (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.battleshipnewjersey.org/">www.battleshipnewjersey.org</a>) in Camden. The USS New Jersey is one of the most decorated battleships in US naval history.</p>]]><p><b>Wildwoods</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the Wildwoods (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.wildwoodsnj.com/">www.wildwoodsnj.com</a>) and Ocean City (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.oceancityvacation.com/">www.oceancityvacation.com</a>) boardwalks that buzz with excitement, in contrast to the quieter retreats of Stone Harbor (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.stoneharbor-resort.com/">www.stoneharbor-resort.com</a>) and Avalon (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.avalonbeach.com/">www.avalonbeach.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>New Jersey offers everything from gourmet cuisine to 'home-cooking' country food, in settings ranging from restaurants to diners. The area has been influenced by continuing waves of immigrants from England and Europe, and restaurants reflect the cosmopolitan mix, with rich cultural traditions. Food and wine festivals can be found throughout the year.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; Seafood. <br />&bull; Steaks.<br />&bull; Italian.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Atlantic City's nightclubs are open until the small hours and there is round-the-clock gambling available at the casinos. Some of the oceanfront towns have clubs and entertainment centres, with a lively atmosphere along the boardwalks into the evenings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shopping in New Jersey appeals to all tastes and budgets. Jersey Gardens Mall in Elizabeth is the state's largest outlet shopping mall, while upmarket shopping malls feature the famous department stores of Macy's, Bloomingdales and Saks Fifth Avenue. Bargains on brand-name merchandise can be found at the Secaucus Outlet Center in Secaucus. Liberty Village and Turntable Junction outlet centres in Flemington offer equally attractive deals. Antique stores fill small New Jersey towns like Chester, Haddonfield and Mullica Hill, while outdoor flea markets offer an eclectic array of jewellery, clothing, housewares, furniture and more. There is no sales tax on clothing in New Jersey.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide range of accommodation in New Jersey, from large chain hotels in Atlantic City and Princeton to bed and breakfasts, motels and camping in the rest of the state. There are options to suit all budgets and tastes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide range of accommodation in New Jersey, from large chain hotels in Atlantic City and Princeton to bed and breakfasts, motels and camping in the rest of the state. There are options to suit all budgets and tastes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide range of accommodation in New Jersey, from large chain hotels in Atlantic City and Princeton to bed and breakfasts, motels and camping in the rest of the state. There are options to suit all budgets and tastes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[40.058324]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-74.405661]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>21,274 sq km (8,214 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>9 million (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>421.1 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Trenton.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholicism holds the largest religious affiliation in New Jersey, followed by Judaism. The greatest Protestant denominations include Methodist, Presbyterian and Episcopal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Jerseyans are often associated with similar cultural stereotypes to their neighbours in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a>. They are stereotyped as rude, loud and often mocked for a heavy mid-Atlantic accent. In recent years many of these perceptions derive from reality television programmes. However, New Jerseyans are known for pride in their state, generally maintaining strong connections to their hometowns and to the famous Jersey Shore where they spend their summers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The first known inhabitants of New Jersey were the Delaware Indians 10,000 years ago. Italian explorer, Giovanni de Verrazano, was the first to sail in New Jersey&rsquo;s waters in approximately 1524. In 1609 Henry Hudson, an English explorer who sailed on behalf of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/netherlands">Netherlands</a>, passed through Newark Bay. Hudson acquired the area and named it New Netherlands; the state&rsquo;s early settlers came from The Netherlands, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/finland">Finland</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sweden">Sweden</a>. <br />
<br />
The British took over New Netherlands in 1664 and renamed the area New Jersey after the Isle of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/channel-islands/jersey">Jersey</a>. New Jersey was broken up into east and west regions and overseen by the proprietors, Sir George Carteret and Lord John Berkley. The two Englishmen decided to sell the land and give the colonists political and religious freedoms. However, this did not last for long as New Jersey was given a joint British governor who also oversaw <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a>. In 1738 New Jersey was granted its own governor.<br />
<br />
During the Revolution the majority of battles were fought in New Jersey due to its proximity to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/philadelphia">Philadelphia</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York City</a>. The Battles of Trenton and Princeton were two important points in the Revolution for both the Americans and General George Washington. New Jersey was the first state to sign the Bill of Rights in 1787. Three years later, Trenton became its capital city. <br />
<br />
New Jersey entered the 19th century with a flourishing economy in manufacturing and factory industries such as textiles, trains and steel. A successful economy combined with the advent of canals and railways attracted European immigrants to the area. The southern region of New Jersey remained agricultural, but underwent change as railroads forged through the state. Post-Civil War New Jersey experienced an influx of immigrants from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ireland">Ireland</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany">Germany</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy">Italy</a> and Eastern Europe. <br />
<br />
The state suffered through the Great Depression in the 1930s, but experienced a revival in its industries during WWII. In the 1950s suburban culture emerged due to the openings of the New Jersey Turnpike and Garden State Parkway. <br />
<br />
Famous New Jersey residents include President Woodrow Wilson who also served as governor from 1910 to 1913, and Thomas Edison, inventor of the light bulb.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The famed home of fictional gangster, Tony Soprano, New Jersey might be a compact state, but it packs in bustling cities, hedonistic seaside towns and excellent beaches.</p>
<p>Separated from NYC by the Hudson River, New Jersey&rsquo;s own cities might feel like an extension the Big Apple, but they have a charm of their own. In fact, Jersey City&rsquo;s creative culinary scene has wooed many visitors from the other side of the river, while Newark and Hoboken offer a gamut of cultural attractions, leafy parks and hallowed Civil War grounds.</p>
<p>But most fun is the Jersey Shore, an irresistible stretch of coastline luring beachgoers to expansive sweeps of white sand, historic boardwalks and buzzing resorts.</p>
<p>Atlantic City, a kind of Vegas-by-the-sea, glitters most brightly with its palatial casinos, whirring arcades and big-name shows, not to mention a full menu of watersports, as much saltwater taffy as your teeth can handle, and the state&rsquo;s tallest lighthouse. For culture vultures AC also boasts modern art parks, professional ballet corps, and the Noyes Arts Garage, home to working studios, galleries and the African American Heritage Museum.</p>
<p>Escape the city at Cape May National Wildlife Refuge, a protected area of swamps, grasslands and maritime forests frequented by hundreds of thousands of migrating birds each year. Or head further inland to Egg Harbor City, where the Renault winery has been keeping oenophiles tipsy for some 150 years, even continuing under a special permit during Prohibition (purely for medicinal purposes naturally).</p>
<p>Adventurers can bike gnarly trails at Mountain Creek during the summer and return in winter to ski, or saddle up and explore northern New Jersey&rsquo;s by horseback.</p><p>The famed home of fictional gangster, Tony Soprano, New Jersey might be a compact state, but it packs in bustling cities, hedonistic seaside towns and excellent beaches.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
