<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Sark Herm" ColCode="sah" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="cs" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Sark & Herm]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These islands enjoy a temperate climate with warm summers and milder winter temperatures than those experienced in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>. The most popular holiday season is from April to October, with temperatures averaging 20-21°C (68-70°F). These months give an average of 200 and 260 hours of sunshine. Rainfall is mainly during the cooler months. The sea is 17°C (63°F) on average during the summer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Take a stout pair of shoes for negotiating the uneven roads and footpaths. Waterproof clothing is also recommended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For visiting yachtsmen, there are public yellow buoy moorings at Havre Gosselin on the west coast of Sark, and at La Gr&eacute;ve de la Ville bay on the east coast. Kayaks are available for hire with Outdoor Guernsey (tel: (01481) 267 627; <a href="http://outdoorguernsey.co.uk" target="_top">http://outdoorguernsey.co.uk</a>). You can also book a boat trip around Sark with George Guille&rsquo;s Island Boat Trips (tel: (01481) 832 345).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The road surface in Sark is affectionately dubbed 'Sark tarmac' by the locals, but the roads in both Herm and Sark are essentially dirt tracks. They are reasonably well maintained, although they can become waterlogged in the winter. The islands have a network of footpaths that are the best means of both exploring and getting A to B. Contact the respective tourist boards for more information.</p><p>During the summer season (May-September) horse and carriage 'taxis' wait at the top of harbour hill to offer sightseeing tours. Out of season, horse and carts can still be booked through the Sark Visitor Centre. On arrival at the island, you will be greeted by the Harbour Hill transport, a tractor-drawn trailer, which takes passengers and their luggage up the hill to the village. Transfer by tractor from the village can be booked via your hotel. Visitors to Herm should arrange luggage transfers via quad bike with their hotel.</p><p>All carriage drivers must obtain a Carriage Drivers Licence.</p><p>There is a blanket speed limit of 10mph (16kph) across the islands.</p><p>Most tourists choose to explore Sark by bicycle and bikes are for hire from Avenue Cycle Hire close to the harbour (tel: (01481) 832 102; <a href="http://www.avenuecyclessark.co.uk" target="_blank">www.avenuecyclessark.co.uk</a>) or from A to B Cycles (tel: (01481) 832844). On Herm, however, bikes are banned and the only way to avoid walking is to arrange a lift on a quad bike or tractor.</p><p>There is a blanket speed limit of 10mph (16kph) across the islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no flights to Sark. It is necessary to fly to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/channel-islands/jersey">Jersey</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/channel-islands/guernsey">Guernsey</a> and take a boat connection to Sark, which takes 50 minutes by ferry from Guernsey and 55 minutes using the inter-island service from Jersey (April-September only). There are no flights to Herm, but there are connections by sea from Guernsey using the Trident ferry.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>London to Guernsey is one hour; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to Jersey is 50 minutes. Visitors from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a> must fly to London (7 hours and 30 minutes) and then change onto a connecting flight.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flybe (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.flybe.com">www.flybe.com</a>), Aurigny (<a href="http://www.aurigny.com" target="_blank">www.aurigny.com</a>) and Blue Islands (<a href="http://www.blueislands.com" target="_blank">www.blueislands.com</a>) all fly to Guernsey from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, while Jersey is served by a host of airlines including British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), Manx2 (<a href="http://www.manx2.com" target="_blank">www.manx2.com</a>), easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>) and Jet2 (<a href="http://www.jet2.com" target="_blank">www.jet2.com</a>). It is also possible to reach Guernsey from Dinard, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/switzerland/geneva-international-airport">Geneva</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/switzerland/zurich-international-airport">Zurich</a>, while Jersey is served by flights from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ireland/dublin-airport">Dublin</a>, , <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany/frankfurt-airport">Frankfurt</a>, Geneva, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france/paris-roissy-charles-de-gaulle-airport">Paris Charles de Gaulle</a>, and Zurich. Non-British nationals will need a passport to travel to the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/channel-islands">Channel Islands</a>, but for British nationals and residents of the Republic of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ireland">Ireland</a> a photographic driver&rsquo;s licence will suffice.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flybe (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.flybe.com">www.flybe.com</a>), Aurigny (<a href="http://www.aurigny.com" target="_blank">www.aurigny.com</a>) and Blue Islands (<a href="http://www.blueislands.com" target="_blank">www.blueislands.com</a>) all fly to Guernsey from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, while Jersey is served by a host of airlines including British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), Manx2 (<a href="http://www.manx2.com" target="_blank">www.manx2.com</a>), easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>) and Jet2 (<a href="http://www.jet2.com" target="_blank">www.jet2.com</a>). It is also possible to reach Guernsey from Dinard, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/switzerland/geneva-international-airport">Geneva</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/switzerland/zurich-international-airport">Zurich</a>, while Jersey is served by flights from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ireland/dublin-airport">Dublin</a>, , <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany/frankfurt-airport">Frankfurt</a>, Geneva, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france/paris-roissy-charles-de-gaulle-airport">Paris Charles de Gaulle</a>, and Zurich. Non-British nationals will need a passport to travel to the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/channel-islands">Channel Islands</a>, but for British nationals and residents of the Republic of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ireland">Ireland</a> a photographic driver&rsquo;s licence will suffice.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All visitors arriving from the UK must transfer at Guernsey or Jersey. Sailings from the UK are with Condor Ferries (tel: 0845 609 1024; <a href="http://www.condorferries.co.uk" target="_blank">www.condorferries.co.uk</a>) departing from Poole, Portsmouth or Weymouth.</p>
<p>Transfer time is approximately 2 hours 10 minutes from Poole and Weymouth to Guernsey, 3 hours 25 minutes to Jersey, and 10 hours 30 minutes from Portsmouth to Jersey or Guernsey. The Manche Iles Express (tel: (01534) 880 756; <a href="http://www.manche-iles-express.com" target="_blank">www.manche-iles-express.com</a>) also operates sailings from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> to Sark via Jersey departing from Granville, with a transfer time of approximately 2 hours. The Isle of Sark Shipping Company (tel: (01481) 724 059; <a href="http://www.sarkshippingcompany.com" target="_blank">www.sarkshippingcompany.com</a>) runs services between Guernsey and Sark (journey time: 45 to 50 minutes). The Manches Iles Express runs from Jersey to Sark and takes approximately 50 minutes. </p><p>There is a landing tax for all visitors to Sark, which is included in the cost of the boat ticket.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>No cars are allowed on either island. Transport options include horse and cart, bicycle and tractor.</p><p>Roads are not tarmacked and cyclists should beware of potholes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good in most areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is one internet café on Sark and free Wi-Fi is available at the Island Hall (tel: (01481) 832 666).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sark has an independent monthly journal, the Sark Scribe (tel: (01481) 832 855; <a href="http://www.sarkscribe.com" target="_blank">www.sarkscribe.com</a>) and a quarterly magazine The Sark Life (<a href="http://www.smallislandpublishing.sark.gg" target="_blank">www.smallislandpublishing.sark.gg</a>). Herm also has a regular newsletter &ndash; sign up through <a href="http://herm.com" target="_blank">http://herm.com</a>. British media are free and able to report on all subjects. The local Channel Islands radio stations are Island FM (<a href="http://www.islandfm.com" target="_blank">www.islandfm.com</a>) and BBC Guernsey.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a post office on Sark (tel: (01481) 832078).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bird watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Birdwatchers from around the world list Sark and Herm as one of their top birding destinations. More than 200 species have been recorded, most being migratory.</p>]]><p><b>Charter a boat trip</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A boat ride around the islands can offer fantastic views of the coastline and make for an enjoyable day trip. There's a chance to spot dolphins as well as get a full view of cliff nesting birds.</p>]]><p><b>Climb inside a cave</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At low tide, it is possible to explore some of the many coastal caves. The Jewel Cave in Sark is one of the most beautiful – it's home to thousands of anemones that cling to the walls and turn the rocks every colour from yellow to mauve. Bear in mind, however, that the cave is only accessibly at low tide and caution is recommended.</p>]]><p><b>Cross La Coupée</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Crossing La Coupée, Sark's iconic isthmus, is a must-do activity. A heady 79m (260ft) above sea level, the crossing was certainly precarious for the island's residents before guard rails, and later, pavement were constructed. Cyclists and horse riders must still dismount.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Creux Harbour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Sark's original serving harbour. Cliff-cut tunnels and pretty bays make for fun exploring or a tranquil picnic stop.</p>]]><p><b>Gardens of La Seigneurie</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Royal Horticultural Society ranked these gardens as among the finest in the Channel Islands. The gardens are open every day from the beginning of April to the end of October.</p>]]><p><b>Go on a day trip to Brecqhou</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Guests at Sark Estate Management's hotels can now take advantage of guided tours to the Barclay brothers' famous private island.</p>]]><p><b>Oystercatcher's Rock</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sark's northernmost point, Bec du Nez or 'Oystercatcher's Rock', provides the viewer with a natural stage from which to take in the sea fresh surroundings.</p>]]><p><b>Pack in the action</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Coasteering, geocaching and kayaking are all on offer in Sark and Herm. For more information, contact Adventure Sark (<a href="http://www.adventuresark.com" target="_blank">www.adventuresark.com</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Sailing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Yacht and boats lovers are drawn to Sark and Herm Island for the splendid sailing. Moorings are located at Havre Gosselin on the west coast of Sark, and at La Gréve de la Ville bay on the east coast.</p>]]><p><b>Sark Windmill</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the Channel Island's remaining old windmills, the Sark windmill was in use until 1917.The tower is topped with a jaunty onion shaped ogee cap.</p>]]><p><b>Sark prison</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Built in 1856, Sark's prison must be one of the world's smallest. Prisoners in the past didn't exactly get a 5-star treatment as it is entirely windowless. The prison is still used today – although not very often!</p>]]><p><b>Sip a pint</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Herm's only pub, the Mermaid Tavern, is the centre of the island's social life. Sandwiches and stomach lining meals are available, not to mention a glorious view with which to enjoy a pint to. On Sark there are three pubs as well as several cafes and restaurants.</p>]]><p><b>Swimming</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Swim in Sark's clean waters and discover secluded beaches. Dixcart Bay has two sandy beaches separated by a natural arch. Tidal pools are also numerous, such as the Venus Pool (a 6.1m/20ft tidal pool) and Adonis Pool; accessible at low tide. Herm Island's coastline is also a great environment for snorkeling, and, further out, diving.</p>]]><p><b>Take a stroll</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Few places in the world can boast zero traffic. Make the most of this safe and picturesque landscape on foot. There are scenic walks along cliffs and pathways throughout. Herm Island takes less than two hours to complete. Pop into the tourist office for maps.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Tom Thumb</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Herm's Tom Thumb Village has been restored from dereliction. Houses, a chapel and woods make for a lighthearted visit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Consumer goods, raw materials, fuels and foodstuffs.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Guernsey, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/channel-islands/jersey">Jersey</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sark and Herm both have economies which are primarily dependent on tourism. There is some farming on both islands, although most local produce is grown to supply the hotels and restaurants. Sark has also attracted wealth from overseas through its status as a tax haven &ndash; it has been described as the only true remaining &lsquo;fiscal paradise&rsquo; in the world, and residents pay an annual property tax, but there is no requirement to disclose income or keep accounts. To claim residency and take advantage of the tax benefits, it is necessary to buy a property or purchase a long-term leasehold on the island. Other cottage industries on Sark and Herm include chocolate-making&nbsp; and fishing.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>The Sark economy suffered a major blow in 2008, when the Barclay brothers resident on neighbouring Brecqhou pulled their investments from the island after local voters did not support their candidates in government elections. They have since re-established their operations in Sark, and now own a third of the island including hotels, restaurants and vineyards. The brothers have reportedly invested &pound;30 million in Sark since 2007.</p>
<br />]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businesspeople are still generally expected to dress smartly (suits are the norm), although the lack of conventional office environments on either island means protocol can be relaxed a little. Roads can be muddy and this, coupled with minimal transport options, means that sensible shoes are recommended. Appointments should be made and the exchange of business cards is customary. Knowledge of English is essential. Business facilities include a business services suite at the Clos De Vaul Creuz (tel: (01481) 832 527; <a href="http://www.closdevaulcreux.co.uk" target="_blank">www.closdevaulcreux.co.uk</a>), which levies a weekly charge of &pound;25 on users. Most hotels have Wi-Fi for the use of guests.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>With its endless supply of fresh seafood, fledgling wine industry and sustainable ethos, Sark is reinventing itself as a true gourmet destination. Much of the produce is grown organically, and the local chefs build their menus around what&rsquo;s in season.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>On Herm, oysters, lobsters and crab dishes sourced straight from the fishing boats are popular, and fantastic French wines and cheeses are imported from nearby Normandy. The island has a small selection of restaurants, including the Ship Inn Brasserie at the White House Hotel (tel: (01481) 750 075) and The Conservatory Restaurant (<a href="http://www.herm.com" target="_blank">www.herm.com</a>). </p>
<br />
<br />
<p>For a taste of Sark, head to one of the six hotels which all offer seasonal, organic produce grown in gardens across the island. Alternatively, Hathaways at La Seigneurie Gardens (<a href="http://www.laseigneuriegardens.com/hathaways.html" target="_blank">www.laseigneuriegardens.com/hathaways.html</a>) is a cafe bar and brasserie that boasts a fusion of English, French and Spanish cuisine prepared by a team of award-winning chefs. There are three other restaurants in the Avenue too. Classic British afternoon teas with cream and scones are a treat that can be found on both islands.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull;	Classic seafood platter<br />
&bull;	Locally caught oysters<br />
&bull;	Fish and chips<br />
&bull;	Roast lamb raised organically on Sark<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>In hotels, a service charge of 10 to 12% is usual, which may be added to the bill. 10 to 15% is usual for restaurants; if this has already been added to the bill, a further tip is not required.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Going out on the islands of Sark and Herm can be a starry experience. The islands provide a relatively light pollution-free spot to gaze at the night sky and its stunning shooting stars. In fact, Sark is considered such a rarity by astronomers that it was recently named the world&rsquo;s first &lsquo;dark sky island&rsquo; by the International Dark Sky Associations (IDA). Nightlife tends to be more about watching the boats bob along at sea, and enjoying a long, leisurely meal. On winter evenings, head the Mermaid Tavern in Herm where its warming fire makes it one of the cosiest spots on the island.</p>
<p>Sark also has a pub called The Mermaid, and other good places to while away an enjoyable evening include the Bel Air Inn (<a href="http://www.belairsark.com" target="_blank">www.belairsark.com</a>) and the Old Smuggler&rsquo;s Bar at Stock&rsquo;s Hotel. Alcohol tends to be well-priced thanks to the liberal taxation system.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shopping is limited in Herm (as you would expect from such a small island), but there are small gifts available. The best place to shop is the small, pretty piazza of shops on the harbour side. One of the most interesting items to take home would be a first day cover with a Herm stamp from the Post Office. Most shops have the classic bucket and spade kits for children, as well as beachwear. There are beach toys aplenty too, such as Frisbees, and some very colourful beach towels. Sea-themed gifts and shells can also be found in the gift shops.</p>
<p>Sark has a good selection of duty free shops along its main shopping street, the Avenue. Look out for Sarkstone jewellery as well as local honey and chocolate. The monthly markets at Sark Visitor Centre are fun, sociable occasions, and feature a range of stalls selling arts and crafts items as well as produce from around the island. </p><p>Generally Mon-Sat 0930-1700, but opening times vary from shop to shop.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a choice of several hotels in Sark, with all tastes and budgets catered for. Some of the best include the Aval du Creux (<a href="http://www.avalducreux.co.uk" target="_blank">www.avalducreux.co.uk</a>), located close to the harbour and within an easy stroll of the main Avenue; La Sablonnerie (<a href="http://www.sablonneriesark.com" target="_blank">www.sablonneriesark.com</a>), an award-winning hotel with a good restaurant and beautiful views; and Stocks (<a href="http://www.stockshotel.com" target="_blank">www.stockshotel.com</a>), an upmarket establishment with spa, gym and swimming facilities.  Herm has one hotel, the White House Hotel, which has a tennis court, croquet lawn and outdoor swimming pool. For further information, contact the Herm Island Administration Office.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guest houses offering B&amp;B facilities are numerous in Sark, and include Sue&rsquo;s B&amp;B and Tea Garden (tel: (01481) 832 107), a friendly, family-run affair; Clos de Menage Country House (tel: (01481) 832 091) and Beau Sejour (<a href="http://www.beausejour.sark.gg" target="_blank">www.beausejour.sark.gg</a>), a luxurious <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/channel-islands/jersey">Jersey</a> stone farmhouse. Some of the guest houses on Sark are run by families who have been living on same plot for hundreds of years, and the owners are happy to talk to guests about the island&rsquo;s history</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a choice of several hotels in Sark, with all tastes and budgets catered for. Some of the best include the Aval du Creux (<a href="http://www.avalducreux.co.uk" target="_blank">www.avalducreux.co.uk</a>), located close to the harbour and within an easy stroll of the main Avenue; La Sablonnerie (<a href="http://www.sablonneriesark.com" target="_blank">www.sablonneriesark.com</a>), an award-winning hotel with a good restaurant and beautiful views; and Stocks (<a href="http://www.stockshotel.com" target="_blank">www.stockshotel.com</a>), an upmarket establishment with spa, gym and swimming facilities.  Herm has one hotel, the White House Hotel, which has a tennis court, croquet lawn and outdoor swimming pool. For further information, contact the Herm Island Administration Office.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a choice of several hotels in Sark, with all tastes and budgets catered for. Some of the best include the Aval du Creux (<a href="http://www.avalducreux.co.uk" target="_blank">www.avalducreux.co.uk</a>), located close to the harbour and within an easy stroll of the main Avenue; La Sablonnerie (<a href="http://www.sablonneriesark.com" target="_blank">www.sablonneriesark.com</a>), an award-winning hotel with a good restaurant and beautiful views; and Stocks (<a href="http://www.stockshotel.com" target="_blank">www.stockshotel.com</a>), an upmarket establishment with spa, gym and swimming facilities.  Herm has one hotel, the White House Hotel, which has a tennis court, croquet lawn and outdoor swimming pool. For further information, contact the Herm Island Administration Office.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Early May Bank Holiday :
							07 May </p><p>Spring Bank Holiday :
							28 May </p><p>Summer Bank Holiday :
							27 August </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Channel Islands are not part of the UK or the EU and are subject to different allowances. To complicate matters further there are duty free differences between the Bailiwick of Jersey and the Bailiwick of Guernsey (which includes the islands of Alderney, Sark, Herm, Jethou and Lihou).</p><p>The following goods may be imported into the Bailiwick of Jersey by travellers over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p><p>• 200 cigarettes or 250g of other tobacco products.<br/>• 1L of spirits.<br/>• 4L of wine.<br/>• 16L of beer or cider.<br/>• Other goods to a value of £390 (reduced to £270 if arriving by private plane or boat).</p><p>Alternatively, you may import more wine or beer if you don't bring in any spirits or tobacco. In this case, you may import:</p><p>• 36L of table wine or 48 x 750ml bottles of wine or 110L of beer.</p><p>The following goods may be imported into Bailiwick of Guernsey by travellers over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p><p>• 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br/>• 4L of still table wine.<br/>• 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of fortified wine/sparkling wine/liqueurs or an additional 4L of still table wine.<br/>• 50L of beer of cider.<br/>• An unlimited value of other goods (if coming from within the EU) or goods to the value of £390 (if coming from a non-EU country; reduced to  £270 if arriving by private plane or boat).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted goods include unlicensed drugs, offensive weapons, obscene or pornographic material, and counterfeit goods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Channel Islands have their own notes – the Guernsey pound and the Jersey pound, both of which are at par with the UK pound. Pound Sterling (JEP; symbol £) = 100 pence. Notes are in denominations of £50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of £2, £1, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 pence.<br/><br/>Channel Islands notes and coins are not accepted in the UK, although they can be reconverted at parity in UK banks. Sark, Herm and Alderney use the Guernsey pound.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies can be exchanged at bureaux de change, in banks and at many hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are all widely accepted.</p><p>On the main islands of Jersey and Guernsey ATMs are widespread and accessible, whilst on Alderney there are two ATMs.</p><p>There are no cash machines on Sark or Herm, so visitors are advised to withdraw money before travelling to the islands - Guernsey has a multitude of ATMs. Sark has a NatWest bank (tel: (01481) 832 090;<a href="http://www.natwestinternational.com" target="_blank">www.natwestinternational.com</a>), which is open Mon-Fri 0930-1230 and 1400-1500, and an HSBC (tel: 0845 600 6161;<a href="http://www.hsbc.com" target="_blank">www.hsbc.com</a>), open Mon-Fri 0930-1230 and 1400-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted in larger establishments. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0930-1530. Some banks are open later on weekdays and Saturday mornings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[49.430191]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-2.360903]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Sark:</strong> 5.5 sq km (2.1 sq miles). <strong>Herm:</strong> 2 sq km (0.8 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sark: 492 (2015). Herm: 79 (2015, includes the island of Jethou).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sark: 89.5 per sq km. Herm: 39.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sark: Self-governing depency of the British Crown. Herm: Dependency of Guernsey.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sark and Herm are close to mainland <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a>. To the east of the islands lies <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/channel-islands/guernsey">Guernsey</a>, to the west the Normandy coast, to the north <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/channel-islands/alderney">Alderney</a> and to the south <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/channel-islands/jersey">Jersey</a>.</p>
<p>Just 2.4km (1.5 miles) long and 0.8km (0.5 miles) wide, Herm is largely flat and is dominated by its sandy beaches. The tiny island of Jethou, which lies just off its south coast, was connected to Herm before a storm washed away the land that connected the two in the late eighth century. &nbsp;</p>
<p>Sark&rsquo;s landmass is divided into two parts &ndash; Greater Sark and Little Sark &ndash; which are connected by a narrow belt of land called La Coupee. Until protective railings were erected here at the beginning of the 20th century, residents wishing to cross had to crawl on their hands and knees to avoid being blown over the side.</p>
<p>The island&rsquo;s highest point is just 114m (374 ft) above sea level, and is nicknamed <em>Le Moulin</em> after the windmill that once stood there. Its interior is mainly gently rolling fields bordered by sandy bays and dramatic granite cliffs &ndash; the sea cave formations that pepper these cliffs are one of the most spectacular features on Sark.</p>
<p>The island of Brecqhou to the west, owned by the Barclay brothers since 1993, is also officially part of Sark.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Church of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england">England</a>, Presbyterian, Baptist, Congregational and Methodist.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is the customary form of greeting and normal social courtesies should be observed when visiting someone's home. It is not usual to start eating until everyone is served. If invited to someone's home, a small present such as flowers or chocolates is appreciated. Casual wear is acceptable in most places. Smoking is banned in enclosed public places.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with three square pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sark: Seneschal Jeremy La Trobe-Bateman since 2013 and President of Chief Pleas Reg Guille since 2013. Herm: Chief Minister Jonathan Le Tocq since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Lieutenant Governor Ian Corder since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Swashbuckling pirates, secretive smugglers, daring invasions &ndash; the history of Sark and Herm reads more like a book of fairy tales than a plain account of fact.</p>
<p>William the Conqueror annexed both islands to the Duchy of Normandy in 1066 when monks formed the majority of the population, but after the division of Normandy in 1204 the community dwindled. Herm became a hunting ground for the governors of Guernsey and Sark became a raiding base for pirates and smugglers.</p>
<p>Both islands were occupied by the Nazis during WWII and Sark almost suffered a more recent invasion in 1990&hellip; from an unemployed nuclear physicist called Andre Gardes. He set out for Sark armed with a semi-automatic weapon and a box of flyers advertising his intention to seize control the next day at noon. The morning before the invasion he was tracked down by Sark&rsquo;s constable, who complimented his weapon, persuaded him to hand it over and promptly arrested him.</p>
<p>Sark has a fully democratic government &ndash; 28 members elected to the parliament, called the Chief Pleas. Its first full elections in 2008 ended the 450-year-old fiefdom and the island&rsquo;s status as Europe&rsquo;s last remaining feudal state. However, the feudal lord, the Seigneur (aka John Michael Beaumont, who inherited the title in 1974) remains in a largely ceremonial role.</p>
<p>Herm is owned by the States of Guernsey and leased to a single tenant, on condition that the public has access to its foreshore and other parts of the island.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Until 2008 the Seigneur was the only person on Sark allowed to keep pigeons, or an unspayed dog.<br />
&bull;	Sark has no tax on income, capital gains or inheritance and no VAT on goods and services.<br />
&bull;	There is no airport on Sark and it is a car-free zone.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Life moves at an altogether slower place on Sark and Herm. Floating off the coast of northern France, these lesser-known Channel Islands are amongst the last car-free islands in Europe &ndash; the only way to explore their secluded bays and wind-bitten headlands is by bike or on foot. How quaint.</p>
<p>Though not part of France or the United Kingdom, Sark and Herm are officially classed as British Crown Dependencies and offer a chance to escape the trials and tribulations of life in mainland Europe.</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s plenty to keep visitors occupied. Indulge your taste buds with a gastronomic tour of the islands, sampling local produce at restaurants such as La Sablonnerie, Stocks Hotel and the Ship Inn Brasserie.</p>
<p>Nature lovers are also well catered for. Climb down the rocky steps at La Grande Greve and explore one of the most stunning sandy bays in the Channel Islands or take your binoculars to Little Sark and scout for puffins and oystercatchers.</p>
<p>Unspoiled by rampant development, Sark and Herm are almost entirely devoted to tourism and have long been popular day-tip destinations for those staying on the larger Channel Islands of Guernsey and Jersey.</p>
<p>Despite their fledgling adventure tourism industry, which is focussed on coasteering and kayaking, Sark and Herm are essentially destinations based around peace, quiet and relaxation.</p>
<p>If your idea of a great time is a quiet country ramble followed by an afternoon on the beach, a cream tea and then a fantastic evening meal, these tranquil islands are the place for you.</p><p>Life moves at an altogether slower place on Sark and Herm. Floating off the coast of northern France, these lesser-known Channel Islands are amongst the last car-free islands in Europe &ndash; the only way to explore their secluded bays and wind-bitten headlands is by bike or on foot. How quaint.&nbsp;Though not part of France or the United Kingdom, Sark and Herm are officially classed as British Crown Dependencies and offer a chance to escape the trials and tribulations of life in mainland Europe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
