<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Northern Ireland" ColCode="nir" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ni" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Northern Ireland]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In general the weather is similar to the rest of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, but Northern Ireland tends to have less sunshine and more rain. The hilly nature of the terrain tends to attracts clouds, and westerly winds are common in some areas. Extremes of temperature are rare but conditions can be changeable. In broad terms, however, it has an equable climate – the effects of the Atlantic Gulf Stream have a moderating influence, leading to mild winters and relatively cool summers. The mean annual temperature in Northern Ireland at low-lying altitude is around 9C. </p><p>
The height of summer draws the largest numbers of tourists, particularly to headline attractions such as Giant's Causeway, so it can be advisable to come in spring or autumn to make the most of the reduction in visitors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Similar to the rest of the UK, according to season. Waterproofs are advisable throughout the year. If you find yourself lacking any vital wardrobe items on arrival – formal or informal – all key towns and cities are well stocked with clothing outlets, with the larger cities particularly good in terms of picking up high quality outdoor equipment. Camping essentials are also straightforward to come by.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no scheduled internal flights within Northern Ireland, due to the short distances between major centres. Belfast and Derry/Londonderry are separated by just 100 km (62 miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Northern Ireland's only inhabited island is Rathlin, a few kilometres off the north coast. Rathlin Island Ferry Ltd (tel: 028 2076 9299; <a href="http://www.rathlinballycastleferry.com" target="_blank">www.rathlinballycastleferry.com</a>) operates regular services between Ballycastle and Rathlin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main rail routes out of Belfast include those heading north to Derry/Londonderry via Ballymena and Coleraine; northeast to the port of Larne; and east to Bangor along the shores of Belfast Lough.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Freedom of Northern Ireland Pass is available for unlimited travel on trains and buses. It can be bought at main Northern Ireland railway stations as a one-day, three-day or seven-day pass.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are several freeways leading in and out of Belfast, with subsidiary main roads linking all the key settlements around the country. There are currently no toll roads, although this is due to change with the building of the Belfast-Larne toll road.</p>l<p>Road quality is typically of a high standard in Northern Ireland, with similar levels of maintenance to the rest of the UK.</p><p>Ulsterbus, managed by Translink (tel: 028 9066 6630; <a href="http://www.translink.co.uk" target="_blank">www.translink.co.uk</a>)  has a comprehensive network of bus routes around the country.</p><p>Available at main stations, ports and Belfast International Airport and are also bookable by telephone in larger towns and cities.</p><p>A valid drivers' licence is required if driving a car in Northern Ireland.</p><p>The speed limit is 30mph (48kph) in towns and cities unless signs show 40mph (64kph) or 50mph (80kph). On country roads, the limit is 60mph (96kph); on dual carriageways, trunk roads and motorways, 70mph (112kph), unless signs show otherwise.</p><p>If the car is hired, contact the hire company. Members of the continental equivalent of the AA (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.theaa.com/">www.theaa.com</a>) can contact their 24-hour breakdown service. The RAC (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.rac.co.uk/">www.rac.co.uk</a>) provides a similar service. They can be contacted from their roadside phones or from any call box. Non-members should consult the Yellow Pages for breakdown services.</p><p>The main firms operate in Northern Ireland and have desks at both Belfast airports with cars available on the spot. There is also a host of smaller firms.</p><p>Cycling is a fantastic way of taking in the country's diverse scenery. The National Cycle Network in Northern Ireland extends for more than (1290 km) 800 miles, mainly on quiet rural roads. It includes more than 160 km (100 miles) of traffic-free paths. Bike rental is available in most regions.</p><p>The speed limit is 30mph (48kph) in towns and cities unless signs show 40mph (64kph) or 50mph (80kph). On country roads, the limit is 60mph (96kph); on dual carriageways, trunk roads and motorways, 70mph (112kph), unless signs show otherwise.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public transport is of a good standard in Belfast with numerous rail and bus lines, although the lines tend to radiate from the centre, making it time-consuming to get from one suburb to another. There are good bus routes around Derry/Londonderry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are frequent direct flights to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/northern-ireland/belfast-international-airport">Belfast</a> from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> airports as well as other major regional <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> airports. Derry/Londonderry is also served. Airlines that serve Northern Ireland from the UK include Flybe (<a href="http://www.flybe.com" target="_blank">www.flybe.com</a>) and easyJet (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.easyjet.com">www.easyjet.com</a>), which also flies between Belfast and several other European cities. From North America, United Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.united.com">www.united.com</a>) currently has a direct service between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a> (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-jersey/newark-liberty-international-airport">Newark Liberty International Airport</a>) and Belfast. As elsewhere, flights to Northern Ireland become pricier over major holiday periods.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London to Belfast is 1 hour 15 minutes. From New York to Belfast is 6 hours 35 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It's not obligatory for British nationals to carry a passport when taking a flight between Northern Ireland and other parts of the UK. However, most carriers will insist on some form of ID.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It's not obligatory for British nationals to carry a passport when taking a flight between Northern Ireland and other parts of the UK. However, most carriers will insist on some form of ID.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>George Best Belfast City Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.belfastcityairport.com<p>George Best Belfast City Airport is situated 3km (2 miles) east of Belfast.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+44 28 9093 9093</p>]]><b>Belfast International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.belfastairport.com<p>Belfast International Airport is located 30km (18 miles) northwest of Belfast city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+44 28 9448 4848</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Northern Ireland is easily accessible by water. The main ports are Belfast (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.belfast-harbour.co.uk/">www.belfast-harbour.co.uk</a>) and Larne (<a href="http://www.portoflarne.co.uk" target="_blank">www.portoflarne.co.uk</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a cross-border rail service from Belfast Central Station, heading south to Dublin, in the Irish Republic, via Newry. The Belfast-Dublin non-stop express takes approximately two hours. For information on timetables for rail services, contact Translink (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.translink.co.uk">www.translink.co.uk</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Numerous roads cross the border from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ireland">Ireland</a> into Northern Ireland, by far the most travelled being the Irish N1/M1 motorway from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ireland/dublin-airport">Dublin</a>, which becomes the A1 road when it reaches the Northern Irish border.</p><p>It was announced in late 2012 that a new toll road is to be built between Belfast and the port of Larne on the northeast coast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Cast a line into Lough Erne</b></p><![CDATA[<p>From its salmon to its sea trout, Northern Ireland's fish stock means it's considered one of Europe's best angling destinations. Try Lower Lough Erne in the Fermanagh Lakelands for a prime fishing spot. The rivers of the Causeway Coast in Antrim have several fruitful options too.</p>]]><p><b>Climb Cave Hill</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Giving a broad panorama over Belfast city and the surrounding coastal hills, Cave Hill is a rewarding place to head for an overview of the capital region – from the bold cranes of the docks to the silvery waters of Belfast Lough. Measuring 368m (1207 ft) at its peak, it's said that on a clear day, you can see as far as Scotland.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the Marble Arch Caves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take an underground boat trip to see the magnificent caverns of Marble Arch Caves in County Fermanagh. Together with the rolling landscapes above ground, the caves form the Marble Arch Caves Geopark give rich insight into the region's 650 million years of geological glory.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the charms of Derry</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Northern Ireland's second city, which combines a riverside setting and a glut of historical sights with an artsy oomph that saw it named the UK's Capital of Culture for 2013. Its name remains a slightly hazy notion (the politically correct version is Londonderry), but its visitor appeal is anything but.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy a pint in a fine Victorian gin palace</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Belfast's most famous pub, the Crown Liquor Saloon is a splendidly ornate Victorian gin palace renowned for its glittering decor, its long history (it dates back to 1826) and its wide selection of real ales. Order a pint, find a nook and let the worries of the world drift away.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy the striking landscape over the Glens of Antrim</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Admire the nine interlinking Glens of Antrim, a designated Area of Outstanding Natural Beauty, which run inland from the rugged and spectacular eastern coast. Covering a distance of some 52sq km (20sq miles), the area incorporates everything from glacial valleys and sandy beaches to waterfalls and forests.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Devenish Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A 'holy island' in Lough Erne, Devenish Island in County Fermanagh still bears the remains of an Augustinian monastery, including a church, an abbey and a plethora of old gravestones. It's stirring stuff – the island is accessible by ferry from the landing in nearby Trory.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the remains of Dunluce Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once the seat of the Earls of Antrim, the fiercely picturesque Dunluce Castle sits half-ruined on a coastal crag. Its cliff top remains can be explored at will (once you've paid for entry) and crossing the bridge and entering the courtyard, it's surprising to see how large the medieval castle once was.</p>]]><p><b>Hike the heights of the Mourne Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The granite bulk of the Mourne Mountains forms a brooding backdrop to one of the most appealing corners of Northern Ireland – a picture-book amalgam of coast, hillside and wide sky. Their tranquil centrepiece, the aptly named Silent Valley Reservoir, sits surrounded by cottage-speckled valleys and wild slopes. It's little wonder it draws hill walkers and rock climbers.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the links</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rory McIlroy, Darren Clarke and Graeme McDowell – familiar names on golf leaderboards the planet over – all hail from Northern Ireland, and the country has the courses to match. Royal Portrush and Royal County Down at Newcastle are among its most renowned links courses.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in Belfast</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once the most troubled city in Europe, the last two decades have wrought an extraordinary transformation in Belfast and have seen the Northern Ireland capital become one of the UK's most interesting cities. Fine restaurants, lively boozers and a burgeoning collection of cultural attractions are just part of the city's appeal.</p>]]><p><b>Learn of the Troubles with a tour of Shankill and Falls Road</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The best guided tours to brace the Troubles (the ethno-nationalist conflict that blighted Northern Ireland for 50 years) are by black cab drivers who bring</p><p>Belfast's troubled modern history to life. They head along the Shankill and the Falls Roads, taking in the imposing Peace Lines and the famed Republican and Unionist wall murals.</p>]]><p><b>Revel in the relics at Ulster Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Trawl through Northern Ireland's best collection of art, archaeology and natural history at Belfast's Ulster Museum. It's free to enter, and inside you'll find eye-opening relics from Ancient Egypt, the South Pacific, Africa and elsewhere. There's also some very interesting stuff on Ireland's early days too, as well as various art collections.</p>]]><p><b>Step aboard the Titanic</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Unveiled to great fanfare in 2012, on the slipways where the RMS Titanic was built, this large-scale visitor attraction extends over nine galleries, taking visitors through the construction, launch and ill-fated voyage of the world's best-known ocean liner. Titanic Belfast opened 100 years after the ship's infamous sinking.</p>]]><p><b>Step back in time at the Ulster Folk &amp; Transport Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located on the outskirts of Belfast, the Ulster Folk & Transport Museum is two quality attractions in one. The Folk Museum gives visitors the chance to wander through farms, cottages and homesteads preserved as they would have been 100 years ago. The Transport Museum is a lovingly maintained collection of trams, motorbikes and vintage cars.</p>]]><p><b>Taste a tumbler of fine Irish whiskey</b></p><![CDATA[<p>You'll find the Old Bushmills Distillery in the village of (that's right) Bushmills in the north of County Antrim. It bills itself as Ireland's oldest distillery, and has been knocking out barrels of the good stuff for more than 400 years. Take a tour to get to the heart of the whiskey-making process.</p>]]><p><b>Tour the country on two wheels</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its quiet minor roads, exceptional natural sites and fine coastal paths, cyclists in Northern Ireland are spoilt for choice. Whether you take to the tarmac or venture off-road, the National Cycle Network has over 1,600km (995 miles) of routes from long distance rides to short trails for a lighter jaunt.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the grave of St Patrick, Down Cathedral</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the pilgrimage site of Ireland's patron saint, St Patrick. He may be the reason that massive amounts of Guinness are imbibed worldwide every 17 March, but his burial site at Down Cathedral is a more sobering affair – a lonely granite slab in the churchyard marks his grave.</p>]]><p><b>Wonder at the Giant's Causeway</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ireland's most famous World Heritage Site is a natural wonder, an otherworldly rock formation of some 40,000 basalt columns. Located on the Antrim coastline, the Giant's Causeway draws visitors in droves – try arriving at sunset for fewer crowds and spectacular photo opportunities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>With its rich agricultural land and winding coastline, it's no surprise that Northern Ireland has a good quality of fresh meat and plentiful fish. Eel is used in dishes around the Lough Neagh area. Hearty stews, speciality bread and sticky cakes are specialities across the province. Look out for good independent bakeries where you can try distinctive local breads such as puffy soda farls or the flatter potato farls. Portion size tends to lean towards the massive, so you shouldn't go hungry. A hearty breakfast is a must at least once, when the traditional Ulster Fry, including bacon, eggs, sausages and soda bread, will set you up nicely for the day.</p>
<p>Northern Ireland is presently the only country in the United Kingdom without any Michelin-starred restaurants. It has had them in the recent past, however, and the fact is far from indicative of there being a paucity of good places to eat. Belfast and Derry/Londonderry are particularly strong when it comes to &lsquo;casual&rsquo; fine dining, with an emphasis on fresh local produce and some genuinely inventive menus to choose from. The Good Food Guide &ndash; a rival to Michelin &ndash; has been particularly glowing about several Northern Irish restaurants. </p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; An Ulster fry - eggs, sausages, bacon rashers, mushrooms, beans, fried tomato, sometimes with further components.<br />
&bull; Shellfish.<br />
&bull; Homemade vegetable soups.<br />
&bull; Irish stew.<br />
&bull; Dried seaweed.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Pubs are open all day Mon-Sat 1130-2300 and Sun 1230-2200 with half an hour 'drinking-up' time. Pubs in Belfast often stay open Thurs-Sat until 0100. As elsewhere in the UK smoking is banned in pubs and restaurants.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>There's a similar attitude to tipping as there is in other parts of the UK, with 10 to 15% a typical amount if you've enjoyed a meal out and been pleased with the service you've received. When eating in basic cafes or drinking in pubs, tipping is not generally expected.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>You must be 18 to legally purchase alcohol in a pub. 16-year-olds are able to drink with a meal if the drink is purchased by an adult.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Northern <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/i/ireland"><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ireland">Ireland</a></a> has a strong tradition for musical entertainment, from toe-tapping live folk bands playing in crowded pubs to the soulful lyrics of Van Morrison and the world-famous talent of flautist James Galway. The country&rsquo;s punkier heritage shines through with legendary rock bands like The Undertones and Stiff Little Fingers, while modern rock alumni include the likes of Ash and Snow Patrol.</p>
<p>Visitors, therefore, can generally find something to suit, from dance music to opera or classical concerts. Belfast&rsquo;s nightlife has earned itself a pretty serious reputation, with many of its bars and pubs drawing plaudits and a host of nightclubs banging out beats for seemingly insatiable crowds of clubbers.</p>
<p>For a slightly gentler pace, traditional Irish music in 'singing pubs' provides a good evening's entertainment in many places, particularly <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/i/belfast"><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/northern-ireland/belfast-international-airport">Belfast</a></a> and Londonderry. Special musical events include the summerJazz and Blues Festival in Londonderry and Limavady and the October Ards Guitar Festival held in Newtownards.<br />
<br />
There are also a wealth of theatres and art galleries located in and around Belfast, including the famous Lyric Theatre, where Liam Neeson started his career. There are summer theatres in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england/newcastle-international-airport">Newcastle</a> and Portrush, plus theRiverside Theatre at Coleraine. The Belfast Festival at Queen's (three weeks in November each year) is Ireland's biggest international festival. Other main venues for drama performances and concerts are the Grand Opera House, Ulster Hall, King's Hall and the Waterfront Hall (all in Belfast), the Armagh Theatre and Arts Centre and the Millennium Forum in Derry, and numerous regional theatres. Further information can be obtained from the Northern Ireland Arts Council (<a href="http://www.artscouncil-ni.org/" target="_blank">www.artscouncil-ni.org</a>)<em> </em>or from the Northern Ireland Tourist Board&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.discovernorthernireland.com" target="_blank">www.discovernorthernireland.com</a>).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Northern   <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ireland">Ireland</a> is renowned for its crafts; whether it is pure Irish linen, cut-glass goblets, creamy Belleek pottery, handmade tweed, hand-embroidered wall hangings, Carrickmacross lace, or silver jewellery. For trendy boutiques packed with designer clothes, art and jewellery, <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/i/belfast"><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/northern-ireland/belfast-international-airport">Belfast</a></a>'s Lisburn Road is the place to visit, while Victoria Square in Belfast is a contemporary shopping centre for fashion and toys &ndash; it has more than 70 stores, cafes and restaurants. Major towns such as Ballymena also have a good selection of high street shops. &nbsp;</p>
<p>For fresh produce and the simmering atmosphere of a traditional place of commerce, meanwhile, St George&rsquo;s Market has been drawing Belfast shoppers since the early 1600s. The market has been in its present building since the 1890s, and thrums to life every Friday and Saturday for the Variety Market (Friday 0600 - 1300) and the City Food &amp; Garden Market (Saturday 0900 - 1500).</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the city of Lisburn &ndash; located a short way outside of Belfast &ndash; has become something of a retail attraction in its own right, with two large shopping complexes &ndash; Bow Street Mall and the Sprucefield Shopping Centre. &nbsp;</p>
<p>Away from the capital, Derry/Londonderry is home to what claims to be the world's oldest independent department store, the classy Austins, which opened its doors in 1830. It occupies a five-storey Edwardian building and makes an excellent place to purchase Irish crystal and giftware. In the south, Newry has a couple of diverting weekly markets &ndash; the Buttercrane Farmers&rsquo; Market, held each Sunday, is a great showcase for local produce.</p><p>Shops are generally open Mon-Sat 0900-1800, Sun 1300-1800 (Thurs late-night shopping in Belfast city centre until 2100). Other cities and towns close for a half-day one day a week (it differs from town to town). Modern shopping centres on the outskirts of towns have late-night shopping Thurs-Fri until 2100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A wide range of accommodation is available in Northern Ireland. Most establishments belong to the Northern Ireland Hotels Federation (<a href="http://www.nihf.co.uk/" target="_blank">www.nihf.co.uk</a>).which is the representative body for hotels, guesthouses and other accommodation providers. The broad choice of different properties means the country can cater well for those in search of a specific theme, be that a golfing break, pet-friendly accommodation, a rural hideaway or a family holiday. The best of the city and countryside hotels, meanwhile, are of an impressive quality – five-star options include Lough Erne Resort and the sumptuous Merchant Hotel, which occupies what was once the headquarters of the Ulster Bank. <br /><strong><br />Grading:</strong> The Northern Irish Tourist Board operates a 'star' classification system, rating hotels from 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are numerous bed & breakfasts and guest houses listed on the Northern Ireland Tourist Board's website.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A wide range of accommodation is available in Northern Ireland. Most establishments belong to the Northern Ireland Hotels Federation (<a href="http://www.nihf.co.uk/" target="_blank">www.nihf.co.uk</a>).which is the representative body for hotels, guesthouses and other accommodation providers. The broad choice of different properties means the country can cater well for those in search of a specific theme, be that a golfing break, pet-friendly accommodation, a rural hideaway or a family holiday. The best of the city and countryside hotels, meanwhile, are of an impressive quality – five-star options include Lough Erne Resort and the sumptuous Merchant Hotel, which occupies what was once the headquarters of the Ulster Bank. <br /><strong><br />Grading:</strong> The Northern Irish Tourist Board operates a 'star' classification system, rating hotels from 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A wide range of accommodation is available in Northern Ireland. Most establishments belong to the Northern Ireland Hotels Federation (<a href="http://www.nihf.co.uk/" target="_blank">www.nihf.co.uk</a>).which is the representative body for hotels, guesthouses and other accommodation providers. The broad choice of different properties means the country can cater well for those in search of a specific theme, be that a golfing break, pet-friendly accommodation, a rural hideaway or a family holiday. The best of the city and countryside hotels, meanwhile, are of an impressive quality – five-star options include Lough Erne Resort and the sumptuous Merchant Hotel, which occupies what was once the headquarters of the Ulster Bank. <br /><strong><br />Grading:</strong> The Northern Irish Tourist Board operates a 'star' classification system, rating hotels from 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>St Patrick's Day :
							18 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Early May Bank Holiday :
							07 May </p><p>Spring Bank Holiday :
							28 May </p><p>Battle of the Boyne (Orangemen's Day) :
							12 July </p><p>Summer Bank Holiday :
							27 August </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pound (GBP; symbol &pound;) = 100 pence. Notes are in denominations of &pound;50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of &pound;2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 pence. Euros are also accepted in larger stores.</p>
<p>Ulster Bank issues banknotes specifically for use in the country. These are technically not legal tender elsewhere in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> &ndash; just as Bank of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england">England</a> notes are technically not legal tender outside of England and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/wales">Wales</a>. It&rsquo;s not uncommon for either note to be accepted outside of its set zone (the official line is that &ldquo;the&nbsp;acceptability of a Northern Ireland note as a means of payment is essentially a matter for&nbsp;agreement between the parties involved&rdquo;), but it may be advisable not to travel elsewhere in the UK with a surplus of Ulster Bank notes. &nbsp;</p>
<p>If crossing into the Irish Republic, be aware that pound sterling is not accepted as a means of payment, other than in a few outlets in the border regions. Have a supply of euros.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some hotels will change money but banks and bureaux de change give the best rate of exchange.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa and Mastercard are accepted, as are Maestro debit cards. Acceptance of Amex is generally lower, and confined to larger businesses.</p><p>Cash can be obtained from a multitude of ATMs available across the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Widely accepted. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1600. In very small villages, the bank may open two or three days a week only, so aim to get cash in the bigger centres.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[54.787715]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-6.492315]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>13,576 sq km (5,242 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1.8 million (2014).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>135.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belfast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A consociational (which roughly means 'power-sharing') devolved government within a constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Northern Ireland contains some beautiful scenery, from the rugged coastline in the north and northeast to the gentle fruit-growing regions of Armagh. To the west are the Sperrin Mountains and the lake of Fermanagh, where the winding River Erne provides excellent fishing.</p>
<p>The high moorland plateau of Antrim in the northeast gives way to the glens further south and to the Drumlin country of County Down; further south still, the Mountains of Mourne stretch down to the sea.</p>
<p>The country comprises six historic counties: County Antrim, County Armagh, County Down, County Fermanagh, County Derry/Londonderry and County Tyrone. On which note, Northern Ireland is still sometimes spoken about as Ulster, despite the fact that it includes only six of the nine counties that comprised the historic Irish province (the other three are across the border in the Irish Republic).</p>
<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/northern-ireland/belfast-international-airport">Belfast</a> sits in the east of the country, at the point where the River Lagan reaches the sea. This strategic location, being easily accessible from various parts of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> mainland, was integral to its heritage as a major shipbuilding destination. The hills around the city, which some claim resemble a sleeping giant, are said to be the inspiration for Jonathan Swift&rsquo;s classic novel Gulliver&rsquo;s Travels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Predominantly Christian (Church of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england">England</a>, Roman Catholic, Presbyterian, Methodist), sizeable Muslim, Sikh, Jewish and Hindu minorities. Around 15% of the population have no (or unstated) religion, despite the fact that Northern Ireland is considered the most religious country in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">United Kingdom</a>, with more churchgoers than elsewhere.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Due to the still-sensitive political situation in Northern Ireland, visitors should avoid expressing dogmatic opinions on political or religious topics. At the same time, it&rsquo;s important not to overplay the risks involved with visiting the country, which for tourists are very slim. <br />
<br />
Handshaking is customary when introduced to someone for the first time. Likewise, normal social courtesies should be observed when visiting someone's home and a small present such as flowers or chocolates will always be appreciated. It is standard practice to wait until everyone has been served before eating.</p>
<p>In general terms, the Irish people are renowned for their congeniality, good humour and easygoing nature, and the pub remains perhaps the ideal setting in which to get a true feel for the pulse of the nation. Smoking is banned in all public enclosed spaces, including pubs, bars and restaurants.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with three square pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Theresa May since 2016 (head of UK&nbsp;government); First Minister Arlene Foster since 2016 (First Minister of Northern Ireland Assembly).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sectarian divisions between its Catholics and Protestants scar the history of Northern Ireland where huge murals depict conflicts past and present, but increasingly document peace and cultural diversity.</p>
<p>In the 17th century, the so-called Ulster Plantations saw Scottish Presbyterian settlers come to the region although English monarchs before and after laid claim to it, often ruthlessly.</p>
<p>The 1920 Partition of Ireland gave home rule to its six north-eastern counties and created the Irish Free State (now the sovereign Republic of Ireland) ruled from Dublin. This remains the root cause for the ethno-nationalist violence that overshadowed Northern Ireland for much of the 20th century. The most strife-ridden period, from 1968 to 1998, is known as the Troubles.</p>
<p>The 1970s brought civil disorder, internment, troops on the streets and bombing campaigns that spread throughout the United Kingdom before peace negotiations began in the mid-1990s. The Good Friday Agreement (officially the Belfast Agreement) was signed on 10 April 1998 and the Northern Ireland Assembly was set up in 1999.</p>
<p>Representatives of all parties took part and, although the Assembly was largely suspended from 2000 to 2006, an historic meeting between Gerry Adams of the republican Sinn F&eacute;in and ardent nationalist Ian Paisley of the Democratic Unionist Party took place in 2007 as the Assembly was restored.</p>
<p>Sadly, while life goes on relatively peacefully, it would be wrong to claim the scars of the Troubles have completely healed.&nbsp;Social tensions have raised their heads periodically since the restoration of the Assembly, notably in December 2012 and early 2013, when a decision to limit the number of days the Union Flag flew outside Belfast City Hall was met with violent demonstrations.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Having suffered 28 bomb attacks during the Troubles, Belfast&rsquo;s four-star Europa Hotel continues to be known as the most bombed hotel in Europe.<br />
&bull;	Louise Walsh&rsquo;s sculpture, <em>Monument to the Unknown Woman Worker </em>on Great Victoria Street in Belfast is a testament to women&rsquo;s rights.<br />
&bull;	Belfast City Airport was renamed in 2006 in honour of football hero George Best.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Northern Ireland distils the best of Britain into a bite-sized bundle: its plunging glens and pristine lochs are as gorgeous as any in Scotland; its quaint countryside villages as olde-worlde as anything in rural Wales; and Belfast borrows its Victorian pomp from London.<br />
<br />
Of course, it&rsquo;s irrefutably Irish too, and few visitors get further than ordering a pint of Guinness before encountering the wit and loquacious charm of its inhabitants.</p>
<p>This hasn&rsquo;t always been the case. For decades it was best avoided due to the riots and bombings of The Troubles, which erupted between Unionists and Republicans. But since 1998&rsquo;s Good Friday Agreement, which calmed the fighting and quelled the geopolitical disorder, tourists are starting to appreciate what they&rsquo;ve missed for so long.</p>
<p>Covering little more than a sixth of the Irish landmass, Northern Ireland has plenty to pique attention: from majestic mountains and bracing coastline to ancient monasteries and toe-tapping live music joints.</p>
<p>As locals will proudly tell you, <em>Game of Thrones</em> was filmed across the country, and coaches now make their way to Dragonstone (Downhill Beach), The Haunted Forest (Tollymore Forest Park) and Beric Dondarrion&rsquo;s hideout (Pollnagollum Cave) for picture opportunities.</p>
<p>Belfast remains the showpiece. Its patched history offset by unbridled nightlife, major cultural attractions (not least the incredible Titanic Belfast museum) and an invigorating restaurant scene. Further west, highbrow arts and goodtime festivals thrive in absorbing Londonderry, while the tiny cathedral city of Armagh still stands as the ecclesiastical capital of all Ireland.</p>
<p>From the rugged hills of County Armagh and the quiet loughs of County Down to the granite bulk of the Mountains of Mourne, its al fresco treats are many, but one indoor pursuit prevails: drinking, which is as important here as it is south of the border. From countryside boozers to time-burnished city saloons, you&rsquo;re never far from a pub here.</p>
<p>Northern Ireland&rsquo;s compact size stands as a selling point. You can sample the pulse of city living, see the sea-bashed magnificence of the Giant&rsquo;s Causeway, and then mosey back via its mollifying mountains &ndash; all in the space of a few days.</p>Northern Ireland distils the best of Britain into a bite-sized bundle: its plunging glens and pristine lochs are as gorgeous as any in Scotland; its quaint countryside villages as olde-worlde as anything in rural Wales; and Belfast borrows its Victorian pomp from London.
 
Of course, it's irrefutably Irish too, and few visitors get further than ordering a pint of Guinness before encountering the wit and loquacious charm of its inhabitants.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
