<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Uruguay" ColCode="ury" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="uy" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Uruguay]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Uruguay has an exceptionally fine temperate climate, with mild summers and winters. Summer is from December to March and is the most pleasant time, especially along the coast. Beach resorts get crowded between Christmas and February, with peak crowds during the month of January. In the interior and along the Río Uruguay, January is the hottest month, with temperatures sometimes climbing uncomfortably above 30˚C (86°F). For fine weather and quieter conditions countrywide, December and March are good months to visit. Winter and spring can get chilly due to wind and rain, but temperatures remain dependably above freezing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bring lightweight clothing in summer; mediumweight clothing for winter, autumn and spring. A raincoat is advisable year-round.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Regularly scheduled commercial flights within Uruguay have been discontinued. Bus and rental car are the two best ways to get around the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no scheduled boat services along the principal rivers, but the River Uruguay is navigable from Colonia to Salto, and the R&iacute;o Negro (flowing across the country from northeast to northwest) is navigable as far as the port of Mercedes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A few local services run between Montevideo and surrounding suburbs. These are not usually used by tourists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main national routes, numbered 1 through 9, fan out from Montevideo like fingers of a hand. All are paved and well maintained, including some excellent sections of four-lane highway linking the capital to Colonia and Punta del Este. Secondary routes along the R&iacute;o de la Plata, R&iacute;o Uruguay and Atlantic Ocean are also of good quality. Travel elsewhere can be more challenging, often involving long sections of unpaved road.</p>r<p>Road conditions vary but are excellent along the main coastal highways.&nbsp;Outside of Montevideo, congestion is rarely a problem.</p><p>The major domestic coach routes from Montevideo are:</p>
<p>&bull;	West and north along the R&iacute;o de la Plata and the R&iacute;o Uruguay to Paysand&uacute; and Salto. <br />
&bull;	East and north along the R&iacute;o de la Plata and the Atlantic Ocean to Punta del Este and Rocha. <br />
&bull;	North on national routes 3, 5, 7 and 8 to Tacuaremb&oacute; and other cities of the interior.</p>
<p>Main coach operators include COT (tel: +598 2409 4949; <a href="http://www.cot.com.uy" target="_blank">www.cot.com.uy</a>), Copsa (tel: +598 217 120; <a href="http://www.copsa.com.uy" target="_blank">www.copsa.com.uy</a>), Agencia (tel: +598 4724 1717; <a href="http://www.agenciacentral.com.uy" target="_blank">www.agenciacentral.com.uy</a>) and Turil (tel: +598 4622 4888; <a href="http://www.turil.com.uy" target="_blank">www.turil.com.uy</a>).</p><p>Metered taxis are available in all cities and from the airports at Carrasco and Punta del Este. Service is especially good in Montevideo, where taxis are safe, ubiquitous and reasonably priced. Look out for a red light in the front window to signify a taxi is free. Drivers will carry a list of fares. A surcharge is often made for each item of baggage. Rates are 20% higher on nights, weekends and holidays.<p>A valid driving licence from your home country is required.</p><p>Drivers and passengers are required to wear seat belts. Use of mobile phones while driving is prohibited. Speed limits, ranging from 45kph (28mph) to 110kph (68mph), are clearly posted.</p><p>The Autom&oacute;vil Club del Uruguay (<a href="http://www.acu.com.uy" target="_blank">www.acu.com.uy</a>) offers year-round towing and mechanical assistance throughout the country.</p><p>Car hire is readily available at Carrasco and Punta del Este International Airports and in major cities including Montevideo, Punta del Este and Colonia. Drivers must be aged 23 or above.</p><p>Drivers and passengers are required to wear seat belts. Use of mobile phones while driving is prohibited. Speed limits, ranging from 45kph (28mph) to 110kph (68mph), are clearly posted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Extensive, dependable and safe bus services operate in Montevideo and most other Uruguayan cities. There are flat fares, one for the central area and another for suburban services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines with regular flights to Montevideo's Carrasco airport include Iberia (<a href="http://www.iberia.com" target="_blank">www.iberia.com</a>) and LATAM (<a href="http://www.latam.com" target="_blank">www.latam.com</a>).
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/uruguay/carrasco-international-airport-aeropuerto-de-carrasco-montevideo">Carrasco International Airport (Aeropuerto de Carrasco - Montevideo)</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 16 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 13 hours 30 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The oneworld Visit South America Pass (<a href="http://www.oneworld.com" target="_blank">www.oneworld.com</a>) is valid within Argentina, Bolivia, Brazil, Colombia, Chile (except Easter Island), Ecuador, Paraguay, Peru, Uruguay and Venezuela. Participating airlines are American Airlines (AA), British Airways (BA), LATAM, Qatar Airways (QR), and their affiliates. The pass must be bought outside South America in the country of residence. It allows unlimited travel to over 60 destinations. You can take as many flights as you like, but a you must book a minimum of three flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$31 on international departures (US$17 to Buenos Aires), payable in cash (Uruguayan pesos or US&nbsp;Dollars) or by credit card at the airport fee counter near check-in. This departure tax is often included in the air fare; check with your airline.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The oneworld Visit South America Pass (<a href="http://www.oneworld.com" target="_blank">www.oneworld.com</a>) is valid within Argentina, Bolivia, Brazil, Colombia, Chile (except Easter Island), Ecuador, Paraguay, Peru, Uruguay and Venezuela. Participating airlines are American Airlines (AA), British Airways (BA), LATAM, Qatar Airways (QR), and their affiliates. The pass must be bought outside South America in the country of residence. It allows unlimited travel to over 60 destinations. You can take as many flights as you like, but a you must book a minimum of three flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Carrasco International Airport (Aeropuerto de Carrasco - Montevideo)</b><![CDATA[http://www.aeropuertodecarrasco.com.uy<p>Carrasco Airport is located 19km (12 miles) northeast from central Montevideo.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>2604 0329.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Montevideo, the main international port, is served by cargo lines and cruise ships from the USA and Europe.</p>
<p>Buquebus (<a href="http://www.buquebus.com" target="_blank">www.buquebus.com</a>) operates high-speed ferries between Montevideo and Buenos Aires (journey time - 2 hours 15 minutes). Colonia Express (<a href="http://www.coloniaexpress.com" target="_blank">www.coloniaexpress.com</a>) and Seacat (<a href="http://www.seacatcolonia.com" target="_blank">www.seacatcolonia.com</a>) offer services from Colonia (160km/100 miles west of Montevideo) to Buenos Aires by ferry and hydrofoil. A port departure tax may be levied.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main points of entry from Argentina are Paysand&uacute; (from Col&oacute;n), Salto (from Concordia) and Fray Bentos (from Gualeguaych&uacute;).</p>
<p>From Brazil, the main point of entry is at Chuy (called Chu&iacute; on the Brazilian side). There are five lesser points of entry further west along the Uruguay-Brazil border: R&iacute;o Branco (from Jaguar&atilde;o), Acegu&aacute; (from Isidoro Nobl&iacute;a), Rivera (from Santana do Livramento), Artigas (from Quara&iacute;), and Bella Uni&oacute;n (from Barra do Quara&iacute;).</p>
<p>Uruguay's main international coach operator is EGA (tel: +598 2902 5335; <a href="http://www.egakeguay.com" target="_blank">www.egakeguay.com</a>), with services to Argentina, Chile, Paraguay and Brazil. Flecha Bus (tel: +598 11 4000 5200; <a href="http://www.flechabus.com.ar" target="_blank">www.flechabus.com.ar</a>) and Condor Estrella (tel: +54 221 423 2745; <a href="http://www.condorestrella.com.ar" target="_blank">www.condorestrella.com.ar</a>)&nbsp;also run regular coaches between Uruguay and Argentina.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>The local telephone service Antel, which is operated by the government, is good and operates call centres in all major towns (www.antel.com.uy). There are also numerous <em>locutorios</em> (privately run call centres). Public phone boxes require a prepaid card, available in denominations of $U25 to $U400 from Antel call centres and newspaper kiosks. Skype calls can be made from most internet caf&eacute;s and are generally the cheapest way to call home.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Antel, Movistar and Claro are the three principal network operators. All three have stores throughout Uruguay. Mobiles operate on the standard GSM cellular network.<br /><br />Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone operators. Visitors should check with their service provider before travelling. Mobile phones and SIM cards can also be easily obtained locally and are usually a less expensive option, especially for longer stays. Coverage is good in urban areas and patchy elsewhere.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafés in main urban areas. Connections are good and prices reasonable (around US$1 per hour).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Uruguayan constitution guarantees a free press and freedom of speech. There are dozens of private newspapers, radio stations and TV channels. Leading Uruguayan TV broadcasters include Canal 10, Montecarlo and Teledoce. State-run radio and television broadcasts are operated by SODRE. International cable channels are also available, especially at better hotels in Montevideo. Domestic English-language news sources are limited to the internet, but UK and other international papers can be purchased at some Montevideo newsstands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes three to five days.</p><p>0800-1800 (main post office in the old city, Montevideo: 0900-1900).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Beef up on the Oxo cube</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Not many people may know this but the humble Oxo cube was invented in Uruguay. Today, you can contemplate the international impact of this stock cube, which was manufactured here and prized by everyone from Edmund Hillary to WWI troops, by visiting the Museo de la Revolución Industrial. This 19th-century meat processing plant-turned-museum is in Fray Bentos, where another gastronomic icon was born: corned beef.</p>]]><p><b>Experience a Uruguayan football match</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wedged between two of the world's great footballing nations, Argentina and Brazil, Uruguayans are also passionate about the beautiful game. Attend a match and share in the uniquely South American carnival spirit on the terraces. Serious fans can also visit the Museo del Fútbol in the Estadio Centenario, the Montevideo stadium where Uruguay's national team won the first World Cup in 1930.</p>]]><p><b>Have a soak in Salto’s hot springs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Northwest Uruguay is home to one of the world's most important underground aquifers, producing warm medicinal springs. Near the town of Salto are some wonderful spas where you can wash off the Pampas dust, including the remote and tranquil Termas de Arapey, the family-friendly Termas de Daymán, or the Termas de San Nicanor.</p>]]><p><b>Hit Montevideo’s markets</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Savour the racks of roasting meat and vegetables at Montevideo's Mercado del Puerto, a popular lunch spot in an old covered market by the waterfront, and get lost in a sea of street vendors at Montevideo's Tristán Narvaja market, just east of downtown. Every Sunday several city blocks are filled with stalls selling everything from antiques to jewellery to live birds.</p>]]><p><b>Join Montevideo’s Carnival frenzy</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get swept up by the joyous dancing and drumming in the streets every February during Montevideo's exuberant Afro-Uruguayan Carnival. Although celebrated throughout the country, the capital hosts the best carnival festivities, with its roots in the Candomble beliefs of the African slaves brought here by the Spanish. The main events take place over two days before Mardi Gras, but many locals take the whole week to join in the fun.</p>]]><p><b>Meander around Montevideo, Uruguay’s stylish capital</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy the eclectic mix of colonial, European and modern influences in Uruguay's capital. Walk around the palm-shaded plazas of the Ciudad Vieja (Old Town), see the fascinating Gaucho Museum, the Carnival Museum and cool off in appealing beach suburbs such as Playa Carrasco, east of town.</p>]]><p><b>Party with the jet set of Punta del Este</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spend the day parasailing, windsurfing, waterskiing, sport fishing or lounging on the long sandy beaches at Punta del Este, one of South America's most exclusive resorts. And when the sun goes down, put on your party togs and shimmy with the rich and famous at Punta's chic nightclubs, in Punta Ballena and La Barra.</p>]]><p><b>Relive the border battles at Santa Teresa and San Miguel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get a feel for the historic conflict between Spanish and Portuguese forces at the fortresses of Santa Teresa and San Miguel near the northeastern town of Chuy close to the Brazilian border. Built in the 18th century, today the fortresses have been completely restored and are open to visitors, offering an impressive experience of the region's colonial past.</p>]]><p><b>Saddle up with the gauchos on an Estancia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go for a horse ride, stargaze by the barbecue and get a taste of gaucho life at one of Uruguay's tourist estancias, dozens of which are dotted all over the vast pampas. Two of the best are San Pedro de Timote and La Sirena, or if you fancy trying an authentic experience some ranches offer working stays, such as the Estancia El Silencio.</p>]]><p><b>Sample Uruguay’s Swiss cheeses</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Low-lying, temperate Uruguay may hardly be comparable to the Alps, but thousands of visitors each year seek out the fine dairy products in the 19th-century Swiss settlement of Nueva Helvecia (formerly Colonia Suiza: Swiss Colony), west of the capital. The town also features Swiss-style hotels and restaurants, which are popular with locals and homesick Europeans alike.</p>]]><p><b>See a tango at Teatro Solís</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Attend a concert, play, or tango performance at Montevideo's renovated 19th-century opera house, Teatro Solís; or enjoy live music and dance at one of the city's dozens of other nightspots, with many clustered along Ciudad Vieja's pedestrianised areas, as well as in Punta Carretas and Pocitos.</p>]]><p><b>Stay in Casapueblo, a ‘liveable sculpture’</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Carlos Paéz Vilaró was one of Uruguay's foremost abstract artists and you can visit one of his most famous works: the extravagantly whimsical art studio, Casapueblo. This nine-story whitewashed 'liveable sculpture' cascades down the cliffs of Punta Ballena, near Punta del Este. The remarkable complex now also includes a gallery, museum, cafe and a hotel.</p>]]><p><b>Stroll along the Rambla</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For an unforgettable slice of Montevideo life, take a weekend stroll along the Rambla (riverfront promenade), where you'll find joggers, windsurfers and throngs of sociable locals cradling thermoses of <em>mate </em>(herb tea) as they chat with friends on the beach. Go at dusk to see a stunning sunset over the Rio del Plata.</p>]]><p><b>Surf the South Atlantic at Punta del Diablo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ride the waves and wander the endless sandy beaches at the low-key Atlantic resort of Punta del Diablo, then head south to the perfect surf breaks of La Paloma and La Pedrera. Punta del Diablo is a quiet fishing village for most of the year, but every summer it fills up with diehard surfers and other adventurers kept busy with dune surfing, horseback riding and jeep forest safaris.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Colonia del Sacramento, Uruguay’s historic treasure</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Colonia del Sacramento's cobblestoned streets and sycamore-shaded plazas are perfect for whiling away a lazy day. Enter this ancient treasure via the reconstructed city gate, the Portón de Campo, and spend the day browsing art galleries, dining in cosy restaurants and kicking back in cafes. Come nightfall, watch sunset over the Río de la Plata.</p>]]><p><b>Watch the wildlife</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Uruguay's vast empty landscapes are a nature-lover's paradise. Trek over sand dunes to see the lighthouse and abundant marine life at Cabo Polonio on the Atlantic coast. Observe the rich array of bird life at one of eastern Uruguay's coastal lagoons, including Laguna de Rocha near La Paloma, Laguna de Castillos near Barra de Valizas, and Laguna Negra near Punta del Diablo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$53.4billion (2015).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Beef, wool, leather products, cellulose and rice.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, chemicals, fuel, vehicles and cellular phones.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Brazil, Argentina, USA and China.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Uruguay is one of the more prosperous Latin American countries. The economy has a traditionally strong agricultural sector, with beef and wool being the most important products; dairy exports to other Latin American countries are substantial. Crop farming is widespread, producing mostly cereals, rice, fruit and vegetables.<br />
<br />
Manufacturing is concentrated in oil and coal-derived products, chemicals, textiles, transport equipment and leather products. The oil and coal, both for manufacturing and energy consumption (the latter supplemented by Uruguay's own hydroelectricity stations), are imported. Mining is confined to small-scale extraction of building materials, industrial minerals and some gold. The tourism industry brings in just under US$1 billion annually.<br />
<br />
Uruguay's economic health depends heavily on that of its two large neighbours, Argentina and Brazil. In August 2002, both Argentina and, to a lesser extent, Brazil were gripped by financial crises. This led to a collapse in the cross-border trade upon which Uruguay is heavily dependent.<br />
<br />
The government was forced to take emergency measures in the form of currency devaluation, loan rescheduling and, in an unusually drastic move, closing down the country's entire financial system as it approached meltdown. It also appealed for support from the IMF, which responded with a US$3 billion package. With the worst of the crisis past, Uruguay is now returning to something approaching economic health. Annual growth was at 2.8% in 2015, while inflation in the same year was at approximately 7.9%.<br />
<br />
Uruguay is a member of Mercosur, the principal regional trade bloc, as well as the Asociaci&oacute;n Latinoamericana de Integraci&oacute;n (ALADI) and the Inter-American Development Bank.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Uruguayans pride themselves on being very European in attitude and conduct business accordingly. While timing of social engagements is flexible at best, business meetings here start promptly at the agreed time. While European-style cheek-kissing is the norm for greetings between friends (even males), business associates shake hands. </p>
<p>Businessmen should wear conservative suits and ties. As far as communication is concerned, some knowledge of Spanish will prove invaluable, although English may be spoken by many in business and tourist circles. Business cards are essential and it would be an advantage to have the reverse printed in Spanish. Avoid visits during Carnival week or Easter week.</p><p>Business hours tend to be Monday to Friday, 0900-1700. Some businesses open until noon on Saturday. Closing for the long midday siesta was once commonly practiced, but is now generally viewed as a thing of the past.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cámara Nacional de Comercio y Servicios del Uruguay</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 916 1277
					Website:http://www.cncs.com.uy
					Address: CP 11000,Rincón 454,Piso 2,Montevideo,]]><b>Uruguayan American Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (212) 722 3306
					Website:http://www.uruguaychamber.com/
					Address: Suite 714,130 West 42nd Street,New York,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>For the country that introduced corned beef to the world, it's no surprise that Uruguayans love to eat meat above all else. The most common restaurants are <em>parrilladas</em> (grill-rooms), where huge racks of beef sizzle over hot coals.</p><p>Italian food is also popular, thanks to the many immigrants who came from Italy in the early 20th century, while seafood is excellent along the Atlantic coast. Uruguayan wine is pretty good too, though the nation's favourite spirit is whisky, and they even produce a well-rated brand of their own, Dunbar.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bife de chorizo:</strong> A sirloin steak.<br />
<strong>Asado de tira: </strong>Short ribs, and other barbecued meats, predominantly beef and lamb, including offal.<br />
<strong>Chivito:</strong> Steak sandwich with accompaniments including cheese, lettuce, tomato, bacon, ham, olives and pickles.<br />
<strong>Morcilla: </strong>Blood sausage served either <em>dulce</em> (sweet, made with orange peel and walnuts), or <em>salada</em> (salty).<br />
<strong>Dulce de leche: </strong>Boiled milk and caramel; typically spread on toast and used as the filling in <em>alfajores </em>biscuits.<br />
<strong>Chaj&aacute;:</strong> Ball-shaped sponge cake filled with cream and jam.<br />
<strong>Wine:</strong> Uruguayan wines are of good quality, particularly reds of the tannat grape variety. Popular wine-based drinks include <em>cleric&oacute; </em>(wine mixed with fruit juice) and <em>medio y medio </em>(half dry white wine and half sparkling wine).<br />
<strong>Yerba mate:</strong> A bitter tea of a native herb that&rsquo;s extremely popular with locals.<br />
<strong>Ca&ntilde;a:</strong> A clear liquor made from sugarcane.<br />
<strong>Grappa: </strong>A grape based brandy with Italian origins.<br />
<strong>Whisky:</strong> Uruguayans love their whisky and even make their own, which is called Dunbar.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>There are no set licensing hours.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% when no service charge is added.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Theatre, ballet and symphonic concerts are staged in Montevideo from March to January. Tango is nearly as popular as in Argentina. Top venues for live performances include Teatro Solís and Sala Zitarrosa. There are discos in downtown Montevideo and coastal suburbs such as Pocitos and Carrasco, as well as a plethora of summer-only nightclubs in Punta del Este. Large Montevideo hotels have good bars, and there are several dinner-dance places. When there is music for dancing, the price of drinks increases considerably. There are also casinos in Montevideo, Punta del Este and Colonia del Sacramento.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Montevideo, Punta del Este and Colonia del Sacramento are the best places for shopping. Special purchases include leather goods, suede jackets, woollens and amethyst jewellery. On Sunday mornings Montevideo's Tristan Narvaja Market is famous for its antiques, books and countless other items sold from stalls spread over several blocks. Equally eclectic and worthwhile is the Saturday Flea Market held in Plaza Constitucion in Montevideo's Old Town. There are also many antique shops in the Old Town. Uruguayan handicrafts are on display at Montevideo's port and also the Ferias Artesanales (artisanal fairs) in Punta del Este and Colonia del Sacramento. The Manos de Uruguay cooperative sells fine woollens at its stores in Montevideo, Punta del Este and Colonia del Sacramento.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1200 and 1400-1900; Sat 0900-1230. Large shopping malls are open daily 1000-2200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are numerous first-class hotels in Montevideo and in Uruguay's coastal resorts. Prices tend to be higher during the summer tourist season, especially at the beaches. It is essential to book during Easter Week nationwide, in the summer along the coast and during carnival week in Montevideo. Outside of Montevideo, the cities offering the best range of hotel options are Colonia del Sacramento and Punta del Este. There are also lower-priced hotels throughout the country offering more basic accommodation. A star rating system of 1 to 5 stars is used. The Ministry of Tourism has a hotel listing page on its website (<a href="http://www.turismo.gub.uy" target="_blank">www.turismo.gub.uy</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Aside from hotels, guest houses are the most common form of lodging throughout Uruguay. Most are categorized as <em>residenciales</em> (budget hotels) or <em>hospedajes</em> (family homes). These typically offer fewer amenities and cost less than full-fledged hotels. Because they are often family-run, guest houses also tend to offer a more down-to-earth atmosphere than hotels or inns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are numerous first-class hotels in Montevideo and in Uruguay's coastal resorts. Prices tend to be higher during the summer tourist season, especially at the beaches. It is essential to book during Easter Week nationwide, in the summer along the coast and during carnival week in Montevideo. Outside of Montevideo, the cities offering the best range of hotel options are Colonia del Sacramento and Punta del Este. There are also lower-priced hotels throughout the country offering more basic accommodation. A star rating system of 1 to 5 stars is used. The Ministry of Tourism has a hotel listing page on its website (<a href="http://www.turismo.gub.uy" target="_blank">www.turismo.gub.uy</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are numerous first-class hotels in Montevideo and in Uruguay's coastal resorts. Prices tend to be higher during the summer tourist season, especially at the beaches. It is essential to book during Easter Week nationwide, in the summer along the coast and during carnival week in Montevideo. Outside of Montevideo, the cities offering the best range of hotel options are Colonia del Sacramento and Punta del Este. There are also lower-priced hotels throughout the country offering more basic accommodation. A star rating system of 1 to 5 stars is used. The Ministry of Tourism has a hotel listing page on its website (<a href="http://www.turismo.gub.uy" target="_blank">www.turismo.gub.uy</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Uruguay has an excellent medical service. Private health insurance is recommended. To call an ambulance, dial 105; for general emergency services, call 911.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is considered safe to drink. Drinking water outside main cities and towns may be contaminated and sterilisation is advisable. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;According to advice from the World Health Organisation, Uruguay has no known risk of Zika virus transmission from mosquitos.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Many businesses close during Carnival Week and during Tourism Week (Holy Week).</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Carnival :
							12 February </p><p>Maundy Thursday :
							29 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Landing of the 33 Patriots Day :
							19 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Battle of Las Piedras :
							18 May </p><p>D :
							19 June </p><p>Constitution Day :
							18 July </p><p>National Independence Day :
							25 August </p><p>New Year's Day :
							25 August </p><p>D :
							08 October </p><p>All Soul's Day :
							02 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Customs Allowances for Uruguay DUTY FREE SHOPS are:<br />
&bull; USD$650 for products acquire at arrivals Duty Free Shops. (Decree 108/010 and its modifications).<br />
&bull; For Travelers arriving to Uruguay, tax-free for alcoholic beverages and cigarettes income is limited to the following maximum amounts: distilled alcoholic beverages up to six (6) liters and four (4) cartons of cigarettes (General Resolution 16 / 2016). This regime does not apply to wines, sparkling wines and similar.</p>
<p>Please check Customs official web page at <a href="https://www.aduanas.gub.uy">https://www.aduanas.gub.uy</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited items include flammable objects, narcotics and obscene or pornographic materials.</p>
<p>Restricted items include firearms, plants, fruit, vegetables, seeds, flowers, and animals and their products.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Peso Uruguayo (UYU; symbol $U) = 100 centécimos. Notes are in the denominations of $U2,000, 1,000, 500, 200, 100, 50 and 20. Coins are in denominations of $U10, 5, 2 and 1 and 50 centécimos.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors are advised to buy local currency at banks and exchange shops, as hotels tend to give unfavourable rates. Inflation in Uruguay, though less severe than in other Latin American countries, leads to frequent fluctuations in the exchange rate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard, Visa, American Express, and Diners Club are the most commonly used credit cards. All are widely accepted in major tourist and business destinations including <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/montevideo">Montevideo</a>, Punta del Este and Colonia del Sacramento. In rural areas, it's best to carry cash as many businesses will not accept credit cards.</p><p>ATMs marked with the green Banred or blue RedBROU logo are reliable and available in all cities, as well as some smaller towns. These serve all major international banking networks, including Cirrus, Visa, Link, MasterCard and Maestro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's Cheques can still be cashed at some banks and exchange shops in major tourist hubs. US Dollar traveller's cheques are more widely accepted than those issued in Euros or Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 1300-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Uruguay, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visa: US$42.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To extend your stay, contact the Direcci&oacute;n Nacional de Migraci&oacute;n.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-32.863016]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-56.007021]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>176,215 sq km (68,037 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>3,444,071 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>19 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Montevideo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Uruguay is bordered to the north by Brazil, to the southeast by the Atlantic, and is separated from Argentina in the west and south by the River Uruguay, which widens out into the Rio de la Plata estuary. The landscape is made up of hilly meadows broken by streams and rivers. There are a string of beaches along the coast. Most of the country is grazing land for sheep and cattle. Montevideo, the most southern point of the nation, accommodates nearly half of the population. About 90% of the land is suitable for agriculture, although only 12% is used in this way.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic is the predominant religion (47%), followed by Protestantism (11%). Other religious minorities, including Judaism, account for less than 2% of the population. 40% of Uruguayans claim no religious affiliation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shaking hands is the normal form of greeting. Uruguayans are very hospitable and like to entertain both at home and in restaurants. Normal courtesies should be observed. Smoking is not allowed in public spaces, including restaurants, cinemas, theatres and public transport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs (two round pins) and Australian-style plugs (three flat, angled pins) are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Tabar&eacute; V&aacute;zquez since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Tabar&eacute; V&aacute;zquez since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Originally settled by the tribal Charr&uacute;a people, Uruguay's territory was hotly contested from the arrival of the first Europeans, due to its strategic position near the mouth of the R&iacute;o de la Plata. The Spanish established the capital Montevideo in 1726 but continued to battle with the Portuguese for control of the region.</p>
<p>In 1828, a scrappy band of patriots led by General Juan Lavalleja and inspired by nationalist hero Jos&eacute; Artigas finally won independence for Uruguay, establishing it as a buffer between the newly formed nations of Brazil and Argentina.</p>
<p>Regional strife continued for several decades, as Uruguay's two major political parties emerged. The liberally inclined Colorado Party, associated with Montevideo's business owners, and the right-wing National Party, representing rural interests, came to be known as Colorados ('Reds') and Blancos ('Whites') &ndash; terms that survive to this day. The Great War of 1843-52 and the War of the Triple Alliance (Argentina, Brazil and Uruguay against Paraguay, 1864-1870) pitted the two parties against one another, prompting continued interventions by Argentina and Brazil. The Blancos and Colorados finally reached a stable power-sharing agreement in 1872.</p>
<p>In the late 19th century, an influx of European immigrants helped transform Uruguay into an agricultural powerhouse. Under the progressive Colorado administrations of Jos&eacute; Batlle y Ordonez between 1903 and 1915, Uruguay established Latin America's first welfare state, gave women the vote and abolished both the death penalty and the link between church and state.</p>
<p>As the 20th century progressed, Uruguay's economic fortunes deteriorated and in the 1970s the country slid into a dictatorship under Juan Maria Bordaberry Arocena. Civilian rule resumed in 1985, accompanied by the ascendancy of the Frente Amplio, a leftist coalition that became Uruguay's first successful third party under President Jos&eacute; Mujica.</p>
<p>Before taking the presidency, Mujica had spent 14 years in prison for opposing the previous dictatorship. Whilst in power he donated 90% of his salary to charity, legalised marijuana and continued to pick up hitchhikers in his old VW Beetle, making him something of a hero around the world. He was succeeded by Tabar&eacute; V&aacute;zquez in 2015.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	In 1930, Uruguay hosted the first FIFA World Cup, beating their arch-rivals, Argentina, 4-2 in the final. <br />
&bull;	The Tupamaros were Marxist urban guerrillas, who wrought havoc in the late 1960s. Their leader and future president Jose Mujica was imprisoned at the bottom of a well.<br />
&bull;	Fray Bentos, a town in western Uruguay, was the original home of corned beef, and is now a listed UNESCO World Heritage Site.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Uruguay in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 331 1313 or 4219 (consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.uruwashi.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 331 1313 or 4219 (consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700; Visa section: Mon-Fri 0900-1300 and 1400-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1913 I Street<br/>Washington<br/>20006<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Uruguay in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7937 4170.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7937 4170.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700; Visa section: Mon-Fri 1000-1600 (appointment only).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/> 4th Floor, 150 Brompton Rd<br/>London<br/>SW3 1HX<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Uruguay]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>2622 3630</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinuruguay.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>2622 3630</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thu 0900-1300 and 1400-1730, Fri 0900-1430; Jan 0830-1430.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Calle Marco Bruto1073<br/>Montevideo<br/>11300 <br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A peaceful, laidback destination with a long history of liberalism (Uruguay was the first country to fully legalize marijuana) this pint-sized nation finds itself squeezed between Brazil and Argentina, and is often overshadowed by its heavyweight neighbours. However, as Uruguay has come to appreciate its subtle charms and small-scale attractions, so too have travellers.</p>
<p>Veer off the Gringo Trail and into Uruguay, and you will be pleasantly surprised. Considering its size, the country boasts an astonishing variety of diversions. Its windswept Atlantic coastline features dunes, lagoons and perfect surf; visitors can hop between hip beach resorts, clustered around the chic Punta del Este, abscond to sleepy fishing villages or take wildlife excursions to see penguins, sea lions and whales. The interior is equally rewarding. Journey up the Rio de la Plata and discover charming colonial towns, thermal springs and working haciendas, which offer an authentic taste of traditional gaucho life.</p>
<p>The jewel in Uruguay&rsquo;s crown, though, is the capital, Montevideo. Punching well above its weight culturally and economically, this buzzing metropolis is classified as a Beta World City and is considered the most gay-friendly city in Latin America. Montevideo is a handsome place of stunning architecture, breezy promenades and sandy beaches. It&rsquo;s also home to the world&rsquo;s longest carnival, a heady six-week street party that puts other South American cities to shame.</p>
<p>Sleepy Colonia del Sacramento is another gem. Situated on the banks of the Rio de la Plata, opposite Buenos Aires, this amorous city offers enchanting cobbled streets, leafy plazas and 18th-century Portuguese architecture. It&rsquo;s unflappably laidback, but for something even cooler head to Cabo Polonio, an off-grid eco-resort founded by hippies and fishermen, where the stresses of modern life ebb away and there&rsquo;s time to appreciate nature and likeminded people.</p>
<p>All things considered, Uruguay should be treated like one of its famous beefsteaks; take your time over it, savour it and when you&rsquo;re done, come back for more. You&rsquo;ll never get your fill.</p><p>A peaceful, laidback destination with a long history of liberalism (Uruguay was the first country to fully legalize marijuana) this pint-sized nation finds itself squeezed between Brazil and Argentina, and is often overshadowed by its heavyweight neighbours. However, as Uruguay has come to appreciate its subtle charms and small-scale attractions, so too have travellers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
