<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Uzbekistan" ColCode="uzb" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="uz" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Uzbekistan]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Uzbekistan has an extreme continental climate. It is generally warmest in the south and coldest in the north. Temperatures in December average -8&deg;C (18&deg;F) in the north and 0&deg;C (32&deg;F) in the south. However, extreme fluctuations can take temperatures as low as -35&deg;C (-31&deg;F). During the summer months, temperatures can climb to 45&deg;C (113&deg;F) and above. Humidity is low. In recent years Uzbekistan has been notably affected by general global warming and the specific effects of the drying-out of the Aral Sea. This has turned snowy cold winters to mild ones with less precipitation. The best time to visit is during the spring and autumn, with September being the absolute optimum month.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the winter it can be bitterly cold so bring layers - mountain-wear works well. In the summer, it gets very hot so loose, breathable cottons are best.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Uzbekistan Airways (<a href="http://www.uzairways.com" target="_blank">www.uzairways.com</a>) flies to all the major towns and cities in Uzbekistan on a regular basis. Destinations include Andijan, Karshi, Namangan, Navoi (which is 45 minutes by bus from Bukhara), Nukus, Samarkand, Tashkent and Termez.</p><p>There's good infrastructure in Tashkent (compared with airports in surrounding countries such as Tajikistan and Kyrgyzstan) but expect delays and allow plenty of time to clear security.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are railways linking Termez, Samarkand, Bukhara, the Fergana Valley and Nukus. There are two railway stations in Tashkent. The Trans-Caspian Railway traverses the country from Chardzhou in Turkmenistan via Kagan (near Bukhara), Samarkand and Dzhizak, where the railway branches off to serve the capital, Tashkent. Passengers should store valuables under the bed or seat, and should not leave the compartment unattended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It's not advisable to drive yourself in Uzbekistan, or to drive at night even with a driver - road speeds increase, drunk driving is an issue and roads are perilous with potholes and few markings. While outside of the cities the roads are relatively quiet, in the cities the roads are disorganised and few drivers abide by the rules. Petrol stations are available but it's advisable to carry supplies in your driver&rsquo;s car. Visitors wishing to travel around Termez (in the territory of the border patrol) require a permit from the National Company Uzbektourism.</p>r<p>The majority of Uzbekistan's roads are paved. Highways account for more than 90% of domestic travel, but outside of the cities they are relatively quiet.</p><p>The old, battered state buses are disappearing, replaced by private buses that do not keep official schedules and leave when full.</p><p>As with most central Asian countries, most taxis are unlicensed, so always negotiate a fare before getting in and have your destination noted in Russian or Uzbek.</p>
<p>Also typical of the region is the shared taxi phenomenon. At taxi ranks or bus stations, drivers will have a destination city marked on a board, or will be calling the name out. Negotiate a rate, check with others what to pay, but as a tourist you may pay more. The car only leaves when full. Try to get the front passenger seat, or a window &ndash; it can get very hot in Uzbekistan and not all cars have air conditioning.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required for car hire.</p><p>No one wears a seatbelt and you are not required by law to do so. The speed limit is 60-80kph (37-50mph) in urban areas and 90kph (56mph) on highways.</p><p>There is no national breakdown service.</p><p>There are very few official car hire services in the country, but you can easily hire drivers with cars via travel agencies. Car Rental Uzbekistan (<a href="http://www.carrental.uz" target="_blank">www.carrental.uz</a>) offers a range of vehicles for self-drive.</p><p>You can hire bikes from the East Line Tour company (<a href="http://www.eastlinetour.uz" target="_blank">www.eastlinetour.uz</a>) in Bukhara, a city that lends itself to cycling (the same cannot be said for Samarkand).</p><p>No one wears a seatbelt and you are not required by law to do so. The speed limit is 60-80kph (37-50mph) in urban areas and 90kph (56mph) on highways.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tashkent is served by taxis, buses, trolleybuses, trams and underground. Public transport is cheap and generally reliable. There are regular bus services to all major towns in Uzbekistan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Uzbekistan Airways (<a href="http://www.uzairways.com" target="_blank">www.uzairways.com</a>), which offers direct flights from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>. There are also plenty of indirect flight options with carriers such as Lufthansa (<a href="http://www.lufthansa.com" target="_blank">www.lufthansa.com</a>), Aeroflot (<a href="http://www.aeroflot.com" target="_blank">www.aeroflot.com</a>), Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>) and Air Baltic (<a href="http://www.airbaltic.com" target="_blank">www.airbaltic.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 7 hours.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Customs forms are sometimes cause for concern with travellers entering or departing by air &ndash; these forms (there are two copies to fill out, one for them, one that you keep) simply require you to declare any currency you are either bringing into, or taking out of, Uzbekistan, along with the amount. Essentially the authorities are checking that you are not leaving Uzbekistan with more foreign money than you brought in; if this is found to be the case you will incur a significant fine.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Customs forms are sometimes cause for concern with travellers entering or departing by air &ndash; these forms (there are two copies to fill out, one for them, one that you keep) simply require you to declare any currency you are either bringing into, or taking out of, Uzbekistan, along with the amount. Essentially the authorities are checking that you are not leaving Uzbekistan with more foreign money than you brought in; if this is found to be the case you will incur a significant fine.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Tashkent International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is in the south of the town, about 11km (7 miles) from the centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Uzbekistan is doubly landlocked. There are no sea ports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With an ever-growing flight network and cheaper airfares, rail travel into Uzbekistan fares poorly in comparison with tales of discomfort and occasional theft. Still, it is an adventure, and in most cases foreigners are treated well and are sometimes toasted with clinks of vodka glasses. The Uzbekistan Railways site (<a href="http://www.uzrailpass.uz/index.php" target="_blank">www.uzrailpass.uz/index.php</a>) is a useful website.</p>
<p>There are good rail connections into Tashkent from Almaty in Kazakhstan. From Almaty connecting trains are possible through to to Urumchi in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a>. From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a> there is a train that departs from Kazanski station to Tashkent, four times a week; it takes over 60 hours and crosses in and out of Kazakhstan on the route, therefore a multiple Kazakh visa may be needed - double check before departing. Other major Russian cities also have direct trains to Uzbekistan, including <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/st-petersburg">St Petersburg</a>, Ufa, Novosibirsk and Yekaterinburg (all of these routes also cross into Kazakhstan).</p>
<p>There is also a train from Kharkov in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ukraine">Ukraine</a> to Tashkent, and it crosses through both <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a> and Kazakhstan; visas are needed for both countries.</p>
<p>There is a run-down, little-used rail line into Tajikistan that is entirely dependent on the current political situation between the two countries. In theory you can travel on the Moscow &ndash; Dushanbe train which passes through Uzbekistan, or you can take the train to Termez and get off at Kumkurgan, from where you can take a taxi to the border with Tajikistan.<br />
<br />
There is also a spur line to the Fergana Valley in the east of the country, which leads to Osh in Kyrgyzstan. It is possible to connect to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> through Almaty; and to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iran">Iran</a> and the Middle East (via Turkmenistan). Foreigners have to pay for rail tickets in hard currency, preferably US Dollars, but it is still a cheap option by Western standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Uzbekistan has road connections to all its neighbours. A Friendship Bridge links <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/afghanistan">Afghanistan</a> with Termiz in Uzbekistan (Termiz is a small city of little interest sitting at the southern most point of Uzbekistan), which while open to tourists, can sometimes close due to security concerns. It is advisable to check with a travel agent or locals before setting off.</p>
<p>The neighbouring country of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kyrgyzstan">Kyrgyzstan</a>, popular with trekkers and mountaineers, offers three main border crossings into Uzbekistan: Uchkurgan, Dustlyk (Dostyk) and Khanabad (not to be confused with the &lsquo;Khanabad&rsquo; in Afghanistan). The third is the most problematic. The region remains conservative and sees very few travellers.</p>
<p>Security can be tight at all crossings; you need to fill out customs forms and there can be long waits, so try to arrive early in the morning. Buses do travel between Tashkent and Bishkek (Kyrgyzstan) but as they pass through <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kazakhstan">Kazakhstan</a>, you need to arrange a Kazakh visa in advance. Visas are not available at any of these land borders.</p>
<p>For crossing into <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tajikistan">Tajikistan</a>, the best, most scenic route, is between Samarkand and Penjikent (although this border often closes due to political tensions and there is no public transport). Taxis, which are readily available, are the only way to cross. Alternatively, the Oybek (Uzbekistan) border crossing, (a one-hour drive to Khujand in Tajikistan), is easier and is usually open. The last option is Denau (a two-hour drive from Termiz in Uzbekistan) -Tursanzade (a 45-minute drive to Dushanbe, capital of Tajikistan). Again, arrive early, be patient and arrive with the correct visas.</p>
<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkmenistan">Turkmenistan</a> and Uzbekistan are also linked by road. Most locals do this journey by shared taxi. The two easiest border crossings are the crossing that joins Bukhara with Turkmenabat and the Khiva/Urgench (the &lsquo;Shavat to Dashoguz&rsquo; crossing). These borders have lengthy lunch breaks, and the Turkmen authorities will charge each traveller around US$12 &lsquo;entry tax&rsquo;, which must be paid in US&nbsp;Dollars only.</p>
<p>Kazakhstan offers two main entry points: the Chernyaevka crossing between Tashkent and Shymkent (easy, but long waiting times) and the more remote crossing between Karakalpakstan and Beyneu in western Kazakhstan.</p><p>Most crossings in Central Asia open and close regularly without warning; the best advice is to check with a local travel agent or to ask around before setting off. Always travel with US Dollars just in case - for example, if you happen to lose a declaration form on exiting Uzbekistan, a small US$10 bribe will smooth things over. Expect to have to cobble together a combination of minibuses and taxis to get to and from all border points.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>International calls can be made from main post offices (in Tashkent on Prospekt Navoi). Direct-dial calls within the CIS are obtained by dialling 8 and waiting for another dial tone and then dialling the city code. Calls within the city limits are free of charge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mobile connections works in most parts of Uzbekistan and services are cheap. The number of mobile phone service users exceeded 19 million people by the end of 2010.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The number of internet users was estimated at 7.55 million in March 2011. Internet cafés exist in Tashkent, Bukhara, Samarkand and Khiva.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pre-publication press censorship has been abolished but self-censorship is widespread. A law holds media bodies accountable for the impartiality of their output, and as a result many locals depend on Russian TV and the BBC for news. Reporters Without Borders (RWB), who publish the World Press Freedom Index, placed Uzbekistan at 164th place in 2013, in between Saudi Arabia and Bahrain.</p>
<p>In August 2011, the government approved the creation of a new &lsquo;committee of experts on information and mass communication&rsquo; that would monitor the media for news that could weaken national cultural traditions, or that could help to induce violent overthrow of the government. In addition, the government, concerned about the Arab Spring uprisings in the Middle East and North Africa, restricted the internet and social media in 2011. Authorities also ordered the closure of the decade-old <em>Zerkalo XXI</em>, one of the few independent newspapers left in the country. Foreign media have been gradually expelled since the 2005 Andijan uprising.</p>
<p>The main editions are published in Tashkent and include <em>Khalk Suzi</em> and <em>Narodnoye Slovo</em> (in Russian and Uzbek), <em>Hurriyat </em>(published by a government agency) and <em>Uzbekistan</em><em> Ovizi.</em></p>
<p>Television channels include the<strong> </strong>National Television and Radio Company, the NTT and TV-Markaz, which is national and is watched for music and entertainment. There are several radio stations, some national and some private &ndash; these include the National Television and Radio Company, Oriat FM, Uzbegim Taronasi and Radio Grande.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Letters to Western Europe and the USA can take between two weeks and two months. Stamped envelopes can be bought from post offices. Addresses should be laid out in the following order: country, postcode, city, street, house number and, lastly, the person's name. There are a number of international courier services based in Tashkent.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Boi-Bulok Caves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the deepest caves in Asia at Boi-Bulok where the depths reach 1,415m (4,641ft) in depth, and Kievskaya whose depths hit 990m (3,247ft). These are suitable for experienced cavers only. Beautiful gypsum formations can be seen at the Kugitang cave, while the caves of Baisuntau contain mummified bears and those in western Tian Shan feature underground rivers and lakes.</p>]]><p><b>Bukhara</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Noted by many as one of the most interesting cities in the world, Bukhara, offers the visitor more than 350 mosques and 100 religious colleges to admire. At the centre of it all, is the Shakristan (the old town), where the Ark, or palace complex of the Emirs, can be found. Close by is the 47m-high (145ft) Kalyan Minaret. Other sites of interest in Bukhara include the covered bazaars, and the Kalyan Mosque which is open to non-Muslims. This is the place to do your shopping as everything from ikat fabric to silk road spices to Soviet memorabilia can be bought.</p>]]><p><b>Chatkalsky Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Keep an eye out for snow tigers, the rare Tian-Shan grey bear and the Berkut eagle in the Chatkalsky Reserve, a narrow unspoilt gorge in the western Tian-Shan. In the winter months trekking, skiing and snowboarding are popular and there are chairlifts, a marked sledge route, skiing equipment rental and training sessions for beginners.</p>]]><p><b>Chorsu Bazaar, Tashkent</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tashkent's Chorsu ('four ways') Bazaar is a typical, but especially lively, bustling Central Asian bazaar. Covered stalls protect the piles of fruit and vegetables from the hot sun, and it is possible to barter for souvenir-friendly slippers, shawls, carpets, gowns and skull-caps just as traders and merchants have done over hundreds of years.</p>]]><p><b>Cycle the Silk Road </b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cycle from Tashkent via Lake Aidarkul to Khiva. Easier rides can be done in the Ferghana Valley and around Tashkent, where lake and mountain scenery can be enjoyed. Organised tours are available.</p>]]><p><b>Ice climbing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If climbing an ice waterfall appeals, Uzbekistan offers plenty of opportunity with its many mountains, ice climbing is possible on the Gissar, Matcha and Turkestan ridges. Also, vertical rock faces for rock climbing can be found in the Fan mountains (at Bodkhana, Chapdara, Maria-Mirali and Zamok) and on the Matchi Ridge (at Aksu, Asan-Usan and Sabakh).</p>]]><p><b>Khiva</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Khiva, northeast of Bukhara, is near to the modern and disappointingly uninteresting city of Urgench. Khiva, though, is fascinating. Completely and painstakingly preserved, the city still lies within its original walls, and has changed little since the 18th century. As a museum town it is hardly inhabited, which many visitors notice immediately, although it is possible to imagine what it was like in its prime – a place of plumed turbans and pomegranates.</p>]]><p><b>Kokand</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Built in the early 19th century, the Juma Mosque complex is centred around a 22m- (72 ft-) minaret and includes 98 red-wood columns brought from India. The entire compound has reverted to its former Soviet guise as a museum, with one room housing a collection of <em>suzani</em> (textiles) and ceramics from the region. Admission includes a free tour, but only in Russian.</p>]]><p><b>Nukus Museum (Karakalpak Museum of the Arts)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>View the best collection of Russian avant-garde art outside St Petersburg in Nukus, the capital of Karakalpakstan, in the west of the country. It is also home to one of the largest collections of archeological objects and folk, applied and contemporary art originating from Central Asia.</p>]]><p><b>Observatory of Ulug Beg</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Other sites of interest in Samarkand include the Observatory of Ulug Beg, Timur's grandson, which was the most advanced astronomical observatory of its day. There is also the Afrasiab Museum, not far from the observatory, containing a frieze dating from the sixth century, which shows a train of gifts for the Sogdian ruler of the day.</p>]]><p><b>Samarkand</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the site of Alexander the Great's slaying of his friend Cleitos at Samarkand, the pivot of the Silk Road and the city transformed by Timur in the 14th century into one of the world's greatest capitals. Much of its past glory survives or has been restored. The centre of the historical town is the Registan Square, where three huge madrassas (Islamic seminaries) - including Shir-Dor and Tillya-Kari - built between the 15th and 17th centuries, dominate the area. Decorated with blue tiles and intricate mosaics, they give some idea of the grandeur that marked Samarkand in its heyday. The Bibi Khanym Mosque, not far from the Registan, is testimony to Timur's love for his wife. Now it is a pale shadow of its former self, having been partly destroyed in the 1897 earthquake, and seems permanently under repair. Timur himself is buried in the Gur Emir. On the ground floor, under the massive cupola, lie the ceremonial graves of Timur and his descendants. The stone that commemorates Timur is reputed to be the largest chunk of Nephrite (jade) in the world. The actual bodies are situated in the basement, which unfortunately is not open to the public.</p>]]><p><b>Shah-i-Zinda</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Shah-i-Zinda is a collection of the graves of some of Samarkand's dignitaries. The oldest date from the 14th century as Samarkand was starting to recover from the depredations of the Mongol hordes of the 13th century. Its shiny restoration in 2005, remains controversial.</p>]]><p><b>Skiing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The mountain resort of Beldersay, covered with snow in the winter months, and juniper and apple forests in the spring and summer, is located 80km to the southeast of Tashkent. The Beldersay route, divided into three skiing zones, is registered in the FIS (Federation of International Skiing) and has a length of 3020m (9900 ft).</p>]]><p><b>Tashkent</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Compare old and new in Tashkent. The capital preserves only a small proportion of its architectural past. A massive earthquake in 1966 flattened much of the old city and it was rebuilt with broad, tree-lined streets. The new buildings are of little architectural interest but earlier buildings lie in the old town to the west. A myriad of narrow winding alleys, it stands in stark contrast to the more modern Tashkent. Of interest among the older buildings are the 16th-century Kukeldash Madrasa and the Kaffali-Shash Mausoleum. Many of the Islamic sites in Tashkent are not open to non-Muslims, and visitors should always ask permission before entering a mosque or any other religious building.]]><p><b>Tashkent Museums</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tashkent has many museums to explore. The eccentric State Fine Arts Museum of Uzbekistan is one of the most popular and aside from the Soviet masterpieces and the Uzbek art that dominates the ground and first floors, out the back is the wonderful Fidoliyar garden which is full of the graves of Bolsheviks who died in revolutionary street fighting. Elsewhere in the city there is the Museum of Applied Arts, a Literary Museum (Alisher Navoi Literary Museum) and the Art Gallery of Uzbekistan.</p>]]><p><b>Trekking</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Trek in the mountains in the south of the country. There are high peaks for those wanting a challenge, while easier treks can be done in the foothills and on the plateaux. The best time to go is between March and November. There is superb hiking along the spurs and gorges of the Chatkal Range to the ancient silver mine in the Chatkal Natiore Preserve.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$45.3 billion (2011).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Cotton, gold, natural gas, mineral fertilisers, ferrous metals, textiles and motor vehicles.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, food, chemicals and metals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Russia, China, Kazakhstan, Republic of Korea and Turkey.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Uzbekistan has not been too affected by the global economic downturn, due to its relative isolation. However, while the country registered an impressive 8.5% growth in 2010, according to the World Bank in 2013, GDP growth is anticipated to slow to 7% as Uzbekistan&rsquo;s trading partners battle the financial crisis.</p>
<p>Uzbekistan's government is actively encouraging foreign investment, particularly in the processing industries for its raw material output. The January 1994 decree put into law a number of tax incentives for foreign investors, formally laid out guarantees for property protection, and promised a faster and less bureaucratic method of registration for foreign concerns.</p>
<p>Agriculture still makes up one-third of the annual GDP and provides livelihoods for 60% of the rural population. Livestock is reared in the steppes while a variety of crops, including grains, fruit and vegetables, are grown in the more fertile valleys. <br />
<br />
Due to its badly planned boom in irrigated agriculture, Uzbekistan consumes well over three-quarters of all of the water available to the Central Asian region. This is a disaster for many reasons, most famously the huge withdrawal of the Aral Sea, but also less publicized, general waterlogging.</p>
<p>Some of Uzbekistan's economic policies &ndash; such as a difficult currency conversion rules &ndash; have driven back potential foreign investors. While now official full currency convertibility has been applied for a decade now, strict controls mean it is not effective. <br />
<br />
While all foreign companies currently have to be registered with the Ministry of Foreign Economic Relations (which can open the door to all manner of bureaucracy), Uzbek companies remain keen and encourage foreign investment for areas such as energy production, textiles, telecommunications, tourism and ecology.</p>
<p>Import taxes &ndash; which can amount to as much as 150% of the actual value of the product &ndash; are applied to protect locally produced goods, making imported goods unaffordable for nearly everyone.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Uzbekistan's government is actively encouraging foreign investment, particularly in the processing industries for its raw material output. The January 1994 decree put into law a number of tax incentives for foreign investors, formally laid out guarantees for property protection, and promised a faster and less bureaucratic method of registration for foreign concerns.<br /><br />Other areas in which the Uzbeks would like to encourage foreign investment include the financial sector, energy production, extraction and processing of mineral raw materials, textiles, telecommunications, tourism and ecology. All foreign companies currently have to be registered with the Ministry of Foreign Economic Relations.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Uzbekistan Exhibition Centre</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 700084 ,(71) 134 4545 ,135 0973
					Website:http://www.uzexpocentre.uz
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Business Information Service for the Newly Independent States</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (202) 482 4655
					Website:http://www.bisnis.doc.gov
					Address: USA Trade Center,US Department of Commerce,Stop R*BISNIS,]]><b>Agency for Foreign Economic Relations</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 700029 ,(71) 138 5000
					Website:http://www.mfer.uz
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Uzbek food is similar to that of the rest of Central Asia. During the summer and autumn, there is a wide variety of fruit: grapes, pomegranates, apricots (which are also dried and sold at other times of the year) and, dwarfing them all, mountains of honeydew and watermelons which you will see in huge piles at markets and on roadsides. Unlike other Asian cuisines, Uzbek food is not spicy and tends to be quite bland. Uzbeks pride themselves on the quality and variety of their bread, which is disk-like in shape and quite hard, and is often decorated with patterns and sometimes colours too. In general, hotel food shows a strong Russian influence, soups, cold cuts, cheeses, yogurt and meat is generally served, and unless sweet, nearly all plates will be liberally sprinkled with dill. There are a number of restaurants that serve both European and Korean food. Beer, wine, vodka, brandy and are all widely available in restaurants.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull;<em> </em><em>Plov</em> (dozens of variations of this dish but usually consists of chunks of mutton, shredded red and yellow carrot and rice fried in a cast iron or aluminium pot. Staple food for both every day and celebrations). <br />
&bull; <em>Shashlyk</em> (skewered chunks of mutton barbecued over charcoal, served with sliced raw onions).<br />
&bull;<em> Lipioshka</em> (rounds of unleavened bread). Served in restaurants and often sold on street corners, to make an appetising meal. <br />
&bull; <em>Samsa</em> (samosas) are also sold in the street, but the quality is variable. <br />
&bull; <em>Manty</em> (large boiled dumplings stuffed with meat).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Uzbekistan, while Muslim, has kept hold of many its Soviet habits, including a love of alcohol. A small wine scene has started up as a result and now Uzbekistan has 14 wineries, the oldest and most famous being the Khovrenko Winery in Samarkand.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>It is usual to tip 5 to 10% in restaurants, bars and nightclubs. Restaurants in international hotels usually include service in the bill.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>No minimum age.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Like most of Central Asia, Uzbekistan doesn&rsquo;t have a great deal of nightlife going on. There are the usual slightly soulless bars in larger hotels in Tashkent, and a few better places in cities where tourists tend to congregate. In Bukhara there is a very small wine scene, with one or two wine shops setting up shop in old buildings and offering tastings of the local wines, some of which are surprisingly good. There are also a few cabarets and puppet shows in the early evening. In Samarkand you can find some blues bars and cafes that attract a mixture of tourists and locals, as well as one or two restaurants that stay open until midnight, which is unusual.</p>
<p>The scene in Tashkent isn&rsquo;t particularly sophisticated either, but there are some cinemas, ballet options and theatres that show European operas as well as traditional Uzbek dancing and music. The Navoi theatre, opposite the Tashkent Hotel, shows opera and ballet. Prices are low by Western standards; shows generally start at 1800. There are also a number of themed Western-style bars, restaurants and discos. Bear in mind, it&rsquo;s not a good idea to be out on the streets alone after 2300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As the capital, it&rsquo;s not surprising that Tashkent offers some of the best shopping in Uzbekistan. Boutiques and small independent shops sell the best Central Asian style carpets, skull caps, <em>suzani</em> and other textiles, as well as presenting the odd fashion show to encourage shoppers. At the other end of the spectrum there are the large Soviet-style malls and the traditional bazaars where most locals still shop. For travel essentials, like money belts and rucksacks these are where you&rsquo;ll find range and value. Traditional rugs and clothes, silk, spices and handicrafts can also be found in the smaller bazaars of Tashkent&rsquo;s Old City.</p>
<p>In more touristy centres, like Bukhara and Khiva, the shops around the main sights sell everything a tourist might wish to remind them of their Silk Road adventures &ndash; crockery, textiles, ikat printed cushion covers, old Soviet memorabilia, knives and spices.</p>
<p>Good buys include Islamic tiles, paintings, hand-stitched bedspreads and linens &ndash; beware, the cost difference between chemical and vegetable dye, and machine versus handmade is significant. Make sure you know what you are buying. Carpets are another good buy and in Bukhara, the silk weaving and carpet centres located around the late 16th-century Tim Abdulla Khan, near Taqi-Telpaq Furushon Bazaar, are a good choice. Generally workers are honest about advising whether the carpet is either handmade or machine-made. There are a couple of bookshops in Bukhara that have interesting selections of photographic books and maps about Uzbekistan. Khiva has many similar shops and stalls that line the main tourist drags and has plenty of craft centres where you can watch a traditional <em>suzani</em> being stitched.</p><p>Food shops open 0800-1700, all others open 0900-1900.</p><p>Bartering is commonplace but it's not as lively as elsewhere in Asia. A gentle approach works best.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourists are still required to stay in hotels that are licensed by Uzbektourism, and most hotels are run by them. However, a growing number of independent hotels are now being licensed. It is necessary for visitors to have a slip of paper stamped by the hotel to prove that they have stayed there. Most receptionists will remind you of this when you check-in but do remember to keep the slips safe. <br />
<br />
Services and facilities are not generally up to Western standards, but efforts are being made to improve them and there is a growing number of Western-style hotels owned by foreign companies. Most tourist hotel rooms have a shower and WC ensuite, although supplies of soap and toilet paper can be unreliable. Rooms tend to be clean and will usually be decorated in the typical Central Asian style, with rugs, carpets and rich colours. Front doors and entrance gates may be locked relatively early at night so it pays to enquire what time reception closes. <br />
<br />
All regional capitals have at least one Uzbektourism hotel that will accept foreigners. Many tourists will have booked tours which include accommodation, others will have to pay in US Dollars, unless they have special exemptions. Many large city hotels are Soviet in style, especially in the capital, so they can look very dated to western eyes and are often overpriced. Samarkand and Bukhara have the widest range of accommodation options, some with excellent views and atmosphere &ndash; often these are good value too, including breakfast and outdoor areas in which to relax.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guesthouses and bed and breakfasts are springing up all over Uzbekistan. These are cheaper than hotels and often mean you'll get the chance to meet and spend time with Uzbek families. B&B accommodation may not always offer a private bathroom, whereas guesthouses generally do.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourists are still required to stay in hotels that are licensed by Uzbektourism, and most hotels are run by them. However, a growing number of independent hotels are now being licensed. It is necessary for visitors to have a slip of paper stamped by the hotel to prove that they have stayed there. Most receptionists will remind you of this when you check-in but do remember to keep the slips safe. <br />
<br />
Services and facilities are not generally up to Western standards, but efforts are being made to improve them and there is a growing number of Western-style hotels owned by foreign companies. Most tourist hotel rooms have a shower and WC ensuite, although supplies of soap and toilet paper can be unreliable. Rooms tend to be clean and will usually be decorated in the typical Central Asian style, with rugs, carpets and rich colours. Front doors and entrance gates may be locked relatively early at night so it pays to enquire what time reception closes. <br />
<br />
All regional capitals have at least one Uzbektourism hotel that will accept foreigners. Many tourists will have booked tours which include accommodation, others will have to pay in US Dollars, unless they have special exemptions. Many large city hotels are Soviet in style, especially in the capital, so they can look very dated to western eyes and are often overpriced. Samarkand and Bukhara have the widest range of accommodation options, some with excellent views and atmosphere &ndash; often these are good value too, including breakfast and outdoor areas in which to relax.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourists are still required to stay in hotels that are licensed by Uzbektourism, and most hotels are run by them. However, a growing number of independent hotels are now being licensed. It is necessary for visitors to have a slip of paper stamped by the hotel to prove that they have stayed there. Most receptionists will remind you of this when you check-in but do remember to keep the slips safe. <br />
<br />
Services and facilities are not generally up to Western standards, but efforts are being made to improve them and there is a growing number of Western-style hotels owned by foreign companies. Most tourist hotel rooms have a shower and WC ensuite, although supplies of soap and toilet paper can be unreliable. Rooms tend to be clean and will usually be decorated in the typical Central Asian style, with rugs, carpets and rich colours. Front doors and entrance gates may be locked relatively early at night so it pays to enquire what time reception closes. <br />
<br />
All regional capitals have at least one Uzbektourism hotel that will accept foreigners. Many tourists will have booked tours which include accommodation, others will have to pay in US Dollars, unless they have special exemptions. Many large city hotels are Soviet in style, especially in the capital, so they can look very dated to western eyes and are often overpriced. Samarkand and Bukhara have the widest range of accommodation options, some with excellent views and atmosphere &ndash; often these are good value too, including breakfast and outdoor areas in which to relax.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No**]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;While emergency health care is available free of charge for visitors it is, as in most parts of the former Soviet  Union, inadequate. Doctors and hospitals often expect cash payment for health services. There is a severe shortage of basic medical supplies, including disposable needles, anaesthetics, antibiotics and vaccines. Travellers are therefore advised to take a well-equipped first-aid kit with them containing basic medicines and any prescriptions that they may need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For minor difficulties, visitors should ask the management at their hotel for help. In case of emergency, travellers should get a referral from either the Tashkent International Medical Clinic or from the appropriate embassy, since foreigners are strongly advised not to approach local health care facilities without somebody who knows local conditions and the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, if you are travelling around the country, it is worth bringing some motion sickness pills from home as the roads are rough, bumpy and long. Supplies of sanitary products for women are non-existent in small villages so bring supplies from home; the same applies to birth control. For major problems, visitors are well advised to seek help outside the country. Travel insurance is essential.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water, particularly outside main centres, should be regarded as being a potential health risk. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. However brucellosis, while rare in travellers, is common with locals &amp;ndash; this is transmitted via unpasteurised dairy products. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled. Ask for an &lt;em&gt;apoteka&lt;/em&gt; (pharmacist), if needed and clinics are called as &lt;em&gt;polikliniks&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Ramazon Hayit (End of Ramadan), Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Ramazon Hayit itself. Ramazon Hayit and Qurbon Hayit (Feast of Sacrifice) may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Day of Remembrance and Honour :
							09 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							01 September </p><p>Constitution Day :
							08 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Uzbekistan by visitors over 16 years without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes.<br />
&bull; 2L of beer and 2L of other alcoholic drinks.<br />
&bull; 2 bottles of perfume or eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; Other goods to the value of US$1,000 (reduced to US$10 if arriving from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/afghanistan">Afghanistan</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kazakhstan">Kazakhstan</a>, Krygyzstan, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tajikistan">Tajikistan</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkmenistan">Turkmenistan</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include narcotics, pornography, explosives, and printed and recorded matter directed against the country or inciting violence, religious hatred etc.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics, grain, flour, meat and meat products, sugar, vegetable oil and fur.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Uzbek Sum (UZS; symbol лв) = 100 tiyn. Notes are in denominations of лв1,000, 500, 200, 100, 50, 25, 10, 5, 3 and 1. Coins are in denominations of лв100, 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 3 and 1 tiyn.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourists and businesspeople without special status have to pay for hotels, hotel services and transport in hard currency. All bills are normally settled in cash.  <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars are the most widely accepted foreign currency, by far. Euros and Sterling will attract much poorer rates of exchange. It is illegal to change money on the black market and penalties can be harsh, although in the provinces this is sometimes the only way. Money exchangers can be found in bazaars but be wary of corrupt police who will demand large, on-the-spot fines if they catch you – undercover police are not unheard of. Banks and the currency exchange bureaux in major hotels will change at the official rates (which nowadays, due to reform, are about the same as the black market).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Acceptable in some of the major hotels in tourist centres. Uzbekistan has said that it intends to introduce its own Visa card in the near future.</p><p>Credit cards are now accepted at an increasing number of midrange and top-end hotels and at (very few) top restaurants in the capital. ATMs can be found in Tashkent. For cash advances in rural areas, MasterCard users should look for Asaka Bank, while Visa and Amex holders will usually (but not always) be able to get cash advanced at National Bank of Uzbekistan. Always take your passport with you as proof of ID when requesting a cash advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Very limited acceptance, especially outside of the capital. Be sure to list your travellers cheques on your customs declaration form or you won't be able to cash them.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800. Some banks open Sat 0900-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Uzbekistan, a passport valid for three months beyond the date of arrival is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>
<p>One blank page is needed for the visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If children are travelling with a single parent or third party, they must have documentary evidence of relationship to the person travelling with the child and permission for the child's travel from the parent or legal guardian not present.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As of August 2018, citizens from 101 countries can visit Uzbekistan without a visa if they are transiting and can provide an air ticket showing the next destination. The only requirement is transit passengers must depart Uzbekistan within five days of arrival.</p>
<p>These countries are: Albania, Algeria, Andorra, Antigua and Barbuda, Argentina, Austria, Australia, Bahamas, Bahrain, Barbados, Belgium, Belize, Bhutan, Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina, Brazil, Brunei, Bulgaria, Canada, Chile, China (including Hong Kong), Colombia, Costa Rica, Croatia, Cyprus, Czech Republic, Denmark, Dominica, Dominican Republic, Ecuador, Equatorial Guinea, Estonia, Fiji, Finland, France, Gabon, Germany, Greece, Grenada, Guatemala, Guyana, Honduras, Hungary, Iceland, India, Ireland, Italy, Jamaica, Kuwait, Latvia, Lebanon, Liechtenstein, Lithuania, Luxembourg, Macedonia, Maldives, Malta, Mauritius, Mexico, Monaco, Mongolia, Montenegro, Morocco, Nauru, Netherlands, New Zealand, Norway, Oman, Palau, Panama, Peru, Philippines, Poland, Portugal, Qatar, Romania, San Marino, Saudi Arabia, Serbia, Seychelles, Slovakia, Slovenia, St Vincent and the Grenadines, St Kitts and Nevis, St Lucia, South Africa, Spain, Sri Lanka, Suriname, Sweden, Switzerland, Thailand, Trinidad and Tobago, Tunisia, Turkmenistan, United Arab Emirates, United Kingdom, United States, Uruguay, Vatican, Venezuela and Vietnam.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An e-visa is valid for a period of stay of up to 30 days with a single entry. And you must visit Uzbekistan within 90 days from the date of issue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you're from a country that is not listed in the e-visa section above, visit your nearest embassy or consulate to apply for a visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow three working days for an e-visa processing. If you apply in person, please allow 10 working days but be aware that visa processing time entirely depends upon the embassy. An express service may be available for an additional fee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>This is not usually required but note that you cannot take more foreign currency out of the country than the amount you declared when you entered the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is sometimes possible to get a one-time Uzbek visa extension in Uzbekistan, at the OVIR (Department of Foreign Travel and Exit) office in Tashkent.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Uzbekistan does not quarantine healthy pets if the owner can produce a valid veterinary certificate. Owners can transport up to two dogs or cats or pet birds, except pigeons. Your pet must be vaccinated for rabies no earlier than 30 days and no more than 12 months before the departure.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[41.772024]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[63.146023]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>447,400 sq km (172,742 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>30,300,446 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>65.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tashkent.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Covering approximately 448,000 sq km (173,000 square miles), Uzbekistan (literally &lsquo;land of the Uzbeks&rsquo;) is one of the larger countries in Central Asia (Kazakhstan is by far the largest) and the only one sharing borders with four other Central Asian states. Mountainous Kyrgyzstan lies to the northeast, Tajikistan to the south, Turkmenistan to the southwest, and Kazakhstan to the north with which it shares a suitably long border at 2,203km (1,370 miles). There is also a very short 137km (85 miles) border with war-torn Afghanistan.</p>
<p>To the north, and in the central part of the country, lies one of the largest deserts in the world &ndash; Kyzyl Kum (meaning &lsquo;red sand&rsquo; in Turkic), where the odd camel grazes and where gold is mined in the centre. Elsewhere, the terrain of Uzbekistan is mostly flat. Desert dunes cover the country and some river valleys flow along the courses of the Amu Darya, Syr Darya (Sirdaryo), and Zarafshon rivers.</p>
<p>Steppe land and desert plains account for two-thirds of the land mass, with the remainder of the land rising into the foothills of the Tien Shan mountain range. The peaks along the border of Tajikistan and Kyrgyzstan reach to over 4,000m (13,000ft). While less than 10% of the land is arable, there are plenty of minerals, containing stocks of natural gas, lignite and coal, gold (it is the world&rsquo;s ninth largest producer) and copper.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Predominantly Sunni Muslim, with Shia (15%), Russian Orthodox and a remaining but tiny, Jewish minority (in Bukhara).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Uzbekistan is a Muslim country, albeit a fairly liberal one where women often wear jeans and skirts in the cities. However, for visitors it&rsquo;s best to cover up out of respect to the local culture and to avoid unwanted attention in all areas, but especially in the conservative Ferghana Valley. Minorities include Tajiks, Kazakhs, Tatars, and Karakalpaks who all contribute to the host culture with their own Central Asian customs.</p>
<p>In general,<em> lipioshka</em> (bread) should never be laid upside down and should never be put on the ground, even if it is in a bag. It is normal to remove shoes but not socks when entering someone's house or sitting down in a <em>chai-khana</em>.</p>
<p>Hospitality is genuine in Uzbekistan and many follow the saying: &quot;The visitor is dearer than your father.&quot; While crime is rare, it&rsquo;s wise to avoid ostentatious displays of wealth (eg jewellery) in public places. Homosexuality is illegal.<br />
<br />
<strong>Photography: </strong>Photography near airports, military barracks and police stations can upset the authorities. Most people in Central Asia react well to requests for photographs, but be respectful, always ask and be aware that some older people might not be so forthcoming.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs (two round pins) and Australian-style plugs (three flat, angled pins) are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Shavkat Mirziyoyev since 2003.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Islam Karimov since 1991.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The territory of modern-day Uzbekistan and its close neighbours have seen many empires rise and fall. The Sogdians, the Macedonians, the Huns, the Mongolians, the Seljuks, the Timurids and the Khanates of Samarkand, Bukhara Khiva and Khorezm all held sway at one time or another.</p>
<p>Central Asia really came of age with the development of the Silk Road from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> to the West, the most valuable trading route of its day. The riches that it brought were used to build fabulous mosques and madrassars (Islamic colleges), most of which were destroyed by the Mongol hordes in the 13th century. Much of the damage was repaired and under Timur the Lame, many new cities were built in the 14th century. Timur conquered all before him and, at its height, his empire stretched to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a> and Baghdad and as far west as <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ankara">Ankara</a> in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkey">Turkey</a>.</p>
<p>After his death, the empire crumbled and Central Asia was split into warring Khanates. The Russians had long had their eyes on the lands over their southern border, ever since Peter the Great sent his first military mission to Khiva in 1717, but it was to be another 150 years before they started to make any real headway.</p>
<p>In 1865, Russian General Konstantin Kaufmann took Tashkent and signed agreements with the Khans. However, following the Russian Revolution, the Bolsheviks were resisted in Central Asia by bands known as Basmachi until the 1930s when they were finally suppressed and Moscow took control.</p>
<p>The history of Central Asia under Soviet rule is one of exploitation. Uzbekistan was turned into a cotton monoculture and most of the product was processed north of the Urals, in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ukraine">Ukraine</a>. Intensive cotton cultivation in Uzbekistan has in fact been linked to the drying out of the Aral Sea, one of the biggest ecological disasters in Central Asia.</p>
<p>Politically the country hasn&rsquo;t fared much better. Islam Karimov has governed Uzbekistan with an iron fist since 1989 when he took over as head of the Uzbek Communist Party (now the People&rsquo;s Democratic Party of Uzbekistan), retaining his position as the new country declared independence from the Soviet Union in 1991. His government has taken an uncompromising line against all opposition, resulting in a dreadful human rights record with reports of violations such as torture, arbitrary arrest and the forced sterilisation of women.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Muslims constitute some 90% of Uzbekistan&rsquo;s population. Most are non-denominational and independence does not seem to have precipitated an upsurge in fundamentalism.<br />
&bull;	Uzbekistan has the largest armed forces in Central Asia, with some 65,000 servicemen.<br />
&bull;	Around a third of the country&rsquo;s population is aged under 14.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Uzbekistan]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+99 871 120 1500.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/uzbekistan</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+99 871 120 1500.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1230 and 1330-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>67 Gulyamov Street<br/>Tashkent<br/>100 000 <br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Uzbekistan in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+99 202 887 5300.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.uzbekistan.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+99 202 887 5300.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 1000-1200 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1746 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Uzbekistan in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7229 7679. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.uzbekembassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7229 7679. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1800; Mon-Wed and Fri 1000-1300 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>41 Holland Park<br/>London<br/>W11 3RP<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most people would struggle to find Uzbekistan on a map, let alone get around to visiting. But while this Central Asian nation remains a mystery to the masses, its obscurity makes it all the more appealing for more adventurous travellers.</p>
<p>Those who do make the trip are following in famous footprints: from Alexander the Great to Genghis Khan, some of the world&rsquo;s most famous pioneers and conquerors have blazed a trail through this land.</p>
<p>Granted, Uzbekistan has its fair share of problems. It would be remiss not to mention the hard-line government, corrupt officials and Islamic militants that besmirch the reputation of the country. But they are the exception rather than the rule: most people in Uzbekistan extend legendary hospitality to visitors.</p>
<p>While the country is young, having gained independence in 1991 after the break-up of the Soviet Union, the roots of Uzbekistan are ancient.</p>
<p>The historic town of Samarkand, once a crossroads on the Silk Road, has long been known as the &lsquo;Jewel of Islam&rsquo;. One of the so-called Big Three (a term used to describe Uzbekistan&rsquo;s three main Silk Road cities) its cityscape is dominated by sparkling turquoise domes and towering minarets adorned with intricate mosaics.</p>
<p>Stunning examples of this architecture can be found across Uzbekistan, most notably in Khiva, the best-preserved and most remote of the Big Three. It&rsquo;s a living museum, home as it is to a vast collection of Islamic architecture, which remains frozen in time within the city walls.&nbsp;And then there&rsquo;s Bukhara. The last one of the Big Three, it is also known as the &lsquo;Pillar of Religion&rsquo; and is surely one of the most exquisite cities in the Islamic world.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s not all about manmade attractions, though. The Ferghana Valley is a place of unremitting natural beauty where fertile valleys give out to the snow-capped Tien Shan and Pamir mountains.</p>
<p>This also happens to be the country's most fertile region, its breadbasket, where visitors can enjoy stunning landscapes, local produce and friendly bazaars rarely seen by Western eyes.</p><p>Most people would struggle to find Uzbekistan on a map, let alone get around to visiting. But while this Central Asian nation remains a mystery to the masses, its obscurity makes it all the more appealing for more adventurous travellers.</p>
<p>Those who do make the trip are following in famous footprints: from Alexander the Great to Genghis Khan, some of the world&rsquo;s most famous pioneers and conquerors have blazed a trail through this land.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
