<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Vanuatu" ColCode="vut" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="vu" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Vanuatu]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical/sub-tropical. Summer is from November to March, the average temperature is 28°C (up to 32°C) and it can be hot, wet and humid. Winter is from April to October with the temperature averaging 23°C. Sea temperature varies from 22 to 28 degrees making swimming enjoyable all year round. Rainfall is moderate and cyclones are possible, usually between December and April every couple of years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Casual, light clothing year round with perhaps a light sweater or jacket in the winter months.  Outside resorts women should dress modestly.  A sarong can be handy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Vanuatu (<a href="http://www.airvanuatu.com" target="_blank">www.airvanuatu.com</a>) operates domestic routes in Vanuatu.  From Port Vila there are daily flights to the islands of Tanna and Espiritu Santo and less regular scheduled services to other islands within the archipelago. Unity Airlines (<a href="http://www.unity-airlines.com" target="_blank">www.unity-airlines.com</a>) offers charter flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Inter-island ferries operate very infrequently from Port Vila and this mode of travel is not recommended for visitors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>These are plentiful and are metered (costing around VUV100 per km) although a fixed rate can be agreed on.</p><p>A current driving licence from your country is acceptable.  Normally drivers need to be 25 years or over.</p><p>Major car hire operators have offices in Port Vila. Cars, 4-wheel drive vehicles and jeeps are available.</p><p>Some resorts have pushbikes for guest use.  Vanuatu Ecotours offers mountain bike tours. You can hire scooters from a company located near the markets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local buses are plentiful (look for a &lsquo;B&rsquo; on the number plate). They drop door-to-door so you may get a &lsquo;scenic route&rsquo; depending on where other passengers are going.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Air Vanuatu (<a href="http://www.airvanuatu.com" target="_blank">www.airvanuatu.com</a>).  Air Vanuatu flies to Port Vila from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sydney">Sydney</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brisbane">Brisbane</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/melbourne">Melbourne</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/auckland">Auckland</a>. Virgin <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a> (<a href="http://www.virginaustralia.com" target="_blank">www.virginaustralia.com</a>) flies from Brisbane. There are also flights from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-caledonia">New Caledonia</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/fiji">Fiji</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sydney">Sydney</a> - 3 hours 30 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/auckland">Auckland</a> - 3 hours 15 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Vanuatu is a full-service airline (meals and drinks included in the fare) and allows 23kg stowed luggage.  Virgin Australia has a &lsquo;user pays&rsquo; policy for in-flight meals, drinks, entertainment and stowed luggage.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the ticket price.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Vanuatu is a full-service airline (meals and drinks included in the fare) and allows 23kg stowed luggage.  Virgin Australia has a &lsquo;user pays&rsquo; policy for in-flight meals, drinks, entertainment and stowed luggage.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Bauerfield International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 6km (4 miles) from Port-Vila (journey time - 15 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are no area codes. For outgoing international calls dial 00 and then the country code and number. There are public telephones at airports and post offices. SIM cards and pre-paid phone cards can be purchased in local currency from the post office and some retail outlets. For emergency services, dial: 22333 for fire services; 22222 for police; 22100 for an ambulance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with a few international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good.  SIM cards can be purchased from TVL and the post office (and in-flight with Air Vanuatu) – the cost for a SIM usually comes with the same amount in pre-paid phone credit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are several internet cafés in Port Vila and Luganville. Internet facilities are also available at some post offices.  Most resorts offer internet access.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vanuatu provides locals and visitors news and entertainment through television, radio and newspapers in French, English and Bislama.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Post offices are located on the main streets in Port Vila and Luganville, on Espiritu Santo. Airmail to Europe takes about seven days.  There are novelty post offices at Hideaway Island (underwater with waterproof postcards) and at Mt Yasur, the active volcano on Tanna island (literally 'hot mail).</p><p>Post office hours: Mon-Fri 0730-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bathe beneath the waterfalls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Whether you take an organised tour or catch the local bus, the Mele Cascade waterfall is only 15 minutes from Port Vila. The best views are directly below, so pack bathers and enjoy the swimming around the plunge pools. Following cyclone Pam and the subsequent closure of Edge Adventure, visitors cannot currently abseil down the falls.</p>]]><p><b>Dare to look at the lava, Yasur</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Drive to the summit of the world's most accessible active volcano, Yasur, on Tanna Island. Peer into the crater at a seething mass of bubbling lava. You can also learn about the John Frum cargo cult; it began with the arrival of an American soldier in WWII, and believers now wait for him to return to the island with great riches.</p>]]><p><b>Drive a dune buggy on an off-road tour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Adventure operators run tours from Port Vila, so jump in a dune buggy and get off-road and dirty. Follow the leader in convoy as you power along a black sand beach, through forest tracks by way of some local villages. The most adventurous should tackle this tour if there has been some rain. Embrace it – you will get very muddy. </p>]]><p><b>Gasp at the Naghol</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Every Saturday from April to June, Pentecost Island holds the world famous <em>Naghol</em> ("land dive").  The forerunner to bungee jumping, this traditional festival involves men diving from 100m-high (328ft) towers with only vines tied around their ankles. The <em>Naghol</em> is a celebration of the yam harvest and is a fertility rite for men.</p>]]><p><b>Go wreck diving at Espiritu Santo Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover James A Michener's inspiration for <em>South Pacific</em>, Espiritu Santo Island. Here, scuba divers can see the liner President Coolidge and the destroyer USS Tucker rest on the seabed, and explore Million Dollar Point where military equipment was dumped at the end of the war. The snorkelling is also excellent at one of Vanuatu's most scenic islands.</p>]]><p><b>Haul a catch with deep-sea fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With marlin, wahoo, swordfish and tuna, Vanuatu offers some of the best deep-sea fishing in the South Pacific, and game fishing tournaments are held throughout the year. For smaller catches reef fishing is also available and boats for both depart from Port Vila Harbour. Take to Espiritu Santo for the best in-shore fishing trips. </p>]]><p><b>Seek out Hideaway Island Marine Sanctuary</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located just off Mele Bay, Hideaway Island is a resort that features excellent offshore snorkelling, a fine restaurant and the world's only underwater post office – complete with waterproof postcards. Day-trippers are welcome to this marine sanctuary to enjoy the snorkel safari and scuba dives.</p>]]><p><b>Spot dolphins from your sailboat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Set sail in search of dolphins aboard the Coongoola. The lovely timber ketch departs from Havannah Harbour and takes passengers to the turtle sanctuary on Tranquillity Island (Moso) for a beach barbecue and spot of snorkelling. If the wind is favourable you return under sail and there is a good chance of being joined by dolphins off the bow.</p>]]><p><b>Try the national dish at the Mama's Market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Seek out the harbour-front markets in Port Vila where a wonderful array of fruit, vegetables and flowers await. Mama's Market is run by local women and is the best place on the island to sample the national dish, <em>lap lap</em> (cooked yam roots with coconut cream and meat). Further along the handicraft market sells carvings, sarongs and other items of clothing, ideal for souvenirs.</p>]]><p><b>Understand local traditions at Ekasup Cultural Village</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ekasup Cultural Village is 10 minutes from Port Vila and it explains Vanuatu's traditional village life, medicines, food, dancing and hunting methods (like how to catch fish with a spider's web). Local men, women and children participate, so the traditional culture is passed through the generations. Tours run twice a day (except Sundays) and Friday night is Melanesian Feast night.</p>]]><p><b>Understand the cultures of each island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Vanuatu Museum & Cultural Centre is opposite Parliament house, near the Chief's Nakamal (meeting place). There are permanent displays of traditional artefacts, pottery, fossils, masks and slit-gongs on show to reflect the diversity of culture and history on the various islands. As well as daily video screenings, the centre hosts vibrant temporary exhibits and performances (sand-drawing, bamboo flute, traditional dance and story-telling).</p>]]><p><b>Unearth history at The Secret Garden</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located in Mele, The Secret Garden offers the chance to learn about the local flora and fauna, explore thatched huts from the various islands and see iguanas, pythons and flying foxes. It presents a quirky look at Vanuatu's history including missionaries, cannibalism and traditional customs, as well as the more serious subjects of blackbirding and WWII.</p>]]><p><b>View Vanuatu from a helicopter above</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the serene South Pacific islands from above with a seaplane or helicopter flight. Both operate on the island with a number of flights available from short scenic flyovers, trips to a private island for a Robinson Crusoe-esque picnic or to one of the out-of-town restaurants for lunch. The helicopter is also great for aerial photography opportunities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$721 million (2011).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Cocoa, beef and veal, copra, timber, kava and coffee.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and transport equipment, food, fuel, basic manufactured goods and chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Australia, New Zealand, Indonesia and the EU.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Agriculture and fishing occupy 40% of the working population. Fruit and vegetables are grown for domestic consumption while coffee, copra, beef and veal are the main export commodities. The sale of fishing licences to foreign fleets is another important source of revenue.<br /><br />There is also a sizeable timber industry, originally encouraged by the government but now strictly regulated in the wake of international pressure. The industrial sector is mostly concerned with food processing and construction. Identified mineral resources, including manganese, gold and copper have yet to be exploited on a commercial scale. <br /><br />While mineral deposits may be of future value to the Vanuatu economy, the government's recent efforts to diversify the economy have been focused on the service sector. The most important of these is tourism (backed by the construction of new hotels and airport improvements, allied to a focus on 'ecotourism') and 'offshore' financial services. Tourism is worth about US$55 million to the economy annually. Visitor numbers have increased significantly over the last 12 months. A 'flag of convenience' shipping register was also created.<br /><br />Despite these efforts, the economy is still vulnerable to its geographical circumstances; a severe earthquake followed by a tsunami in late 1999 caused considerable damage to several islands. Meanwhile, offshore finance has run into trouble. In April 2002, Vanuatu was one of seven countries 'named and shamed' by the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) and threatened with sanctions for its failure to take adequate measures against money-laundering. Since then, the Vanuatu authorities have tightened their financial services regulatory regime.<br /><br />Foreign aid remains essential to sustain the economy. In 2002, Vanuatu signed up to the newly-established regional trade bloc created under the Pacific Island Countries Trade Agreement (PICTA). Australia, New Zealand, Japan, the UK and France are the principal donors. <br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A casual approach to business prevails. Shirts and smart trousers will suffice - ties are only necessary for the most formal occasions. Business is conducted in English, French or Bislama.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1130 and 1330-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Vanuatu Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Vanuatu Investment Promotion Authority</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:http://www.investinvanuatu.com
					Address: Pilioko House,1st Floor,Port-Vila,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The multicultural nature of Port Vila is reflected in the cuisine – there's French, Mediterranean, Chinese, Italian, Thai, Asian Fusion, tapas and seafood.  There are about 40 cafes and restaurants in and around Port Vila, many of them excellent. Some are located within resorts (it is fine to 'resort-hop').  Local beef is arguably the best in the world and the local fruit is also very good.  The chefs in Vanuatu are very good and many are trained at the Hospitality School (Nambanga Restaurant)  - it opens to the public for lunch several times a week for top restaurant quality at cafe prices.  Phone 24066 for reservations and hop on a local bus.<br /><br />Imported alcohol (wines, spirits and beer) can be expensive – apart from the transportation costs, there is duty payable.  As an example, an Australian or New Zealand wine will be about double the cost in a liquor outlet at home and up to double that price in a restaurant.  The local beer, Tusker, is very good and well-priced.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; <em>Lap Lap</em> (grated yam, banana or manioc smothered in coconut cream and cooked in an earth oven) can be sampled at the markets. 

&bull; Coconut crab is a Vanuatu specialty but many restaurants have put a moratorium on serving it as the species is becoming endangered.]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Not expected or encouraged, as it goes against local tradition.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>The jury is sort of out on this one.  Some people say the legal drinking age is 21, some say it is 18 and some say it is 15 (the age travellers can legally arrive in the country with duty free alcohol).  It matters little as age is never asked and ID is never asked for.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Port-Vila has several nightclubs with music and dancing. There is also a cinema. Evening cruises are organised with wine, snacks and island music. Traditional music and dancing take place at various island festivities to which visitors are welcome, and some hotels put on evening entertainment and dancing. Details are available from the Vanuatu National Tourism Office.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many boutique and speciality shops in Port Vila and excellent duty free shops that sell perfumes, jewellery, sound equipment and alcohol.  The 'lower' main street (nearest the harbour) has the banks, chemists, boutiques and duty free shops while the 'upper' main street has an array of Chinese owned shops.  There are souvenir markets on the harbour front that sell handicrafts, carvings, sarongs, necklaces and novelty items like WWII Coke bottles and 'baskets blong titi' (coconut shell bras).  Inexpensive hair-braiding is also offered here.  Fresh fruit, vegetables and flowers are available at the colourful Mama's Markets (open 24 hours, close Saturday afternoon to Monday morning) and there are a number of well-stocked supermarkets.  There are several liquor outlets (they also close Saturday lunchtime to Monday morning).  Alcohol is available in resorts on Sundays.</p><p>Shopping hours vary – most open at 0730 and close at 1700 Mon-Fri and supermarkets stay open until around 2000. Shops open Saturday mornings. Some businesses close for 'siesta' from 1130-1330 (except restaurants, banks, supermarkets and the post office).  The market in the town centre is open 24 hours (closed Saturday afternoon to Monday morning) for flowers, fruit, vegetables and handicrafts.</p><p>While most carvings and wooden artefacts will be fine to take home, they should be declared for inspection.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vanuatu has many international-standard resorts in and around Port Vila that cater for different needs and budgets.  There are large family resorts with lots of facilities (watersports, pools, tennis, golf etc), boutique adult-only resorts targeting the romance market, self-contained apartments and budget accommodation. Because of the competition between resorts there are often excellent specials (e.g. Stay 7 nights Pay 5 nights).  There is a tourism levy of 100 vatu per night.<br /><br />On Santo there is a range of accommodation to suit couples, divers and families. On Tanna, White Grass Ocean Resort and Friendly Bungalows cater well to both ends of the market.  Accommodation on other islands can be more basic (guesthouse).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vanuatu has many international-standard resorts in and around Port Vila that cater for different needs and budgets.  There are large family resorts with lots of facilities (watersports, pools, tennis, golf etc), boutique adult-only resorts targeting the romance market, self-contained apartments and budget accommodation. Because of the competition between resorts there are often excellent specials (e.g. Stay 7 nights Pay 5 nights).  There is a tourism levy of 100 vatu per night.<br /><br />On Santo there is a range of accommodation to suit couples, divers and families. On Tanna, White Grass Ocean Resort and Friendly Bungalows cater well to both ends of the market.  Accommodation on other islands can be more basic (guesthouse).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vanuatu has many international-standard resorts in and around Port Vila that cater for different needs and budgets.  There are large family resorts with lots of facilities (watersports, pools, tennis, golf etc), boutique adult-only resorts targeting the romance market, self-contained apartments and budget accommodation. Because of the competition between resorts there are often excellent specials (e.g. Stay 7 nights Pay 5 nights).  There is a tourism levy of 100 vatu per night.<br /><br />On Santo there is a range of accommodation to suit couples, divers and families. On Tanna, White Grass Ocean Resort and Friendly Bungalows cater well to both ends of the market.  Accommodation on other islands can be more basic (guesthouse).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There is a hospital in Port Vila as well as medical centres.  Doctors 'on-call' will visit resorts.  The chemists/pharmacies in Port Vila also have good knowledge regarding tropical ailments.  On the outer islands there are small clinics and medical dispensaries.  Health insurance is advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is safe to drink but some visitors do get mild abdominal upsets. There is high calcium content in the water, which can result in a few white specks in tea or coffee.  Bottled water is inexpensive and readily available.  It is important to keep well-hydrated in the tropics.  Most milk is UHT/long life milk.  Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are considered safe to eat.  The local beef (organic) is excellent.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;While there have been no recorded cases of malaria on the main island of Efate for many years, for travel to some of the outer islands, anti-malaria medication is recommended.  Consult your doctor/physician.  Your doctor may also recommend a vaccination against hepatitis.  A tetanus injection can be required for some cuts/abrasions but this can be had after the event.  Coral cuts are common and they can become infected.  Treat with hydrogen peroxide, antiseptic and keep covered.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Father Walter Lini Day :
							21 February </p><p>Custom Chief's Day :
							05 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Children's Day :
							24 July </p><p>Independence Day :
							30 July </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Constitution Day :
							05 October </p><p>Unity Day :
							29 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Family Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Vanuatu by passengers aged 18 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 250 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 25 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2L of spirits and 2L of wine and 9L of beer.<br />
&bull; 250ml of eau de toilette and 100ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; Other articles up to a value of VUV50,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted goods include firearms, ammunition, indecent publications, illicit drugs and endangered species.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vatu (VUV) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of VUV5,000, 1,000, 500 and 200. Coins are in denominations of VUV100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Australian Dollars are also accepted in some shops and restaurants.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Exchange facilities are available at the airport and trade banks. It is advisable to exchange foreign currency after arriving in Vanuatu. Australian Dollars are accepted by many shops, restaurants and hotels in Port-Vila, but rarely outside major towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted, American Express and Diners Club less so.  Fees may apply for using credit cards for payments (3% to 5%).</p><p>There are ATMs at the airport, outside the Westpac and ANZ Banks and outside supermarkets.  Money can be exchanged at the National Bank counter at the airport, at the ANZ or Westpac banks, at Goodies souvenir shop or 7/11 in Port Vila.  Resorts also exchange money but the rate will be lower than banks/money exchange outlets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are accepted but most visitors use cash or credit/debit cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>ANZ: Mon-Fri 0800-1500; Westpac Bank: Mon-Fri 0830-1600; Bred Bank: Mon-Fri 0830-1530.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Vanuatu, a passport valid for six months beyond the date of planned departure is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visa: VUV3,600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Principal Immigration Officer, Immigration Department Vanuatu, Private Mail Bag 0092, Port Vila, Vanuatu (<a href="mailto:immigration@vanuatu.gov.vu">immigration@vanuatu.gov.vu</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can extend your stay to a maximum of 120 days at the Immigration Department in Port Vila.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-15.376706]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[166.959158]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>12,190 sq km (4,707 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>270,470 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>22.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Port-Vila.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vanuatu is in the heart of Melanesia, with Papua New Guinea and Solomon Islands to the north, Fiji to the east and New Caledonia to the southeast. The Vanuatu Archipelago is a Y-shaped 1,300km (808 miles) and long chain of four main islands and 79 smaller islands, of which 68 are inhabited. The islands themselves are mostly mountains of volcanic origin (several of the islands still have active volcanoes) with narrow coastal plains and have a combined area of 12,200 sq km (7,581 miles) and a combined coastline length of 2,528km (1,571 miles).   The Ambrym and Lopevi volcanoes are permanently active and highly dangerous. Lopevi was extinct for many years but became active 50 years ago. Further to the south, on the island of Tanna, is Yasur, cited as the most accessible active volcano in the world and a major tourist attraction. Geophysical activity is under constant monitoring by the French scientific organisation, IRD (Institut de Recherche pour le D&eacute;velopement). Most of the islands are densely forested and mountainous with narrow bands of cultivated land along the coasts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mostly Christian, the principal religions are Presbyterian (36.7%), Anglican (15%), Roman Catholic (15%), indigenous beliefs (7.6%), Seventh-Day Adventist (6.2%), and Church of Christ (3.8%).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Informal wear is suitable for most occasions. Some establishments appreciate men wearing long trousers in the evenings. Life goes at its own pace ('island time') and while modern influences can be seen in the main centres, in some villages on the outer islands, age-old customs continue. Those hiking or exploring must be aware that Vanuatu has strict and sensitive land ownership regulations and permission should be sought before venturing onto private property.  Vanuatu is also a tax haven so there is much off-shore investment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Australian-style plugs with three flat, angled pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Charlot Salwai&nbsp;since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Acting President Esmon Saimon since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Settlement in Vanuatu dates back to around 500BC. For centuries the ni-Vanuatu have recorded their history orally, passing stories from one generation to the next. Sometimes myths and events blur. For example, Roy Mata, the chief for Efate and the Shepherd Islands, died around 1265 and stories were told of his burial that his wives, close relatives and clan leaders chose to be buried alive with him. The stories were so accurate that in 1967 the digs were easy to locate and revealed the stories were true.</p><p>European explorers visited the islands in the 17th and 18th centuries from various parts of the globe. In 1774, Cook sailed to Malekula, Erromango, Tanna, Santo and Efate (which he named Sandwich Island). The 19th century saw the indigenous population decimated by atrocities – slaughtered by sandalwood traders, kidnapped as cheap labour for the cane fields and the infected by missionaries who introduced many diseases.</p><p>In 1906, it was decided without any consultation with the indigenous people that the New Hebrides would become an Anglo-French Condominium. This caused chaos with French and English currencies, two prisons, two hospitals, 'Bobbies' patrolling one side of the street and gendarmes the other and, for a short time, vehicles drove on both sides of the road.</p><p>The early part of the 20th century saw the local people employed on low wages by white plantation owners in conditions not much better than slavery. Later, the planters recruited labour from Malaya, China, Vietnam, Fiji and Tonga, which explains today's multicultural mix.</p><p>After World War 2, a complex power struggle began between the indigenous islanders and the dual colonial interests over the future political and economic course of the islands. The constitutional position was settled in 1977, at a conference between British, French and New Hebridean representatives in Paris, and the islands became fully independent in 1980 with the New Hebrides becoming the Republic of Vanuatu.</p><p>Under its written constitution Vanuatu elects a President (currently Baldwin Lonsdale) as head of state, but power rests with the Prime Minister (since 2016 Charlot Salwai) who is the elected head of government and appoints a Council of Ministers. As with NiVan society, politics tend to divide along linguistic English and French lines making the formation of coalition governments somewhat troublesome. The country's legal system is based on British common law and French civil law.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>• The traditional music of Vanuata is created on percussive instruments, but in the 20th century string band music became popular with its guitars, ukuleles and popular songs.</p><p>• The national dish, laplap, is cooked in an underground oven.</p><p>• The indigenous flying fox, or fruit bat, lays a vital role in pollinating native trees.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Permanent Mission of the Republic of Vanuatu to the United Nations in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(212) 661 4323</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.un.int/wcm/content/site/vanuatu</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(212) 661 4323</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>Suite 1200-18<br/>42 Broadway,12th Floor<br/>New York<br/>10004<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Fiji]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ukinfiji.fco.gov.uk/en/</p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs: 0800-1240 / 1300-1600, Fri: 0800-1300&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>PO Box 1355 <br/>Victoria House, 47 Gladstone Road <br/>Suva <br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you can confidently point to Vanuatu on a map then you&rsquo;re a better geographer than most. Drifting like flotsam in the Pacific Ocean, this little-known nation has much to offer intrepid travellers and is all the more appealing for its obscurity.</p>
<p>Made up of approximately 83 islands, the geologically active archipelago is a natural playground of colourful coral reefs, bubbling volcanoes and lush rainforest. Visitors can drive up to the crater of Yasur, cited as the most accessible active volcano in the world, sea kayak round the islands' sandy shores, explore underwater WWII relics, or hike and bike through coconut plantations and steamy jungles.</p>
<p>Those less disposed to physical exertion can always while away lazy days on Vanuatu&rsquo;s bountiful beaches, which really are the picture of tropical island idyll. Or why not charter a boat and hop from one island to the next? Wherever you go expect a good feast: the food here is absolutely exquisite, a testament not only to talented local chefs, but also the profusion of fresh ingredients that grow on this fertile archipelago.</p>
<p>Warm and welcoming, with a rich and sometimes mysterious traditional culture, the ni-Vanuatu people greet visitors as friends and are keen to share stories about their country, which was declared the happiest nation on the planet in 2006. The Happy Planet Index hasn&rsquo;t bestowed this title on Vanuatu since, but it&rsquo;s still pretty jovial by all accounts.</p>
<p>Tourism in Vanuatu is largely centred on the islands of Tanna, Espiritu Santo and Efat&eacute;, with most international visitors arriving on the latter. From here it is easy to travel by boat or plane to the rest of the country, which caters for travellers of all stripes. Sure, it&rsquo;s skewered to the well heeled, but amongst the high-end beach resorts are a smattering of wallet friendly options. Proof that paradise needn&rsquo;t break the bank.</p><p>If you can confidently point to Vanuatu on a map then you&rsquo;re a better geographer than most. Drifting like flotsam in the Pacific Ocean, this little-known nation has much to offer intrepid travellers and is all the more appealing for its obscurity.</p>
<p>Made up of approximately 83 islands, the geologically active archipelago is a natural playground of colourful coral reefs, bubbling volcanoes and lush rainforest. Visitors can drive up to the crater of Yasur, cited as the most accessible active volcano in the world, sea kayak round the islands' sandy shores, explore underwater WWII relics, or hike and bike through coconut plantations and steamy jungles.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
