<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Venezuela" ColCode="ven" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ve" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Venezuela]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Venezuela's location perched 8° above the equator, means it generally enjoys a balmy warm climate. Temperatures don't fluctuate wildly, hovering between 26°C (79°F) and 28°C (82°F) and making the country something of an all year round destination. The coastal regions on the Caribbean feel balmiest, and the lowland areas also enjoy a tropical climate.</p><p>The main factor in temperature variance is altitude. The mountainous Andean regions are significantly cooler, and temperatures can drop to around 9°C (48°F).</p><p>Venezuela's rainy season runs from May to December. During this period, there is the possibility of flooding in certain low-lying areas, such as the Llanos and in some valleys of the Andes. The dry season is from December to April, with January and February being the coolest months, and July and August being the warmest. The best time to visit the Andes mountains is from October to May, before the rains come in June. Venezuela's weather is quite changeable, and even during the dry season there's always a chance of rain. If you're up in the northern mountainous region, you're likely to encounter a good few downpours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and jeans will be suitable in most locations, whether in the lowlands or on the coast. Pack a sweater or jacket if you're planning to spend any time in the Andes. It's also a good idea to take some waterproofs or a sturdy umbrella whichever region you're visiting.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Almost all significant towns are connected with scheduled services operated by domestic airlines, including Aeropostal (<a href="http://www.aeropostal.com" target="_blank">www.aeropostal.com</a>), Aserca Airlines (<a href="http://www.asercaairlines.com" target="_blank">www.asercaairlines.com</a>), Avior (<a href="http://www.aviorair.com" target="_blank">www.aviorair.com</a>) and SBA Airlines (<a href="http://www.sbairlines.com" target="_blank">www.sbairlines.com</a>).</p>
<p>A flight may be the best, though not the cheapest, option for reaching some of the more far-flung destinations, particularly Angel Falls (Canaima) and the Amazon region. Schedules are unreliable however, and you should book flights in advance, especially during the summer and national holidays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ferries link Isla de Margarita with the mainland at Puerto La Cruz (journey time is around 2 hours from either point).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Apart from the Caracas subway and a suburban light-rail line, there are no passenger trains operating in Venezuela.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For most visitors, driving in Venezuela is not worth the effort. The paperwork is daunting, and many locals drive aggressively and with scant regard to the rules of the road. Above all, there are plenty of cheaper and easier alternatives, primarily buses and taxis. If you decide to drive, do be aware that drivers routinely ignore red lights. When filling up on petrol, pump attendants expect a tip.</p>r<p>The quality of roads is variable but the main roads in Caracas and to the interior are good.</p>
<p>Most major roads are paved, but some routes have many potholes; on these roads a 4-wheel drive is recommended. Many smaller backroads are dirt or gravel, which turn into a mudbath in the wet season; a 4-wheel drive is best at this time too.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p>There is an abundance of buses covering the whole country, making this the best way to get around. Fares are cheap, though the condition of the buses varies widely, from rusty old wrecks to gleaming modern luxury coaches complete with bed-seats, icy air-conditioning and TV/DVD players.</p>
<p>Bus terminals in Caracas serve different parts of the country. Terminal de Oriente, for the east, southeast and Colombia, is found at metro Terminal de Oriente and is 15 minutes away by taxi. Terminal la Bandera serves the west and southwest and is five minutes by taxi from the metro station of same name. Luxury coaches with their own terminals, and serving various destinations, include Aeroexpresos Ejecutivos (<a href="http://www.aeroexpresos.com.ve/" target="_blank">www.aeroexpresos.com.ve</a>).</p><p>Taxis are plentiful in Caracas and other cities; they are not expensive but they don&rsquo;t have meters so agree on the fare before you set off. Official taxis in Caracas are white, with yellow licence plates; they are safer than unmarked minicabs.</p>
<p>&lsquo;Por puesto&rsquo; shared taxis are also common and usually take the form of minibuses or old US cars (known as <em>busetas</em> or <em>carritos</em>). They follow set routes and are considerably cheaper, but you will probably have to pay the extra passengers&rsquo; fares if you don&rsquo;t want to wait for it to fill up.</p><p>Drivers must have their licence and insurance documents with them at all times; both foreign licences and International Driving Permits are valid.</p><p>All vehicles must carry a spare tyre, wheel block, jack wrench and special reflector triangle. You must be at least 18 years old to drive in Venezuela and 21 years old to rent a car. Speed limits are officially 80 to 120kph (50 to 75mph) on major roads and 40 to 60kph (25 to 37mph) in residential areas, though in reality limits are rarely enforced. Seat belt use is compulsory. You can't ride motorbikes in Caracas after 2200.</p><p>TACV (tel: +58 212 781 9743; www.automovilclubvenezuela.com). In the event of an accident, both vehicles must remain in the position of the accident until a Traffic Police Officer arrives, otherwise insurance companies will be unable to pay claims. For emergencies, call 911.</p><p>Most of the international car hire companies operate at the airport and in major city centres. You can often get better rates by booking online from home. Drivers need to be at least 21 years old to rent a car, and sometimes older for 4-wheel drive or luxury vehicles.</p><p>All vehicles must carry a spare tyre, wheel block, jack wrench and special reflector triangle. You must be at least 18 years old to drive in Venezuela and 21 years old to rent a car. Speed limits are officially 80 to 120kph (50 to 75mph) on major roads and 40 to 60kph (25 to 37mph) in residential areas, though in reality limits are rarely enforced. Seat belt use is compulsory. You can't ride motorbikes in Caracas after 2200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Caracas has a metro which is comfortable and inexpensive; with convenient links to long-distance bus stations (<a href="http://www.metrodecaracas.com.ve" target="_blank">www.metrodecaracas.com.ve</a>). Elsewhere, local transport is handled by both conventional bus services and <em>por puestos </em>(share-taxis). Fares for the latter are similar to those on the buses, though generally higher after 2100 and at weekends.</p>
<p>From the airport, authorised taxis (black Ford Explorers, with an oval yellow logo) line up in front of the international and domestic terminals. Pay in advance at the signposted ticket office. Do not go with unlicensed taxi drivers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Venezuela</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">porlamar</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Venezuela</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">maracaibo</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Venezuela</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">cumana</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Venezuela</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">canaima</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>National carriers LASER Airlines (<a href="http://www.laser.com.ve" target="_blank">www.laser.com.ve</a>)&nbsp;and SBA Airlines (<a href="http://www.sbairlines.com" target="_blank">www.sbairlines.com</a>) offer direct flights to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/miami">Miami</a> but not to any other <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> or European destinations. European carriers such as Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>), Iberia (<a href="http://www.iberia.com" target="_blank">www.iberia.com</a>) and Air Europa (<a href="http://www.aireuropa.com" target="_blank">www.aireuropa.com</a>) operate direct flights from mainland Europe.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/venezuela/caracas-maiquetia-international-airport-simon-bolivar">Caracas Simon Bolivar International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To Caracas: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 13 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 7 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/miami">Miami</a> - 3 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The exit tax and airport fee are usually included in the air fare; check with your airline before you travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Caracas Simón Bolívar International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aeropuerto-maiquetia.com.ve<p>Caracas Simón Bolívar International Airport is situated 21km (13 miles) north of Caracas in the city of Maiquetía.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+58 424 2067470</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main ports are La Guaira (<a href="http://www.bolipuertos.gob.ve" target="_blank">www.bolipuertos.gob.ve</a>), Puerto Cabello, and Maracaibo. Ferries between Venezuela and Trinidad have been suspended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no international rail links with neighbouring countries. Plans to revive the national passenger rail network were drawn up at the end of the 1990s, but to date only a short section between Caracas and the nearby town of C&uacute;a is in operation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are road connections with Colombia and Brazil, with international bus services available from both countries: average bus times are approximately 12 hours from the Colombian border at San Antonio del T&aacute;chira to Caracas, and up to 24 hours from the Brazilian border crossing, near to Santa Elena de Uair&eacute;n to Caracas. By car, journeys may be up to 30% quicker.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Venezuela does have a network of public payphones throughout most major cities. Visitors can pay either by cash, or by using a prepaid phone card which often works out cheaper per minute.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies. Travellers on extended stays might consider getting a local SIM card to insert in their own phone.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafes in most urban areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Hugo Ch&aacute;vez was criticized by outsiders for his attempts to muzzle opponents in the media, with his attempts to silence press criticism of his reforms by threatening to shut down TV stations.  In general, however, the Venezuelan press is free to denounce the goverrnment&rsquo;s policies, and the opposition can be downright scathing in their criticism in the country's main newspapers. Some of the more significant Spanish-language dailies include&nbsp;<em>El Nacional (<a href="http://www.el-nacional.com" target="_blank">www.el-nacional.com</a>)</em>, <em>El Universal (<a href="http://www.eluniversal.com" target="_blank">www.eluniversal.com</a>)&nbsp;</em>and <em>&Uacute;ltimas Noticias (<a href="http://www.ultimasnoticias.com.ve" target="_blank">www.ultimasnoticias.com.ve</a>).</em>&nbsp;State-run TV channels include <em>Venezolana de Television</em> and <em>TVes</em> while other channels include private networks <em>Televen</em>, <em>Venevisi&oacute;n</em> and 24-hour news channel <em>Globovisi&oacute;n</em>. <em>Radio Nacional de Venezue</em> is a state broadcaster with several stations, including Canal Informativo and Canal Popular, while <em>Union Radio</em>&nbsp;(<a href="http://unionradio.net" target="_blank">www.unionradio.net</a>) is a commercial news network.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mail service from Venezuela to the USA and Europe is unreliable and using the state-owned postal system could take anywhere from a week to a month to arrive, and there's no guarantee it will.</p>
<p>National courier services Domesa (<a href="http://www.domesa.com" target="_blank">www.domesa.com</a>) and MRW (<a href="http://www.mrw.com.ve" target="_blank">www.mrw.com.ve</a>) are reliable options for handling internal mail. Well established courier companies Fedex (<a href="http://www.fedex.com/do" target="_blank">www.fedex.com/do</a>) and DHL (<a href="http://www.dhl.com.ve" target="_blank">www.dhl.com.ve</a>) offer reliable international mail options.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1300-16:30</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Angel Falls</p><![CDATA[<p>Angel Falls is the tallest waterfall in the world, and, for many, it is also the most stunning. Its glistening waters spill from the rim of an ancient sandstone tepuy (plateau) into a freefall of nearly one kilometre (0.6 miles) before crashing into a pool. Double rainbows can often be seen in the spray-drenched air above. Located in Canaima National Park, 600km (373 miles) south of Ciudad Bolívar, the waterfall was made public in 1937 by American pilot Jimmie Angel, who was searching for gold in the area. Angel Falls used to be a holy site for the region's original inhabitants, and is still sacred to the local indigenous people today. Tours can be made by boat or plane or 'fly-by' on scheduled flights from Ciudad Bolivar.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Climb Mount Roraima</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Marvel at the eerie majesty of Mount Roraima, the inspiration for Sir Arthur Conan Doyle's <em>The Lost World</em>. Spanning the borders of neighbouring Brazil and Guiana, Roraima is the tallest of the Gran Sabana's <em>tepuis</em> (table-topped mountains). Its sheer rock faces are pierced by graceful waterfalls and its ancient crags are lined with endemic, insect-eating plants. Adventure companies take organized treks up Roraima, a challenging but thrilling expedition requiring a minimum of five days.</p>]]><p><b>Dance with the devil in San Francisco de Yare</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Every year as part of the Corpus Christi celebrations in May or June, up to 100 dancers in ghoulish devil masks perform a colourful ceremony in the small town of San Francisco de Yare, south of Caracas. Based on a Catholic tradition dating back to the Middle Ages, the "Diablos Danzantes" can also be seen in several towns along the central coast, including Cata, Chuao, Cuyagua, Naiguatá, Ocumare de la Costa, and Tinaquillo.</p>]]><p><b>Dive at Parque Nacional Mochima</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Snorkel, swim, dive or fish at Parque Nacional Mochima on the northeast coast, with hundreds of offshore islands and islets. Some – like the popular Isla de Plata – are surrounded by coral reefs; and there are countless beautiful beaches for just lazing around. The archipelago Los Roques is another underwater wonderland, fantastic for birdwatching, diving and snorkelling off its gorgeous white-sand beaches.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy a slice of German life in Colonia Tovar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Check out Colonia Tovar, a slice of Deutschland in the forested mountains west of Caracas. Settled by German immigrants from the Black Forest in the mid-19th century, the town retains its Old World traditions, food and architecture. With its quaint rustic hostels and homemade culinary specialities, Colonia Tovar makes for a touristy but surreal excursion from the capital.</p>]]><p><b>Explore downtown Caracas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The capital, Caracas, is a modern metropolis set in the foothills of the Ávila range. Besides a fabulously varied culinary landscape, a vibrant cultural life and throbbing nightlife scene, the city also boasts an array of world-class museums. The city is one of South America's most dangerous, but it offers a loud and brash welcome for first-time visitors, most of whom escape to the countryside's gentler attractions after a couple of days.</p>]]><p><b>Go on safari in Amazonas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get up close to birds, monkeys and caiman on a jungle safari in the far south Amazonas region. Based in the largest town of Puerto Ayacucho, specialist tour operators take river trips to lodges deep in the jungle, where you can go wildlife watching. Treks to see spectacular <em>tepuis</em> (table-top mountains) such as Auyan-Tepui and Cerro de la Neblina are also available.</p>]]><p><b>Head underground in Cueva del Guácharo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Burrow down into the Cueva del Guácharo, the most spectacular of Venezuela's many cave systems. Here you can discover the fascinating <em>guácharos</em> (oilbirds), the nocturnal birds that inhabit this subterranean dwelling and which flock out of the cave mouth at dusk in their thousands, screeching eerily.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in Coro</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Linger in the beautifully preserved centre of Coro, an early colonial settlement near the Caribbean coast. The town is on UNESCO's list of World Heritage Sites and is also the gateway to the Paraguaná Peninusula, a prime windsurfing destination. Surrounding Coro are the Médanos de Coro, a national park composed of huge sand dunes, the country's only desert landscape.</p>]]><p><b>Make your way to Mérida</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get to know Mérida, a delightful university city perched amidst snow-capped Andean peaks. More than just an excellent base for hiking, wildlife watching and whitewater rafting, Mérida has a rich cultural history, with several fine art and archaeology museums and buzzing nightlife.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Angel Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Angel Falls is the tallest waterfall in the world, and, for many, it is also the most stunning. Its glistening waters spill from the rim of an ancient sandstone <em>tepui</em>&nbsp;(table-topped mountain) into a freefall of nearly one kilometre (0.6 miles) before crashing into a pool. Double rainbows can often be seen in the spray-drenched air above. Located in Canaima National Park, 600km (373 miles) south of Ciudad Bol&iacute;var, the waterfall is a sacred site for the local indigenous people.</p>]]><p><b>Move to the sound of Joropo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Catch a display of <em>Joropo</em>, Venezuela's national dance, in Los Llanos, the vast plains region where it originated. The flamenco-influenced step is accompanied by musicians playing harp, guitar and maracas and singing in a high-pitched nasal style. Local <em>Joropo</em> groups perform at family parties and street concerts throughout the country, but the best places to see it in Los Llanos are in Guanare and San Fernando de Apure.</p>]]><p><b>Observe perpetual lightning at Lake Maracaibo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Marvel at the magical natural phenomenon of lightning minus the accompanying thunderclap at the Parque Nacional Ciénagas del Catatumbo, along the southwest shore of Lake Maracaibo. The spectacular displays of forked lightning storms over the water can be witnessed daily throughout the year. The park is also rich with birdlife and animals, including capybara and manatees.</p>]]><p><b>Pick up your binoculars in Cuare Wildlife Refuge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Admire large colonies of pink flamingos and scarlet ibis at the Cuare Wildlife Refuge, a coastal reserve adjoining the Parque Nacional Morrocoy, about four hours north of Caracas. Best glimpsed in September, the flamboyant fowl are among many water birds that congregate in the lagoons near Chichiriviche and along the mangrove canals.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the Teleferico de Mukumbari</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ride the world's longest and highest cable car, which runs a staggering 13km (8miles) from Mérida to the top of Pico Espejo, which kisses the sky at 4,765m high (15,629ft). Called Mukumbari, which means "the place where the sun is born," the cable car offers easy access to starting points for carious mountain treks, though it's worth riding just for the sake of it.</p>]]><p><b>Ski in the Andes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy the novelty of skiing in the tropics: the highest Andean peaks of the Cordillera de Mérida have a permanent snowline and can be skied between November and June, though at an altitude of 4,270m (14,000ft) this is recommended only for the hardiest. Several of the country's highest peaks are located here and specialist local agencies offer experienced guides and equipment in the nearby city of Mérida.</p>]]><p><b>Spot wildlife in Parque Nacional Henri Pittier</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Train your binoculars on hummingbirds, herons, tanagers, toucanets, and curassows; just a few of the 580-plus exotic bird species at the Parque Nacional Henri Pittier a birdwatchers' haven on the central northern coast. This is the oldest national park in the country, and also home to jaguar, puma and monkeys. The main entrance is at Rancho Grande, between Ocumare and Maracay.</p>]]><p><b>Take a break on Isla de Margarita</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Swim, soak up the sun and savour superb seafood on Isla de Margarita, Venezuela's largest Caribbean island. With 168km (104 miles) of beaches, it offers everything from the full-on buzz of its principal town Porlamar, to mangroves, marshes and sand dunes. There are many national and international flights and charters to Porlamar, as well as daily air-shuttles from Maiquetía airport, and ferries from Cumaná, La Guaira (Caracas) and Puerto la Cruz.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the indigenous people of “Little Venice”</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a tour from Maracaibo north to the Guajira Peninsula, via the Sinamaica Lagoon, where the indigenous people of Venezuela live much as they did when the first Spanish settlers arrived, dwelling in houses that are raised above the lake on stilts. The stilt houses reminded the conquistadors of Venice, prompting them to name the country "Little Venice".</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$333.7 billion (2015).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum, aluminium, steel, chemical products, agricultural products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Agricultural products, livestock, raw materials, machinery and transport equipment</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, China, Brazil, Colombia and Mexico</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Venezuela was a primarily agricultural country until the discovery of oil in the 1920s. A prominent founding member of the Organisation of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC), the country ranks fifth in the world for oil reserves, and it is among the world's top 10 oil exporting nations. The resource provides 90% of export earnings, half of government revenues and approximately a quarter of the country's GDP (in contrast, agriculture comprises less than 4% of GDP). Overdependence on oil revenues, however, has left Venezuela vulnerable to world price fluctuations. <br />
<br />
Following an overwhelming electoral victory in December 2006, President Hugo Ch&aacute;vez launched his &lsquo;Bolivarian Revolution&rsquo; a 21st century socialist state. He introduced popular grassroots social programmes and nationalised much of the economy, including the energy, agriculture, and finance sectors, somewhat ruffling the feathers of foreign investors. Today, the new government is continuing Chavez&rsquo;s plan, as well as his vehement anti-American rhetoric. Nevertheless, the US remains the leading trading partner, accounting for more than half of the country's exports (mostly oil).<br />
<br />
Buoyed by major government investments and increased access to credit, consumer spending jumped substantially in 2007, though at the cost of a 20% rise in inflation. In an effort to boost confidence in the currency, in 2008 the government introduced the Bol&iacute;var Fuerte, slashing three zeroes so that a beer now costs about 1 Bol&iacute;var instead of 1,000. Inflation remains rampant, however: in excess of 54% at the end of 2013, exacerbated by falling exports. Adding to the mounting economic crisis, the country has had to endure power cuts and shortages of basic foods and goods. In response to rising crime and social unrest, new president Nicolas Maduro has imposed authoritarian controls, clamping down on opponents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although Venezuelan businesses are generally up to speed on communications technology, the personal touch remains essential, and some socializing should supplement your email and telephone exchanges. <br />
<br />
Appointments are necessary and business visitors should be punctual, even though their Venezuelan counterparts may show up a little late. At introductions, a handshake is customary and it is common to exchange business cards. Although English is becoming more widely spoken in business circles, particularly at the executive level, Spanish is essential for most negotiations. Venezuelans like formal titles, so you should address new acquaintances as <em>Se&ntilde;or or Se&ntilde;ora</em>.<br />
<br />
Business people tend to dress formally in Caracas, despite the heat; dark suits for men, smart business outfits for women, and formal matching shoes for both. Most offices are fiercely air conditioned, so you'll often be glad to have a jacket to wear.</p>
<p>There are five-star hotels in Caracas and other major cities, with all the usual business facilities.</p><p>Working hours vary, but are roughly Mon-Fri 0800-1700. Some businesses take a break in the middle of the day - usually from 1200-1500, to avoid the heat of the day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Consejo Nacional de Promoción de Invensiones, CONAPRI (National Council for Investment Promotion)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (212) 951 6507
					Website:http://www.conapri.org/
					Address: El Rosal,Torre Forum,Planta Baja,Oficina LC-A,Calle Guaicaipuro,Caracas 1060,]]><b>Federación Venezolana de Cámaras y Asociaciones de Comercio y Producción, FEDECAMARAS (Federation of Chambers of Commerce and Industry)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (212) 731 1711
					Website:http://www.fedecamaras.org.ve/
					Address: El Bosque,Apartado 2568,Edificio Fedecámaras,Pent-House 2,Avenida El Empalme,Caracas,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The distinctive flavour of <em>comida criolla</em>, as Venezuela's cuisine is locally known, resides in roots and vegetables: yams, yucca, plantains, rice and beans. Beef from the cattle ranches of Los Llanos also figures prominently, most popularly cooked <em>a la parilla</em> (charcoal grilled) at the country's many steakhouses. Equally enticing are the varieties of fresh fish and seafood, often prepared in <em>sancochos</em> (stews) along the Caribbean coast. Freshwater trout are popular in the Andean regions, while <em>pargo</em> (snapper), <em>carite</em> (king fish) and dorado are delicious local sea fish, as well as shellfish, lobster, oysters and conch.</p><p>Authentic Italian, Chinese, Spanish and Middle Eastern cuisines are also widely available, thanks to the presence of substantial immigrant communities. Exotic regional dishes can also be found; from deep-fried ants and piranhas in the Amazon, to capybara stew in Los Llanos, and even turtle – despite its protected status – served up as <em>ropa especial</em> in the Paraguaná Peninsula.</p><p>Venezuelans have a sweet tooth, and popular desserts include <em>huevos chimbos</em> (egg yolk in sugar syrup), <em>cachitos</em> (stuffed croissants), <em>bienmesabe</em> (sponge cake soaked in coconut milk) and <em>quesillo</em> (a creamy pudding made of egg, milk and caramel).<br/><br/>From pineapples to papayas, mangos and <em>chirimoya</em> (custard apples), tropical fruit is fabulously varied and blended into <em>batidos</em> (shakes). Venezuela produces excellent rum and is a major importer of Scotch. Polar (served ice-cold, naturally) is the most popular of several local beers; Brazilian Brahma beer, a lighter option, is also brewed in Venezuela.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; <em>Arepas</em> (corn buns, toasted and generously stuffed with all manner of savoury fillings).<br />
&bull; <em>Pabell&oacute;n criollo</em> (shredded meat cooked with onions, peppers and coriander; served with fried plantains, black beans and rice and a slab of cheese): the national dish. <br />
&bull; <em>Hallaca</em> (corn dough filled with beef, pork, olives, etc, and steamed in banana leaves; a Christmas favourite).<br />
&bull; <em>Cachapas</em> (slightly sweet corn pancakes, usually folded over hunks of white cheese and/or ham). <br />
&bull; <em>Hervido</em> (hearty soup of beef, chicken or fish with root vegetables).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Avoid tap water at all costs; ask for bottled mineral water. In Caracas, locals eat late. Outside of the capital and other major cities, however, many restaurants may close as early as 2000. The 'menu ejecutivo' fixed-price lunch is a good bargain, available at most larger restaurants.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>In most bars and restaurants, 10% is added to the bill; at fancier establishments it's customary to leave an additional 10% on the table.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Venezuelans love their rumba, salsa and merengue, and indulge in their music and dance with infectious passion. The evening's activities usually get started with a couple of cold Polar beers or rum cocktails at a bar, followed up by a night of dancing. Most discos cover the musical spectrum from salsa to Latin pop, while the more youth-oriented venues tend toward rock and reggaet&oacute;n.</p>
<p>The capital, Caracas, boasts the country's most hedonistic nightlife scene, with multi-hall clubs thumping through the night. El Man&iacute; es As&iacute; is the acclaimed home of salsa in downtown S&aacute;bana Grande; latin jazz is also catered for, with the Juan Sebastian Bar attracting top international artistes. S&aacute;bana Grande can get a bit rowdy at night; leafier districts such as Chacao and Las Mercedes offer swankier but safer settings.</p>
<p>Most towns of any significant size will also have a disco or two. For a less frenetic night out, stately old theatres in Caracas, Maracaibo, Maracay and Valencia feature classical music, opera, ballet, and (if your Spanish is up to it) plays. Cinemas, often located in shopping malls, generally feature recent Hollywood fare with Spanish subtitles.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Venezuelans are mad about shopping, and much social activity revolves around the glitzy malls that dot the urban areas - when the country's erratic electricity supply allows. Shoppers flock to Isla de Margarita, particularly the town of Porlamar, to take advantage of the island's duty-free status.<br />
<br />
Travellers are more likely to be interested in the quality handicrafts produced by Venezuela's indigenous inhabitants, including hand-woven baskets by the Ye'Kuana people of the Orinoco Basin, <em>chinchorros</em> (palm fibre hammocks) by the Way&uacute;u (also know as Guajiros), and devil masks from San Francisco de Yare. The northwestern state of Lara is renowned for its woodwork and blankets, particularly from the village of Tintorero, while adjacent Cojedes state is a producer of harps, cuatros (small guitars) and maracas. Bead jewellery, wooden carvings and other handicrafts made by the indigenous inhabitants of Amazonas can be bought at the Plaza Romulo Betancourt in Puerto Ayacucho. Gems and gold and silver jewellery also make good purchases.</p>
<p>It's best to look for these items where they're made, but if you're unable, try Hannsi, an enormous crafts department store in El Hatillo, an outlying district of Caracas.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0930-1800; shopping malls, daily 1100-2200. Smaller outlets often close for lunch, until about 1500. Opening hours are currently subject to change at short notice due to government restrictions and inadequate electricity supply.</p><p>With the runaway inflation levels afflicting the country, there are few real bargains available for shoppers. The parallel or black market rate of exchange offers up to seven times the official rate, however. Do not on any account change money on the street, but ask someone in a senior position in your hotel or travel agency. The black market, although widely used, is actually illegal. Casas de cambio &ndash; bureaux de change &ndash; and banks, are the safest places to change money, with US dollars the preferred currency. Credit cards are accepted in most larger establishments, but beware of hidden surcharges.</p>
<p>Due to government energy rationing, the advertised opening times&nbsp;for malls and supermarkets are often subject to last minute change.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Venezuela&rsquo;s hotel scene has hugely expanded over the past decade as tourism and nowadays, hotels are easily found throughout the country in a wide range of prices, with the exception of Caracas where budget accommodation is scarce. Book ahead if you plan to visit Isla de Margarita, Archipi&eacute;lago Los Roques, Canaima or other major destinations during holiday periods, when rates may increase by 30%.</p>
<p><strong>Grading: </strong>Hotels in Venezuela have been graded 3- to 5-star.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Venezuela&rsquo;s hotel scene has hugely expanded over the past decade as tourism and nowadays, hotels are easily found throughout the country in a wide range of prices, with the exception of Caracas where budget accommodation is scarce. Book ahead if you plan to visit Isla de Margarita, Archipi&eacute;lago Los Roques, Canaima or other major destinations during holiday periods, when rates may increase by 30%.</p>
<p><strong>Grading: </strong>Hotels in Venezuela have been graded 3- to 5-star.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Venezuela&rsquo;s hotel scene has hugely expanded over the past decade as tourism and nowadays, hotels are easily found throughout the country in a wide range of prices, with the exception of Caracas where budget accommodation is scarce. Book ahead if you plan to visit Isla de Margarita, Archipi&eacute;lago Los Roques, Canaima or other major destinations during holiday periods, when rates may increase by 30%.</p>
<p><strong>Grading: </strong>Hotels in Venezuela have been graded 3- to 5-star.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Treatment at public hospitals is free, though Venezuela's public healthcare system, like much of the country, is in a state of crisis. Private facilities are of a much higher standard and comparable to the facilities you might find in Europe or the USA. The best-equipped hospitals are located in Caracas and the state capitals, although many are overrun with more patients than they can cope with. Taking out travel insurance is advisable. 24-hour pharmacies are recognizable by a red-lit sign labelled '&lt;em&gt;turno'&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water, where it's accessible, is not drinkable and should be sterilised, either through boiling or filtering. Alternatively, drink bottled water; it is the subject of price controls and rationing, which means it can be difficult to find. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat. When it comes to eating out use common sense, stick to food that's been freshly cooked, and be wary of fruit or vegetable salads where the ingredients may have been washed in mains water. The same goes for ice used in cold drinks.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccination against hepatitis B is advised for visitors on long-term stays who have regular contact with the local population. The risk of malaria in Venezuela is in the main limited to those visiting the Amazon basin area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venezuela is considered to have a high risk of Zika virus transmission. The mosquito-borne illness can be spread from a pregnant woman to her unborn baby as well as through sexual contact. The World Health Organisation recommends travellers to Venezuela protect themselves from mosquito bites and suggests wearing clothes (preferably light-coloured) that cover as much of the body as possible, sleeping under mosquito nets and using repellents that contain DEET. Pregnant women are advised to postpone non-essential travel until after pregnancy and pregnant women whose sexual partners live in or travel to areas with Zika virus transmission should follow safe sexual practices or abstain from sex for the duration of their pregnancy.&amp;nbsp;Women who are pregnant, at risk of getting pregnant, or planning pregnancy should seek further advice from their doctor before travelling to Venezuela.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>There are some additional regional holidays.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Carnival :
							12 February </p><p>Holy Thursday :
							29 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Declaration of Independence :
							19 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Battle of Carabobo :
							24 June </p><p>Independence Day :
							05 July </p><p>Sim :
							24 July </p><p>Day of Indigenous Resistance :
							12 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Venezuela without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes and 25 cigars.<br />
&bull; 2L of alcoholic drinks.<br />
&bull; 4 small bottles of perfume.<br />
&bull; Goods up to a value of US$1,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics are prohibited.</p>
<p>Restricted items include dairy products, flowers, animals, birds, weapons and artworks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bol&iacute;var Fuerte (VEF; symbol Bs.F.) = 100 c&eacute;ntimos. Notes are in denominations of Bs.F. 100,000, 20,000, 10,000, 5000, 2000, 1000 and 500; coin denominations are Bs.F. 500, 100, 50, 20 and 10; 50, 25, 12.5, 10, 5 and 1 c&eacute;ntimos.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Banks and <em>casas de cambio </em>(exchange offices) will exchange cash; some, such as Italcambio, convert traveller's cheques as well. High-end hotels can also change money, though often at a less favourable rate. Travellers are advised to bring currency in US Dollars. It is illegal to exchange money on the black market, and it's worth noting that if you want to change any money back into dollars, you will need to produce an official receipt of the original exchange.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard, Visa and American Express are accepted in the main cities and tourist centres. However, some outlets may have difficulty accepting foreign cards. Venezuela is a cash-dominated society and you may be better off with dollars in most instances.</p><p>Most major banks have ATMs and they're generally available throughout major cities. ATMs have extremely low limits for cash withdrawals on international cards and queues are frequently targeted by criminals. If you're heading to the Amazon basin, or rural areas where access to cashpoints will be limited, be sure to stockpile some cash beforehand.</p>

Venezuela also has a serious problem with card fraud and cards being cloned. Take care when using credit or debit cards.]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These used to be widely accepted, but as their usage declines, there are fewer places accepting them and the places that do, may ask you to produce a receipt of purchase. American Express is the standard; other types of traveller's cheques may not be accepted. A commission of 3% or more is charged. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0830-1530.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Venezuela, a passport valid for six months on arrival is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Children travelling without one or both of their parents must carry a notarised letter from the parent(s) not travelling authorising them to travel. They may need to show this letter on arrival and again when leaving the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Multiple-entry tourist visa: $30.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visa: 72 hours; multiple-entry tourist visa: valid for up to one year with a maximum stay of 90 days per entry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). Tourist entry cards are available at the airport check-in desk prior to departure.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow three days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If applying for a tourist visa, you must show your most recent bank statement.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can extend your stay by an additional 90 days at any SAIME office (<a href="http://www.saime.gob.ve" target="_blank">www.saime.gob.ve</a>). You must apply before your tourist card expires.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[7.673975]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-66.150017]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>912,050 sq km (352,144 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>31,518,855 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>32.1 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Caracas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Situated in the north east corner of the South American continent, Venezuela is bordered to the north by the Caribbean, to the east by Guyana and the Atlantic Ocean, to the south by Brazil, and to the west and southwest by Colombia.</p>
<p>The country consists of four distinctive regions: the Venezuelan Highlands in the west; the Maracaibo Lowlands in the northwest; the vast central plain of Los Llanos around the Orinoco River; and the Guyana region in the extreme south, which includes part of the Amazon rainforest and the Guyana highlands. Various parts of Venezuela, including Caracas and the eastern part of Sucre, are vulnerable to earthquakes, although there have been no serious ones for many years.</p>
<p>Important topographical features include the Orinoco river, the largest river in South America after the Amazon, at a length of 2,140km (1,330 miles), and the dramatic table top mountains known as <em>tepuis,</em> which are found in the Guyana highlands. Angel Falls, situated in the Canaima National Park is the highest waterfall in the world, plunging into the Orinoco from a height of 979m (3,212ft). The Andes mountain range crosses the northwestern region of the country, with the highest peak Pico Bolivar reaching heights of 5,007m (16,427ft).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Venezuela is majority Roman Catholic (77%), with small but influential Protestant, Jewish, Muslim and Buddhist communities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Venezuelans are known for being warm and friendly, with people often greeting each other with a kiss, or using the local <em>abrazo</em> (a cross between a hug and a handshake). Handshakes are reserved for greeting strangers. Personal space is much less of a concern, so don&rsquo;t be alarmed if people stand very close when holding a conversation.</p>
<p>In Caracas, conservative casual wear is the norm. Men are expected to wear suits for business, and jackets and ties are usual for dining out and social functions. Dress on the coast is less formal but beachwear and shorts should not be worn away from the beach or pool. In&nbsp;2011 Venezuela introduced a ban on smoking in all enclosed public and commercial spaces, including malls, restaurants, bars, discos and workplaces.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>120 volts AC, 60Hz. North American-style plugs with two flat ins (with or without grounding pin) are the most commonly used fittings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Nicol&aacute;s Maduro since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Nicol&aacute;s Maduro since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Originally inhabited by Carib and Arawak Indians, Venezuela was claimed as a Spanish territory by Christopher Columbus in 1498. Spanish rule was administered from a distance, leaving the various regions to develop separately from the capital, Caracas. In the 18th century, an attempt to inject a measure of unification was met with widespread resistance led by Sim&oacute;n Bol&iacute;var, who remains a national hero.</p>
<p>Bol&iacute;var&rsquo;s dream of creating a mega-territory, Gran Colombia, composed of Venezuela, Colombia and Ecuador, collapsed through in-fighting. Instead, in 1830, Venezuela became a sovereign state, led by Jos&eacute; Pa&eacute;z. The precise territorial limits were not, however, well defined, and Venezuela's borders have since been subject to periodic disputes.</p>
<p>The exploitation of the country's substantial oilfields began in 1918 with an oil boom similar to the cocoa and coffee booms of the 17th and 19th centuries. In each case, the wealth was largely export driven, making a small elite spectacularly rich but failing to develop the country&rsquo;s wider economy, leaving the majority poor and exploited. Widespread political corruption was the norm and despotic military leaders ran the country throughout most of the first half of the 20th century, until democracy was introduced in 1958.</p>
<p>In the 1980s, successive governments struggled to stabilise the country in the face of persistent social unrest and in 1992, a number of army units launched an unexpected military coup that was suppressed by loyal army units but introduced the world to its charismatic figurehead, Colonel Hugo Ch&aacute;vez.</p>
<p>Five years later he formed his own party then fought and won the 1998 election. Further polls in 2000 secured his position and, de facto, an endorsement of the constitutional changes that he planned, which increased presidential powers. Land reforms and a nationalisation programme boosted the government&rsquo;s popular appeal, but sparked strong opposition from both the ruling classes and international business interests that typified the Chavez era until his death from cancer in 2013. His successor, Nicolas Maduro&rsquo;s term in office has been characterised by protests and the suppression of his political opponents as&nbsp;Venezuela has lapsed into an economic, political and social crisis.</p>
<p>Food and medical shortages have become commonplace and basic goods are rationed.&nbsp;Violent crime has also reached an all-time high with a record 28,479 people killed in 2016, according to the independent group the Venezuelan Violence Observatory.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Venezuela is one of 17 mega-diverse countries, habitats range from river deltas, Caribbean coast and extensive plains to rainforest, cloud forest and the Andes mountains.<br />
&bull;	Venezuela has the world&rsquo;s largest oil reserves and is a founding member of OPEC.<br />
&bull;	Venezuela first formed a professional baseball league in 1945 and today baseball is the nation&rsquo;s most popular sport..</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Venezuela in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7584 4206.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://reinounido.embajada.gob.ve</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7584 4206.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1 Cromwell Road<br/>London<br/>SW7 2HW<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Venezuela (Consular Section) in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7529 8620.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.venezlon.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7529 8620.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>56 Grafton Way<br/>London<br/>W1T 5DL<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 627 1444.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://eeuu.embajada.gob.ve</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 627 1444.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fr: 0900-1300, 1400-1700&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1099 30th Street NW<br/>Washington<br/>20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With its reputation for violence and political instability, many travellers opt to give Venezuela a wide berth. But those brave enough to visit this feisty South American nation will discover a country of extraordinary diversity and abundant natural beauty; a land of lofty Andean peaks, mysterious Lost World plateaus, wildlife rich rainforests, vibrant cities and idyllic Caribbean islands. <br />
<br />
At the heart of all this lies Caracas, Venezuela&rsquo;s thronging capital. A hotchpotch of hillside favelas, crumbling colonial buildings and glistening skyscrapers, the city has much to offer visitors; there&rsquo;s a fine collection of museums, galleries and historic monuments, not to mention a pulsating nightlife. Even the food&rsquo;s good, nowadays. But for all its appeal, most of Venezuela&rsquo;s attractions lie beyond the capital city, hidden away in national parks and reserves which cover an impressive 40% of the country.</p>
<p>The lush tropical lowlands of Los Llanos harbour abundant wildlife, with eco-conscious&nbsp;<em>hatos</em> (ranches) offering safaris to view caiman, puma, anaconda, capybara, hundreds of birds and much more. Then there are the table-top mountains of the Guyana Highlands, whose summits loom over golden savannahs and bristle with prehistoric flora and fauna. These towering peaks spawn dramatic waterfalls, including the awesome Angel Falls, officially the world&rsquo;s highest.</p>
<p>Those with an appetite for adventure can be sated with an excursion into the virgin rainforest of Amazonas, Venezuela&rsquo;s least-visited region, where indigenous communities cling onto traditional lives in the jungle. Alternatively, head to M&eacute;rida to tackle the soaring Andean peaks or go piranha fishing in the Orinoco, South America&rsquo;s second longest river, which empties into the wildlife-rich wetlands of the Orinoco Delta.</p>
<p>Beyond that, the clear waters of the Caribbean lap onto Venezuela&rsquo;s stunning coastline, where numerous offshore islands provide ample opportunities for reef diving, partying and pandering to pleasure. Amongst them the Los Roques archipelago, which is the epitome of Caribbean island idyll and a very long way from the unsavoury headlines of the mainland.</p><p>With its reputation for violence and political instability, many travellers opt to give Venezuela a wide berth. But those brave enough to visit this feisty South American nation will discover a country of extraordinary diversity and abundant natural beauty; a land of lofty Andean peaks, mysterious Lost World plateaus, wildlife rich rainforests, vibrant cities and idyllic Caribbean islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
