<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Vietnam" ColCode="vnm" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="vn" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Vietnam]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Because of its geography, the climate in Vietnam varies greatly from north to south with three distinct climatic zones. Tropical monsoons occur from October to April in the centre and from May to September in the north and south. It is almost totally dry throughout the rest of the year. It can get exceptionally hot, however, all year round, but the north has a cooler time between October and April. Temperatures around the country can reach up to 40C in the height of the hot and rainy season (May to September), but the northern highlands and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hanoi">Hanoi</a> can often seem chilly and damp in the winter.  </p>
<p>There is no one ideal time to visit Vietnam as a whole but at any time of year there will be sun somewhere. The high season is from September to March but bad weather can disrupt travel in the centre of the country during this period, particularly from September to December. For the beaches in the centre of Vietnam, Danang, Hoi An and Nha Trang, it is best to go between May and August. The autumn is the best time to visit Halong Bay when there should be clear skies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Loose, natural fabrics all year, but warmer clothing is required in the highlands, and in the winter in north Vietnam. Rainwear is essential during the wet season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vietnam Airlines (<a href="http://www.vietnamairlines.com" target="_blank">www.vietnamairlines.com</a>) operates daily flights between Hanoi, Ho Chi Minh City, Hu&eacute;, Danang and Nha Trang. Jetstar Pacific (<a href="http://www.jetstar.com" target="_blank">www.jetstar.com</a>)  also operates flights on these routes. Regular services are also  provided by Vietnam Airlines between Hanoi and Ho Chi Minh City to Buon  Ma Thuot, Dalat, Phu Quoc, Pleiku and Qui Nhon.</p>
<p>The road situation has improved dramatically so flights are  used for long distances and to save time. It is still easier to fly to  places like Dien Bien Phu. Flights are particularly busy around the Tet  holiday in January/February and it is essential to book ahead.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cat Ba Island, in the north, is a popular place for visitors and is accessible by hydrofoil from Haiphong. A hydrofoil also serves the beach resort, Vung Tau, with a daily service from Ho Chi Minh City. You can reach the tropical getaway island of Phu Quoc in the Gulf of Thailand by hydrofoil from Rach Gia in the Mekong Delta.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors may use the rail transport system independently or as part of a rail tour. Express long-distance trains are faster than local services, more reliable and more comfortable. Although a few carriages now have air conditioning, facilities are still short of international standards.</p>
<p>The main rail route connects Hanoi and Ho Chi Minh City and the journey can take between 30 and 40 hours. There are also services from Hanoi to Haiphong, Dong Dang and Lao Cai. Contact Vietnam Railways (tel: +84 4 3942 5972; <a href="http://www.vr.com.vn" target="_blank">www.vr.com.vn</a>) for more information. You should buy tickets at railway stations.</p>
<p>There are private tourist carriages attached to long-distance trains on the Hanoi to Danang (tel: +84 4 3942 9919 or +84 4 39421199; <a href="http://www.livitrans.com" target="_blank">www.livitrans.com</a>) and Hanoi to Sapa routes (also served by Livitrans) where the standard is higher and there is a dining car.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>The road network throughout Vietnam is reasonable, but the standard of the roads varies dramatically from good to appalling. Road conditions can deteriorate during the rainy season.&nbsp;Roads throughout Vietnam are designated by numbers, and the main north-to-south route is Highway 1 connecting Hanoi with Ho Chi Minh City.</p><p>Long-distance coaches operate throughout the country, between Hanoi, Hu&eacute;, Danang and Ho Chi Minh City. You must buy tickets in person at the bus station.</p><p>Taxis are plentiful and cheap. They can be flagged down on the street or arranged through your hotel or the restaurant where you are eating. Always make sure the driver has set the meter before starting the journey.</p><p>An International Driving Permit and a test (taken in Vietnam) are required for long-term residents.</p><p>Seat belts are not compulsory in Vietnam. Helmets are compulsory for motorbike riders.</p><p>It is possible to hire chauffeur-driven cars from travel companies. Self-drive car hire is non-existent.</p><p>You can hire bikes for a day or longer from shops in the main towns and cities. Many Vietnamese people still have a bicycle as their main form of transport, but now there are many more motorbikes as well as cars and lorries. Take particular care when cycling in towns and on main roads outside the towns as drivers do not always observe road rules and are not cyclist-aware.</p><p>Seat belts are not compulsory in Vietnam. Helmets are compulsory for motorbike riders.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are local bus services in Ho Chi Minh City and in Hanoi. It is also possible to travel by taxi, motorbike or cyclo (cycle rickshaw; motorised version also exists). Most foreigners forgo the bus, preferring to use these. Taxi drivers do not expect to be tipped, but it is welcomed. Hopping on the back of a 'moto' is the cheapest way to travel, if you have the stomach for the crazy driving. Agree the price first and make sure they have a good helmet.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Vietnam</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">phan_thiet</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Vietnam</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">dalat</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Vietnam</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">ho_chi_minh_city</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">30.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Vietnam</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">halong_bay</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Vietnam Airlines (<a href="http://www.vietnamairlines.com" target="_blank">www.vietnamairlines.com</a>), which runs direct flights from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hanoi">Hanoi</a>.&nbsp;Vietnam is also served by many airlines via nearby hubs, including Cathay Pacific (<a href="http://www.cathaypacific.com" target="_blank">www.cathaypacific.com</a>) and Thai (<a href="http://www.thaiairways.com" target="_blank">www.thaiairways.com</a>). Flights to Vietnam are at their most expensive around Christmas, New Year and Tet (January/February).</p>
<p>Major airports are: Tan Son Nhat International Airport and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vietnam/noi-bai-international-airport">Noi Bai International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 12 hours 10 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 20 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Long Thanh International Airport, a new airport 40km (25 miles) south of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ho-chi-minh-city">Ho Chi Minh City</a>, is expected to be open by 2020.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the price of the ticket.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Long Thanh International Airport, a new airport 40km (25 miles) south of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ho-chi-minh-city">Ho Chi Minh City</a>, is expected to be open by 2020.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Tan Son Nhat International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://en.vietnamairport.vn<p>The airport is located within the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ho-chi-minh-city">Hồ Ch&amp;iacute</a>; Minh city limits, about 8km (5 miles) north of the central business district.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+84 8 3848 5383.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The only international arrival point into Vietnam with a regular ferry service is Chau Doc in the Mekong Delta. There are daily speedboat ferries from Phnom Penh along the Mekong River taking 4.5 to 5 hours. Cruise ships call at Ho Chi Minh City, Nha Trang, Danang and Haiphong.</p>
<p>Blue Cruiser (tel: +84 8 3926 0253; <a href="http://www.bluecruiser.com" target="_blank">www.bluecruiser.com</a>) operates a daily speedboat service between Chau Doc in the Mekong Delta and Phnom Penh.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is possible to cross into Vietnam from China by rail from Beijing-Dong Dang-Hanoi and back. Contact Vietnam Railways (tel: +84 4 3942 5972; <a href="http://www.vr.com.vn" target="_blank">www.vr.com.vn</a>) for details. A useful number in Vietnam is 1080, where English-speaking operators can give information on timetables.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are routes to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> through Lang Son, Mong Cai and Lao Cai, to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cambodia">Cambodia</a> through Moc Bai and Xaxia and also to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/laos">Laos</a> through Lao Bao, Nam Can, Na Meo, Tay Trang and Cau Trieu. There is a regular bus service from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/phnom-penh">Phnom Penh</a>, Cambodia, operated by the Saigon Passenger Transport Company (tel: +84 8 3854 6110; <a href="http://www.saigonbus.com.vn" target="_blank">www.saigonbus.com.vn</a>).</p>
<p>There are bus services from Vientiane, Laos to Hanoi and Savannakhet, Laos to Hue; you need to buy tickets for these in person from the bus station and neither journey is the most comfortable of rides. There are no buses travelling from China that cross into Vietnam. Passengers have to change buses at the border.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>It is expensive to call home from hotels but international calls from post offices are much better value.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies. Coverage is available throughout large parts of the country. It is possible to buy competitively priced SIM cards for use in the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet caf&eacute;s are widely available throughout the country and they are good value. High-speed connections are only available in major towns and cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The media is controlled by the Communist Party. Newspapers straying beyond restrictive government reporting guidelines are shut down and journalists fined. Internet access is tightly controlled. Web content is subject to government approval and sites deemed unacceptable are blocked.<br />
<br />
The main daily English-language paper is the state-run Vietnam News. Vietnam Television is also state-run and VTV broadcasts from Hanoi. Some weekly versions of British newspapers are available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Vietnamese postal service isn't the most efficient so allow around 7-14 days for post to arrive in the UK and US. Send mail from the post office in main towns and cities. Postal services can be slow. Airmail to Europe can take up to three weeks.</p><p>Post office hours and days vary from town to town but many can be open from early morning until late evening.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Hué</p><![CDATA[<p>The former imperial city of Hue is crammed with wonderful sights. The Imperial Citadel, suffering from the ravages and war and the tropical weather, is slowly being painstakingly renovated; riverside is the Thien Mu pagoda where novice monks peek shyly at the visitors; and the mausoleums of the Emperors, each unique in style.</p>]]><br/><p>My Son</p><![CDATA[<p>Situated in a narrow valley in the <i>Duy Xuyen District</i> in the <i>Quang Nam Province</i>, <i>My Son</i> is the site of a former Champa Kingdom that in its day rivalled other great Southeast Asian kingdoms such as <i>Angkor</i> in Cambodia or <i>Bagan</i> in Myanmar (see separate entries). The site was the religious centre of the Cham people with the oldest temple dating back to the fourth century. Successive Cham rulers added towers and structures to the site with the majority added in a 700-year period starting from the seventh century. Whilst war, time and neglect have reduced many of the structures to crumbling ruins, it's still possible to see the remnants of the site's former grandeur and significance. The My Son sanctuary was listed as a UNESCO World Heritage Site in 1999.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Cruise Halong Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sure it's touristy, and if you take a boat trip you'll be among a flotilla of dozens of old converted junks, but Halong Bay still remains one of the most impressive natural sights in Southeast Asia, its limestone kart islands jutting dramatically from the sea. Overnight trips are available.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy Ho Chi Minh City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gleaming skyscrapers sit side by side with ramshackle buildings and crumbling colonial houses. Monks pass deluxe car showrooms collecting alms. Sun-baked streets heave with honking motorbikes as the Saigon River thrums with small boats and ferries. Our advice? Give yourself plenty of time to take it all in.</p>]]><p><b>Escape the heat in Dalat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>To escape the heat of the plains, head for Dalat, a former colonial hill station, reminiscent of a French town. Its faded, elegant villas are evocative of another era. Colonists from Saigon headed to its cool climes, as did the emperor and his entourage. The romantic lakes and alpine scenery are magnets for Vietnamese honeymooners.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the Central Highlands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dalat is as far as most people go into the Central Highlands but if you head further into the mountains you'll find gorgeous, waterfall-laced hillscapes. The area around Buon Ma Thuot, a coffee-growing region, is a good option – and serves as a reminder that Vietnam is the world's second-largest coffee producer.</p>]]><p><b>Get a suit made in Hoi An</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Meander the narrow streets of Hoi An, where tiny shop-houses sit cheek by jowl with riverside bars. It's an obvious place to buy souvenirs – silk items, T-shirts and ceramics are all commonplace – but the headline draw is the chance to have bespoke clothing made by one of the many tailors.</p>]]><p><b>Go hiking</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are hundreds of long distance hiking trails around the country, and a significant infrastructure for visitors wanting guided trekking tours. A strong option? Head south from Hanoi into Cuc Phuong National Park, a wilderness of forest-covered limestone mountains rising up from green rice paddies. It's also home to many rare species and a primate rescue centre.</p>]]><p><b>Learn more about the Vietnam War</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It's now more than 40 years since the Vietnam War (known locally as the American War) finished, but is legacy remains tangible. Visitors can tour the DMZ (Demilitarised Zone), walk parts of the one-time supply route known as the Ho Chi Minh Trail, and see tunnels – most notably those at Cu Chi – used in the conflict.</p>]]><p><b>Learn to cook</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The food in Vietnam can be astonishingly good. Learn the subtleties of the national cuisine by joining a cookery class – you'll be submerged into the melee of a local market to buy provisions before retreating to a kitchen to prepare (and, naturally, taste) a few dishes. Hoi An and Ho Chi Minh are both good spots to try.</p>]]><p><b>Lose yourself in Hanoi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hanoi is a hyperactive, sense-spinning whirl of a city, particularly in the maze of narrow lanes and street kitchens in and around the Old Quarter.  Elsewhere, wide, leafy boulevards are lined by colonial buildings in the French quarter. Wherever you are, the background noise is the buzzing of the motorbikes that crowd the capital.</p>]]><p><b>Sail the Mekong Delta</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the watery world of the Mekong Delta, where the channels of the mighty Mekong crisscross the land past shimmering emerald paddy fields and sugar cane plantations. Discover riverine towns and floating markets, or try spending the night in a waterside homestay.</p>]]><p><b>See Sapa’s rice terraces</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the very north of the country, the one-time French hill station of Sapa is surrounded by hefty alpine scenery, its hills carpeted in spectacular rice terraces. It's also a good place to learn more about some of the hill tribes that still live in the area, most notably the Hmong. Hiking is popular, and village homestays can be arranged.</p>]]><p><b>See the country on two wheels</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Motorbike hire is easily arranged in various parts of the country. The vehicles are most commonly Russian-made 125cc Minsks – some travellers even ride the full distance between Hanoi to Ho Chi Minh City. Riddled with all sorts of dangers, not least the vast amount of bikes in the cities, it is nevertheless an exhilarating way to see the country.</p>]]><p><b>Taste history in Hué</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The former imperial city of Hue is crammed with wonderful sights. The imposing Imperial Citadel, weathered by the ravages of war and the tropical weather, is slowly being painstakingly renovated. Down at the riverside, meanwhile, you'll find the Thien Mu pagoda, where novice monks peek shyly at the visitors, and the mausoleums of the Emperors, each unique in style.</p>]]><p><b>Travel on the Reunification Express</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The rail lines of the so-called Reunification Express run virtually the length of the country, from Hanoi to Ho Chi Minh. 'Express' is a misnomer, however. It can take between 30 and 40 hours to travel between the two cities, so it's advisable to do one section only. Popular is the 18-hour journey between Hanoi and Hue.</p>]]><p><b>Unwind on the beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The beaches of Vietnam are superb. Nha Trang is the perfect combination of wide, palm-lined sands and lively, bar-lined town – boat trips can take you out to nearby islands and coral reefs. Alternatively, Vung Tau offers superb snorkelling, while Mui Ne is where to head for surfing and adrenaline thrills.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the Cao Dai Temple</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head out to Tay Ninh to view the colourful midday service of the intriguing Cao Dai sect, held in a large temple almost Disney-esque in style. The followers wear red, blue and yellow robes and chant to the accompaniment of a traditional orchestra. The religion combines various beliefs – its saints include Joan of Arc, Buddha, Christ, Muhammad and Victor Hugo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$202 billion (2016)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude oil, clothing and footwear, rice, rubber, tea and coffee.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, refined petroleum, steel, cotton and grain.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, Japan, Australia, China and European Union.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The economy of Vietnam was devastated by 30 years of war up to 1975, after which policy errors and a USA-enforced trade boycott combined to stifle development. Since the government's economic liberation policy, known as <em>doi moi</em> and the end of the boycott in 1994, and the introduction of liberalising and deregulating measures by the government, the Vietnamese economy achieved significant annual growth until the world economic downturn in 2008. <br />
<br />
Despite the global economic and financial crisis Vietnam's GDP grew 6.8% in 2010, a three-year high. The year in general was positive for many market sectors with growth in exports for rice and garments. There was positive growth in consumer confidence and the trade deficit reduced. However, inflation increased to 9.19% in 2010 and foreign investment was still down. There was a slight reduction in the unemployment figures for 2010.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most senior staff in large and international companies will speak English but it is not common in smaller companies. It is essential to make appointments for business meetings and to exchange business cards.</p>
<p>Vietnamese are quite likely to present visitors with a gift, such as laquerware, so visitors should take along a small gift from their home country in order to reciprocate. It is important to realise that the Vietnamese do not like to say no to any request, so arrangements and contracts should be checked and rechecked.</p>
<p>Vietnamese business people are gradually becoming more formal in their dress, as contact with international business increases. However, because of the extreme heat, it is quite acceptable, and practical, to dispense with the wearing of a suit jacket.</p><p>Offices tend to open between 0730 and 0800 and close around 1700 or 1800 with a long lunch break between 1130 and 1400 hrs. Some offices are also open on Saturdays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Vietnam Trade Promotion Agency (VIETRADE)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:http://www.vietrade.gov.vn
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Business Information Centre Portal</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 80 44092
					Website:http://www.business.gov.vn/
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Vietnam Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (4) 574 3985
					Website:http://www.vcci.com.vn/
					Address: 9 Dao Duy Anh Street,4th Floor,Hanoi,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Vietnamese cooking is fresh, flavourful and usually superb, as the profusion of Vietnamese restaurants in New York, London and Berlin attests. Within the country, there&rsquo;s a plethora of regional variations. And as in all parts of the region, rice or noodles usually form the initial basis of a meal.</p>
<p>Not surprisingly, fish is plentiful.  There&rsquo;s a reliance on fresh herbs and vegetables, as well as the gloriously pungent presence of shrimp paste and fermented fish sauce. Vietnamese cuisine is generally considered healthy.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Pho:</strong> An omnipresent noodle soup, usually with meat.<br />
<strong>Nem:</strong> Spring rolls with pork, noodles, eggs and mushrooms wrapped in rice paper, sometimes fried and served hot<em>.<br />
</em><strong>Banh chung:</strong> Sticky rice wrapped in large leaves and cooked for up to 48 hours, to be eaten cold at any time.<br />
<strong>Nuoc mam:</strong> Fermented fish sauce, widely used.<br />
<strong>Bun cha:</strong> Grilled pork with cold rice noodles and a big bowl of salad leaves.<br />
<strong>Banh bao:</strong> A steamed dumpling typically stuffed with onions, pork and other ingredients.<br />
<strong>Banh mi:</strong> A French baguette stuffed with pickled daikon and carrot, chili, coriander, cucumber and various meats.<br />
<strong>Com hen:</strong> Rice served with clams. Popular in Hue.<br />
<strong>Lau:</strong> Vietnamese hot pot.<br />
<strong>Bia hoi:</strong> Fresh beer produced daily and served cold in small, local bars. It is not particularly alcoholic but very refreshing.<br />
<strong>Coffee:</strong> Vietnam is the world&rsquo;s second largest producer of coffee and the local brew is usually served with condensed milk.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tipping is now quite customary, especially in tourist areas, and is much appreciated in a country where salaries are still low. Upscale restaurants and hotels may add a 5-10% service charge to the bill.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>16 for beer and wine; 18 for distilled alcoholic drinks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ho Chi Minh City is packed with bars and clubs ranging from dingy bars to some very upmarket venues. Most of the nightlife is concentrated in District 1. Hanoi's nightlife is much quieter and the streets can appear quiet after 2200 hrs. The venues tend to be small here and are concentrated in the Old Quarter and Hoan Kiem lake. </p>
<p>Live music is mainly restricted to international acts from the Philippines and Thailand performing in international hotels, with a few bars hosting local jazz and rock bands. Elsewhere, the nightlife is generally restricted to small bars and hotels but there is a particularly good bar/caf&eacute; scene in Hoi An in central Vietnam. For visitors seeking out something more cultural a visit to the water puppet theatre is entertaining.  The <em>bia hois</em> (pavement pubs) also offer a fun social experience and the friendly locals will often talk to visitors. Food and snacks such as boiled quails&rsquo; eggs are also usually available. Traditional music and dance is performed in some restaurants in the main tourist areas, particularly Hanoi, Ho Chi Minh City, Danang and Hue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For anyone who likes handicrafts and a bargain, Vietnam is nirvana. Wooden water puppets, with ingenious mechanisms, silk, lacquerware, ceramics, colourful hill-tribe bags, clothing and hand-painted silk greetings cards are all a must-buy. Clothes are particularly good value and tailors can make up clothes within 24 hours in many places, particularly Hoi An.</p>
<p>Each town and city has one or more markets and these are always worth visiting as much for the experience as for the shopping. Hanoi and Ho Chi Minh City have seen the arrival of upmarket shopping malls selling leading international and domestic brands.   </p>
<p>In small shops and markets have a go at bargaining for any items that catch your eye, but remember to keep it good-natured. Many of the souvenir shops in major towns and cities don't budge much on prices and some are even fixed price.</p><p>Shops are generally open seven days a week from 0800 to 2000 ; some are open until 2200 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Vietnam have vastly improved and most towns have small hotels and guest houses. In the major towns, there is a full range of accommodation to suit all budgets. Both Hanoi and Ho Chi Minh City have excellent standard hotels and international chains such as Hilton (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.hilton.com">www.hilton.com</a>), Sofitel (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.sofitel.com">www.sofitel.com</a>) and Intercontinental  (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.intercontinental.com">www.intercontinental.com</a>) with the facilities expected in 4- to 5-star hotels such as air conditioning, room service, swimming pool, health club and good restaurants. The major beach resorts of Nha Trang, Hoi An, Danang, Phan Thiet, Phu Quoc and Vung Tau have an excellent range of accommodation.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> There is no formal grading of hotels, but usually the price gives an idea of the standard. However, make sure you look at the rooms and shop around; there are some superb deals to be had, particularly in Hanoi and Ho Chi Minh City, where quality budget hotels are sprouting up everywhere.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are very many value-for-money guest houses, or mini-hotels, across the country, mainly without air conditioning and some with shared bathrooms or without hot water. Generally they are simply furnished but usually very clean.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Vietnam have vastly improved and most towns have small hotels and guest houses. In the major towns, there is a full range of accommodation to suit all budgets. Both Hanoi and Ho Chi Minh City have excellent standard hotels and international chains such as Hilton (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.hilton.com">www.hilton.com</a>), Sofitel (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.sofitel.com">www.sofitel.com</a>) and Intercontinental  (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.intercontinental.com">www.intercontinental.com</a>) with the facilities expected in 4- to 5-star hotels such as air conditioning, room service, swimming pool, health club and good restaurants. The major beach resorts of Nha Trang, Hoi An, Danang, Phan Thiet, Phu Quoc and Vung Tau have an excellent range of accommodation.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> There is no formal grading of hotels, but usually the price gives an idea of the standard. However, make sure you look at the rooms and shop around; there are some superb deals to be had, particularly in Hanoi and Ho Chi Minh City, where quality budget hotels are sprouting up everywhere.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Vietnam have vastly improved and most towns have small hotels and guest houses. In the major towns, there is a full range of accommodation to suit all budgets. Both Hanoi and Ho Chi Minh City have excellent standard hotels and international chains such as Hilton (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.hilton.com">www.hilton.com</a>), Sofitel (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.sofitel.com">www.sofitel.com</a>) and Intercontinental  (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.intercontinental.com">www.intercontinental.com</a>) with the facilities expected in 4- to 5-star hotels such as air conditioning, room service, swimming pool, health club and good restaurants. The major beach resorts of Nha Trang, Hoi An, Danang, Phan Thiet, Phu Quoc and Vung Tau have an excellent range of accommodation.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> There is no formal grading of hotels, but usually the price gives an idea of the standard. However, make sure you look at the rooms and shop around; there are some superb deals to be had, particularly in Hanoi and Ho Chi Minh City, where quality budget hotels are sprouting up everywhere.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There are excellent hospitals in Hanoi and Ho Chi Minh City, and health care centres in all provinces, but facilities are limited and there is a lack of medicines. Health insurance is essential and should include cover for emergency repatriation by air. Immediate cash payment is expected for services. Call 115 in the case of a medical emergency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travellers who stay longer than three months need a negative HIV-test.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. However, bottled water is widely available and cheap; make sure the seal is unbroken before drinking. Unpasteurised milk should be boiled. However, pasteurised milk is widely available now.  Avoid dairy products that are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes advised. Dengue fever continues to be a problem; guarding against mosquito bites is advised. Japanese encephalitis is found in Northern Vietnam, including Hanoi.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Liberation Day :
							30 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>National Day :
							02 September </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be freely imported into Vietnam by travellers without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigars or 500g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1.5L of spirits over 22%&nbsp;volume or 2L of fortified wines or liqueurs under 22% volume or 3L of other alcoholic drinks.<br />
&bull; Other goods to the value of ₫10,000,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include weapons, ammunition, explosives, military equipment, antiques, drugs, toxic chemicals, immoral products, firecrackers, more than 200 cigarettes, and raw gold.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited exports include weapons, ammunition, explosives, military equipment, antiques, drugs, toxic chemicals, wild animals, endangered plants and animals, documents related to national security, and raw gold.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dông (VND; symbol ₫). Notes are in denominations of ₫500,000, 200,000, 100,000, 50,000, 20,000, 10,000, 5,000, 2,000, 1,000 and 500. Coins are in denominations of ₫5,000, 2,000, 1,000 and 500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The US Dollar is the most favoured foreign currency. Australian, British, Japanese, Singaporean and Thai currency, as well as the Euro, can usually be changed in the larger cities; great difficulty may be encountered in trying to exchange any other currencies. There is a commission charge for changing money in banks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An increasing number of outlets accept MasterCard and Visa. However, outside main towns and cities, it is wise to carry cash. There are ATMs in many major towns, but not in rural areas.</p><p>There are plenty of ATMs in major towns, but they can be scarce in rural areas. ATMs issue Dông, and the single withdrawal limit varies, depending on the bank, ranging from ₫2,000,000 to much larger amounts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers' cheques are accepted in banks, money changers and some hotels although most travellers now use debit cards because of the increased number of ATMs. It is best to take US Dollar travellers' cheques to avoid additional exchange rate charges and expect to pay a high commission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Varies from bank to bank but generally Mon-Fri 0830-1600; some may close for lunch.  Many banks are also open on Saturday morning; all banks are closed on Sunday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/2</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes/1/2</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Vietnam, a passport valid for at least one month after the visa expiration date is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Make sure your passport has not been damaged in any way or you may be refused entry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas are not required for passengers in transit, provided they have an onward/return ticket, are continuing their journey within 24 hours and do not leave the transit area of the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visa: fees vary according to the type of visa and length of stay and are regularly adjusted. Please contact the nearest embassy for up-to-date fee information.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visas are valid for 30 days or 90 days from the proposed date of entry depending on the type of visa granted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>
<p>There are also a number of agencies offering a visa on arrival. You apply and pay for a letter of approval online through a commercial company and collect your visa on arrival at the airport (not at overland border crossings). These agencies usually charge an additional service fee. The Vietnamese Embassy in the UK advises against obtaining visas using this method however, as it cannot verify the validity of the visas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreigners can take up temporary residence if they are invited to work in Vietnam by an organisation there. You must give details of the type of work and duration before a visa and temporary resident permit can be issued.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow three working days for visa processing. For an additional fee, a next-day service is available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can extend tourist visas for up to a month and the best way to do this is through a travel agent in Vietnam.&nbsp;Rates vary depending on the agent used. Do not overstay your visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[14.058324]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[108.277199]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>331,230 sq km (127,889 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>94,569,072 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>276 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hanoi.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Socialist republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vietnam lies within the tropics and is principally agricultural with a central tropical rainforest. The 'S'-shaped country shares borders to the north with the People's Republic of China and to the west with Laos and Cambodia. The eastern and southern shores are lapped by the South China Sea and the Pacific Ocean.</p>
<p>Northern Vietnam is dominated by the Red River plains that bisect Hanoi, and the Lo and Chay rivers. To the north and west of Hanoi are green hilly areas; particularly well known is the Sapa Valley. East of Hanoi, Halong Bay features a stunning natural formation of more than 3,000 limestone islands jutting sharply out of the South China Sea.</p>
<p>To the south, it is the Mekong River and its fertile plain that governs the geography and consequently the rice industry. Among the plains, in the middle of the thin country and to the southwest are mountainous areas, known as the highlands, where farmers grow rubber, tea and coffee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Buddhist majority. There are also Taoist, Confucian, Hoa Hao, Caodaist and Christian (predominantly Roman Catholic) minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking and a vocal greeting is normal. Clothing should be kept simple, informal and discreet. Avoid shorts if possible as they are usually only worn by children. Footwear should be removed when entering Buddhist pagodas. Vietnamese people should not be touched on the head. It is also polite to give and receive gifts and business cards using two hands.<br />
<br />
<strong>Photography:</strong> There are restrictions at ports, airports and harbours, and in similar areas elsewhere. It is courteous to ask permission first before taking photographs of people.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with two flat pins, two round pins or three square pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Nguyễn Xu&acirc;n Ph&uacute;c since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Nguyen Phu Trong since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Under its current boundaries Vietnam has only existed since the 19th century, although the nation&rsquo;s history stretches back thousands of years, incorporating various powerful kingdoms and a long period of Chinese occupation.</p>
<p>In modern times, for many years Vietnam formed part of the French colony of Indochina, along with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cambodia">Cambodia</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/laos">Laos</a>. In 1941, the Japanese occupied Vietnam during their WWII sweep through Southeast Asia. The resistance to the Japanese was led by the Indochinese Communist Party.</p>
<p>Communist revolutionary Ho Chi Minh established the Viet Minh during WWII in order to gain independence from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a>. Fighting continued until 1954 when the French surrendered to the Viet Minh at Dien Bien Phu and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hanoi">Hanoi</a> became capital of North Vietnam, but Ho Chi Minh was determined to reunite the whole country.</p>
<p>The USA came to the support of South Vietnam and full-scale war &ndash; with the southern communist guerrillas (known as the Viet Cong), the North Vietnam Army and the Soviet Union on one side, and the Americans and the South Vietnamese Army on the other &ndash; broke out in 1965.&nbsp;The weary Americans withdrew in 1973 and fighting continued until 1975 when Saigon fell to North Vietnamese troops. Vietnam was reunited under communist rule the following year.</p>
<p>Vietnamese troops occupied Cambodia in 1978 to drive out the genocidal Khmer Rouge regime and stayed there until it withdrew its troops in 1989. After withdrawing from Cambodia, Vietnam concentrated on rebuilding its own economy and, following years of rampant inflation, poverty and repression, the government introduced economic reform or <em>doimoi</em> in 1986, allowing people to own their own businesses.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, the Vietnamese economy suffered from the withdrawal of aid and subsidised goods from the former USSR and from Eastern Europe, as well as the continuing US-organised trade boycott instituted after the US withdrawal. Relations with the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> eased after full diplomatic relations were restored in 1995.</p>
<p>Recent reforms resulted in rapid economic growth, until the global crisis in 2008, but there has been no parallel development in the country's political environment &ndash; the Communist Party has no intention of relaxing its hold on political power and has been criticised by human rights groups for increasingly suppressing online dissent and freedom of expression.</p>
<p>The country is involved in ongoing territorial disputes with its old foe <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> over the sovereignty over the South China Sea.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	It&rsquo;s estimated that Hanoi&rsquo;s seven million residents collectively own four million scooters.<br />
&bull;	The 19th century diplomat Phan Thanh Gian went on hunger strike to protest against French incursions. He was still alive after 15 days, so swallowed poison instead. <br />
&bull;	Ho Chi Minh once made a living as a pastry chef on the Newhaven-Dieppe ferry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Vietnam]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+84 (0)24 3936 0500 </p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/world/organisations/british-embassy-hanoi</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+84 (0)24 3936 0500 </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thu 0830-1230 and 1330-1645; Fri 0830-1230 and 1300-1500&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Central Building, 4th Floor<br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[US Embassy in Vietnam]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+84 (0)24 3850 5000</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://vn.usembassy.gov/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+84 (0)24 3850 5000</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0800-1700&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>7 Láng Ha Street<br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Socialist Republic of Vietnam in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 861 0737 or 202 716 8666  (consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.vietnamembassy-usa.org/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 861 0737 or 202 716 8666  (consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1200 and 1400-1700&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Suite 400<br/>1233 20th Street,NW<br/>Washington<br/>20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Socialist Republic of Vietnam in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 (0)20 7937 1912</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.vietnamembassy.org.uk/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 (0)20 7937 1912</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1230 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>12 Victoria Road<br/>London<br/>W8 5RD<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some destinations evoke mental images the moment their names are mentioned, and Vietnam is one of them. A frenetic and fascinating country, it calls to mind conical-hatted street vendors, water buffalo plodding across rice fields, mopeds buzzing through cities and floating markets on the Mekong River.</p>
<p>The days when Vietnam was best known for its conflict with America are long gone. From the temples of Hanoi and the islands of Halong Bay to the beaches of Nha Trang and the palaces of Hue, it is a country now firmly etched in the travel psyche.</p>
<p>At times, Vietnam is an assault on the senses. Life in its feverish cities is conducted largely on the streets, among chattering <em>bia hois</em> (pavement pubs) and steaming <em>pho</em> (noodle soup) stands. The country&rsquo;s two main cities &ndash; Hanoi in the north, Ho Chi Minh in the south &ndash; are different in many ways, but they share an intoxicating energy. Ancient pagodas and colonial houses jostle for space with new-build skyscrapers, while labyrinthine back-alleys hum with life. These narrow streets are atmospheric places to spend time, day or night.</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s long, thin shape, sometimes compared to two rice baskets at either end of a pole, means these two cities form natural start and end points to an itinerary. The highlights along the way, meanwhile, are as well packed as the spring rolls which adorn market stalls: nature-lovers, history buffs, beach bums and foodies are all catered for in singularly Vietnamese style.</p>
<p>Those heading into the countryside can expect not only glorious scenery, but a rich cultural web of different ethnic groups. The US wartime legacy can still be readily explored &ndash; perhaps most notably at the Cu Chi Tunnels near Ho Chi Minh &ndash; but this is a country to enjoy for what it is today, whether you&rsquo;re here for a few days or a month.</p><p>Some destinations evoke mental images the moment their names are mentioned, and Vietnam is one of them. A frenetic and fascinating country, it calls to mind conical-hatted street vendors, water buffalo plodding across rice fields, mopeds buzzing through cities and floating markets on the Mekong River. The days when Vietnam was best known for its conflict with America are long gone. From the temples of Hanoi and the islands of Halong Bay to the beaches of Nha Trang and the palaces of Hue, it is a country now firmly etched in the travel psyche.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
