<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Yemen" ColCode="yem" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ye" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Yemen]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s generally accepted that the best time to visit Yemen and therefore the &lsquo;high season&rsquo; falls between October and April, after the rains and before the intense heat of the summer.  However, temperatures, humidity and rainfall all vary radically with altitude. </p>
<p>The southern coastal areas see limited rainfall and are hot and humid year round, summer temperatures sometimes topping 54&deg;C (129&deg;F).</p>
<p>The central highlands are hot in summer with average temperatures of 30&deg;C (86&deg;F), but winters are cold with frequent frosts.  Average rainfall in the central highlands varies from 400mm to 750mm per year. </p>
<p>Northern regions, and Wadi Hadhramawt, are hot and dry year round.  Summer temperatures hover around the high 30s and it&rsquo;s not uncommon to find areas where it hasn&rsquo;t rained for years.  That said, Wadi Hadhramawt suffered severe floods in 2008 which threatened to engulf the ancient mud city of Shibam.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight clothes are worn in the coastal plain all year. Warmer clothes are needed from November to April in the highlands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Yemenia (<a href="http://www.yemenia.com" target="_blank">www.yemenia.com</a>) operates flights from Sana'a to  Aden, Al Ghaydah, Al Hudaydah, Riyan (Al Mukalla), Seiyun, Socotra and Ta'izz. Note, most flights in Yemen are currently suspended.</p>
<p>Felix Airways (<a href="http://www.felixairways.com" target="_blank">www.felixairways.com</a>) operates similar domestic routes to Yemenia, as well as some regional international routes. &nbsp;Booking in advance is essential and it&rsquo;s  always advisable to double-check flight reservations and times before departure.</p>
<p>Due to the prevailing insecurity, in some instances domestic flights are the only way for foreign nationals to reach certain destinations.  For example, travel between Sana&rsquo;a and Seiyun is not permitted except by air for non-Yemeni passport holders.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Though hardly recommended, ferries do connect some ports. For details, contact port authorities.  Mariners should be aware that increasingly sophisticated armed Somali pirates regularly attack shipping of all varieties in the Gulf of Aden beyond.  International naval forces are attempting to patrol shipping lanes but to date have not succeeded in curtailing piracy. Travellers are advised against yachting in this area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Road conditions and driving standards are quite poor and many roads are in a state of disrepair, with mountain roads particularly hazardous.  Within Sana'a and from Ta'izz to Mokha, the roads are reliable.  From Aden to Ta'izz is three to five hours' driving time.  A road links Aden and Sana'a, otherwise the road network is mainly limited to desert tracks.  Use of 4-wheel drive vehicles and a guide is recommended.  There is a road from Aden to Mukalla of 500km (310 miles).</p><p>Taxis are generally cheap and easy to find with two types operating in Sana&rsquo;a; those recognisable by yellow licence plates without meters, and newer yellow cabs with meters operated by Raha Transport.</p>
<p>Manic minibuses known as <em>debubs</em> operate on certain fixed routes and, if you&rsquo;re prepared to suffer the crush, can be a very cheap way to get around town.</p>
<p>Hardly a safe option but for those preferring the wind in their hair, motorcycle taxis are often the quickest way to negotiate roads jammed with traffic.  Be sure to agree a fare before getting on the back.</p>
<p>Long-distance share taxis, often Peugeot 504s, operate to other towns and villages. Again, fares need to be clearly agreed in advance.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required. A temporary licence valid for three months is available from local authorities on presentation of a valid national licence.</p><p>The maximum speed limit is 100kph (62mph) but speed limit signs are exceptional and limits rarely enforced.</p>
<p>Seatbelts, though recommended, are not required by law.  In the event of an accident resulting in injury or death of a third party, tribal custom often takes precedence.  Family members will expect to negotiate recompense commensurate with the severity of the injuries.</p>
<p>Driving under the influence of alcohol or drugs can result in a fine or prison sentence.</p><p>Refer to information provided by your rental company.</p><p>Car hire is available from Sana&rsquo;a airport and in main towns &ndash; the minimum age to rent a car is 25, though this is rarely enforced. Chauffeur-driven cars are also available.</p><p>The maximum speed limit is 100kph (62mph) but speed limit signs are exceptional and limits rarely enforced.</p>
<p>Seatbelts, though recommended, are not required by law.  In the event of an accident resulting in injury or death of a third party, tribal custom often takes precedence.  Family members will expect to negotiate recompense commensurate with the severity of the injuries.</p>
<p>Driving under the influence of alcohol or drugs can result in a fine or prison sentence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving standards in Yemen are questionable and an element of risk is inherent in every journey.  <em>Qat</em>-addled drivers, unpredictable pedestrians and suicidal livestock are the norm, as are big trucks cutting corners on blind bends.  That said, the only other option is to walk&hellip;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Yemen</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">tarsquoizz</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Yemen</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">hodeida</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Yemen</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">aden</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Yemenia (<a href="http://www.yemenia.com" target="_blank">www.yemenia.com</a>). The UK Foreign and Commonwealth Office currently advises against all travel to Yemen; most flights have been suspended.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 8 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Aden International Airport </b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 11km (7 miles) from the city (journey time - 20 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Hodaidah International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 8km (5 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Sana'a International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://sanaa.airport-authority.com]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Taiz Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 4km (2.5 miles) from the city (journey time - 10 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main ports are Aden, Al Hudaydah, Al Mocha, Al Khawkha, Al Mukalla, and Nashtoon.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Other than hotel land lines, Skype or another VOIP service may be  the best way to call home.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone operators. GSM coverage is good in the west and in coastal areas of the east but 3G data coverage is currently non-existent.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Increasingly internet cafes are opening throughout Yemen and many hotels now have Wi-Fi facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All broadcasting is controlled by the Ministry of Information through the Public Corporation for Radio and Television.  Satellite television is widely available. </p>
<p>The main government-owned newspaper is Al Thawra (<a href="http://www.althawranews.net" target="_blank">www.althawranews.net</a>) and the ruling party&rsquo;s print mouthpiece is Al Motamar (<a href="http://www.almotamar.ne/en" target="_blank">www.almotamar.ne/en</a>). Several independent English language newspapers exist including Yemen Times (<a href="http://www.yementimes.com" target="_blank">www.yementimes.com</a>), Yemen Observer (<a href="http://www.yobserver.com" target="_blank">www.yobserver.com</a>). </p>
<p>UK newspapers are not generally available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe from Sana'a takes about four days; mail to and from other towns may take longer.</p><p>Sat-Thurs 0800-1400 and 1600-2000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>al Medina al qadima Sanaa fi Sanaa</p><![CDATA[<p>The UNESCO-preserved site of the Old City of Sana'a is the largest preserved old city in the Arab world. Sana'a, which translates from Arabic as 'fortified place', has been the political capital of Yemen since the unification of the Yemen Arab Republic and the People's Democratic Republic of Yemen in 1990. It is one of the oldest continuously inhabited cities in the world, and according to Yemeni legend was founded by Shem, one of the three sons of Noah, possibly as early as the second century BC. Once an Arabian centre for Christians and Jews, the city was converted to Islam in AD 632. Apart from brief periods of Ottoman control – in the 16th century and between 1872 and 1940 – members of the Zaydi dynasty thereafter ruled Sana'a more or less continuously until 1962, when it became the capital of the newly founded Yemen Arab Republic. Surrounded by ancient clay walls which stand six to nine metres (20-30ft) high, the old city is a wonderland of over 100 mosques, 12 hammams (baths) and 6500 houses. Most of the buildings date back to the seventh and eighth centuries BC, when the city achieved prominence as an important centre for Islam, and were constructed from dark basalt stone and brick. One of the most popular attractions is the 1000-year-old Suq al-Milh (Salt Market), where it is possible to buy not only salt but also bread, spices, raisins, cotton, copper, pottery, silverware, antiques, and a host of other goods. The seventh century al-Jami'al-Kabir (Great Mosque) is one of the oldest in the Muslim world and its Persian-style minarets pierce the city's skyline. The Liberty Gate, formerly known as Bab al-Yaman (Yemen Gate) until the 1962 revolution, is one of the many points of entry through the city walls and is over 700 years old. The National Museum consists of three floors of displays and exhibitions, including ancient Yemeni writings, coins, jewellery and traditional costume.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Aden</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the port of Aden with its biblical history and fine museums. Crater, the oldest part of the city, lies in the crater of an extinct volcano and is where the most ancient constructions in Aden may be seen.</p>]]><p><b>Al Hudaydah</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Colourful wooden fishing boats skippered by crews from Yemen, Eritrea and Djibouti fill the harbour of this Red Sea fishing port.  A visit to the fragrant and thronging and fish market sees myriad species including shark, swordfish and tuna auctioned fresh off the boat to the highest bidder.</p>]]><p><b>Amran</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See Amran, lying on the edge of the fertile basin of al-Bawn. The city is surrounded by the old clay city walls of pre-Islamic, Sabean origin.</p>]]><p><b>Bab al-Yemen Market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Shop for souvenirs in Sana'a's 1,000-year-old Bab al-Yemen Market, which is divided into 40 different crafts and trades. The spice market is one of the best to visit. Other markets include the Souk al-Nahaas selling embroidered head-dresses, belts and jambias (curved daggers).</p>]]><p><b>Dive</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dive in the balmy Red and Arabian seas, or take to the water for a spot of sailing.</p>]]><p><b>Great Mosque of Sana'a</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the Great Mosque of Sana'a, the oldest and largest of the mosques in Sana'a and one of the oldest in the Muslim world, constructed in the lifetime of the Prophet and enlarged in AD705.</p>]]><p><b>Hadda Mountain</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Scale Hadda Mountain and take in picturesque villages dotted with orchards growing apricots, peaches, walnuts and almonds.</p>]]><p><b>Haraz Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>These central mountains provide one Yemen's best trekking areas.  Guided hikes maybe arranged to take in the larger villages of Manakha, Al Hajjarah and Huytayb along with those barely-visited lost in the Haraz uplands.</p>]]><p><b>Hodeida</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the modern Red Sea port of Hodeida and see the fish market, where fishing boats have been built from wood in the same way for hundreds of years.</p>]]><p><b>Little Aden</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lounge on several superb beaches fringing the Indian Ocean at Little Aden, situated in the crater of an extinct volcano; this is an area of small fishing villages in sheltered bays. Hike and camp on Socotra Island; the island's remarkable landscape is home to a huge array of wildlife and plants.</p>]]><p><b>National Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the National Museum in Taherir Square in Dar al-Shukr (Palace of Gratefulness); it contains engravings of pre-Islamic times, bronze statues, a beautiful mashrabia (cooling place for water) and several examples of folk art.</p>]]><p><b>Rawdha</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Rawdha, some 8km (5 miles) north of Sana'a, a garden city famous for its sweet grapes, the mosque built by Ahmed ibn al-Qasim and the Rawdha Palace, now used as a hotel.</p>]]><p><b>Sa'dah</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the walled city of Sa'dah. The al-Hadi Mosque is still an important institution for education in Zaydism. It is possible to walk along the top of the city walls, which offer good views of the city.]]><p><b>Sad'ah Basin</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Walk amongst Yemen's early crops of grapes in the strikingly fertile Sad'ah Basin.</p>]]><p><b>Sana'a</b></p><![CDATA[<p>To see Old Sana'a, drive along the sunken street of the Sailah towards Sana'a's ancient heart, which for many visitors, is their first and possibly most enduring memory of Yemen.  Here the treasure of Sana'a, its characteristic tower houses defines a capital like no other the world over. Other highlights include the Souk al Milh for a shopping experience that's a far cry from the global High Street, and for a street bursting with simple and cheap Yemeni food head to Restaurant Street off Hadda Street.</p>]]><p><b>Sana’a Mountain Villages</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Even those limited to San'a can still make a full day excursion to its surrounding villages.  Head for fortified Kawkaban, the silversmiths of Thula and the famed Hamida restaurant of Shibam.</p>]]><p><b>Shibam (Hadhramawt)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This walled desert city on the open plain is another architectural gem designated a World Heritage Site by UNESCO.  Likened to a 'Manhattan of the Desert' by early 20th-century traveller and writer Freya Stark, Shibam's 500 mud tower houses, some nine stories high, are 500 years old and are home to 5,000 people.</p>]]><p><b>Socotra</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Finally designated as a World Biosphere Reserve in 2008 the remote Socotra archipelago is the Arabian answer to the Galapagos in terms of unique flora and fauna.  700-year-old Dragon's Blood trees and Socotra Desert Rose set against the Tolkeinesque peaks of the Haggier Mountains characterise a unique lanscape.  Undeveloped, unspoilt, with few roads - only 2,000 visitors make landfall each year.</p>]]><p><b>Ta'izz</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Capital of North Yemen until 1962 this town has a very different feel to Sana'a.  Though the 'old city' has been all but swallowed up by the fast-growing modernity, beautiful old houses and mosques remain within the line of the 13th-century city wall, still intact along the southern perimeter.</p>]]><p><b>Wadi Wa'aar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy the subtropical climate of Wadi Wa'aar, lying between Sana'a and Sa'dah in the north. Out of this rises the Shahara, a huge mountain massif, the highest point being nearly 3,000m (9,840ft) above sea level. This can be climbed by foot or by 4-wheel drive car.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$30,02 billion (2010). [CIA]</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude petroleum, liquefied natural gas, refined oil products, fish and coffee.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Foodstuffs, live animals, chemicals, machinery.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China, France, Kuwait, United Arab Emirates and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Yemen is one of the poorest countries in the Arab world, and among the principal motivations behind the unification of Yemen in 1990 was the prospect of economic transformation and expansion.<br /><br />Under IMF auspices, the government has implemented a programme of structural reforms involving privatisation and an overhaul of the financial system. In exchange, the Yemenis received financial support and some relief of Yemen's US$5 billion foreign debt. Large-scale unemployment persists; an estimated 30% of the workforce is out of work.<br /><br />Agriculture is concentrated in the fertile northern part of the country. The principal cash crops are cereals, cotton, coffee, fruit, vegetables and qat (a narcotic leaf). Livestock rearing, fishing and some manufacturing also contribute to the economy.<br /><br />However, the most important industrial activity is oil and gas production. Yemeni reserves are modest by regional standards but since the opening of the refining complex at Aden in 1994 and new fields coming on stream, the sector accounts for the majority of export earnings.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business people are expected to dress smartly for meetings and formal social occasions. English is commonly used in business circles. Appointments are needed and visitors should be punctual. Business cards are often exchanged. Ideally avoid the month of Ramadan.  Do not be surprised during a meeting if Yemeni businessmen chew <em>qat</em>.</p><p>Sat-Wed 0800-1500, during Ramadan 1000-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>General Investment Authority</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 262 962
					Website:http://www.giay.gov.ye
					Address: Southern Safya,Al-Quds Street,PO Box 19022,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Surprisingly for a country whose narcotic leaf-chewing habit actually suppresses appetite, Yemeni cuisine is excellent.  As well as dishes familiar across the Middle East such as ful, falafel, lamb, chicken or goat kebab, uniquely Yemeni flavours are on offer and a fair degree of regional variation is manifest across the country.  Outside upmarket hotels meals are generally consumed communally, often sitting on the floor, sharing bowls and using crisp, freshly baked flat bread to scoop up choice mouthfuls with ones right hand.  Sweet desserts precede tea, with or without milk.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull;	<em>Saltah</em> (a mostly vegetable stew topped with foamed fenugreek, served piping hot in an earthenware bowl) <br />
&bull;	<em>Fahsah</em> (like Saltah but with more meat) <br />
&bull;	<em>Fassolia</em> (white beans lightly spiced) <br />
&bull;	<em>Bint as Sahn</em> (&lsquo;girl of the plate&rsquo;, a honeyed bread dessert cooked in the oven)<br />
&bull;	Q<em>ishr</em> (a light, spicy coffee drink made with the husks of coffee beans)</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol is forbidden to Yemenis and its legal sale is limited to a very few hotels.  However, foreigners  are allowed to import up to two litres of alcoholic beverages and consume these in private.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Outside restaurants catering specifically for tourists tipping is not common practice in Yemen.  That said, the practice of tipping is becoming more common so if you've received exceptional service an extra 10 – 15% is always welcome.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Western nightlife doesn&rsquo;t really have a Yemeni equivalent.  The evenings see women securely ensconced at home leaving men to gather, eat and drink tea.  At the weekend some tourist hotels in Sana&rsquo;a&rsquo;s &lsquo;old city&rsquo; encourage sessions by traditional Yemeni musicians but as tourism has declined so have these performances.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, depending upon the circumstances, revelries can extend to all-night qat chewing sessions but this marathon of mastication usually surrounds a festivity such as a wedding or religious feast.  Any notion of a bar culture is present in vestigial form only within the capital&rsquo;s two or three international hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the absence of mass tourism Yemenis have yet to develop a souvenir trade beyond the odd &lsquo;I love Yemen&rsquo;  T-shirt, as such Sana&rsquo;a&rsquo;s Souk al Milh is probably the country&rsquo;s best place for recreational purchases.  Items might include frankincense, polished amber, metalwork, <em>jambiyyas</em> (characteristic curved daggers) and traditional clothing.  Heading east to Shibam and Wadi Do&rsquo;an, Hadhramawt&rsquo;s intense and powerful honey is a revelatory taste experience to those raised on supermarket fare &ndash; though import restrictions mean it&rsquo;s one to be enjoyed locally.  On the coast at Al Hudayhah, shark&rsquo;s teeth are touted by some entrepreneurial fishermen.  However, observing the sorry end that comes to so many of these ferocious beasts in the fish markets, you may feel less like celebrating their demise. </p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t bother stuffing your suitcase with finest <em>qat</em>. The narcotic leaves lose their kick soon after being picked, and though not controlled in the UK, in many other countries qat possession attracts the stiff penalties.</p><p>Sun-Thurs 0800-1300 and 1600-2100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation in Yemen varies from simple village guesthouses and down-at-heel city hotels to converted tower houses, restored Sultans&rsquo; palaces and five star international luxury. Sana&rsquo;a inevitably has the widest range of hotels, and to soak up the atmosphere there&rsquo;s nowhere better than the Old City, though narrow streets make life difficult for drivers and thus it&rsquo;s a less than convenient choice for those visiting on business. Outside the capital, Ta&rsquo;iz, Seiyun, Wadi Do&rsquo;an, Al Mukalla and Al Hudaydah all have a range of accommodation. Those self-selecting individuals heading for Socotra will return educated in just how simple a simple guesthouse can be.</p>
<p>Leisure travellers to Sana&rsquo;a should consider the lovely Burj Al Salam (<a href="http://www.burjalsalam.com" target="_blank">www.burjalsalam.com</a>) in the Al Fulayhi Quarter of old Sana&rsquo;a.  Another converted tower house, rooms are small but comfortable with clean functional bathrooms.  The upstairs restaurant is very good and the staff helpful when it comes to planning a meal.  The same owners have recently opened a new hotel in Thula one of the scenic mountain villages outside Sana&rsquo;a.  Elsewhere, Yemeni tour operators such as Universal Touring Company (<a href="http://www.utcyemen.com" target="_blank">www.utcyemen.com</a>) or Bazara Travel (<a href="http://www.bazaratravel.com" target="_blank">www.bazaratravel.com</a>) either own or have links with smaller hotels en route and can make informed suggestions regarding accommodation.</p>
<p>Contact the Yemen Tourism Promotion Board for further details of hotels in Yemen (see Important Addresses).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation in Yemen varies from simple village guesthouses and down-at-heel city hotels to converted tower houses, restored Sultans&rsquo; palaces and five star international luxury. Sana&rsquo;a inevitably has the widest range of hotels, and to soak up the atmosphere there&rsquo;s nowhere better than the Old City, though narrow streets make life difficult for drivers and thus it&rsquo;s a less than convenient choice for those visiting on business. Outside the capital, Ta&rsquo;iz, Seiyun, Wadi Do&rsquo;an, Al Mukalla and Al Hudaydah all have a range of accommodation. Those self-selecting individuals heading for Socotra will return educated in just how simple a simple guesthouse can be.</p>
<p>Leisure travellers to Sana&rsquo;a should consider the lovely Burj Al Salam (<a href="http://www.burjalsalam.com" target="_blank">www.burjalsalam.com</a>) in the Al Fulayhi Quarter of old Sana&rsquo;a.  Another converted tower house, rooms are small but comfortable with clean functional bathrooms.  The upstairs restaurant is very good and the staff helpful when it comes to planning a meal.  The same owners have recently opened a new hotel in Thula one of the scenic mountain villages outside Sana&rsquo;a.  Elsewhere, Yemeni tour operators such as Universal Touring Company (<a href="http://www.utcyemen.com" target="_blank">www.utcyemen.com</a>) or Bazara Travel (<a href="http://www.bazaratravel.com" target="_blank">www.bazaratravel.com</a>) either own or have links with smaller hotels en route and can make informed suggestions regarding accommodation.</p>
<p>Contact the Yemen Tourism Promotion Board for further details of hotels in Yemen (see Important Addresses).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation in Yemen varies from simple village guesthouses and down-at-heel city hotels to converted tower houses, restored Sultans&rsquo; palaces and five star international luxury. Sana&rsquo;a inevitably has the widest range of hotels, and to soak up the atmosphere there&rsquo;s nowhere better than the Old City, though narrow streets make life difficult for drivers and thus it&rsquo;s a less than convenient choice for those visiting on business. Outside the capital, Ta&rsquo;iz, Seiyun, Wadi Do&rsquo;an, Al Mukalla and Al Hudaydah all have a range of accommodation. Those self-selecting individuals heading for Socotra will return educated in just how simple a simple guesthouse can be.</p>
<p>Leisure travellers to Sana&rsquo;a should consider the lovely Burj Al Salam (<a href="http://www.burjalsalam.com" target="_blank">www.burjalsalam.com</a>) in the Al Fulayhi Quarter of old Sana&rsquo;a.  Another converted tower house, rooms are small but comfortable with clean functional bathrooms.  The upstairs restaurant is very good and the staff helpful when it comes to planning a meal.  The same owners have recently opened a new hotel in Thula one of the scenic mountain villages outside Sana&rsquo;a.  Elsewhere, Yemeni tour operators such as Universal Touring Company (<a href="http://www.utcyemen.com" target="_blank">www.utcyemen.com</a>) or Bazara Travel (<a href="http://www.bazaratravel.com" target="_blank">www.bazaratravel.com</a>) either own or have links with smaller hotels en route and can make informed suggestions regarding accommodation.</p>
<p>Contact the Yemen Tourism Promotion Board for further details of hotels in Yemen (see Important Addresses).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health care facilities are relatively poor, especially outside major cities. Major hospitals in Sana'a are: Al Jumhuriyya, Modern German Hospital, Saudi German Hospital, University of Science and Technology Hospital,  and Al Thawra. In Aden, there is the Al Jumhuriyya, Al Saber, the Saudi Hospital and the Refinery Hospital. Most large cities have a general hospital. Medical insurance is essential.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tap water is not safe to drink. Bottled water is readily available.  Fresh milk is rarely available but when present it's likely to be unpasteurised.  Similarly  some dairy products may have been made using  unpasturised milk – use common sense.  Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Avoid swimming and paddling in standing  fresh water; swimming pools which are well chlorinated and maintained are safe. Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Unity Day :
							22 May </p><p>September Revolution Day :
							26 September </p><p>Revolution Day :
							14 October </p><p>Independence Day :
							30 November </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into the Republic of Yemen without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 600 cigarettes or 60 cigars or 450g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2 bottles of alcoholic drinks (non-residents only).<br />
&bull; 1 bottle of perfume or eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; Goods up to a value of YER100,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Firearms, illegal drugs, obscene literature and all products of Israeli origin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Yemeni Riyal (YER) = 100 fils, though amounts under 1 Riyal are rarely quoted. Notes are in denominations of YER1,000, 500, 200, 100 and 50. Coins are in denominations of YER20, 10, 5 and 1.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local currency can easily be reconverted at banks, bureaux de change and hotels. US Dollars in cash are the easiest convertible currency.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Outside major hotels cards  are of limited use; American Express, Visa and Diners Club are the most widely accepted.</p><p>Sana'a has a few ATMs; at the airport (though these are not always functioning), at the Moevenpick Hotel and outside a couple of the biggest banks.  Aden and Tai'z also have a handful of machines.  There are very few ATMs elsewhere in the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Can be exchanged at some banks and hotels. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Pounds Sterling or US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sat-Wed 0830-1200, Thurs 0800-1130.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Yemen, a passport valid for at least six months after the date of departure is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: US$35; multiple-entry visa: US$65.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: three months; multiple-entry visa: six months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). Note that the embassy in the USA is not currently issuing tourist visas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow up to four weeks for visa processing. An express service is available for an additional fee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[15.341002]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[47.908034]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>527,968 sq km (203,850 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>27,477,600 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>50.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sana'a.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Republic of Yemen is bordered in the northwest, north and northeast by Saudi Arabia, in the east by Oman and in the south by the Gulf of Aden. To the west lies the Red Sea. The islands of Perim and Karam in the southern Red Sea are also part of the Republic. Yemen is predominantly mountainous, supporting terraced agriculture. The Hadramaut is a range of high mountains in the centre of the country. Highlands rise steeply in central Yemen, ranging in height from approximately 200m (656ft) to the 4,000m (13,123ft) peak of Jabal Nabi Shauib. In contrast is <em>Tihama</em>, a flat semi-desert coastal plain to the west, 50 to 100km (30 to 60 miles) wide. Surface water flows down from the mountains through the valleys during the rainy season and the area is cultivated for cotton and grain. In the east, the mountains drop away to the <em>Rub al-Khali</em> or 'Empty Quarter' of the Arabian Peninsula, a vast sea of sand. The arid coastal plains are fringed with sandy beaches.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sunni Muslim (especially in the north) and Shia Muslim, with some small Christian and Hindu communities. There is still a tiny Jewish minority.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are plenty of jokes about Yemeni hospitality, usually involving enforced stays in hidden mountain caves surrounded by armed men.  However, with rare exceptions, Yemeni hospitality is traditional, courteous and generous. Yemen is a conservative Muslim country with all the prohibitions that this entails; women in particular should dress modestly and in some instances cover their hair.  Mosques with the exception of certain times at Sana&rsquo;a&rsquo;s Al Saleh Mosque, and many Islamic holy sites, are off limits to non-Muslims; alcohol is forbidden to Yemenis and restricted to upmarket tourist hotels for foreigners. No such Islamic prohibition applies to <em>qat</em>.  Pervading almost all strata of society, buying, chewing and waxing lyrical over narcotic <em>qat</em> leaves is a national obsession verging on addiction &ndash; everything stops for <em>qat</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with two flat pins, three round pins or three square pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Maeen Abdul Malik since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President&nbsp;of the Supreme Political Council Mahdi al-Mashat since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To the Romans Yemen was &lsquo;Arabia Felix&rsquo; (&lsquo;Fortunate Arabia&rsquo;), whose mountains and fertile plains caught the tail end of the Indian Ocean monsoon rains and were distinct from the barren desert of the rest of the Arabian Peninsula.&nbsp;However, there&rsquo;s little that can be described as fortunate about modern Yemen.</p>
<p>During the early 17th and early 19th centuries European powers and the Ottoman Empire struggled to control unruly Yemeni tribes and evidence of colonial legacies is visible across the country.</p>
<p>In 1832 British East India Company soldiers captured the port of Aden, which provided a strategic staging post en route to the company&rsquo;s territories in India. Britain split the country with the region&rsquo;s other colonial power, the Ottomans, in 1904 and when that empire collapsed after WW1 its slice of Yemen gained independence until Arab nationalists acting with Egypt established the Yemeni Arab Republic in 1962 and precipitated a lengthy civil war.</p>
<p>The British protectorate held out in the face of violent attacks until 1967 and the birth of the Marxist People's Democratic Republic of Yemen, before its union with the Yemeni Arab Republic in 1990 joined the two states under President Ali Abdullah Saleh.</p>
<p>A suicide attack on USS Cole in Aden in 2000 killed 17 US personnel and was blamed on al-Qaeda in a foreshadowing of the 9/11 terror attacks, which saw Yemen stand with President Bush in his War on Terror. The inevitable Shia insurgency in Yemen began in 2004 and continues to this day, as the country is ripped apart by war.</p>
<p>Saleh was ousted in the 2011 Yemeni Revolution and replaced with Abd Rabbuh Mansur Hadi resulting in the intensification of the Shia insurgency. Hadi was swept from power in February 2015 and enlisted the support of a coalition to fight back against Mohammed Ali al-Houthi&rsquo;s newly declared Revolutionary Committee of Yemen. The situation remains volatile: the country faces permanent fragmentation as it teeters on the edge of failure.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	The traditional sport of camel jumping involves men (women are not allowed to take part) competing to jump over the most number of camels from a standing start. <br />
&bull;	Yemen is home to four UNESCO World Heritage Sites &ndash; the Old Walled City of Shibam in Wadi Hadhramaut, the Old City of Sana&rsquo;a, the town of Zabid and the Socotra Archipelago.<br />
&bull;	The average wedding feast in Yemen lasts 21 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[USA Embassy in Yemen]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(967) 1755 2000 </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.yemen.usembassy.gov</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(967) 1755 2000 </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Sa'awan Street, P.O. Box 22347<br/> Sana'a<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Yemen]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(00 967) 1 308 100</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ukinyemen.fco.gov.uk/en/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(00 967) 1 308 100</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Sat- Wed 0800-1530&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>938 Thaher Himiyar Street<br/>Sana'a<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Yemen in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 965 4760.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.yemenembassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 965 4760.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;0900 - 1700; Mon - Thurs 1000 - 1300 (consular section)&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2319 Wyoming Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Yemen in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7584 6607</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.yemenembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7584 6607</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1630&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>57 Cromwell Road<br/>London<br/>SW7 2ED<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If it were an authentic taste of Arabia that you're craving, Yemen was long the answer. An antidote to Arabian Gulf bling, this was long the peninsula's most fascinating destination.</p><p>The largest city in Yemen, Sana'a is where most visits start. The Old City is UNESCO listed, its multi-storey tower houses and ancient Souk Al Milh lending an overwhelming medieval atmosphere. Being woken pre-dawn by competing muezzins from the city's fortyish mosques is a truly remarkable, unforgettable experience.</p><p>Outside the capital, explore fortified cliff-top villages overseeing cultivated plains or hike the foothills of the Haraz Mountains. To the east, walk the shady streets of Shibam, Freya Stark's 'Manhattan of the Desert', where nine-floor mud towers stand testament to Yemeni building skills. On the coast, visit the bustling fishing ports of Al Mukalla or Al Huydaydah. Most remote is Yemen's 'Arabian Galapagos', the Socotra archipelago. Cast adrift at the mouth of the Gulf of Aden, Socotra is two hours by air from Sana'a; 37% of plant species, 90% of reptiles and an estimated 90% of invertebrates here are found nowhere else on earth.</p><p>Once characterised as <em>Arabia Felix</em> (Fortunate Arabia) by the Romans and known as the land of milk and honey by Noah's sons, these days an uncertain security profile deters all but the hardiest travellers from visiting Yemen. In 2011, Arab Spring protests led to a revolution aimed at improving economic conditions and ending corruption. Unfortunately, the aftermath of the protests has been ever-increasing violence between different rebel factions and jihadists.</p><p>When Yemen eventually recovers from this civil war, tourists will surely be drawn back to the land that the Queen of Sheba called home, and where Gilgamesh came in search of the key to eternal life. A country with such a rich history and culture, Yemen certainly deserves more than the present-day tragedy inflicted upon it.</p><p>Yemen is authentic Arabia, an antidote to Arabian Gulf bling, and the Peninsula's most fascinating destination.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
