<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Zambia" ColCode="zmb" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="zm" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Zambia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although Zambia lies in the tropics, the height of the plateau ensures that the climate is seldom unpleasantly hot, except in the valleys. There are three seasons: the cool, dry winter season from May to September; the hot, dry season in October and November; and the rainy season, which is even hotter, from December to April.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights or tropical with rainwear.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Zambia&rsquo;s leading domestic carrier is Proflight (<a href="http://www.proflight-zambia.com" target="_blank">www.proflight-zambia.com</a>), which offers scheduled flights to the main tourist hubs of Mfuwe and Livingstone. Proflight and charter carriers&nbsp;serve Chipata, Kasaba Bay, Kasama, Kitwe, Lusaka, Mongu and Ndola.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local ferries operate on all waterways. Contact local authorities for details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Zambia has three main internal train lines, from Livingstone to Lusaka, from Lusaka to the Copperbelt, and from Kapiri Mposhi to the Northern border with Tanzania. The main train station is in Dedan Kamathi Road in central Lusaka, one road east of Cairo Road.</p>
<p>There is a twice-weekly Kitwe-Lusaka-Livingstone service which leaves Kitwe in the morning and reaches Lusaka at night and Livingstone the following evening. It has no sleepers or first-class carriages. The Golden Jubilee Express runs once a week from Livingstone to Lusaka and uses refurbished carriages from South Africa.</p>
<p>Children under six years of age travel free, and children between six and 15 years pay half price.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Zambia&rsquo;s major cities and tourist destinations are connected by a growing network of tarred or gravel highways and roads, making it straightforward to get from city to city by car. However, minor roads are often in poor condition, with potholed tarmac, poorly maintained gravel or unsealed surfaces. In the rainy season, many unsealed roads become impassable.</p>l<p>There is a fairly good road network, of which around a quarter is tarred. Rural roads can often be left in poor condition.</p><p>Long-distance coaches run from Lusaka&rsquo;s intercity bus terminal to the major regional centres.</p><p>It&rsquo;s easy to hire a taxi in Lusaka, Livingstone and the other major cities by booking over the phone, either direct or via your hotel. It&rsquo;s also possible to hail a cab in the street. Fares are unmetered and should be agreed in advance.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required. UK driving licences may be used for up to 90 days.</p><p>It is an offence to use a mobile phone while driving or to drive under the influence of alcohol.</p><p>In the event of breakdown call your car hire firm. Car firm MacFarlanes (tel: +260 966 401 676; <a href="http://macfarlaneszambia.com" target="_blank">http://macfarlaneszambia.com</a>) offers roadside assistance and a 24-hour breakdown service on a private basis.</p><p>Several firms operate in main centres. The main international operator is Europcar (<a href="http://www.europcarzambia.com" target="_blank">www.europcarzambia.com</a>) which has desks at the airports and in the major cities. Specialist firms offer 4-wheel drive hire. The minimum age to legally hire a car is 18 years. Some firms can also provide chauffeur-driven cars.</p><p>There are a few places in Livingstone where you can hire a bike and some safari lodges have mountain bikes for their guests to borrow, but this is not common. Most people who are planning to tour Zambia by bike bring their own.</p><p>It is an offence to use a mobile phone while driving or to drive under the influence of alcohol.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local bus services in Lusaka and other cities are provided by private minibuses and shared taxis. They&rsquo;re basic, and can become very crowded. Taxis are not metered and fares should be agreed in advance. It is advisable to negotiate a fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Zambia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">ndola</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Zambia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">mfuwe</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Zambia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">livingstone</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">11.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Zambia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">kitwe</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no direct flights to Zambia from the UK. Indirect options include flights with Emirates (<a href="http://www.emirates.com" target="_blank">www.emirates.com</a>) via Dubai, Ethiopian Airlines (<a href="http://www.ethiopianairlines.com" target="_blank">www.ethiopianairlines.com</a>) via Addis Ababa, Kenya Airways (<a href="http://www.kenya-airways.com" target="_blank">www.kenya-airways.com</a>) via Nairobi, and South African Airways (<a href="http://www.flysaa.com" target="_blank">www.flysaa.com</a>) via Johannesburg. The quickest route from the USA is via Johannesburg.</p>
<p>There are also international airports at Mfuwe, near South Luangwa National Park, and Ndola, in the copper-mining region. Fares are usually lowest in the rainy season, December to March, excluding Christmas and New Year.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 13 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 19 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$25 for international flights and US$8 for domestic flights. This is usually included in airline ticket prices; if not, it is payable at the airport in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a>&nbsp;Dollars. Transit passengers and children under two years are exempt. An additional airport tax is about K60 (approx US$7) per person for international flights, payable in cash on departure.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Kenneth Kaunda International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 26km (16 miles) east of the city (journey time - 30 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Mfuwe Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is situated in the South Luangwa National Park, 1 hour 15 minutes' flight from Lusaka International Airport.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a ferry service to Mpulungu in northern Zambia across Lake Tanganyika from Kigoma in Tanzania which runs twice a month. It&rsquo;s provided by the MV Liemba, a historic steam ship. It is often subject to long delays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tanzania-Zambia Railways Authority (TAZARA) (tel: +255 787 099 064;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.tazarasite.com" target="_blank">www.tazarasite.com</a>) operates trains from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dar-es-salaam">Dar es Salaam</a> in Tanzania to Kapiri Mposhi in central Zambia. The train, the Mukuba Express departs Tanzania on Tuesdays and Fridays, arriving in Zambia two days later. There are first-, second- and third class berths, with a dining car on board. Tickets should be booked in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The easiest overland routes into Zambia are to and from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/zimbabwe">Zimbabwe</a>, which in turn is well connected to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-africa">South Africa</a>. It&rsquo;s also straightforward to drive to Livingstone from the Namibia&rsquo;s Caprivi Strip, northern <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/botswana">Botswana</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/malawi">Malawi</a> and southwest <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tanzania">Tanzania</a>. Border crossings are generally open 0600-1800 except for the Victoria Falls crossing which closes at 2000.</p><p>Zambia&rsquo;s land borders with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/angola">Angola</a>, the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/congo">Democratic Republic of Congo</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mozambique">Mozambique</a> are open, but border controls here can be slow. There is a risk of landmines on the Angola side of the Zambia/Angola border and on the Zambia/DRC and Zambia/Mozambique borders.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are public telephones and most calls are made through a post office.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mobile phone ownership and usage is rising all the time in Zambia and by early 2012, well over 60% of the population had a mobile. Mobile coverage can be patchy in some rural areas but is generally good around Lusaka, Livingstone and the other main towns and cities. In some areas rural frequented by tourists, such as South Luangwa National Park, mobile phone masts have been installed for the benefit of local workers and guests. </p>
<p>For visitors who would prefer to avoid roaming charges when making and receiving calls, local SIM cards are easily available. SIM cards from the main service providers, Airtel (<a href="http://www.africa.airtel.com" target="_blank">www.africa.airtel.com</a>) and MTN (<a href="http://www.mtn.com" target="_blank">www.mtn.com</a>), can be bought at mobile phone shops at the airport and in the main towns and cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafés in Lusaka, Livingstone and the other main towns and cities. These are good value but connection speeds can be slow and power cuts sometimes occur. Many hotels and safari lodges provide Wi-Fi for their guests. This is usually free but a small charge may apply.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>State-run radio and TV services dominate Zambia's broadcast media. Private radio stations offer little political reporting. The state also controls the principal daily and Sunday newspapers, <em>The Zambia Daily Mail</em> and <em>The Times of Zambia</em>. Libel and security laws can be used by authorities to intimidate journalists, especially those reporting on corruption. Defaming the president is a crime.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe or North America takes 7 to 14 days.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700, Sat 0800-1300 (closed Sunday and public holidays).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Victoria Falls</p><![CDATA[<p>Mosi-oa-Tunya, or 'the smoke that thunders', is the original, Kololo name for the Victoria Falls. This national park protects a pocket of riverbank on the Zambian side of the falls, where footpaths allow you to get close to the tumbling water. At their highest, the Victoria Falls drop 108m (345ft) from their basalt lip to the Batoka Gorge at their foot, almost twice as far as the Niagara Falls. The flow is most impressive between December and July, peaking in March and April. For a different perspective on this natural wonder, you can soar over the falls in a helicopter or microlight.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Experience Kasanka National Park’s bat migration</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This fascinating pocket of woodland is a conservation zone that&rsquo;s in recovery after a long period of intense hunting and poaching. These days, it&rsquo;s best known for antelopes, birds and bats. Every year between October and December, a staggering population (some says up to 10 millions) of fruit bats migrates into Kasanka. With the setting sun, they cover the skyline as they head out to feed, returning again at dawn.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the fast-growing city of Lusaka</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the attractions in the booming capital, Lusaka, including the Kabwata Cultural Village where you'll find carvers at work, indigenous arts and crafts for sale, and entertainment from traditional dancers. The Lusaka National Museum covers ethnography, witchcraft, history and contemporary art. Lusaka's various bustling markets are its lifeblood, while the city also boasts a good restaurant and nightlife scene.</p>]]><p><b>Get your adrenaline fix in Livingstone</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Livingstone, formerly Zambia's capital city, is now well-established as Africa's adventure sports capital. Among other activities, thrillseekers can bungee jump off the 111m (364ft) bridge linking Zambia and Zimbabwe across the Zambezi River, while below Victoria Falls in Batoka Gorge lie some of the best white water rapids to be found anywhere in the world.</p>]]><p><b>Go on a walking safari in South Luangwa National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The protected woodlands and grasslands beside the Luangwa River teem with wildlife and form one of southern Africa's best game-viewing regions. South Luangwa is Zambia's flagship national park and the undisputed home of the walking safari, a particularly exhilarating way to experience the African bush. Safaris here have an authentic, conservation-conscious feel, with excellent low-impact lodges and exceptional guides.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Victoria Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The original Kololo name for the Victoria Falls is Mosi-oa-Tunya, 'the smoke that thunders'. At their highest, the falls drop 108m (345ft) from their basalt lip into the Batoka Gorge, almost twice as far as the Niagara Falls. The flow is most impressive between December and July, peaking in March and April, when the spray can be seen from miles away.</p>]]><p><b>Meander along the mighty Zambezi River</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The great body of the Zambezi River is a particularly appealing location for a guided canoe safari, especially within Lower Zambezi National Park. You may well see elephants on the banks as you paddle along. Your guide will point out birds and keep a careful watch for hippos. The Zambezi is also a hotspot for tiger fishing.</p>]]><p><b>Revel in colonial nostalgia at Shiwa Ngandu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This extravagant and incongruous manor house, the former home of a British colonial officer, overlooks a lake and is surrounded by pristine gardens. It gives a number of fascinating insights into both the eccentricity and determination of its creator and the colonial heritage of Zambia in general. There's also an idyllic natural hot spring just down the road.</p>]]><p><b>Spy the strange shoebill at Bangweulu Swamps</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The marshy shores of Lake Bangweulu, north of Kasanka National Park in northern Zambia, are an important habitat for shoebills, a large, unusual-looking stork which catches fish by lunging with its huge bill at lightning speed. The best months to see them are May and June.</p>]]><p><b>Take it easy on Lake Kariba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relax for a week on a luxurious houseboat on the world's largest reservoir, Zambia's equivalent of the French Riviera. The Zambian side of the lake is considerably quieter than the Zimbabwean side, but both are beautiful. You can drift along the banks, explore the islands or just admire the magnificent sunsets, drink in hand.</p>]]><p><b>Watch wildlife in Kafue National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy spectacular wildlife watching in Kafue, the second largest national park in the world. Known for its beauty and scenic variety, this underexplored park is bisected by the Kafue River, which attracts hundreds of species of birds as well as herbivores and their predators. You can explore the park on game drives, guided bushwalks and riverboat trips.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$20.68 billion (2012).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Copper, cobalt, electricity, tobacco and flowers.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, transport equipment, petroleum products, fertilisers and foodstuffs.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China, Switzerland, South Africa, DR Congo and South Korea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Zambia has experienced strong economic growth in recent years but poverty remains a problem, thanks partly to high birth rates and the effects of HIV/AIDS.</p>
<p>The Zambian economy relies heavily on the country's mineral wealth, particularly copper (of which Zambia is one of the world's largest producers), and also cobalt and zinc. These account for the bulk of export earnings and provide essential raw materials for Zambia's manufacturing industry, which accounts for over one-third of national output. High global prices for copper and a steady increase in output from the copper mines, which have been privatised since the 1990s and have received foreign investment, have both contributed to a growth in prosperity.</p>
<p>Apart from raw material processing, the manufacturing sector includes vehicle assembly and oil refining as well as the production of fertilisers, textiles, construction materials and a variety of consumer products.<br />
<br />
Agriculture, particularly maize and cattle farming, produces 14% of GDP and employs 85% of the population. Zambia's hydroelectric projects have allowed it to become a net exporter of energy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Formal or semi-formal business attire is expected at business meetings. Punctuality is appreciated but it's not unusual for business appointments to run very late. English is widely used in business circles but if you know a few words of greeting in your colleague or associate's own language and make the effort to use them, this will be greatly appreciated. The exchange of business cards forms an important part of greeting new acquaintances.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1300 and 1400-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Mulungushi International Conference Centre</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 290 506 ,291 229
					Website:
					Address: ,PO Box 33200,Lusaka,]]><b>Zambia Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 252 483,253 020
					Website:http://www.zacci.org.zm/
					Address: Box 30844,Showgrounds,Great East Road,Lusaka,]]><b>Zambia Investment Centre</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 254 241
					Website:
					Address: ,PO Box 34580,Lusaka,]]><b>Ministry of Commerce, Trade and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 228 301
					Website:
					Address: Cairo Road,PO Box 31968,Kwacha Annex,Lusaka,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Zambia isn&rsquo;t particularly well-known for its cuisine, but the fare you&rsquo;ll find in luxury lodges and safari camps is generally of an equally high standard to the properties themselves, with interesting barbecued game meats and other South African influences found on many menus.</p>
<p>Towns like Livingstone and Lusaka have some good Western style restaurants and curry houses. Further afield, Zambia&rsquo;s bountiful lakes and rivers provide plentiful fresh fish both for local fisherman and restaurants across the country. The typical Zambian diet is heavy on starch and comfort foods such as stews, soups and beans.</p>
<p>Zambia&rsquo;s most popular lager is called Mosi, taken from the original name for Victoria Falls. But in rural areas, you&rsquo;re more likely to see locals drinking maize or sorghum beer, often homemade.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Freshwater fish:</strong> Bream, Nile perch and salmon from the Kafue, Luapula and Zambezi rivers.<br />
<strong>Nshima:</strong> A stiff porridge made from ground maize &ndash; a staple eaten daily in the rural areas. A thinned down version may be eaten for breakfast with sugar and butter.<br />
<strong>Ndiwo:</strong> A relish or sauce made from meat or fish boiled with green vegetables, usually served with <em>nshima.</em><br />
<strong>Ifisashi:</strong> Vegetarian stew of peanuts, tomatoes, spinach and cabbage, used to accompany <em>nshima</em>.<br />
<strong>Samp and beans:</strong> Starchy dish made from crushed maize kernels and beans.<br />
<strong>Biltong:</strong> Spiced, dried meat usually made from beef or game meat.<br />
<strong>Saut&eacute;ed insects:</strong> Grasshoppers, caterpillars, cicadas, flying ants and mopane worms are seasonal delicacies for rural Zambians.<br />
<strong>Kapenta:</strong> A small sardine from Lake Tanganyika that is salted and sundried before eating.<br />
<strong>Munkoyo:</strong> Zambians&rsquo; favourite non-alcoholic drink, made from maize meal and the roots of the Munkoyo tree.<br />
<strong>Mosi:</strong> The local beer.<br />
<strong>Chibuku:</strong> An opaque, often homemade beer made from maize or sorghum.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Some restaurants will add a service charge to your bill, if not 10% is standard</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18 years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lusaka&rsquo;s main hotels, cinemas, theatres, casinos and nightclubs host dancing, live music and floorshows, particularly at weekends. The smarter places have a dress code and an over-21s policy; some only admit over-25s. Livingstone and the Copperbelt also offer a variety of entertainments. For a more informal after-dark experience, head for a shebeen (local bar) for drinking and dancing.</p>
<p>The smaller towns offer fewer options but their shebeens and clubs can get every bit as lively as the better-known places in Lusaka. If you get the chance to see a Zambian band play live, you&rsquo;re guaranteed a memorable experience. Traditional musicians play a leading part in any cultural celebration, performing call-and-response songs with familiar themes, accompanied by drums and guitars. Nightclub gigs may feature gospel music, rumba, Jamaican-style reggae or US-style hip hop and R&amp;B.</p>
<p>Livingstone has a lively tourist-oriented entertainment scene. At or after dinner, all the larger tourist hotels lay on evening shows for their guests with traditional-style music, drumming, dancing or all three. While not wholly authentic, these can be a lot of fun. The audience is always encouraged to get up and join in. Sunset boat trips on the Upper Zambezi with drinks and snacks or perhaps a barbecue are particularly popular among travellers; again, live music often forms part of the evening&rsquo;s entertainment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lusaka&rsquo;s Great East Road, Kafue Road, Leopards Hill and suburban districts have modern shopping centres featuring bookshops, fashion and homeware stores and supermarkets. Lusaka and most other cities and towns also have open-air markets which sell fresh produce, fabric, new and second hand clothing and homewares. Lusaka&rsquo;s biggest markets are on Freedom Way,  Independence Avenue and west of Cairo Road. While shops offer goods at fixed prices, bargaining is the norm in the markets.</p>
<p>Most tourist hotels and lodges have souvenir shops. These can also be found in Lusaka, Livingstone and near national parks. They sell items designed specifically to appeal to tourists, such as safari clothing, carved wooden masks and animals, pottery and copperware, beadwork, baskets, local gemstones, handmade jewellery and bags and homewares made from batik fabric.</p>
<p>Some souvenir shops are run as local craftworkers&rsquo; cooperatives. Tribal Textiles (<a href="http://www.tribaltextiles.co.zm/">www.tribaltextiles.co.zm</a>) in Mfuwe, near South Luangwa National Park, is a particularly good example. Its batik workshop is open to the public, allowing you to watch local workers create and copy original designs inspired by traditional patterns and the natural world. The fabrics they produce are made into beautiful homewares, bags and clothing, all of which are for sale.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s inadvisable to buy items made from leather in Zambia unless they come with a guarantee that the skin is from animals that have been legitimately farmed for the purpose. Very occasionally you may see items made from ivory for sale; it&rsquo;s illegal to export more than one such object per person. It&rsquo;s also illegal to export genuine antiquities. Game trophies such as taxidermy or items made from tooth, bone, horn, shell, claw, skin, hair or feather require an export permit.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700 and Sat 0800-1300 (some stay open until 1700).</p><p>As elsewhere in the world, you should guard against petty thieves in crowded local markets by staying alert and keeping a close eye on your belongings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Zambia are mainly geared either towards business travellers or towards tourists on safari. Zambia's top business hotels, which are of international standard, are concentrated in Lusaka and the Copperbelt region. Livingstone has several high quality tourist hotels, as well as safari lodges. There are also hotels in the smaller cities and near principal road junctions. It is advisable to book in advance and to obtain confirmation in writing. All bills are subject to a statutory 10% service charge; this will usually be included in quoted room rates.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are graded according to a 5-star system. The most basic places are ungraded.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Zambia's bed and breakfasts and guesthouses are found both in urban and rural areas and tend to be smaller than hotels, with simpler facilities and lower prices. They often have a more informal, family-run atmosphere.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Zambia are mainly geared either towards business travellers or towards tourists on safari. Zambia's top business hotels, which are of international standard, are concentrated in Lusaka and the Copperbelt region. Livingstone has several high quality tourist hotels, as well as safari lodges. There are also hotels in the smaller cities and near principal road junctions. It is advisable to book in advance and to obtain confirmation in writing. All bills are subject to a statutory 10% service charge; this will usually be included in quoted room rates.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are graded according to a 5-star system. The most basic places are ungraded.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Zambia are mainly geared either towards business travellers or towards tourists on safari. Zambia's top business hotels, which are of international standard, are concentrated in Lusaka and the Copperbelt region. Livingstone has several high quality tourist hotels, as well as safari lodges. There are also hotels in the smaller cities and near principal road junctions. It is advisable to book in advance and to obtain confirmation in writing. All bills are subject to a statutory 10% service charge; this will usually be included in quoted room rates.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are graded according to a 5-star system. The most basic places are ungraded.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health care in Zambia is not free. Adequate health care cannot be assured outside main towns. It is advisable to carry basic medical supplies as they are limited in Zambia. Comprehensive health insurance is recommended and it should include emergency air evacuation coverage if you are spending time in remote parts of the country.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Malaria is present throughout Zambia. The risk is highest in densely populated areas, especially near wetlands, in the rainy season. Not all mosquitoes carry malaria but it can take just one bite of an infected insect to transmit the disease, so it&amp;rsquo;s important to follow your GP&amp;rsquo;s advice about taking anti-malarials. Avoid bites by wearing a strong mosquito repellent, covering up with full-length clothing from sunset to dawn, spraying your bedroom with insecticide and sleeping under a mosquito net.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. The filtered drinking water supplied by hotels and safari lodges is safe to drink. Bottled water is also available. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are generally safe for consumption. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;The Zambian sun is extremely strong, so it's wise to wear sunscreen and stay in the shade as much as possible, especially at midday, even if it's cloudy. Daytime temperatures in Zambia can be very high, particularly at the end of the rainy season in October and November. There's a danger of dehydration and heatstroke at this time, particularly when exposed to the full force of the sun on bushwalks or when travelling in an open-topped vehicle. To guard against this, drink plenty of water – little and often is best. If you start to feel faint or nauseous, stay in the shade and take rehydration salts. The start of the rainy season in November and December brings high humidity which can cause fatigue. Avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water; swimming pools that are well chlorinated and maintained are safe.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Youth Day :
							12 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>African Freedom Day (Anniversary of the OAU's Foundation) :
							25 May </p><p>Heroes' Day :
							02 July </p><p>Unity Day :
							03 July </p><p>Farmers' Day :
							06 August </p><p>Independence Day :
							24 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Zambia by travellers over 18 years without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 400 cigarettes or 500g of cigars or 500g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1.5L of spirits and 2.5L of wine and 2.5L of clear beer.<br />
&bull; Goods to the value of US$1,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited items include counterfeit bank notes and coins, obscene material, pirated or counterfeit goods and prison-made goods.</p>
<p>Restricted items include animals, plants and their products, medicines and drugs, minerals and precious stones, and firearms and ammunition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Zambian currency is the kwacha, K (international currency code ZMW), which is equivalent to 100 ngwee. Zambian banknotes are in denominations of K100, 50, 20, 10, 5 and 2. Coins are in denominations of K1 and 50, 10 and 5 ngwee.</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> On 1 January 2013, the Zambia government re-based the Zambian currency. The old currency code was ZMK. One new kwacha (ZMW) is equivalent to 1000 old kwacha (ZMK). The old banknotes cannot used as currency after 1 July 2014, but can be exchanged for new kwacha at the Bank of Zambia until 31 December 2015.</p>
<p>Payments within Zambia can be made in kwachas only, by law, even if the price is quoted in USD; foreign currency will not be accepted once you have cleared immigration at the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Exchange of foreign currency is carried out at authorised banks and bureaux de change.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most hotels, restaurants, travel agents and bigger shops accept credit cards. Visa is more readily accepted than MasterCard or American Express.</p><p>ATMs are available within Lusaka and some of the major towns in Zambia. Standard Chartered and Barclays Bank have ATMs which accept Visa but not MasterCard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers cheques are widely accepted, though no longer commonly used. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take travellers cheques in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars, euros or pounds sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vary from bank to bank. Most are open Mon-Fri 0830-1430 but some stay open until 1600. Some banks also open from 0815-1030 or 1200 on Saturdays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Zambia, a passport valid for six months beyond the end of your intended stay, with at least two blank pages, is required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A day tripper visa is issued to visitors entering Zambia for less than 24 hours and leaving through the same port. Certain nationals need to apply for this in advance; check with the embassy/high commission.</p>
<p>Transit visas are issued to those who require visas and who are travelling overland through Zambia. They are valid for seven days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Day tripper visa: US$20; transit or single-entry visa:&nbsp;US$50; double- or multiple-entry visa: US$80.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Zambian visas are valid for six months from the date of issue for UK passport holders, three years for US passport holders and three months for all other passport holders. Tourists can stay for up to 90 days within a year. Business visitors can stay for up to 30 days within a year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>On arrival (for nationals in the chart above) or at your nearest Zambian high commission/embassy in advance. You can also apply online for an e-Visa (<a href="http://evisa.zambiaimmigration.gov.zm" target="_blank">evisa.zambiaimmigration.gov.zm</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You should allow three to five working days for your visa to be prepared if you submit your application in person at the consulate/high commission. For postal applications, you should allow additional time for mailing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dogs and cats must be accompanied by a veterinarian health certificate issued at the point of origin and an import permit, obtained in advance from the Department of Research and Specialist Services, Mulungushi House, PO Box 50060, Lusaka, Zambia. Dogs also require a rabies vaccination certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-14.197036]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[27.996034]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>752,614 sq km (290,586 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>16,717,332 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>20 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lusaka.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Zambia is a vast, land-locked tropical plateau in southern Africa bordered by Angola to the west, the Democratic Republic of Congo to the north, Tanzania to the northeast, Malawi to the east, Mozambique to the southeast, Zimbabwe and Botswana to the south and the Caprivi Strip of Namibia to the southwest.</p>
<p>The Zambezi River, together with Lake Kariba, forms the frontier with Zimbabwe and lies at Zambia&rsquo;s lowest point in altitude. Victoria Falls, formed by the Zambezi tumbling over a cliff into the Batoka Gorge, is one of the most spectacular sights in Africa (if not the world). Lake  Kariba, which was created by the construction of the Kariba Dam in the 1950s, is the world&rsquo;s largest reservoir by volume.</p>
<p>The Zambian capital, Lusaka, lies roughly in the centre of the country, a region of thinly wooded bush. In the east and northeast, the country rises to a plateau 1,200m (3,937ft) high, covered by deciduous savannah, small trees, grassy plains or marshland.</p>
<p>In central Zambia, South Luangwa National  Park, east of Lusaka, and Kafue National Park, west of Lusaka, are magnificent expanses of riverside grassland, woodland and forest with some of the densest and most diverse populations of wild animals in Africa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Around 30% of the population is Christian (Protestant and Roman Catholic), a smaller number are Muslim and Hindu, and a small minority have traditional animist beliefs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Zambian culture, traditions and folklore remain prominent and long-standing tribal customs and crafts are practised throughout the country, particularly in the rural areas. These include rituals and ceremonies to mark rites of passage such as coming-of-age or marriage, and colourful annual festivals to commemorate revered ancestors celebrate the changing seasons. Most Zambian festivals feature traditional music, drumming and dancing.</p>
<p>Visitors to the more remote rural areas should expect to be met with curiosity. Shaking hands is the normal form of greeting. Gifts are often offered to visitors as a sign of gratitude, friendship or honour. One should never refuse a gift but accept it with both hands.</p>
<p>Same-sex sexual activity is illegal for both males and females in Zambia and social attitudes towards LGBT people are mostly negative.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with two round pins, three round pins or three square pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Edgar Lungu since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Edgar Lungu since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The original inhabitants of Zambia were nomadic San hunter-gatherers. The first people to introduce agriculture and copper mining were Bantu settlers who started arriving in the 4th century.</p>
<p>In 1855, Dr David Livingstone became the first British explorer to visit Zambia and &lsquo;discovered&rsquo; the Victoria Falls (so-named in honour of Queen Victoria) on his famous exploration of the Zambezi River. The town of Livingstone was later named after him, and would serve as the capital for a time.</p>
<p>Cecil Rhodes and the British South African Company colonised Zambia in 1889, then in 1924 the company ceded administrative control to the British Crown, whereupon it became the colony of Northern Rhodesia and serious European exploitation of Zambia&rsquo;s main natural resource, copper, began.</p>
<p>The colonial authorities ceded independence in 1964 and the country was re-named Zambia. The pre-independence elections were won by Kenneth Kaunda's United National Independence Party. Zambia soon became involved in the war in Southern Rhodesia (now Zimbabwe). Kaunda closed the southern border and gave safe haven to cadres from Joshua Nkomo's ZAPU party and its associated guerrilla army, ZIPRA.</p>
<p>Relations with the Zimbabweans improved after Zimbabwe became independent in 1980 and Kaunda's foreign policy focused elsewhere. However, a decline in global copper prices caused economic decline in Zambia throughout the 1980s and 1990s.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Kaunda became a major regional statesman. He played a significant part in the initiatives leading to independence in Namibia and South Africa and, in the 1990s, chaired both the Organisation of African Unity and the 'front-line' group of Southern African states confronting the South African apartheid regime.</p>
<p>During 1990, domestic unrest, sparked by price rises, developed into demands for a more democratic system of government. The principal opposition, the Movement for Multi-party Democracy (MMD) led by Frederick Chiluba, won a substantial majority in the ensuing 1991 election, which marked an end to single-party rule.</p>
<p>In the years since, Zambia&rsquo;s inherently peaceful democracy has prevailed despite the occasional scare. In January 2015, Edward Lungu became the latest Zambian president, after his predecessor Michael Sata died in office.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Iron and copper have been mined in Zambia for over 2,000 years.<br />
&bull; Zambia&rsquo;s is one Africa&rsquo;s most urbanized countries.<br />
&bull; In 2015, the Global Peace Index rated Zambia the most peaceful country in Africa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Zambia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(211) 423 200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ukinzambia.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(211) 423 200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thur 0800-1300 and 1400-1645; Fri 0800-1300&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>5210 Independence Avenue, PO Box 50050, 15101 Ridgeway<br/>Lusaka<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Zambia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 265 9717.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.zambiaembassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 265 9717.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1700. Visa applications Mon-Wed 0930-1230, pick-ups (winter) Mon-Thu 1500-1530, Fri 1200-1400; (summer) Mon-Thu 1600-1700, Fri 1200-1400.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2419 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[High Commission for the Republic of Zambia in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7589 6655. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.zambiahc.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7589 6655. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1700; immigration section closes at 1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Kensington<br/>2 Palace Gate<br/>London<br/>W8 5NG<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the United States in Zambia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>0211 357 000</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.zambia.usembassy.gov</p><p><b>Tel:</b>0211 357 000</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon, Wed-Thurs: 1330-1600, Fri: 0800-1100&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Eastern end of Kabulonga Road, Ibex Hill, P.O. Box 31617<br/>Lusaka<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vast lakes and wetlands, long and life-giving rivers, breathtaking African sunsets and a rich tradition of guiding all contribute to Zambia&rsquo;s immense appeal as a safari destination.</p>
<p>Its most famous landmark, Victoria Falls, which it shares with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/zimbabwe">Zimbabwe</a>, attracts nature lovers and thrill-seekers alike. Visit in March or April, when the falls are in full spate, and you&rsquo;ll be bowled over by the rainbows, the roar of the cascading water and the dense, drenching clouds of spray.</p>
<p>Livingstone, the closest urban hub to the falls and once Zambia&rsquo;s colonial capital, has a number of accommodation options, colourful markets and a busy restaurant and nightlife scene.&nbsp;The mighty Zambezi River itself is glassy-smooth above the falls and wild below. It&rsquo;s perfect for booze cruises, canoe safaris and adrenaline activities such as white-water rafting and river surfing. There are a plethora of beautiful riverside lodges dotted along its banks.</p>
<p>Beyond the falls, Zambia is not as high-profile a safari destination as Kenya, Tanzania or South Africa, but it&rsquo;s a favourite with those in the know. Packed with untamed wilderness and fascinating wildlife, minus the crowds, Zambia is the African bush at its most raw and romantic.</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s excellent safari lodges and camps will put you fully in touch with your wild surroundings. You&rsquo;ll fall asleep to the hooting of owls, the whooping of hyenas, the distant roar of lions, and the loud munching of hippos grazing nearby.</p>
<p>Almost a third of Zambia&rsquo;s landmass is given over to national parks and game reserves, but South Luangwa National Park is the cream of the crop for sheer density of big game. It&rsquo;s also the home of the legendary African walking safari.</p>
<p>Another of Zambia&rsquo;s drawcards is the people. The country is home to a staggering 72 different ethnic groups, each of whom have their own distinctive cultural traits and traditions, but all of whom are unfailingly warm and welcoming.</p><p>Vast lakes and wetlands, long and life-giving rivers, breathtaking African sunsets and a rich tradition of guiding contribute to Zambia&rsquo;s immense appeal as a safari destination. Its most famous landmark, Victoria Falls, which it shares with Zimbabwe, attracts nature lovers and thrill-seekers alike. Visit in March or April, when the falls are in full spate, and you&rsquo;ll be bowled over by the rainbows, the roar of the cascading water and the dense, drenching clouds of spray.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
