<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Zimbabwe" ColCode="zwe" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="zw" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Zimbabwe]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although located in the tropics, temperate conditions prevail all year, as the climate is moderated by altitude and the inland position of the country. The hot and dry season is from August to October, and the rainy season from November to March. The best months to visit are April to May and August to September. Night-time temperatures can fall below freezing.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Light- to mediumweights with warmer clothes for evenings and rainwear for the wet season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Zimbabwe (<a href="http://airzimbabwe.aero" target="_blank">http://airzimbabwe.aero</a>) runs domestic flights to Bulawayo, Harare and Victoria Falls, but the national airline has ceased much of the rest of its domestic operation. There are special light-aircraft services at Kariba and Victoria Falls offering sightseeing and game-viewing flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ferries run on Lake Kariba from Kariba to Binga and Mlibizi.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are trains between Bulawayo, Chiredzi, Harare, Labatse, Mutare, Plumtree, Triangle and Victoria Falls run by<em> </em>National Railways of Zimbabwe<em> </em>(<a href="http://www.nrz.co.zw" target="_blank">www.nrz.co.zw</a>). The rail system is underdeveloped and poorly maintained.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is an excellent road network, with paved roads connecting all major towns and many rural areas.  There are often fuel shortages, even in the main cities, and therefore it's wise to drive with a full tank of petrol when possible and be aware that public transport may be cancelled.</p>l<p>International Driving Permit or national licence; if not in English, it must be accompanied by a certificate of authority or translation of text. Valid for 90 days.</p><p>Speed limits are 40kph (25mph) in national parks, 120kph (75mph) on open roads and 60 to 80kph (40 to 50mph) on other roads. Police road blocks are common.</p><p>Available at airports and main hotels.</p><p>Speed limits are 40kph (25mph) in national parks, 120kph (75mph) on open roads and 60 to 80kph (40 to 50mph) on other roads. Police road blocks are common.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Harare, plans are afoot to introduce an improved public transport system. In 2015, the city bought 500 buses in the hope it can tempt commuters out of kombi (minivan) taxis and reduce congestion.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no direct flights to Zimbabwe from the UK. Indirect options include flights with British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) or South African Airways (<a href="http://www.flysaa.com" target="_blank">www.flysaa.com</a>) via Johannesburg, Ethiopian Airlines (<a href="http://www.ethiopianairlines.com" target="_blank">www.ethiopianairlines.com</a>) via Addis Ababa, and Kenya Airways (<a href="http://www.kenya-airways.com" target="_blank">www.kenya-airways.com</a>) via Nairobi. From the USA, the quickest route is via Johannesburg with South African Airways.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 13 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 18 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$30.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Bulawayo Joshua Mqabuko Nkomo Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.caaz.co.zw<p>The airport is 24km (15 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Harare International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.caaz.co.zw<p>The airport is 14km (9 miles) southeast of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Victoria Falls Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.caaz.co.zw<p>The airport is 22km (13 miles) from the town.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A train runs three times a week from Francistown, Botswana to Bulawayo. There are no trains from South Africa or Zambia to Zimbabwe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Coverage is limited to a few urban areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are Internet cafes in Harare and in Mashonaland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All broadcasters transmitting from Zimbabwe and the main newspapers are state-controlled and follow the government line. The private press has come under severe pressure. The only privately-owned daily, the <em>Daily News</em>, is subject to a publication ban. The paper and the government had waged war in the courts.<br /><strong></strong></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes up to one week.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Great Zimbabwe National Monument</p><![CDATA[<p>A holiday in Zimbabwe would be incomplete without a visit to the Great Zimbabwe National Monument, the largest complex of ruins in Africa south of the pyramids in Egypt. The Main Enclosure, or Temple, has walls over 9m (30ft) tall, 4m (14ft) thick and over 228m (250 yards) in circumference, giving approximately 485,521 cubic metres (635,000 cubic ft) of hand-trimmed mortarless stonework. The remains are what is left of a city-state that flourished between the 13th and 15th centuries, trading in gold. Lake Kyle National Park is not far away; there is a well-organised campsite close to the lake.</p>]]><br/><p>Victoria Falls</p><![CDATA[<p>Made known to the wider world by the famous British explorer Dr David Livingstone in 1855, the Victoria Falls, which form a natural border between Zimbabwe and Zambia, are one of Africa's best-known natural wonders and one of the world's most impressive waterfalls. The falls, which Livingstone named after Queen Victoria, were known to native Kololo tribes in the 18th century as Mosi-oa-Tunya, meaning 'the smoke that thunders', and the spray that they generate can be seen for miles around. The cascade is formed as the calm, 2km-wide (1.2 miles) Zambezi River spills out of a flat basalt lip and plunges into the gorge below. At their highest, the Victoria Falls drop a distance of 108m (345ft), almost twice as far as the Niagara Falls.<br /><br />As much as 546,000,000 cubic metres (713,725,490 cubic yards) per minute plummet over the edge at the height of the flood season. The 111m-high (364 ft) Victoria Falls Bridge, commissioned by British statesman Cecil Rhodes in 1900 as a railway crossing, is now a popular place for bungee jumping, and can be crossed by foot for excellent views of the falls and the winding blue-green waters of the Zambezi River. White-water rafting through the Zambezi Gorge is at its wildest between July and August. Canoeing and kayaking can be practised on the more subdued river stretches above the falls. It is also possible to see an aerial view of the falls from a Micro-light or fixed-wing plane. The area around the falls is a prime game-viewing location.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Enjoy the natural wonders of Nyanga National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Situated in the stunning mountain range that covers the eastern part of Zimbabwe, Nyanga National Park is an area of high grasslands, evergreen forests, waterfalls, cliffs and lovely lakeside cottages. Trout fishing is very popular and the trout hatchery is well worth a visit. For the twitchers, there is lots of birdlife to be seen on a hike.</p>]]><p><b>Experience Zambezi National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Just a few kilometres from the town of Victoria Falls is the Zambezi National Park, a scenic reserve that remains surprisingly remote and is having a considerable resurgence after decades of poaching and neglect. The riverine sections are particularly picturesque and the wildlife more abundant.  A good spot for a canoeing safari.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Bulawayo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pretty Bulawayo, Zimbabwe's second city, is rich in historical associations and is the home of the National Museum. Nearby are the ancient Khami ruins, while to the south is the Rhodes Matopos National Park, notable for its exotic formations of huge granite boulders. Dams with excellent fishing, caves with rock paintings and Cecil Rhodes' grave also add to the town's popularity with tourists.</p>]]><p><b>Gawk at Great Zimbabwe National Monument</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A holiday in Zimbabwe would be incomplete without a visit to the Great Zimbabwe National Monument, the largest complex of ruins in Africa south of the Egyptian pyramids. These miraculous and expansive stone remains are what is left of a powerful city-state that flourished between the 13th and 15th centuries, trading in gold.</p>]]><p><b>Go on a canoeing safari</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Canoeing and boat safaris are popular alternatives to the traditional game drive in Zimbabwe. At Lake Kariba, boats can be hired for a day, week or longer. Canoeing safaris ranging from three to 10 days are especially popular between April and November along the Zambezi River past the Mana Pools flood plains.</p>]]><p><b>Hang out in Harare</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Zimbabwe's capital Harare is the country's commercial and industrial centre and also the usual starting point for most visits. It's a clean and sophisticated city, characterised by flowering trees, colourful parks and contemporary architecture. Local sights also include various museums, art galleries and craft markets. Due to its pleasant climate, Harare is known as the 'Sunshine City'.</p>]]><p><b>Hike the Eastern Highlands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The string of mountains and the lush countryside in Zimbabwe's Eastern Highlands are particularly sought after by walkers and trekkers. Climbing Zimbabwe's highest mountain, Mount Nyangani, takes around one hour 30 minutes. The World's View offers incredible vistas across northern Zimbabwe. From here, a steep footpath leads to the road to Nyanga village with its English gardens, village common and church.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back on Lake Kariba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Situated in the northwest of the country on the Zambian border, Lake Kariba is the world's largest manmade dam. Both the game and the stellar sunsets can be viewed from the comfort of various waterfront lodges, or from well-appointed cruise vessels and self-contained houseboats.</p>]]><p><b>Map Zimbabwe’s history at Matobo National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located close to Bulawayo, Zimbabwe's second biggest city, Matobo National Park is noted for its spectacular granite rock formations and its wealth of ancient rock paintings. Cecil Rhodes' tomb can be visited at Malindidzimu (View of the World). The Nswatugi and Pomongwe caves are also worth visiting.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the Victoria Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>'Discovered' by the famous British explorer Dr David Livingstone, Victoria Falls, which form part of the border between Zimbabwe and Zambia, are one of Africa's best-known natural wonders and one of the world's most impressive waterfalls. The town of the same name is worth a visit too, and is a good place to book one of the many activities available in and around the falls.</p>]]><p><b>See the natural beauty of Mana Pools National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mana Pools National Park is one of Zimbabwe's most beautiful national parks, occupying 2,196 sq km (848 sq miles) of forest along the banks of the Zambezi River. Four of the 'Big Five' are present. Game-viewing on foot is allowed. The birdlife along the river is prolific. The park is also a great spot for fishing.</p>]]><p><b>Spot the Big Five in Hwange National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hwange is one of Zimbabwe's largest parks, covering 14,620 sq km (5,644 sq miles) of pristine bushveld. It's also one of the most diverse, with an astonishing array of wildlife. It's considered one of the last of the great elephant sanctuaries in Africa, with over 40,000 inside the park, and was the home of the late, great Cecil the Lion.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$3.2 billion (2005).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Cotton, tobacco, gold, ferroalloys, textiles and clothing.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and transport equipment, other machines, chemicals and fuels.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China (PR), Germany and South Africa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Zimbabwe's economy is now in freefall. Half the workforce is unemployed; the economy contracted by 6.5% in 2005 and by November 2006, hyper-inflation had reached 1,100%. There are four main reasons: a catastrophic decline in the value of the Zimbabwean Dollar; the chaos in the vital agricultural and agro-industrial sectors caused by government policies on land redistribution; the drought that is afflicting the entire region; and the growing impact of the very high rates of HIV/AIDS infection on the workforce.<br /><br />Approximately two-thirds of the population face food shortages. The situation is now extremely serious and the immediate prospects of recovery are virtually zero without radical political change. Under other circumstances, Zimbabwe would have one of the most diverse and best-performing economies on the African continent. <br /><br />The agricultural base relies on tobacco and other cash crops, including sugar, coffee, cotton and maize, as the main export earners. Livestock rearing is also important. The mining industry produces gold and nickel, mainly for export, as well as smaller quantities of a host of other minerals including silver, emeralds, lithium, tin, iron ore, manganese, cobalt, coal, diamonds and a number of rare metals. Large coal deposits and hydroelectric plants supply the country's power stations. The manufacturing industry was well developed by regional standards: food processing, metals, chemicals and textiles were the main components. In the service sector, tourism grew rapidly in the period after independence, but the industry has now all but vanished. <br /><br />Although Zimbabwe is better developed than many of its neighbours (especially as regards basic infrastructure such as roads, telecommunications, water and electricity), much of this benefit has been squandered or allowed to disintegrate through neglect. <br /><br />Zimbabwe's economy remains heavily dependent on South Africa. The South Africans have been more sympathetic to the Zimbabwean government than most of the international community; all the major donors in Europe and North America have now suspended grants and loans to Zimbabwe, further depressing economic prospects. The IMF has expelled Zimbabwe, as has the Commonwealth (formerly a valuable source of aid).<br /><br />Although Zimbabwe is a member of the Southern African Development Community and has signed up to the Common Market for Eastern and Southern Africa, these are of marginal assistance in present circumstances. Zimbabwe's once thriving trade patterns have been all but wrecked as the country has become isolated internationally. <br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normal courtesies should be observed and men should wear a suit and tie. The atmosphere will generally be less formal than in many European countries.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Zimbabwe National Chambers of Commerce (ZNCC)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (4) 749 335
					Website:http://www.zncc.co.zw
					Address: 42 Harare Street,PO. Box 1934,ZNCC Business House,Harare,]]><b>Ministry of Industry &amp; International Trade</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (4) 702 731
					Website:
					Address: Causeway,Private Bag 7708,13th Floor,Mukwati Building,Fourth Street,Harare,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>British colonisation certainly left its mark on Zimbabwe&rsquo;s food culture, as is clearly shown by the excellent high teas that you&rsquo;ll find at many hotels and safari camps.</p>
<p>Meat in Zimbabwe is very good, and interesting game meats such as warthog and crocodile are readily available in most towns and tourist areas. In the major urban areas a variety of international restaurants are also available, while the local diet includes tasty peanut-based stews, wild mushroom soup and starchy staples.</p>
<p>Zimbabwean markets generally have sumptuous fruit, especially papaya, and good locally-grown vegetables. Beer is never far away, whether it&rsquo;s European-style lager or the opaque maize beer that is a favourite with many locals.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Sadza:</strong> A stiff maize meal porridge eaten with meat or stew.<br />
<strong>Nhedzi:</strong> A rich wild mushroom soup.<br />
<strong>Game meat:</strong> Including ostrich, warthog and crocodile tail.<br />
<strong>Whawha:</strong> Traditional maize beer.<br />
<strong>Bota:</strong> Porridge flavoured with peanut butter, milk, butter or jam and traditionally eaten for breakfast.<br />
<strong>Dovi:</strong> Traditional peanut butter stew with meat and/or vegetables.<br />
<strong>Mapopo candy:</strong> Papaya cooked in and dusted with sugar.<br />
<strong>Mopane worms:</strong> A large insect usually dried or fried as a protein-rich snack, or sometimes added to stews.<br />
<strong>Mupotohayi:</strong> Traditional homemade cornbread.<br />
<strong>Biltong:</strong> Seasoned and dried meat usually made from beef or game.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A 10 to 15% tip is usual.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rather limited outside the cities with emphasis on eating and discos, but larger cities have nightclubs, cinemas and repertory theatres. The three main tourist areas have casinos.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A sales tax of 10 to 22% is added to all purchases, the higher rate being on luxury items, except those which are to be exported. Special purchases are copper, wooden and soapstone carvings, gameskin and leather products, pottery and basketwork.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700 and Sat 0800-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are hotels and lodges (which are similar to guest houses and provide bed and breakfast). A list of registered hotels is available from the Zimbabwe Tourism Authority (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>). Non-residents must pay hotel bills in foreign currency (usually US Dollars) or by credit card. Local currency is not acceptable, even on presentation of exchange certificates.<br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> All hotels are graded on a 5-star system, with those classified 1-star or above being registered with the Zimbabwe Tourism Authority.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are hotels and lodges (which are similar to guest houses and provide bed and breakfast). A list of registered hotels is available from the Zimbabwe Tourism Authority (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>). Non-residents must pay hotel bills in foreign currency (usually US Dollars) or by credit card. Local currency is not acceptable, even on presentation of exchange certificates.<br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> All hotels are graded on a 5-star system, with those classified 1-star or above being registered with the Zimbabwe Tourism Authority.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are hotels and lodges (which are similar to guest houses and provide bed and breakfast). A list of registered hotels is available from the Zimbabwe Tourism Authority (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>). Non-residents must pay hotel bills in foreign currency (usually US Dollars) or by credit card. Local currency is not acceptable, even on presentation of exchange certificates.<br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> All hotels are graded on a 5-star system, with those classified 1-star or above being registered with the Zimbabwe Tourism Authority.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical facilities are good in the major towns and there are well-equipped clinics in most outlying areas, although medical costs can be high. There may be drugs shortages in public hospitals. Health insurance is essential; adequate medical provision is often only provided privately, especially in urban areas. Private hospitals may require health insurance or a cash payment before admission.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being a potential health risk. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water; swimming pools which are well chlorinated and maintained are safe. HIV/AIDS is a high risk throughout the country and precautions should be taken. Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Independence Day :
							18 April </p><p>Workers' Day :
							01 May </p><p>Heroes' Day :
							13 August </p><p>Armed Forces Day :
							14 August </p><p>Unity Day :
							22 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Zimbabwe by travellers aged 18 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 5L of alcoholic drinks (of which up to 2L may be spirits).<br />
&bull; Goods up to the value of US$200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited items include pornographic or obscene literature, flick knives, lockable knives, skin lightening creams containing hydroquinone and mercury, counterfeit money, prison-made goods, alcoholic drinks containing noxious chemicals, and anything deemed to threaten the morals of Zimbabweans.</p>
<p>Restricted items include drugs, firearms and ammunition, wildlife and wildlife products, agricultural produce, plants and plant products, soil, cultural relics and monuments, and local and foreign currency.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All banned and restricted imports and also banned or restricted from being exported.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Zimbabwean Dollar was abandoned early 2009.<br /><br />Zimbabwe Dollar (ZWD; symbol Z$) = 100 cents. Notes were in denominations of Z$200,000, 100,000, 50,000, 10,000, 5,000, 1,000, 500, 100, 50, 20, 10, 5 and 2. Coins are in denominations of Z$5, 2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5 and 1 cents. <br /><br />The country has adopted a multi-currency scheme; the US Dollar and South African Rand can be used for domestic transactions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major foreign currencies can be exchanged at bureaux de change, banks and major hotels at the official exchange rate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club and Visa are widely accepted, whilst MasterCard has more limited use. Some ATMs accept credit cards.</p><p>Some ATMs accept credit cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Banks and major hotels will exchange these. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars or Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Tues and Thurs-Fri 0800-1500, Wed 0800-1300 and Sat 0800-1130.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for at least six months beyond the date of departure is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above. Two blank pages are needed.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If in transit, you do not require a visa provided you have a confirmed onward booking, remain in the transit lounge, and depart within six hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: US$30; double-entry visa: US$45; multiple-entry visa: US$55.</p>
<p>Single-entry visa in advance from the embassy: &pound;40.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas are usually valid for up to 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy), online (<a href="http://www.evisa.gov.zw">www.evisa.gov.zw</a>) or on arrival (if eligible). For multiple-entry visas, travellers must apply in person on arrival in Zimbabwe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow 10 days for visa processing if applying via the embassy. Online applications usually take two days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-19.000011]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[29.868970]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>390,757 sq km (150,872 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>15,966,810 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>36.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Harare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Zimbabwe is bordered by Zambia to the northwest, Mozambique to the north and east, South Africa to the south and Botswana to the southwest. The central zone of hills gives rise to many rivers, which drain into the manmade Lake Kariba to the northwest, the marshes of Botswana to the west or into the Zambezi River to the northeast. The <em>highveld</em> landscape is dotted with <em>kopjes</em> (massive granite outcrops). Along the eastern border for some 350km (220 miles) is a high mountainous region of great scenic beauty, rising to 2,592m (8,504ft) at Mount Inyangani, the country's highest point.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Christianity, with traditional beliefs in rural areas, and some Hindu, Muslim and Jewish minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Urban culture in Zimbabwe is greatly influenced by Western culture and education but, in rural areas, traditional values and crafts continue. Shaking hands is the customary form of greeting. European courtesies and codes of practice should be observed when visiting someone's home. Return invitations are appreciated. Giving a token of appreciation is optional. It is an offence to make derogatory or insulting comments about President Mugabe. Visitors should be aware that an open hand is the political symbol of the main opposition political party, the Movement for Democratic Change, and that a friendly wave may therefore be interpreted as a provocative political gesture. Casual wear is suitable for daytime and men are only expected to wear suits and ties for business meetings. Smart restaurants or hotel bars require male guests to wear a jacket and tie. Smoking is common, although it is prohibited on public transport and in some public buildings. There are laws against indecency which equates to homosexual activity being illegal.<br /><br /><strong>Photography: </strong>The local authorities are very sensitive about taking pictures of governmental buildings, military installations and embassies. A permit can be granted by the government office.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. South African-style plugs (three round pins) and British-style plugs (three square pins) are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Emmerson Mnangagwa since November 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Present-day Zimbabwe was the site of a large and complex African civilisation in the 13th and 14th centuries. It was populated by descendants of the Bantu tribes, who had migrated from the north around the 10th century. Evidence of their mainly pastoral lifestyle may still be seen in the ruins of Great Zimbabwe, near the town of Masvingo.</p>
<p>The first contact with Europeans was with the Portuguese at the end of the 15th century. Relations between the two were fairly stable until the 1830s, when the region was thrown into upheaval by the northward migration of the Ndebele people from South Africa.</p>
<p>At this point, a new aggressive breed of colonists arrived in the form of British mining interests led by Cecil Rhodes's British South Africa Company (BSAC). The BSAC took control of the country &ndash; which they called &lsquo;Southern Rhodesia' &ndash; until 1923, when it became, nominally, a British colony.</p>
<p>Between 1953 and 1963, Southern Rhodesia formed part of the Central African Federation with neighbouring Northern Rhodesia (now Zambia) and Nyasaland (now Malawi). In 1965, to resist decolonisation, the settlers &ndash; with South African support &ndash; issued a Unilateral Declaration of Independence (UDI).</p>
<p>This triggered a bitter civil war between the white minority government and fighters for African independence, ending only in 1980, with the granting of independence and the holding of a general election under British auspices, which was won decisively by Robert Mugabe's ZANU party.</p>
<p>Modern Zimbabwe has seen its fair share of suffering and instability. The economy all but collapsed in the wake of the forced and often violent removal of farmers during a violent land redistribution programme.</p>
<p>Still today, there is widespread famine, which has been cynically manipulated by the government so that opposition strongholds suffer the most. The government lacks the resources or machinery to deal with the ravages of the AIDS pandemic, which affects roughly a quarter of the population.</p>
<p>All of the above has provided fodder for increasing international scorn towards the aging and dictatorial President Mugabe, who was previously considered a great liberation hero.</p>
<p>A historic power-sharing deal signed in 2008 between President Mugabe and Movement for Democratic Change (MDC) leader Morgan Tsvangirai put an end to pre-election violence and pledged to improve the country&rsquo;s economy and the lives of Zimbabweans. It has since ushered in a new spell of peace and relative stability that has seen tourists slowly coming back to Zimbabwe.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; In 2008, Zimbabwe recorded a monthly inflation rate rise of roughly 96.6 billion %.<br />
&bull; Robert Mugabe is the world&rsquo;s oldest living head of state. He is 91.<br />
&bull; Contrastingly, Zimbabwe&rsquo;s life expectancy is around 41 years old, almost the lowest in the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Zimbabwe in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 332 7100.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.zimbabwe-embassy.us</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 332 7100.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1608 New Hampshire Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20009<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Zimbabwe in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7836 7755.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.zimbabweembassy-uk.com</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7836 7755.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700; 0900-1230 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>429 Strand<br/>Zimbabwe House<br/>London<br/>WC2R 0JR<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Zimbabwe]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+26 34858 55200 </p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-embassy-harare</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+26 34858 55200 </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thur: 0800-1630&lt;br /&gt;Friday: 0800-1300&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Mount Pleasant<br/>3 Norfolk Road<br/>Harare<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>After a difficult decade or so, stability is returning to Zimbabwe and pioneering tourists are gradually trickling back to the country. They are richly rewarded for their endeavours: with its abundance of natural wonders, welcoming locals, fascinating heritage and good climate, Zimbabwe is one of the most remarkable countries in Africa.<br />
<br />
The jewel in its glistening crown is Victoria Falls. Straddling the border between Zimbabwe and neighbouring Zambia, this waterfall is officially the largest on the planet and hearing the roar of all that cascading water makes for an unforgettable experience.<br />
<br />
As well as awe-inspiring natural spectacles, Zimbabwe offers some of the best wildlife in southern Africa. From the forested mountains of the Eastern Highlands to the sun-washed grasslands of Hwange National Park, the country is teeming with flora and fauna, including the Big 5 (elephant, rhino, leopard, buffalo and lion).</p>
<p>Roughly 11% of Zimbabwe's land has been set aside for parks and wildlife estates, but it can do big cities too. The two most populous are Harare and Bulawayo, which serve up an impressive selection of cultural attractions, hip bars and fine dining restaurants. Between these two urban hubs lie the astonishing late Iron Age stone ruins at Great Zimbabwe, which shoot down theories that sub-Saharan Africa had no great civilizations.<br />
<br />
It&rsquo;s not all smooth sailing, though. Whilst Zimbabwe&rsquo;s fragile economy is slowly improving, there is still widespread poverty and the government lacks the resources to deal with the ravages of the HIV pandemic, which affects an estimated one in four people here. Corruption is rife too, and roadblocks manned by officials looking for any excuse to fleece you can hinder cross-country travel.<br />
<br />
But for the most part Zimbabwe remains a peaceful place full of peaceful people, who desperately need tourism to help build a better future for this incredible corner of Africa.</p><p>After a difficult decade or so, stability is returning to Zimbabwe and pioneering tourists are gradually trickling back to the country. They are richly rewarded for their endeavours: with its abundance of natural wonders, welcoming locals, fascinating heritage and good climate, Zimbabwe is one of the most remarkable countries in Africa.<br />
<br />
The jewel in its glistening crown is Victoria Falls. Straddling the border between Zimbabwe and neighbouring Zambia, this waterfall is officially the largest on the planet and hearing the roar of all that cascading water makes for an unforgettable experience.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
