<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Adelaide" ColCode="adl" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCode="" TimaticCode="" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[
      London
    ]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="SpecialEvents"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[
        Special Events
      ]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CitySpecialEventsSection" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Text
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Royal Adelaide Show</b></p><p>From: 2018-08-31 00:00:00</p><p>To: 2018-09-10 00:00:00</p><p>September.</p><p>Website:http://www.theshow.com.au</p><p>Venue(s): Adelaide Showground.</p><p>&lt;p&gt;First held in 1840, the Royal Adelaide Show is staged by the Royal Agricultural &amp;amp; Horticultural Society of South Australia. Having started as a simple show of local produce such as wheat and barley, it has grown to become one of the biggest community events in South Australia. It maintains strong connections to its roots, with livestock exhibitions, growing competitions and traditional displays, but the event now also includes fairground rides and children's entertainment. For adults, there is the popular 'Wine Tunnel&amp;rsquo;, a spot offering visitors the chance to try a selection of some of Australia's best plonks. Another popular aspect of the show is the showbags, which are filled with gifts, food items and souvenirs of the event.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Adelaide Fringe Festival</b></p><p>From: 2019-02-15 00:00:00</p><p>To: 2019-03-17 00:00:00</p><p/><p>Website:http://www.adelaidefringe.com.au</p><p>Venue(s): Multiple locations around Adelaide.</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Australia&amp;rsquo;s largest arts event takes over the entire city of Adelaide for close to a month each year, when around 800 events take place in a wide assortment of different venues. Cabaret, dance, comedy, music, theatre, film, puppetry and visual arts all feature in the schedule.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Clipsal 500</b></p><p>From: 2019-03-01 00:00:00</p><p>To: 2019-03-03 00:00:00</p><p>March.</p><p>Website:https://www.adelaide500.com.au/</p><p>Venue(s): Victoria Park.</p><p>&lt;p&gt;One of the rounds of the AVESCO V8 Supercar Championship Series, the Clipsal 500 Adelaide is a hugely popular event in Australia that attracts crowds in excess of 250,000. It's an exciting event that sees the Victoria Park Racecourse filled with the sights, sounds and smells of these powerful cars. Visitors can also enjoy a number of other events such as the Clipsal 500 Adelaide Harley Parade, special dinners, autograph sessions and helicopter rides.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Tasting Australia</b></p><p>From: 2019-04-01 00:00:00</p><p>To: 2019-04-30 00:00:00</p><p/><p>Website:http://www.tastingaustralia.com.au</p><p>Venue(s): Various locations throughout Adelaide.</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Held every year in Adelaide, this popular event provides a showcase for the world's top culinary talents. The event not only celebrates the very best of the nation's food, but also covers wine, beer, gastronomic discussion, hospitality, travel and lifestyle issues. First held in 1997, each fair has a particular theme, with past events billed around 'Hot and Happening&amp;rsquo;, 'Taste the Magic' and 'The Elements: earth, air, fire and water'. The festival is an opportunity for the public to enjoy the best that South Australia and the nation at large has to offer in produce, food products, wines and beers, hospitality and tourism.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>WOMADelaide</b></p><p>From: 2018-05-08 00:00:00</p><p>To: 2018-05-11 00:00:00</p><p>March.</p><p>Website:http://www.womadelaide.com.au</p><p>Venue(s): Botanic Park</p><p>&lt;p&gt;The three-day WOMADelaide music festival brings together artists from all over the globe. The emphasis is very much on traditional music and performances of various cultures, although some more popular acts also feature. The beautiful setting of Botanic Park has been WOMADelaide's home since 1992 and the event village includes two concert stages, smaller performance and workshop venues, food stalls, record store and children's play areas.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Adelaide International Guitar Festival</b></p><p>From: 2018-08-09 00:00:00</p><p>To: 2018-08-12 00:00:00</p><p/><p>Website:http://www.adelaideguitarfestival.com.au</p><p>Venue(s): Adelaide Festival Centre</p><p>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no hiding what this festival is all about - the clue is in its name. Centred on the almighty six-stringed axe, this international gathering of guitar lovers includes everything from performances, workshops and talks to dances, displays and master classes.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Adelaide Festival</b></p><p>From: 2019-03-01 00:00:00</p><p>To: 2019-03-17 00:00:00</p><p/><p>Website:http://www.adelaidefestival.com.au</p><p>Venue(s): Multiple locations around Adelaide.</p><p>&lt;p&gt;If there was ever a reason behind Adelaide gaining the tagline of Australia&amp;rsquo;s premier festival city, Adelaide Festival would be it. This internationally renowned, three-week extravaganza of arts includes everything from theatre, music and dance to film, visual art and literary events. Bold and inspiring, the festival isn&amp;rsquo;t just an all-inclusive cultural affair &amp;ndash; good vibes reverberate around the city when it&amp;rsquo;s on.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Tour Down Under</b></p><p>From: 2019-01-10 00:00:00</p><p>To: 2019-01-20 00:00:00</p><p/><p>Website:http://www.tourdownunder.com.au</p><p>Venue(s): Adelaide and regional South Australia.</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Attracting some of the world&amp;rsquo;s best cyclists, the Tour Down Under is a chance for riders to race in and around Adelaide. The tour takes place across seven days, and is relatively flat, meaning fans stick around to see the exciting sprint finishes, which regularly occur en masse. Keen bike lovers can also take part themselves, with four routes to complete during the week.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Barossa Vintage Festival</b></p><p>From: 2019-04-24 00:00:00</p><p>To: 2019-04-28 00:00:00</p><p/><p>Website:http://www.barossavintagefestival.com.au</p><p>Venue(s): Various locations across the Barossa Valley.</p><p>&lt;p&gt;The Vintage Festival is a biennial event that runs for a full week and encompasses all aspects of the Barossa community - particularly its fine wines. The region's many wineries are joined by various local businesses, civic groups, churches and individuals who work together to stage a great weeklong programme of events, which begins on Easter Saturday. Highlights of this popular celebration include a parade, a vintage car rally, craft and trade stalls and numerous food and drink vendors. Events and attractions are hosted at various venues and destinations around Barossa and thousands of visitors come to enjoy a drop of vintage wine, watch the entertainment, and relax with friends and family over a picnic.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Excursions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Excursions]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Excursions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Text
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Clare Valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gourmet food lovers can find a smorgasbord of treats in the rich green dips of Clare Valley, just a 2 hour drive from Adelaide. With everything from olive oil and free-range chicken to carob and fresh pasta either made or produced in these pastures, large Eat Local signs in shops and restaurant point the way for the perfect picnic. Work up an appetite by completing the region&rsquo;s walking trails or cycle routes and finish any excursion with a glass or two of the local plonk in a countryside pub.</p>]]><p><b>Adelaide Hills</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Just 40 minutes by car from Adelaide city centre, these hills are filled with historic villages, orchards and vineyards. Lose track of time by winding down its roads or exploring the local wildlife parks. With renowned farmer markets and the German-inspired Hahndorf town to discover and enjoy, the Adelaide Hills can sometime feel like they&rsquo;re a world away from modern Australia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Culture"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[
        Culture
      ]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Introduction" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Introduction
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[If you are interested in sampling culture within the city, there is a wealth of things on offer.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Shopping"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[
        Shopping
      ]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Introduction
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With its pedestrianised malls, arcades, food courts and markets, Adelaide offers a smorgasbord for the retail therapy-seeker to gorge on while exploring what Adelaide has to offer.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/oceania/australia/south-australia/">South Australia</a> produces 80% of the world&rsquo;s opal, with authentic Coober Pedy, Mintabie and Andamooka opal being of supreme quality. At the family-run Opal Diamond Factory on 32-34 King William Street, you can watch opal be cut, polished and designed into custom-made jewellery.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
          Shopping Areas:<p>Recently redeveloped Rundle Mall has been sewn with rows of Chinese elms, new seating and contemporary paving, and features over 1,000 retailers which includes the 4-storey high addition of H&amp;M. Norwood Parade and Burnside are districts where Adelaide&rsquo;s &lsquo;well-heeled&rsquo; shoppers clip around. They offer international labels and bespoke giftware, as well as gourmet foods stores. Hunt through the outlet stores at Harbor Town for cut-price designer labels.</p>
          Markets:<p>The multicultural lanes at Adelaide Central Market overflow with South Australian produce and international delicacies. Take a guided walk before filling your bags with fresh fruits, gourmet cheeses, freshly-ground coffees, olives, pickles, smallgoods (small meat products), charcuterie meats and fish.</p>
<p>The Sunday morning Adelaide Farmers&rsquo; Market at Adelaide Showground features gourmet produce often plucked from the ground that very morning. Look out for quandong preserves and purple cauliflowers. You can also watch live cooking demonstrations from acclaimed Adelaide hotel chefs.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
          Shopping Centres:<p>Adelaide&rsquo;s main department stores are Myer, David Jones and Harris Scarfe. Adelaide Arcade and the Regent Arcade in Rundle Mall are ornate gallery-style thoroughfares offering unique Australian designs in specialised boutiques. Find Akubra hats and vintage rag dolls and teddy bears here.</p>
          Opening Hours:<p>Central Adelaide's usual shopping hours are Monday to Thursday 0900-1700, though some retailers open until 1900. Friday is late-night shopping until 2100. Saturday opening hours are 0900-1700 and Sunday 1100-1700. Late night shopping at other suburbs (such as at Westfield West Lakes) is on Thursday until 2100. Hours are likely to vary on public holidays like Anzac Day (25 April) and Australia Day (26 January).</p>
          Souvenirs:<p>For fluffy Australian animals, T-shirts, tea towels and coasters, visit Fancy That Gift in the Myer Centre at Rundle Mall. Alternatively, find hand-crafted gifts at Urban Cow Studio on Vaughan Place, or unique, one-off designs in glass, ceramic and wood at Jam Factory on Morphett Street.</p>
          Tax:]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Nightlife"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[
        Nightlife
      ]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Introduction
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
										]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Venues
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b/></p><b>Telephone:</b><![CDATA[+61 8 8216 8600.]]><br/><b>Website:</b><![CDATA[http://www.adelaidefestivalcentre.com.au]]><br/><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/>King William Street<br/>5000</p><![CDATA[<p>Adelaide&rsquo;s iconic performing arts venue brags a prime position, being perched alongside the River Torrens, adjacent to Central Station and facing Adelaide Oval. The catalyst for the city&rsquo;s ever-blossoming festival scene, the Festival Centre includes multiple performance venues, ranging from the intimate to the resplendent. Its versatility sees it host anything from visual art exhibitions to theatre, musicals, opera and comedy. Being one of Australia&rsquo;s artistic treasures, the Festival Centre is host to major international touring performances.</p>]]><p><b/></p><b>Telephone:</b><![CDATA[+61 8 8212 9099.]]><br/><b>Website:</b><![CDATA[https://theapothecary1878.com.au/]]><br/><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/>118 Hindley Street<br/>5000</p><![CDATA[<p>If ever there was a medicinal bar, this is it. Located in the West End inside an elegant Heritage-listed building, this posh establishment houses bottled drinks and old chemist&rsquo;s relics in restored pharmacy chests. The cosy setting seems like it&rsquo;s been plucked straight out of a time-warped French village.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Sip fine award-winning wines (a list of 1,200) and dine on gourmet cuisine in their rustic restaurant, before browsing your way through the glass cabinets containing old tincture bottles and amusing medicinal remedies. The Apothecary 1878 is the intelligent choice for that very special occasion or to ask very important question.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]><p><b/></p><b>Telephone:</b><![CDATA[+61 8 8231 3939.]]><br/><b>Website:</b><![CDATA[http://www.casablabla.com]]><br/><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/>12 Leigh Street<br/>5000</p><![CDATA[<p>One of the city&rsquo;s most multicultural venues, this tapas bar and lounge on trend-setting Leigh Street is the hottest spot in town. It features DJs, live samba, soca, flamenco and Turkish belly dancers as well as African drummers. The tropical fish in the tank almost seem to join in with the grooves.</p>
<p>Kick back in their cushioned courtyard and enjoy a cheeky orange margarita on summer evenings, or slip inside the warmly-lit bar and surround yourself with exotic artworks.</p>]]><p><b/></p><b>Telephone:</b><![CDATA[+61 8 8232 2533.]]><br/><b>Website:</b><br/><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/>270 Rundle Street<br/>5000</p><![CDATA[<p>For chic, 1950s d&eacute;cor, cosy booths, funky upholstered chairs, and a lot of blue light, head to this ex-underground cigar lounge in the East End. Order their signature blue-hued lemonade cocktail, Blue Smoke. Or, if you have the confidence to look the bartender straight in the face, order a Laced Nikkers, before mingling with those who have mastered the art of looking cool.</p>]]><p><b/></p><b>Telephone:</b><![CDATA[+61 8 8231 5500.]]><br/><b>Website:</b><![CDATA[http://graceemilyhotel.com.au/]]><br/><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/>232 Waymouth Street<br/>5000</p><![CDATA[<p>One of Adelaide&rsquo;s most vibrant live music venues, the Grace Emily Hotel is a pub that bends backwards to accommodate performers from all musical inclinations. A glance at its ever-changing events schedule will reveal indie, blues, folk, acoustic, rock and a cappella shows delivered by successful local and interstate bands.</p>
<p>Despite being away from the nightlife hotspots, and proud of being poker-machine free, the Grace Emily is an institution in Adelaide&rsquo;s live music scene. It&rsquo;s also an active venue during Adelaide&rsquo;s annual arts festivals.</p>]]><p><b/></p><b>Telephone:</b><![CDATA[+61 8 8212 8884.]]><br/><b>Website:</b><![CDATA[http://www.labohemebar.com.au]]><br/><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/>36 Grote Street<br/>5000</p><![CDATA[<p>In this pint-sized, Parisian-style lounge-cum-performance art venue, cocktails and cabaret court each other. Enjoy comedy improvisations, live cabaret shows and jazz quartets that appear regularly on La Boh&egrave;me's intimate stage, as well as stimulating cultural poetry evenings. Order one of their designer cocktails, or have the bartender whip up a made-to-order blend to allow your inner poet to flow.</p>]]><p><b/></p><b>Telephone:</b><![CDATA[+61 8 8231 3236]]><br/><b>Website:</b><![CDATA[http://blackbullhotel.com.au]]><br/><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/>58 Hindley Street<br/>5000</p><![CDATA[<p>Adelaide&rsquo;s first permanent hotel, this 19th century-era building is the place to go for all kinds of good fun. During the week they serve highly praised burgers and steaks in their pub, and offer deliciously wood-fired pizzas in their huge beer garden out back. On Friday and Saturday nights the mood goes from laid-back to energetic when the hotel&rsquo;s popular nightclub opens upstairs. If live DJs and great food don&rsquo;t entice you, know that the drinks are cheap!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]><p><b/></p><b>Telephone:</b><![CDATA[+61 8 7123 2935]]><br/><b>Website:</b><![CDATA[https://hqcomplex.com.au]]><br/><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/>149 Hindley Street<br/>5000</p><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;ve come out to dance, this mega-club is the best place to go. With five floors pumping with music and fantastic lighting, HQ Complex has the atmosphere to get everyone having a good time. With multiple cocktail bars, the drinks are cheap and well-prepared. Live bands play almost every night of the week.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]><p><b/></p><b>Telephone:</b><![CDATA[+61 8 8212 7433.]]><br/><b>Website:</b><![CDATA[http://www.crippenplace.com]]><br/><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/>17 Crippen Place<br/>5000</p><![CDATA[<p>Situated down an otherwise innocent looking alleyway in Adelaide&rsquo;s West End, Electric Circus is found behind the doors of Crippen Place, which also hosts the live music venue Rocket Bar upstairs. Expect international and local DJs performing every Friday and Saturday night. If you do need a break from dancing, head up to the top floor, where Rocket Bar operates a rooftop bar and cinema with 360-degree views of Adelaide.</p>]]><p><b/></p><b>Telephone:</b><![CDATA[+61 8 8443 5255.]]><br/><b>Website:</b><![CDATA[http://www.thebartontheatre.com.au]]><br/><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/>112 Henley Beach Road<br/>5031</p><![CDATA[<p>Better known as &quot;Thebby&rsquo;s&quot;, the Thebarton Theatre is a 2000-capacity venue that promotes a range of shows; from up-and-coming bands breaking onto the circuit to more established artists looking to play a more intimate show in Adelaide. The theatre boasts original decor dating back to the 1920s and hosts a number of concert and comedy performances every week. Check the official website for listings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Restaurants"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[
        Restaurants
      ]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Introduction" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Restaurants
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With more restaurants per head than any other Australian capital city, Adelaide offers some of the country&rsquo;s most authentic and multicultural eateries. Prices are relatively low compared to other Australian city restaurants.</p>
<p>The Adelaide restaurants below have been hand-selected by the author, and are grouped into three price bands:<br />
Expensive (over $40)<br />
Moderate ($20 to $40)<br />
Cheap (up to $20)</p>
<p>The above prices are for a main course, including a glass of house wine or soft drink. Tipping is not customary in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a> but diners tend to tip when the service and food have been good.</p>]]><p><b>Jolleys Boathouse</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Set on the banks of the River Torrens, this tucked away boathouse is a stylish restaurant with friendly, down-to-earth staff. Watch the boats and black swans sail by as you feast alfresco. Or gaze through the floor-to-ceiling windows, warmly sat by the flickering fire during winter, banqueting on elaborate seasonal produce.</p>
<p>The menu features suckling pig with caramelised shallots, grass-fed Cape Grim Scotch fillet, roast kangaroo loin and share plates. The crisp-skin barramundi is always cooked to perfection.</p>]]><b>Cuisine: </b><![CDATA[Contemporary Australian]]><br/><b>Telephone: </b><![CDATA[+61 8 8223 2891.]]><br/><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://www.jolleysboathouse.com]]><br/><b>Price: </b><![CDATA[Expensive]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/><br/>1 Jolleys Lane<br/>5000</p><p><b>Let Them Eat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Known locally as the vegetarian caf&eacute; that meat-eaters crave, Let Them Eat offers sophisticated, homemade dishes that are nutrient-packed and chemical and preservative free. Some dishes are suitable for vegans.</p>
<p>Tanya Angius, the caf&eacute;&rsquo;s highly experienced chef, only prepares wholefood that she would be prepared to eat herself. The seductive cabinets have a multi-coloured display of salads that feature quinoa, cracked wheat, mung beans, lentils and chickpeas. Also enjoy outstanding handmade pies, quiches, wholemeal pastries and cakes. The pumpkin and red lentil lasagne is faultless.</p>]]><b>Cuisine: </b><![CDATA[Vegetarian/ Vegan.]]><br/><b>Telephone: </b><![CDATA[+61 8 8211 9302]]><br/><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://www.let-them-eat.com.au]]><br/><b>Price: </b><![CDATA[Cheap]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/><br/>Adelaide Central Markets 44, 44-60 Gouger Street<br/>5000</p><p><b>Pancakes At The Port</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For a fluffy range of sweet and savoury buttermilk-rich pancakes, head to Port Adelaide. As well as the traditional maple syrup, whipped butter and fruit types, this family operated business excels at Hawaiian pancakes topped with ham and pineapple. The sizzling Cajun chicken breast dish with potato chunks and salad is also a fine choice. Sit at a waterside table and watch the resident dolphins glide by.</p>]]><b>Cuisine: </b><![CDATA[American]]><br/><b>Telephone: </b><![CDATA[+61 8 8447 1877.]]><br/><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://www.pancakesattheport.com]]><br/><b>Price: </b><![CDATA[Cheap]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/>Port Adelaide<br/>1 Mercantile Dock<br/>5015</p><p><b>Burger Theory</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Adopting recipes from Adelaide&rsquo;s famous Burger Truck, this East End diner is a hip and funky joint that attracts the bohemian crowd. It&rsquo;s so good that it often has queues into the street. Their Angus beef is ground by hand, with burgers dressed in the diner&rsquo;s Truck Sauce (a tightly-held recipe containing 12 secret ingredients). It&rsquo;s your typical American diner in the middle of South Australia.</p>]]><b>Cuisine: </b><![CDATA[American]]><br/><b>Telephone: </b><![CDATA[+61 426 763 930.]]><br/><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://www.burgertheory.com]]><br/><b>Price: </b><![CDATA[Cheap]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/><br/>8-10 Union Street<br/>5000</p><p><b>2KW Bar and Restaurant</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An eighth floor restaurant on the corner of King William Street and North Terrace, 2KW Bar and Restaurant offers great views of Adelaide in addition to a unique menu made up of traditional Australian dishes creatively prepared. These dishes are made for sharing, so grab a bunch of your friends and enjoy the food and views in 2KW&rsquo;s rooftop garden.</p>]]><b>Cuisine: </b><![CDATA[Australian]]><br/><b>Telephone: </b><![CDATA[+61 8 8212 5511.]]><br/><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://www.2kwbar.com.au]]><br/><b>Price: </b><![CDATA[Moderate]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/><br/>2 King William Street<br/>5000</p><p><b>Penfolds Magill Estate Restaurant</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At the birthplace of Penfolds wine, Magill Estate Restaurant is the number one establishment for discerning wine and dine connoisseurs. Their Michelin-starred chef doesn&rsquo;t just match whites with whites and reds with reds, but expertly fine-tunes flavours, weights and textures between wine and food. The restaurant houses a state-of-the-art, purpose-built underground cellar. Choice menu selections are the Coorong mullet and blue swimmer crab, to be enjoyed overlooking the estate&rsquo;s vineyards and city beyond.</p>]]><b>Cuisine: </b><![CDATA[Contemporary Australian]]><br/><b>Telephone: </b><![CDATA[+61 8 8301 5551.]]><br/><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://www.magillestaterestaurant.com]]><br/><b>Price: </b><![CDATA[Expensive]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/><br/>78 Penfold Road<br/>5072</p><p><b>Sq Restaurant</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Overlooking leafy Hindmarsh Square, this modern restaurant is kitted out with a polished timber floor and furnishings between red and brown walls. Enjoy Asian-influenced modern Australian dishes using the freshest South Australian ingredients. Favourites include chargrilled prawns with watermelon <em>nahm jim</em>, green duck leg curry with rice and mango pickle, wagyu pie with beetroot chutney and twice-cooked goat&rsquo;s cheese souffl&eacute;. Save a spot for the illegally good coconut panna cotta, laced with Malibu ice cream.</p>]]><b>Cuisine: </b><![CDATA[Asian]]><br/><b>Telephone: </b><![CDATA[+61 8 8412 3397]]><br/><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://www.mantrahindmarshsquare.com.au/facilities/sq-restaurant/]]><br/><b>Price: </b><![CDATA[Moderate]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/><br/>55-67 Hindmarsh Square<br/>5000</p><p><b>The Bistro</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Bistro cooks up succulently fresh Adelaide Hills produce within a stylish and contemporary space. The indoor d&eacute;cor of the restaurant is filled with nooks and corners that merge harmoniously with the leafy alfresco section.</p>
<p>Enjoy regional and seasonal local fare, and chew in time to the beats of the weekend DJs and live bands. It&rsquo;s the perfect place to socialise over an exciting range of shared plates, with terrific examples including the Kilpatrick oysters and salt and pepper baby squid.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]><b>Cuisine: </b><![CDATA[Modern international]]><br/><b>Telephone: </b><![CDATA[+61 8 8339 2345.]]><br/><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://www.stirlinghotel.com.au/bistro/]]><br/><b>Price: </b><![CDATA[Moderate]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/><br/>52 Mount Barker Road<br/>5152</p><p><b>Peel Street</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hip and popular, this locale is a treat for wine-lovers and food connoisseurs alike.  The menu, written by hand upon a huge black board hung on the wall, changes regularly, but each share plate is thoughtfully prepared and beautifully presented. The emphasis here is on creating the most favourable combinations of flavours and textures&mdash;but to fully enjoy the experience, be prepared to be adventurous! Consider trying, for instance, the Banana Blossom Chicken.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]><b>Cuisine: </b><![CDATA[Australian]]><br/><b>Telephone: </b><![CDATA[+61 8 8231 8887]]><br/><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://www.peelst.com.au]]><br/><b>Price: </b><![CDATA[Expensive]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/><br/>9 Peel Street<br/>5000</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ToursoftheCity"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[
        Tours of the City
      ]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="ToursoftheCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
         Tours
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Market Tour</b><![CDATA[<p>Adelaide&rsquo;s Central Market is one of Australia&rsquo;s largest fresh produce markets, so a visit can be a little bewildering. To ensure you don&rsquo;t miss the highlights, join gastronome experts from Central Market Tour as they open eyes and turn on taste buds with a 1 hour 30 minute wander around this foodie heaven.</p>]]><b>Gondola Tour</b><![CDATA[<p>For an alternative&ndash;and rather romantic&ndash;view of the city, step aboard an authentic Venetian gondola tour. Adelaide Gondola can carry up to six people along the River Torrens, as visitors slowly and silently take in the sights with a glass of something sparkling to sip from. Tours generally last from 40 minutes to 1 hour and can be booked at any time during the day and into the evening.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="FurtherDistractions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[
        Further Distractions
      ]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FurtherDistractions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><p><b>South Australian Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the most visited museums in Australia, the South Australian Museum houses a collection of national and international significance. It is also a top research facility that is famous for its Aboriginal heritage collections. Visitors can check out artefacts from the South Pacific Islands, contemplate Egyptian antiquities, and learn about local plants and wildlife in the Biodiversity Gallery.</p>]]><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://www.samuseum.sa.gov.au]]><br/><b>Opening Times: </b><![CDATA[<p>Daily 1000-1700.</p>]]><br/><b>Admission Fees: </b><![CDATA[<p>No.</p>]]><br/><b>Attraction Type: </b><![CDATA[off-beat]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/><br/><br/></p><p><b>Tandanya National Aboriginal Cultural Institute</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This is an Aboriginal-owned gem, housing local and national Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander artwork in various galleries.&nbsp;Pieces are showcased from established and emerging artists displaying multimedia and traditional works. Indigenous experts are on hand to talk about the current artworks.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
The institute runs film events, dance performances and cultural presentations, while travelling exhibitions keep this gallery energetic and renewed.&nbsp;Don&rsquo;t miss the inventively shelved shop offering arts and crafts, as well as clothing, books, music and authentic didgeridoos.</p>]]><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://www.tandanya.com.au]]><br/><b>Opening Times: </b><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Sat 1000-1700.</p>]]><br/><b>Admission Fees: </b><![CDATA[<p>No (except for cultural performances).</p>]]><br/><b>Attraction Type: </b><![CDATA[off-beat]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/><br/><br/></p><p><b>Adelaide Zoo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Adelaide&rsquo;s Noah&rsquo;s Arc aims to save rare and endangered species from extinction. It has a furry, scaled, winged and finned community of over 3000 animals. Many are natives, as well as exotic species from across the globe.</p>
<p>Wang Wang and Fu Ni, the two pandas that arrived from China in 2009, are the only pair of giant pandas to reside permanently in the southern hemisphere. They can be seen at close proximity in their enclosure. On your travels, find Tasmanian devils, echidnas, potoroos and tree kangaroos as well as Hamadryas baboons, Sumatran tigers and Malayan Tapirs.</p>
<p>Animal-feeding and keeper talks feature daily, with a thrilling blue and gold macaw free flight show to challenge camera shutter lag. Free half-hour Walkabout Tours are offered daily.</p>]]><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://www.adelaidezoo.com.au]]><br/><b>Opening Times: </b><![CDATA[<p>Daily 0930-1700.</p>]]><br/><b>Admission Fees: </b><![CDATA[<p>Yes.</p>]]><br/><b>Attraction Type: </b><![CDATA[essential]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/><br/><br/></p><p><b>The Migration Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An intimate museum that tells the tale of early Australia and the mass migration from Britain. A story of courage, heartache and happiness, this sensory museum, the only one of its kind in the country, contains a priceless assemblage of personal stories and belongings, colonial costumes, bric-a-brac and toys that arrived with the white settlers.</p>
<p>Among the hundreds of old relics, see Colonel Light&rsquo;s plan of Adelaide, and private items belonging to the early explorer, John McDouall Stuart, the first European to trek the continent on foot. The building was once an Aboriginal boarding school and a destitute asylum for the homeless, sick and elderly.</p>]]><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://migration.history.sa.gov.au/]]><br/><b>Opening Times: </b><![CDATA[<p>Daily 1000-1700.</p>]]><br/><b>Admission Fees: </b><![CDATA[<p>No (except for tours).</p>]]><br/><b>Attraction Type: </b><![CDATA[off-beat]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/><br/><br/></p><p><b>National Railway Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Step back in time at this interactive railway museum, the largest of its kind in Australia. Examine the rolling stock of yesteryear by stepping inside charming carriages and peering into steam engines. Take a ride around the grounds on a train that chugs along the 457mm gauge railway.</p>
<p>Discover intriguing railway memorabilia, such as old cutlery used in the Trans Australian passenger trains and timeworn staff uniforms, or view a coffin cart from the 1880s, used to transport coffins.&nbsp;A highlight is the interactive Tea and Sugar Train carriages, which traversed the continent to deliver provisions to outback communities.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://www.natrailmuseum.org.au]]><br/><b>Opening Times: </b><![CDATA[<p>Daily 1000-1630</p>]]><br/><b>Admission Fees: </b><![CDATA[<p>Yes.</p>]]><br/><b>Attraction Type: </b><![CDATA[off-beat]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/><br/><br/></p><p><b>Haigh’s Chocolate Factory</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Established in 1915 by Alfred Haigh, this is one of the few chocolatiers in the world to create chocolate straight from the raw cacao bean. It&rsquo;s Australia&rsquo;s oldest family-run chocolate manufacturer, managed by fourth-generation family members.</p>
<p>Take a free tongue-tantalising tour of their factory and follow the life of the bean. Journey from when it is picked, through how cocoa nibs are ground into liqueur, to when it arrives in your mouth. There are even some deliciously sinful tastings. Watch the talented chefs in the factory, hand-dipping, hand-marking and hand-wrapping their chocolate treasures. Tea and coffee is provided.</p>]]><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://www.haighschocolates.com.au]]><br/><b>Opening Times: </b><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thu 0800-1900, Tue 0830-1750, Fri 1000-1700, Sat 0800-1750</p>]]><br/><b>Admission Fees: </b><![CDATA[<p>No.</p>]]><br/><b>Attraction Type: </b><![CDATA[off-beat]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="KeyAttractions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[
        Key Attractions
      ]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="KeyAttractions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          List of Attractions
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>State Library of South Australia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Founded two weeks after the passing of the South Australia Act by the British Parliament in 1834, the State Library of South Australia exhibits a catalogue of books and artefacts dating back to the 1800s. The library regularly houses temporary exhibitions and offers an audio tour of various Adelaide neighbourhoods and the library itself, available via an app (<a href="http://guides.slsa.sa.gov.au/walkingtoursapp" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">guides.slsa.sa.gov.au</a>) you can download to your phone.</p>]]><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://www.slsa.sa.gov.au]]><br/><b>Opening Times: </b><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Wed 1000-2000; Thu-Fri 1000-1800; Sat-Sun 1000-1700.</p>]]><br/><b>Admission Fees: </b><![CDATA[<p>No.</p>]]><br/><b>Attraction Type: </b><![CDATA[essential]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/><br/><br/></p><p><b>National Wine Centre of Australia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Adjoining the Adelaide Botanic Garden, the National Wine Centre of Australia is a striking architectural delight. Its Cellar Door eatery with courtyard offers cheese and wine tastings, as well as seasonal menus featuring wood-oven breads, Carpaccio, slow-cooked lamb shoulder and market fish.</p>
<p>The centre also hosts the Wine Discovery Journey, an interactive exhibition on Australia&rsquo;s world-respected wine industry. Track the lifespan of the grape, from planting to glass-swilling.</p>
<p>Lovers of the drop can also embark on wine-appreciation classes, featuring worldly vintages and new releases. The Wine Centre recently started a new event series, City Cellar Door, which celebrates local Australian wineries as well as local produce in a setting &ldquo;reminiscent of a mini-festival experience.&rdquo;</p>]]><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://www.wineaustralia.com.au]]><br/><b>Opening Times: </b><![CDATA[<p>Daily 0900-1800.</p>]]><br/><b>Admission Fees: </b><![CDATA[<p>Yes (for some events).</p>]]><br/><b>Attraction Type: </b><![CDATA[essential]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/><br/><br/></p><p><b>Art Gallery of South Australia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fronted by iconic Rodin sculptures, the Art Gallery of South Australia boasts one of the best collections in the country. Fittingly, it is the host of the Adelaide Biennial too, as it features nearly 40,000 pieces including Australian, European, Asian and North American collections, charting art from Aboriginal cultures, past Renaissance greats, through colonial styles to today's avant-garde.</p>
<p>Exhibitions regularly draw some of the most sought-after collections from across the globe, such as the recent exhibit of Saatchi's best-known pieces. The gallery's cutting-edge smartphone App, with a detailed audio tour, keeps visitors connected to artists and critics' insights for a truly engaging experience. The gallery hosts a vast range of events catered for all ages and tastes.</p>]]><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://www.artgallery.sa.gov.au/agsa/home]]><br/><b>Opening Times: </b><![CDATA[<p>Daily 1000-1700.</p>]]><br/><b>Admission Fees: </b><![CDATA[<p>No (apart from some exhibitions).</p>]]><br/><b>Attraction Type: </b><![CDATA[essential]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/><br/><br/></p><p><b>Adelaide Botanic Garden</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The city&rsquo;s beautiful green oasis showcases tree-lined avenues, rose gardens, palm houses, herb gardens, lily ponds, duck ponds, and rare and endangered plants. The striking Bicentennial Conservatory protects rare lowland tropical plants that would otherwise be at risk. Climb the upper walkway to filter through the tree canopy and view the forest floor below.</p>
<p>The Amazon Waterlily Pavilion contains the precious Victoria amazonica waterlily, while the recently developed First Creek Wetland contains about 20,000 plants, many native. Snake your way through the wetlands via viewing platforms, learning how this habitat offers life to plants, birds, reptiles, insects and fish through a comprehensive water-filtering process. Wander down Australia&rsquo;s oldest and prettiest avenue of Moreton Bay fig trees to capture dreamy photos.</p>]]><b>Website: </b><![CDATA[http://www.environment.sa.gov.au/botanicgardens/home]]><br/><b>Opening Times: </b><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0715-1900, Sat-Sun 0900-1900 (Dec-Jan); Mon-Fri 0715-1830, Sat-Sun 0900-1830 (Feb-Mar and Oct-Nov); Mon-Fri 0715-1800, Sat-Sun 0900-1800 (Apr and Sep); Mon-Fri 0715-1730, Sat-Sun 0900-1730 (May and Aug); Mon-Fri 0715-1700, Sat-Sun 0900-1700 (Jun-Jul).</p>]]><br/><b>Admission Fees: </b><![CDATA[<p>No.</p>]]><br/><b>Attraction Type: </b><![CDATA[essential]]><br/><p><b>Address: </b><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Sightseeing"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[
        Sightseeing
      ]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Tourist Information" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Tourist Information
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><div><h3>Adelaide Visitor Information Centre</h3><b>Address: </b><span>,
							9 James Place, off Rundle Mall,
							Adelaide,
							5000</span><br/><b>Telephone: </b>+61 1300 588 140.<br/><b>Opening times: </b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700; Sat-Sun 1000-1600. Holiday hours 1100-1500.&lt;/p&gt;<b>Website: </b><a href="https://www.cityofadelaide.com.au/explore-the-city/city-information/visitor-information/">https://www.cityofadelaide.com.au/explore-the-city/city-information/visitor-information/</a><br/>&lt;p&gt;Seek expert advice on exploring Adelaide by friendly staff that can offer sightseeing tips, issue maps, and make reservations on your behalf.&lt;/p&gt;</div></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Sightseeing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Passes
        ]]></DataTitle>&lt;p&gt;Adelaide Sightseeing (&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.adelaidesightseeing.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;www.adelaidesightseeing.com.au&lt;/a&gt;) offers a variety of packages for full day and half day tours. These range from a full day tour of Barossa&amp;rsquo;s Food and Wine culture to a half-day &amp;ldquo;Adelaide City Highlights&amp;rdquo; tour.&lt;/p&gt;<DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="GettingAround"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[
        Getting Around
      ]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAround" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Public Transport
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Adelaide Metro (tel: 1300 311 108, in Australia only; <a href="http://www.adelaidemetro.com.au" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.adelaidemetro.com.au</a>) runs the bus, train and tram network. You can obtain single-trip and day-trip tickets on-board or from ticket vending machines within InfoCentres at Adelaide Railway Station and from metrocard agents. The rechargeable metrocard, which cannot be purchased onboard, allows you to preload credit for trips.</p>
<p>There is also an unlimited-travel 3-day Visitor Pass, as well as a 28-day pass. The 28-day pass offers a discount off the cost of 40 trips on the bus, train, and tram, and any trips you take beyond this number are free.</p>
<p>The O-Bahn is a unique guided busway. It travels up to 100kph (62mph) on custom-built tracks (inaccessible to other vehicles) between Adelaide City Centre and Tea Tree Plaza Interchange.</p>
<p>The free 99A and 99C City Loop buses run half-hourly on weekdays, serving the inner-city areas. The 98A and 98C connects the city with North Adelaide, running half-hourly every day. You can spot Adelaide&rsquo;s carbon-neutral Tindo bus (the world&rsquo;s first 100% solar-powered electric bus) on this route.</p>
<p>Tram rides between the Entertainment Centre and South Terrace are free. Bicycles can be carried on trains free of charge during off-peak times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAround" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Taxis
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Reliable taxi companies in Adelaide include Suburban Taxis (tel: +61 8 8400 6280; <a href="http://www.suburbantaxis.com.au/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.suburbantaxis.com.au</a>), Adelaide Independent Taxis (tel: 13 22 11, in Australia only; <a href="http://www.aitaxis.com.au/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.aitaxis.com.au</a>), and Yellow Cab Co&nbsp;(tel: +61 8 7087 9300; <a href="http://www.yellowcabgroup.com.au" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.yellowcabgroup.com.au</a>).</p>
<p>You can find staff-managed taxi ranks throughout the city, including near the Railway Station on North Terrace, by the Exeter Hotel on Rundle Street, and next to the Hilton Hotel on Victoria Square. It's not mandatory to tip taxis in Adelaide, but passengers frequently do to reward good servicee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAround" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Driving in the City
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With its grid orientation and wide roads (originally designed so that horse-and-carts could perform U-turns), Adelaide is mostly gifted with jam-free traffic.</p>
<p>Free parking in the city is restricted, especially during weekdays, but there's plenty of ticketed parking available, both in council and private car parks as well as on the street. Adelaide has no toll roads.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAround" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Car Hire
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Reputable car hire companies include Avis (tel: +61 8 8114 3111; <a href="http://www.avis.com.au" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.avis.com.au</a>), Budget (tel: +61 8 8418 7300; <a href="http://www.budget.com.au" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.budget.com.au</a>), Europcar (tel: +61 8 8114 6350; <a href="http://www.europcar.com.au" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.europcar.com.au</a>), Hertz (tel: +61 8 8231 2856; <a href="http://www.hertz.com.au" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.hertz.com.au</a>) and Thrifty (tel: +61 8 8410 8977; <a href="http://www.thrifty.com.au" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.thrifty.com.au</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAround" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Bicycle Hire
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Adelaide is a relaxing city to pedal around, with wide, flat streets and boulevards. Free bike hire is available at multiple locations across the city, courtesy of Adelaide City Council and BikeSA (tel: +61 8 8168 9999; <a href="http://www.bikesa.asn.au/adelaidefreebikes" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.bikesa.asn.au/adelaidefreebikes</a>). Helmet, lock and map are included. Just show your photo ID and hop on your wheels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="History"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[
        History
      ]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="History" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
         Overview
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Like most Australian cities, Adelaide came into being in the 1800s (1836 to be exact), although prior to the arrival of Europeans, the surrounding land was settled by Aborigines. Known to the locals as Tandanya (&lsquo;The Place of the Red Kangaroo&rsquo;), more than 10,000 Aborigines were thought to have been living on the Adelaide Plains when the settlers landed in 1836.</p>
<p>The location for the new city was chosen by Colonel William Light, who picked a spot on the banks of the River Torrens that could force rainfall from the nearby Adelaide Hills. Underneath a gum tree in modern day Glenelg North, British governor John Hindmarsh proclaimed the colony South Australia on 28th December 1836.</p>
<p>Colonel Light also planned the city, laying streets out in a grid system and allowing for plenty of parklands and open space. In the beginning, however, Adelaide was a farming community, relying on wheat and sheep runs for sustenance.</p>
<p>Things changed in the 1840s when copper and silver were discovered nearby. In 1852, a gold rush ensued when significant quantities of the mineral were found. As a result, the city expanded and the University of Adelaide, the South Australian Art Gallery, and the Happy Valley Reservoir were all in situ by the dawn of the 20th century.</p>
<p>Waves of European immigrants followed, particularly after WWII, and the city built a university and Adelaide Airport in 1955. It wasn&rsquo;t all smooth sailing: a large earthquake in 1954 damaged Blackwood Hospital, the Victoria Hotel, the Post Office clock tower and St Francis Xavier Cathedral, leaving inhabitants shaken.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the city continued to grow and built its reputation for culture over the 1960s and 70s, culminating in the opening of the Festival Centre by Queen Elizabeth in 1977.</p>
<p>Today, Adelaide continues to grow and attract emigrants from all over the world, with progress and expansion looking set to continue into a fourth century.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull; Adelaide was named after Adelaide of Saxe-Meiningen, queen consort to King William IV and aunt of Queen Victoria.<br />
&bull; Colonel William Light, the man who surveyed and planned Adelaide, did the same for Christchurch in New Zealand. The cities are now twinned.<br />
&bull; Adelaide is the only major Australian city that didn&rsquo;t begin life as a penal colony.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Hotels"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[
        Hotels
      ]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Introduction" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Hotel List
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Clarion Soho Hotel</b>&gt;</p><![CDATA[<p>There are only 29 rooms at Clarion Soho Hotel, hence the focus on quality over quantity. With modern Manhattan interiors, commodious king-size beds, crisp white linen and Missoni cushions, comfort and style intertwine in the sleeping chambers. Each room also comes with 42-inch LCD TVs, DVD players with free DVD hire, luxury spa products, iPod docks and cable broadband internet. Don&rsquo;t miss the restaurant with Tom Dixon feature lighting, Kartell chairs and a marble bar imported from Italy.</p>]]><b>Address: </b><span>,
								264 Flinders Street,
								Adelaide,
								5000</span><br/><b>Telephone: </b><![CDATA[+61 8 8412 5600.]]><br/><b>Website: </b><a href="http://www.thesohohotel.com.au">http://www.thesohohotel.com.au</a><br/><p><b>Adabco Boutique Hotel</b>&gt;</p><![CDATA[<p>Set in a striking Venetian gothic-style building, this hotel offers all the luxuries of a boutique bolthole without the usual chequebook costs. The heritage house is dotted with period furniture including red Chesterfield sofas, and all sleeping chambers come with decent-sized bathrooms, large LCD TVs, broadband and crisp white linen. A breakfast buffet is included.</p>]]><b>Address: </b><span>,
								223 Wakefield Street,
								Adelaide,
								5000</span><br/><b>Telephone: </b><![CDATA[+61 8 8100 7500.]]><br/><b>Website: </b><a href="http://www.adabcohotel.com.au">http://www.adabcohotel.com.au</a><br/><p><b>The Hotel Metropolitan</b>&gt;</p><![CDATA[<p>Doubling as a hotel and a pub, this historic location dates back to 1883, and is conveniently placed opposite the Adelaide Central Market and a short walk from the Adelaide Railway Station. Although the rooms are small, the amenities are numerous: a game room with complimentary snacks, outdoor dining and live entertainment, and an art gallery. The guest list is mature&mdash;you must be 16 or older to stay.</p>]]><b>Address: </b><span>,
								46 Grote Street,
								Adelaide,
								5000</span><br/><b>Telephone: </b><![CDATA[+61 8 8231 5471]]><br/><b>Website: </b><a href="http://hotelmetro.com.au">http://hotelmetro.com.au</a><br/><p><b>Hotel Ibis Adelaide</b>&gt;</p><![CDATA[<p>Located in the Central Business District, the Ibis Hotel boasts 311 fresh and modern rooms, a ground-floor restaurant and bar with world-class food, and balconies so guests can enjoy the fresh Adelaide air. Wi-Fi, online check-in and an all-you-can-eat breakfast buffet are complimentary.</p>]]><b>Address: </b><span>,
								122 Grenfell Street,
								Adelaide,
								5000</span><br/><b>Telephone: </b><![CDATA[+61 8 8159 5588.]]><br/><b>Website: </b><a href="https://www.accorhotels.com/gb/hotel-8822-ibis-adelaide/index.shtml">https://www.accorhotels.com/gb/hotel-8822-ibis-adelaide/index.shtml</a><br/><p><b>Largs Pier Hotel</b>&gt;</p><![CDATA[<p>Luxury suites and motel rooms await at the Largs Pier Hotel. Built in 1882 and still dominating the seafront by Largs Bay Pier, this is the hotel where AC/DC and Jimmy Barnes played before they were famous. Heritage rooms are a sensory mix of lofty ceilings and cutting edge bathrooms, complete with king-size, four-poster beds. One suite also contains a dining room. The hotel is the site of the very first drive-through bottle shop in Australia.</p>]]><b>Address: </b><span>Largs Bay,
								198 Esplanade,
								Adelaide,
								5016</span><br/><b>Telephone: </b><![CDATA[+61 8 8449 5666.]]><br/><b>Website: </b><a href="http://www.largspierhotel.com.au">http://www.largspierhotel.com.au</a><br/><p><b>Majestic Minima Hotel</b>&gt;</p><![CDATA[<p>This artsy hotel stands out not only for its green and silver modern-style exterior, but also its unbeatable location in the heart of North Adelaide. Each of Minima Hotel&rsquo;s 46 rooms was painted by a local Australian artist, giving every room a unique feel and aesthetic. Guests can look at the website and request a specific room or be surprised when they walk through the door. Expect decorations ranging from abstract ocean scenes to neon sculptures to a blown-up aboriginal alphabet.</p>]]><b>Address: </b><span>North Adelaide,
								146 Melbourne Street,
								Adelaide,
								5006</span><br/><b>Telephone: </b><![CDATA[+61 8 8334 7766.]]><br/><b>Website: </b><a href="http://www.minimahotel.com.au">http://www.minimahotel.com.au</a><br/><p><b>Majestic Roof Garden Hotel</b>&gt;</p><![CDATA[<p>At the Majestic Roof Garden Hotel, the guest experience is in the name&mdash;expect a gorgeous rooftop garden overlooking the city to compliment the usual amenities of a modern hotel, including free Wi-Fi, 24-hour room service and complimentary breakfast. The location is great for exploring downtown as well.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]><b>Address: </b><span>,
								55 Frome St,
								Adelaide,
								5000</span><br/><b>Telephone: </b><![CDATA[+61 8 8100 4400]]><br/><b>Website: </b><a href="http://www.roofgardenhotel.com.au/">http://www.roofgardenhotel.com.au/</a><br/><p><b>Miller Apartments</b>&gt;</p><![CDATA[<p>One of Adelaide's newest luxury aparthotels, Miller Apartments provides a new level of comfort with fully equipped kitchens, living areas, free Wi-Fi, LED TVs, and an environmentally friendly approach to accommodation. Located at the Rundle Mall side of the vibrant West End, visitors of all ages can appreciate what that city centre has to offer without straying far from the comfort of their own private apartment.</p>]]><b>Address: </b><span>,
								16 Hindley Street,
								Adelaide,
								5000</span><br/><b>Telephone: </b><![CDATA[+61 8 8410 1888.]]><br/><b>Website: </b><a href="http://www.millerapartments.com.au">http://www.millerapartments.com.au</a><br/><p><b>Mayfair Hotel</b>&gt;</p><![CDATA[<p>One of the finest options for accommodation and fine dining in Adelaide. The heritage-listed, newly renovated Colonial Mutual Life building offers high-end dining facilities in addition to stylish suites and rooms. It also supports local business by furnishing the interior in South Australian products, from the comfortable beds to marble top desks and side tables.</p>]]><b>Address: </b><span>,
								45 King William Street,
								Adelaide,
								5000</span><br/><b>Telephone: </b><![CDATA[+61 8 8210 8888.]]><br/><b>Website: </b><a href="http://www.mayfairhotel.com.au">http://www.mayfairhotel.com.au</a><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="CityStatistics"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[
        City Statistics
      ]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Location
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-34.925770]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[138.599732]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TimeZone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Time zone
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Australian Central Standard Time:</strong> GMT/UTC +9:30 (GMT/UTC +10:30 from 6 October to 31 March 2018)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Road"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[
        Getting There By Road
      ]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Road" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Overview
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving regulations across <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/oceania/australia/">Australia</a> differ from state to state, so visitors should make note of any law changes between <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/oceania/australia/south-australia/">South Australia</a> and other territories. The legal age for driving without supervision in South Australia is 18 years.</p>
<p>Traffic drives on the left in Australia with speed limits of 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas and 100kph (62mph) outside built-up areas unless a road sign indicates otherwise.</p>
<p>There are large, good quality roads in and around Adelaide, and the city is linked by main routes to other major cities in Australia.</p>
<p>Short-term visitors to South Australia must have an overseas licence in English, a licence with an English translation or an international driver's licence. You also need an International Driving Permit issued in the country where your licence was issued. You must carry your licence at all times when driving. Third-party insurance is also compulsory in South Australia.</p>
<p>Due to extreme weather conditions, it is also advisable to contact one of Australia's motoring organisations if you plan to drive into the outback. They can offer advice and distribute maps for more remote regions.</p>
<p>The Australian Automobile Association (tel: +61 2 6247 7311; <a href="http://www.aaa.asn.au" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.aaa.asn.au</a>) provides further information. The National Roads and Motorists' Association (NMRA) (tel: 13 11 22, in Australia only; <a href="http://www.mynrma.com.au" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.mynrma.com.au</a>) also provides information and motoring services.</p>]]><b>Emergency breakdown services: </b><![CDATA[<p>Royal Automobile Association (RAA) (tel: +61 8 8202 4600).</p>]]><b>Routes: </b><![CDATA[<p>Adelaide is linked with <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/oceania/australia/new-south-wales/sydney/">Sydney</a> by the Hume Highway and Stuart Highway; <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/oceania/australia/victoria/melbourne/">Melbourne</a> by the Western Highway and Dukes Highway and by the more scenic Great Ocean Road and Princes Highway; <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/oceania/australia/western-australia/perth/">Perth</a> by the Great Eastern and Eyre Highway; and Alice Springs by the Stuart Highway.</p>]]><b>Coaches: </b><![CDATA[<p>The main coach operator is Greyhound Australia (tel: +61 7 3155 1550; <a href="http://www.greyhound.com.au" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.greyhound.com.au</a>), which links Adelaide with major cities like Canberra, <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/oceania/australia/queensland/brisbane/">Brisbane</a>, Melbourne and Sydney as well as over 1,000 smaller destinations. Firefly Express (tel: +61 3 8318 0318; <a href="http://www.fireflyexpress.com.au" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.fireflyexpress.com.au</a>) runs daily coaches connecting Adelaide with Melbourne and Sydney.</p>]]><b>Driving times: </b><b>Time to city: </b><![CDATA[<p>From Sydney - 14 hours 25 minutes; Melbourne - 8 hours 10 minutes; Perth - 28 hours; Alice Springs - 16 hours 10 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Rail"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[
        Getting There By Rail
      ]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Rail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Services]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Adelaide has a good local railway network as well as interstate lines connecting the city with the rest of Australia.</p>
<p>The main hub for local trains is Adelaide Railway Station, located at 125 North Terrace. Interstate trains arrive and depart from Adelaide Parklands Terminal on Richmond Road, 3km (1.9 miles) west of the city centre.</p>]]><p><b>Operators: </b>&lt;p&gt;Adelaide Metro (tel: 1300 311 108, in Australia; &lt;a href="http://www.adelaidemetro.com.au" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;www.adelaidemetro.com.au&lt;/a&gt;) offers reliable rail services across the city and the state. Its central routes are extensive with four lines giving access to the suburbs. Trains reach as far north as Gawler Central, run south to Belair, go southwest to Seaford Interchange, and reach Grange and Outer Harbor in the west. A tram line from Entertainment Centre to Glenelg is good for covering the Central Business District.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great Southern Rail (tel: +61 8 8213 4401; &lt;a href="http://www.greatsouthernrail.com.au" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;www.greatsouthernrail.com.au&lt;/a&gt;) operates several classic journeys to and from Adelaide. The Indian Pacific runs from &lt;a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/oceania/australia/new-south-wales/sydney/"&gt;Sydney&lt;/a&gt; to Adelaide and from Adelaide to &lt;a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/oceania/australia/western-australia/perth/"&gt;Perth&lt;/a&gt;. The Ghan goes from Adelaide to Alice Springs and onto &lt;a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/oceania/australia/northern-territory/darwin/"&gt;Darwin&lt;/a&gt;, while The Overland runs between Adelaide and &lt;a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/oceania/australia/victoria/melbourne/"&gt;Melbourne&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Rail Passes: </b></p><p><b>Journey Times: </b>&lt;p&gt;From Sydney - 21 hours 45 minutes; Perth - 3 days and 2 nights; Alice Springs - 2 days and 1 night; Darwin - 54 hours; Melbourne - 10 hours 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Transfer: </b></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Air"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[
        Getting There By Air
      ]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Air" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Flying to ]]><xls:value-of select="@title"/></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no direct flights from the <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/europe/united-kingdom/">UK</a> to Adelaide but connections can be made via Dubai, Perth, Kuala Lumpur, Singapore, Hong Kong, Doha, Melbourne and Sydney. Airlines include British Airways, Emirates, Malaysia Airlines, Virgin Australia, Qantas and Singapore Airlines. From the USA, you can fly via Sydney, Melbourne or Brisbane with Virgin Australia. The cheapest time to fly is usually between mid-April and mid-June. School holidays and Christmas tend to be the most expensive.</p>]]><b>Flight times: </b><![CDATA[<p>From <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/europe/united-kingdom/england/london/">London</a> &ndash; 21 hours 30 minutes; <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/north-america/united-states-of-america/new-york-state/new-york-city/">New York</a> &ndash; 26 hours; <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/north-america/united-states-of-america/california/los-angeles/">Los Angeles</a> - 19 hours; <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/oceania/australia/new-south-wales/sydney/">Sydney</a> - 2 hours 10 minutes; <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/north-america/canada/ontario/toronto/">Toronto</a> - 26 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="CityOverview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[
        Overview
      ]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Overview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[
          Overview
        ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hedged in by a perimeter of eucalyptus-packed Park Lands, Adelaide salivates the palates of food travellers, festival-loving partygoers and free-spirited culture lovers alike.</p>
<p>Compact enough for easy, on-foot navigation, the city still has an air of enormous space. It&rsquo;s flanked by the European-like Adelaide Hills to its east and world-renowned wineries to its north and south, and garlanded with a dune-draped coastline.</p>
<p>Its majestic boulevards, cobbled laneways and quaint parklets ooze charm and grace. It is refined with some of the country&rsquo;s most handsome colonial architecture.</p>
<p>Being Australia&rsquo;s food capital, Adelaide has perfected the art of oiling taste buds. Find local produce on the stalls of the city&rsquo;s markets; savour it through the hands of expert chefs in the city&rsquo;s hotels or the picturesque Adelaide Hills.</p>
<p>From cheese specialists to ChocoVino winery tours at German-settled Hahndorf, join the slow-food movement that the Adelaideans have passionately embraced. Take a ride out to the Barossa Valley, the Clare Valley and McLaren Vale to sip South Australia&rsquo;s finest vintages.</p>
<p>Adelaide has a menagerie of museums, galleries and shops, showcasing local artworks and installations, precious Aboriginal relics, railway and shipping artefacts and early settler migration memorabilia.</p>
<p>Flash your wallet in Adelaide&rsquo;s gleaming department stores, or find quirky boutiques selling one-off designs, hidden down hip alleyways.<br />
Craving some salt on the skin? The vibrant seaside village of Glenelg is just a quick tram-ride away. Swim with wild dolphins in Gulf St Vincent, before satiating yourself at the seductive restaurants of Holdfast Shores&rsquo; glitzy strip.</p>
<p>Northwest of the city is North Haven, where you can expend some adrenaline kiteboarding. Or head southwest to Waitpinga and get your cool on by surfing the wild crests and challenging sets of this untamed beach.</p>
<p>Dubbed &lsquo;the Festival City,&rsquo; Adelaide is awash with world music, theatre and dance. She keeps all who visit on their toes and in her palm.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
